<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H85776BC7BD1C4FD7BABDA825D6867DD1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7310 RH: Protecting America’s Retirement Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 471</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7310</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–557, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>Referral to the Committee on Ways and Means, extended grace period ending not later than January 2, 2023</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 31, 2022</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Referral to the Committee on<committee-name committee-id="HWM00"> Ways and Means</committee-name> extended for a period ending not later than January 2, 2023</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 31, 2022</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect America’s retirement security, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H0A9E9E58D9BF48368AEB325EC1253571"><section id="H65F9057EF8744ADB8C02F13752977F95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HD96898C8045F4313BD67E192FD9720AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting America’s Retirement Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02A42C541B01454BAF9C0A6FCDA7CE0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc-entry idref="H65F9057EF8744ADB8C02F13752977F95" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFD10B5FCA59F4118AFA86690A033416B" level="section">Sec. 2. Defined contribution plan fee disclosure improvements.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB16D2376424648A5B939E57CEAE1C0EF" level="section">Sec. 3. Personal finance education portal.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6425B102B5E844B79708BA9345A4BAF5" level="section">Sec. 4. Increasing spousal protection under defined contribution plans.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H36FD3BC2521A48F8BC8D215B753828C4" level="section">Sec. 5. Automatic reenrollment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H73966319F6EA401CBFE7AA8E850EF558" level="section">Sec. 6. Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H171E06EC8CF742F59ECFE3DC66008BA2" level="section">Sec. 7. Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HFD10B5FCA59F4118AFA86690A033416B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Defined contribution plan fee disclosure improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall review section 2550.404a-5 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, and explore how the content and design of the covered disclosures may be improved to enhance participants’ understanding of fees and expenses as well as the cumulative effect of fees and expenses on retirement savings over time. As part of such review, the Secretary shall conduct outreach to stakeholders, including those representing plan sponsors and retirement plan participants.</text></section><section id="HB16D2376424648A5B939E57CEAE1C0EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Personal finance education portal</header><subsection id="H56131E2BA16F4D8CB794BA4410A154F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of the Treasury as chair of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission, and the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, shall create a personal finance education portal on a centralized and publicly available website of the Department of Education pertaining to Federal financial aid for voluntary use by recipients of aid awarded under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD47DFDCB2EB4D6C9FEC501B03A803B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of personal finance education portal</header><text>The personal finance education portal created under subsection (a) shall include information on personal finance concepts, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H037F503FB9EC4600A568FB8FD83E518B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Core personal finance concepts, such as earning, saving, investing, spending, and borrowing, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB244E3022DCE4525B076F8AA0DA7D00D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the concept of compound growth as it applies to savings and retirement savings, with information about the different types of retirement savings accounts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21615D97D0FF484DBD3E3820C2840236"><enum>(B)</enum><text>budgeting and credit usage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2D4B397CCB43CC97BA4AA598B41100"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Managing student loan repayment, including—</text><subparagraph id="HAEEE2C5912E74F8485A6447BDB8982DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the interaction between savings and retirement decisions and Federal student loan repayment plans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD08DD23DD64EA8B4A4A27BFEA7978E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal student loan discharge or forgiveness options;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B8F74F521B446609E4F21BFD110A1EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of voluntary benefits employers may use to help workers while they are paying down student loan debt;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H166C8AB55A2549E29623DC5D5D343B96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>tax credits or deductions that are relevant to student loan borrowers in repayment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD6DCFD9BF034CBD8FE3EEF2A0F3A077"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other Federal policies that significantly impact student loan borrowers in repayment, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AA6A17A98814AC19BD0C0C22A5D7E94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other personal finance concepts determined relevant by the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of the Treasury as chair of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission, and the Commissioner of Internal Revenue.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC982F81F92434134860788950DE83842"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of content</header><text>The personal finance content included under subsection (b) may be provided in an interactive format through text or video.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5A38F11D62E74E1BA4929B2F167D5CB7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Analytics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of the Treasury as chair of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission, and the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, shall review not less than once every three years the utilization of the portal, make recommendations to improve the portal, and make such findings and recommendations publicly available.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE4424A3B8564F7CB3A56B568F35398C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6425B102B5E844B79708BA9345A4BAF5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increasing spousal protection under defined contribution plans</header><subsection id="H785CABC8F0F0403DACBD22610C363D2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</header><paragraph id="H9708C7AB0A274D31A4B7043D4A829A16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part 2 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1051">29 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 205 the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H6FE35A3C129E46EE9BF03ECF66D41C92" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="HDE3561E115994F5F814B21A0140ADC29"><enum>205A.</enum><header>Additional spousal consent requirements</header><subsection id="HB22E98AA829D47B98F75017C74704F47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each individual account plan to which section 205 does not apply (but to which this title otherwise applies) shall provide that, except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), no distribution may be made under the plan unless the spousal consent requirements of subsection (e) are met.</text></subsection><subsection id="H024C9692FD194380ADDCA2A208ABA3CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with section 205</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to exempt an individual account plan from the requirements of paragraph (1)(B), (1)(C), or (2) of section 205(b) with respect to any participant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7C7361B3636C4BEF80E31343CE7670AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions for certain distributions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="HDD09164505974B8E8FA04A55B077B26D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any distribution that is—</text><subparagraph id="H3EBEC9B0186C4061B49D54F579068FEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a minimum required distribution described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4974">section 4974(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFA7332D4F1644A0ACB95908E80AD69E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>permitted under section 203(e)(1) to be made without the consent of the participant;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC759884376AD4BDD8E2C945B48B77407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any distribution in the form of a qualified joint and survivor annuity (as defined in section 205(d)(1)), a qualified optional survivor annuity (as defined in section 205(d)(2)), a qualified preretirement survivor annuity (as defined in section 205(e)), or a series of substantially equal periodic payments (not less frequently than annually) made for the joint lives (or life expectancies) of the participant and the participant’s spouse; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25548F7E6B7843109CFF4AC5A0949FAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of a participant who does not elect a form of benefit described in paragraph (2) under the plan or who is participating in a plan that does not provide such a form of benefit, any distribution of the participant’s entire nonforfeitable accrued benefit if 50 percent of such accrued benefit is transferred to an individual retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(37)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of the spouse of the participant.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">A transfer described in paragraph (3) to an individual retirement plan shall be treated in the same manner as a transfer under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">section 408(d)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H1019310FED124B749D48EF0BF7922741"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions for certain rollover contributions</header><paragraph id="HFBE13CD3AE844B9F8938C6BB20999C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to any distribution that is an eligible rollover distribution (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/402">section 402(f)(2)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) made in the form of a direct trustee-to-trustee transfer within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(a)(31)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986—</text><subparagraph id="H865982BF77C14CBE9D0A85C735D11B13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to a plan to which this section or section 205 applies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37888B4CE20347BE808F70A8F396D158"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to an individual retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(37)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) if—</text><clause id="HBF1183835C90487DA4BAFFE351CF5082"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sole beneficiary of such plan is the spouse of the participant, or the spousal consent requirements of subsection (e) are met with respect to any designation of 1 or more other beneficiaries; and</text></clause><clause id="HA07D33FDAE854A51B202B446053932D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under the terms of the individual retirement plan, the beneficiary of such plan (whether the spouse or other beneficiary designated under subparagraph (A)) may not be changed unless—</text><subclause id="H0B184DAABEDE4F93837C2A7AD7E57CBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the spousal consent requirements of subsection (e) are met with respect to any such change; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3703BFA390F942B2B9AC792B3B22DC77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the spousal consent under clause (i) to the designation of a beneficiary other than the spouse expressly permits such designation to be changed without the further consent of the spouse.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBB42E2A903443129558E1B61417A203"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Labor may jointly issue regulations to implement subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0EB6F180F9D499FA8036765B17AC485"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Spousal consent requirements</header><paragraph id="H0D49788534FB4DA99CA9F52F48E1BA2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, except as provided in paragraph (2), the spousal consent requirements of this subsection are met with respect to any distribution or any designation or change of beneficiary if—</text><subparagraph id="H426D87E20A7E470ABC1316F1742419C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the plan provides to each participant, within a reasonable period of time before such distribution or designation or change of beneficiary is made and consistent with such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe, a written explanation of the rights of the participant and the participant’s spouse under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE31FC6772A6140A4B6FDD1A52D04D0B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the spouse of the participant consents in writing to the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79F599B3D2948B0BEBA2FDB2B5FB7C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a distribution, the written consent under subparagraph (B) is made during the consent period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB3A5EC41B49416B87F1DA2197192166"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the written consent under subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HE711EBFA16F047278FF4F6D8AC2E9BD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the effect of such distribution or designation or change of beneficiary; and</text></clause><clause id="H3702D70993764E4F90423E5F2468BDCD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is witnessed by a plan representative or a notary public.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B2D0F15316042A79B12FA53A3F98F83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of paragraph (1) (other than subparagraph (A) thereof) shall not apply with respect to any distribution or designation or change of beneficiary if a participant establishes to the satisfaction of the administrator that—</text><subparagraph id="HAEF8FEEA9ABC4331A70BDEFF0BD3FC06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is no spouse;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12FD71D188AC4EBEB24F232F8E7ED970"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the participant and the participant’s spouse have not been married for at least 1 year as of the date of the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D85D8262CEF4F4F82512D753E6AA905"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such consent cannot be obtained because—</text><clause id="H6E57F70049DD49108DDD2BA7F9C640EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the spouse cannot be located after taking documented search efforts in accordance with guidance from the Secretary of Labor;</text></clause><clause id="HEB88D2530EB94A1DA0A46405B141EDEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the participant to seek the spouse’s consent would be inappropriate; or</text></clause><clause id="H16B11CB271E9456A869031CDAE97B571"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of such other circumstances as the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may by regulations prescribe.</text></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary of Labor may issue regulations to implement this paragraph.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EEEFB229EE64B49ACBB60DEA965BDED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consent limited to spouse and event</header><text>Any written consent by a spouse under paragraph (1), or the establishment by a participant that an exception under paragraph (2) applies with respect to a spouse, shall be effective only with respect to that spouse and to the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary to which it relates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4EC96700F824510A379575760D495FF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consent period</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>consent period</quote> means, with respect to any distribution—</text><subparagraph id="HE10C6DDAB19F4B19BC6E75A77779DD3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 90-day period immediately preceding the date of such distribution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1A9E09688404B26A1482CA16E189F05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other period as the Secretary of the Treasury may provide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD65B96826DE463198A7C54A6B035079"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Discharge of plan from liability</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 205(c)(6) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H66121BE8AED64EE49311324606020B08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections of part 2 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 205 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1AE3B10BBBF6443FA4E3D5AB5CACFB10" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 205A. Additional spousal consent requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB91406F4E94F90BA2F20A6605E7A7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parallel amendment to section 205</header><text>Section 205(c)(2)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1055">29 U.S.C. 1055(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, because due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the participant to seek the spouse’s consent would be inappropriate</quote> after <quote>located</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CE21C2E632D49C3A52BAE1FCC74D684"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">Section 401(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after paragraph (17) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H78E9012019234C71B6448D263BA32FE3" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H20830997ACCB4773AB59AA330086598A"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Additional spousal consent requirements</header><subparagraph id="HDB5560EBEEAC49B38252511BF9E230A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent paragraph (11) does not apply to a defined contribution plan to which title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 applies, except as provided in subparagraphs (C) and (D), a trust forming part of such plan shall not constitute a qualified trust under this section unless no distribution may be made under the plan unless the spousal consent requirements of subparagraph (E) are met.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B149A897334244A6080207A23A6A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination with paragraph (11)</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to exempt a defined contribution plan from the requirements of subparagraph (B)(ii), (B)(iii), or (C) of paragraph (11) with respect to any participant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7811C371EE8D4DEBA7B3C1C5577C8D65"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions for certain distributions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to—</text><clause id="HC988F24F7AC54A448DA3F99FDD47D737"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any distribution that is—</text><subclause id="HE34CC779C2D1447EA23A26CD0FA3E0DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a minimum required distribution described in section 4974(b), or</text></subclause><subclause id="HDA87B4E2D88D4E9F9AE33432CE543DCA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>permitted under section 411(a)(11) to be made without the consent of the participant,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H036A3E2FCA6C4D7C9CB0EDE26540E41C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any distribution in the form of a qualified joint and survivor annuity (as defined in section 417(b)), a qualified optional survivor annuity (as defined in section 417(g)), a qualified preretirement survivor annuity (as defined in section 417(c)), or a series of substantially equal periodic payments (not less frequently than annually) made for the joint lives (or life expectancies) of the participant and the participant’s spouse, or</text></clause><clause id="HDC6CCEEA351143E788CF49FE14FF6CAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a participant who does not elect a form of benefit described in clause (ii) under the plan or who is participating in a plan that does not provide such a form of benefit, any distribution of the participant’s entire nonforfeitable accrued benefit if 50 percent of such accrued benefit is directly transferred to an individual retirement plan of the spouse of the participant.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">A transfer described in clause (iii) to an individual retirement plan shall be treated in the same manner as a transfer under section 408(d)(6) and shall be deemed not to violate paragraph (2) or (13). </continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC615A09C8CE4C878DEB87F49F417360"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exceptions for certain rollover contributions</header><clause id="HBE8F8ECC88D2428F901622FAD548BE37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any distribution, involving a participant who has a spouse, that is an eligible rollover distribution (as defined in section 402(f)(2)(A)) made in the form of a direct trustee-to-trustee transfer within the meaning of paragraph (31)—</text><subclause id="H599FE459212D4888AEDCDAEC2E9430B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to a plan to which this paragraph or paragraph (11) applies; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5EFD1228748D4F7FB68DE4E20E066EC2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to an individual retirement plan if—</text><item id="H50FAF2E7239342FA9E1E094F14A81154"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the sole beneficiary of such plan is the spouse of the participant, or the spousal consent requirements of subparagraph (E) are met with respect to any designation of 1 or more other beneficiaries; and</text></item><item id="HEEDAC9F145494997907B43F2701730E9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>under the terms of the individual retirement plan, the beneficiary of such plan (whether the spouse or other beneficiary designated under clause (i)) may not be changed unless—</text><subitem id="H352A9FC24255499E89E705F989787AFB"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the spousal consent requirements of subparagraph (E) are met with respect to any such change, or</text></subitem><subitem id="HE965706AA68E4189A39A94A010E37D37"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the spousal consent under subclause (I) to the designation of a beneficiary other than the spouse expressly permits such designation to be changed without the further consent of the spouse.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB410E6C47AE24476B658D283432607BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may issue regulations to implement subparagraphs subclauses (I) and (II) or clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B37954107D746DDA35CB48D101B8237"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Spousal consent requirements</header><clause id="HE1E04ED1243C4F128FDBD17BE68ACAA8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, except as provided in clause (ii), the spousal consent requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any distribution or any designation or change of beneficiary if—</text><subclause id="H3E5929F06F4B420B8A28D729F46C473A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan provides to each participant, within a reasonable period of time before such distribution or designation or change of beneficiary is made and consistent with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, a written explanation of the rights of the participant and the participant’s spouse under this paragraph,</text></subclause><subclause id="HA99D37DA472143A0BA1EF3FDD472D263"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the spouse of the participant consents in writing to the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary,</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF789CF3D4E8481FBFDB27985B7D0B84"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of a distribution, the written consent under subclause (II) is made during the consent period, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7197645CA0C3474B8CC0D2F2FBD10C05"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the written consent under subclause (ii)—</text><item id="H4EA3B87023904ED4A596B080C7BFA565"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>acknowledges the effect of such distribution or designation or change of beneficiary, and</text></item><item id="H8F415A46118345388FF0215C3209ED4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is witnessed by a plan representative or a notary public.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HEC4E44580F084B77B3C2D1699A1EE902" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions under section 417(a)(2)(b) to apply</header><text>The requirements of clause (i) (other than subclause (I) thereof) shall not apply with respect to any distribution or designation or change of beneficiary if a participant establishes to the satisfaction of the administrator that—</text><subclause id="H38521931B15F4325BB406F3BC7B72C28" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is no spouse,</text></subclause><subclause id="H8BF829E9BC6F415D89E209308DC5C955" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the participant and the participant’s spouse have not been married for at least 1 year as of the date of the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H2D4EE9B44E384B988C4B5FE9B23BFA65" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such consent cannot be obtained because—</text><item id="HD7C0F7AACE104612BBE3DD04B90E437D" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the spouse cannot be located after taking documented search efforts in accordance with guidance from the Secretary of Labor;</text></item><item id="H4056E46476144990B86C464CD5934481" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the participant to seek the spouse’s consent would be inappropriate; or</text></item><item id="H5AA881CD24B94E11915BB6D6F5422F48" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>of such other circumstances as the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may by regulations prescribe.</text></item></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, may issue regulations to implement this clause.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H36CBD535CBAD4194879D7012C156700C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consent limited to spouse and event</header><text>Any written consent by a spouse under clause (i), or the establishment by a participant that an exception under clause (ii) applies with respect to a spouse, shall be effective only with respect to that spouse and to the distribution or designation or change of beneficiary to which it relates.</text></clause><clause id="H022E4D5826AE4A4AAAE3BE0505C7121E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Consent period</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>consent period</quote> means, with respect to any distribution—</text><subclause id="H105C0CDBBC2649E0A56F5143F471E7FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 90-day period immediately preceding the date of such distribution, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E253823D61645D7A7F1D9802A371A7E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such other period as the Secretary may provide.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H36FD3BC2521A48F8BC8D215B753828C4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Automatic reenrollment</header><subsection id="H0E38042836C54A15B12165031167D73D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible automatic contribution arrangements</header><paragraph id="HF569C12DB8144958B2F08A95C7184B72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</header><text>Section 514(e)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1144">29 U.S.C. 1144(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC4D9BE3702D744F692166BAA1C0B681D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and moving the margins of such clauses 2 ems to the right,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30BC5AA2CBF84A34A78A6654952AACD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2) For purposes of</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)(A) For purposes of</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A33D51A1DA04C42B8638103A616ED33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE92008B3DFA0457F9F6CD7B177D4E507" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subparagraph id="H3B725746849E4A7A97E555A8E60AC9E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an automatic contribution arrangement taking effect after December 31, 2024, the requirements of subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be treated as met only if, under the arrangement, at least every 3 years each employee—</text><clause id="H1D175141D8FA4473AC1A767CE0AAFD22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is eligible to participate in the arrangement, and</text></clause><clause id="H10A274FF25F64959AE166BA8A5FB43FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, at the time of the determination, has in effect an affirmative election pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) not to have contributions described in such subparagraph made,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">is treated as having made the election at the uniform percentage of compensation described in subparagraph (A)(ii) unless the employee makes a new election under such subparagraph. Such determination may be made at one time for all employees described in the preceding sentence for a plan year, regardless of individual employee dates of enrollment.</continuation-text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC545BBBEC9744B17B336BEACF0C3D706"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendment to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">Section 414(w)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H88F8839D7289412D85766E435E4D38A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and moving the margins of such clauses 2 ems to the right;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BE421E8AE96477DA6D86DB97B539E14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote> For purposes of</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCB7085A93B3B457B9AE2F00875D62A61" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subparagraph id="H93F85D0FCA95451DB149DDBFF4266A05"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block/></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2392BC8875C44E02AADE4725A78CD166"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HD95572D18DE64512B4ED95407073C1A1" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subparagraph id="H6C7900CA10A248CE848D3E94799DAEDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic automatic deferral required</header><text>In the case of an eligible automatic contribution arrangement taking effect after December 31, 2024, the requirements of this subsection shall be treated as met only if, under the arrangement, at least every 3 plan years each employee—</text><clause id="H6DBAD8C84C2D4BF59E3F72755C4EA826"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is eligible to participate in the arrangement, and</text></clause><clause id="HE1A07D7D40DA4314B646CB87A0BB11C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, at the time of the determination, has in effect an affirmative election under subparagraph (A)(ii) not to have such contributions described in such subparagraph made,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">is treated as having made the election at the uniform percentage level described in subparagraph (A)(ii) unless the employee makes a new election under such subparagraph. Such determination may be made at one time for all employees described in the preceding sentence for a plan year, regardless of individual employee dates of enrollment.</continuation-text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block/></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AA3B0CB8AE843378A0B224B9818D368"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified automatic contribution arrangements</header><paragraph id="H94BF89C8163C41BE90752F1DBAEA21DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">Section 401(k)(13)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block id="HF6E4311FBE6F4B018EE95608474EA291" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><clause id="HCAE67647ADAF42E780DE2EA62B70845A"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Periodic automatic deferral required for post-2024 arrangements</header><text>In the case of a qualified automatic contribution arrangement which takes effect after December 31, 2024, the requirements of this subparagraph shall be treated as met only if, under the arrangement, at least every 3 plan years each employee—</text><subclause id="H962C73CE16674D879B92C7F8E44CFD94"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who is eligible to participate in the arrangement, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3988A25A5E734408B1E861AE1D9ABC3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, at the time of the determination, has in effect an affirmative election pursuant to clause (ii) not to have contributions described in clause (i) made,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">is treated as having made the election described in clause (i) unless the employee makes a new affirmative election under clause (ii). Such determination may be made at one time for all employees described in the preceding sentence for a plan year, regardless of individual employee dates of enrollment.</continuation-text></clause><after-quoted-block/></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEEA920DADDC42E4AEE0A1D35CB23A60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Clause (iv) of section 401(k)(13)(C) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H0AC97421F5EC4C5B80DC936F3EB92ED9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote>for pre-2025 arrangements</quote> after <quote>required</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E04E1524D94C1ABECD5CD0794F48D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Clause (i)</quote> and inserting <quote>In the case of a qualified automatic contribution arrangement in effect before January 1, 2025, clause (i)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA794B9C71EC046A68F0961FD68218AB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to arrangements taking effect after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section><section id="H73966319F6EA401CBFE7AA8E850EF558"><enum>6.</enum><header>Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative</header><subsection id="H216695129EB4472D80E036709BE79F0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H62AC7438B41F401E998B23718EA5F5A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing program</header><text>The term <quote>existing program</quote> means a program, designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking, that exists on the date on which the Secretary is carrying out a responsibility authorized under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H037F06C0C0A140D7B41930023ED469CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiative</header><text>The term <quote>Initiative</quote> means the Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39C97C02DB034528BA2FBC7293C6A956"><enum>(3)</enum><header>New program</header><text>The term <quote>new program</quote> means a program, designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking, that does not exist on the date on which the Secretary is carrying out a responsibility authorized under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6C7D0E40264B6CA033670888000467"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152241FB6826428B82DAE8C873069FA3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given the term under section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAC315AA03EB4797B43931C4FDB48C11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee ownership and participation initiative</header><paragraph id="HE728E2799D5843BB9DD2EDC72609629A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish within the Department of Labor an Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E4D3F2C43CB43BDB86E9126FE2C2336"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9C20307FBA3D4AFCAF972FD067AD13FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support within the States existing programs designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F08B6A7157C4B5487060FA3DE0495F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate within the States the formation of new programs designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C46CAAD2E704019BF7D72821A238595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>To carry out the functions enumerated in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1AE6B0F84B3C41A6A5E8048BCB5F721D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support new programs and existing programs by—</text><clause id="H5C9D477B0BC1497C9E7571C65C3D52FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making Federal grants authorized under subsection (d); and</text></clause><clause id="H4E45AAD79AC642C890CDC609F686B2C0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>acting as a clearinghouse on techniques employed by new programs and existing programs within the States, and disseminating information relating to those techniques to the programs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H683DDDE85C40414DBBA8BB7CD72BF7BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the formation of new programs, in ways that include holding or funding an annual conference of representatives from States with existing programs, representatives from States developing new programs, and representatives from States without existing programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04ABE9857A894AE8A00981F71C4E6C32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Programs regarding employee ownership and participation</header><paragraph id="HC765A11FF68E49BDAB52F4186083139F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program to encourage new programs and existing programs within the States to foster employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B636B1D715F4145BDFB4BE052EC873C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose of program</header><text>The purpose of the program established under paragraph (1) is to encourage new and existing programs within the States that focus on—</text><subparagraph id="H1DA54680543B49B5B1D478AB9DE800B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing education and outreach to inform employees and employers about the possibilities and benefits of employee ownership, business ownership succession planning, and employee participation in business decisionmaking, including providing information about financial education, employee teams, open-book management, and other tools that enable employees to share ideas and information about how their businesses can succeed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H508943A8E37C48A6A8613CDEF4773978"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to assist employee efforts to become business owners, to enable employers and employees to explore and assess the feasibility of transferring full or partial ownership to employees, and to encourage employees and employers to start new employee-owned businesses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6005467E2BC6466CB2F71FB91558C6F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training employees and employers with respect to methods of employee participation in open-book management, work teams, committees, and other approaches for seeking greater employee input.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED16472F84494CC8B8E24914CAB464D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program details</header><text>The Secretary may include, in the program established under paragraph (1), provisions that—</text><subparagraph id="H07A0857CE14540B8B13520423F16C2C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(A)—</text><clause id="H7C4C36FD719C41DC8BC93DED0D977822"><enum>(i)</enum><text>target key groups, such as retiring business owners, senior managers, unions, trade associations, community organizations, and economic development organizations;</text></clause><clause id="H97335EEB201F4939BFEBF71F2FFE7E94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage cooperation in the organization of workshops and conferences; and</text></clause><clause id="HCBF57AA2F210499F85DD1AEA108172A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prepare and distribute materials concerning employee ownership and participation, and business ownership succession planning;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22AE1AAB2421455493983581CB2D5C6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(B)—</text><clause id="H02EABF4785064B9888BDD6650A211A9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide preliminary technical assistance to employee groups, managers, and retiring owners exploring the possibility of employee ownership;</text></clause><clause id="H63F4A2860B954D16BFC1EE0E494A8464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the performance of preliminary feasibility assessments;</text></clause><clause id="HF9B3E51752BA4CEA93D449859E3FA5A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assist in the funding of objective third-party feasibility studies and preliminary business valuations, and in selecting and monitoring professionals qualified to conduct such studies; and</text></clause><clause id="HEE8455DA2B24429C85A52DD1DD859A09"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide a data bank to help employees find legal, financial, and technical advice in connection with business ownership;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DE364AA8CE24A94BD8EC84488114CF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(C)—</text><clause id="HA2096BB311D14F218A935E74121391F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for courses on employee participation; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B7FDE2C7625475AAE893DC126332082"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the development and fostering of networks of employee-owned companies to spread the use of successful participation techniques; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73BC8183A18644F2AE6E4DE8DCBC0BD2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of training described in paragraph (2)(D)—</text><clause id="HF039FD74167A43599A5590C17282B99B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for visits to existing programs by staff from new programs receiving funding under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H081F6E60EE2540DF98DA1662E318D07E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide materials to be used for such training.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC49695BB903441AB5E2932071AFB6B6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue formal guidance, for recipients of grants awarded under subsection (d) and one-stop partners (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)) affiliated with the workforce development systems (as so defined) of the States, proposing that programs and other activities funded under this section be—</text><subparagraph id="HACC1F01258CB4682B97D4F2A20C5FCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proactive in encouraging actions and activities that promote employee ownership of, and participation in, businesses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF4BE468F17A491D848A6AE93F6BAD3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comprehensive in emphasizing both employee ownership of, and participation in, businesses so as to increase productivity and broaden capital ownership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FF3EB4A991F4F41AE7F0D437B444B3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header><paragraph id="HF7BD8E3EDAFC41488B508209996B24B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (c), the Secretary may make grants to States (except as provided in paragraph (5)) for use in connection with new programs and existing programs within a State for—</text><subparagraph id="HDA477AB4176C41CC9E62B44A95BBDED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>education and outreach as provided in subsection (c)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0B740255228420898E26787A20B507F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technical assistance as provided in subsection (c)(2)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BEDBA1A3C0349BEBB918A32033A8FAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training activities for employees and employers as provided in subsection (c)(2)(C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6657DE3718F747B2954587D5E6B17BAA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>activities facilitating cooperation among employee-owned firms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C7ABBF22952408FBCFBDD56E005433E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>training as provided in subsection (c)(2)(D) for new programs provided by participants in existing programs dedicated to the objectives of this section, except that, for each fiscal year, the amount of the grants made for such training shall not exceed 10 percent of the total amount of the grants made under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DACD47553954F789572A77E592373D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts and conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the amount and any conditions for a grant made under this subsection. The amount of the grant shall be subject to paragraph (6), and shall reflect the capacity of the applicant for the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30E604BCD5EC4013813F4E84BE4E4D94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>Each entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B503AAF28EB4A459A9D5268FF8FCF52"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State applications</header><text>Each State may sponsor and submit an application under paragraph (3) on behalf of any local entity consisting of a unit of State or local government, State-supported institution of higher education, or nonprofit organization, meeting the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B91BA65F9B48F1B3D8BC02369D7C19"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applications by entities</header><subparagraph id="H8F53CF5A54DB416199542706601199A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Entity applications</header><text>If a State fails to support or establish a program pursuant to this section during any fiscal year, the Secretary shall, in the subsequent fiscal years, allow local entities described in paragraph (4) from that State to make applications for grants under paragraph (3) on their own initiative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E8736080E1C4746B74F974CE93B605D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application screening</header><text>In any case in which a local entity makes an application for a grant pursuant to subparagraph (A), the relevant State may take no actions to screen such application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H374872CE93864C5B9F3719BC1899F606"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A recipient of a grant made under this subsection shall not receive, during a fiscal year, in the aggregate, more than the following amounts:</text><subparagraph id="H51755768EDBC413AA2CEE4F1FDF3F6F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2023, $300,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB51759E3EE742098A4EFEA9EB59B767"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2024, $330,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEC3FC399FC6497D9BD1ABC5A080F05A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2025, $363,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD9B88D48DD2452FB859F5F6A9BDCAD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2026, $399,300.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E48937A0CBC4B95853811628D84E67C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2027, $439,200.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5B35245DE14A4492D205377D25C4F7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>For each year, each recipient of a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary a report describing how grant funds allocated pursuant to this subsection were expended during the 12-month period preceding the date of the submission of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H052CCE05329A4A4A9F64D7710F0D5FDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to reserve not more than 10 percent of the funds appropriated for a fiscal year to carry out this section for the purposes of conducting evaluations of the grant programs identified in subsection (d) and to provide related technical assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD781557239340A8AB109E403304C6ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report—</text><paragraph id="H99E6CACFA0314CFDBC551431DA678F2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on progress related to employee ownership and participation in businesses in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BEE727EAD754273847668D916ED7622"><enum>(2)</enum><text>containing an analysis of critical costs and benefits of activities carried out under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E6C1A35FF0542628E1AB13FC33D6099"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H0E2E49F1B9A343AA8F7030CB28CA1357"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of making grants pursuant to subsection (d) the following:</text><subparagraph id="H700869CC8B04479D8AE52F71A813AE4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2023, $4,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE9760E6237D4BE0960DAE62D1DBD49E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2024, $7,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F2C8F05B27D4D03864B1DC7D753664B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2025, $10,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC3F9797C41463B94DF5460DE928240"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2026, $13,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H098AD6DFDC22403B95B755CBAC5811BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2027, $16,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H364091F3DCB54D4AA3513DDB1356FCE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of funding the administrative expenses related to the Initiative, for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, an amount not in excess of the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="H262CF9D8195949318C387A3E96D2CFAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$350,000; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF45528C6CE3A49DA9A5D09A0C26ACEDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5.0 percent of the maximum amount available under paragraph (1) for that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H171E06EC8CF742F59ECFE3DC66008BA2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program</header><subsection id="HA4FD46F9B6144FE59B534C652CEEC8AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H980080032957467E931F9A16185D6D92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2024, the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish and implement a program (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program</quote>) to allow participating taxpayers, pursuant to the requirements established under this section, to defer payment on 20 percent of the amount which would otherwise be refunded to such taxpayer as an overpayment (as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6401">section 6401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04BD1297FD6645488D4389D02BDCAFFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of deferral</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3)(E), a participating taxpayer may elect to defer payment of the amount described in paragraph (1) and have such amount deposited in the Rainy Day Fund (as described in paragraph (3)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD14637B8D01F43DD818F50C79AA7801B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rainy day fund</header><subparagraph id="HBE863A8611A948CFA89A8F2BBD9FA944"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish in the Treasury a fund, in such manner as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, to be known as the <quote>Rainy Day Fund</quote>, consisting of any amounts described in paragraph (1) on which payment has been deferred by participating taxpayers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H342D7279FF1C4153B13B0F3E5EBE70BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investment</header><text>Any amounts deposited in the Rainy Day Fund shall be invested by the Secretary, in United States Treasury securities issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, that are suitable for the needs of the Rainy Day Fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H184BE3CA2139426CB1ACEE9CB6210BB0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disbursements from fund</header><clause id="H20B477DCF781452DA9EE71A451535CBB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 180 days after the date of deposit in the Rainy Day Fund of an amount deferred by such taxpayer under paragraph (1), the amounts in the Rainy Day Fund shall be made available to the Secretary to distribute to such taxpayer in an amount equal to such amount plus any interest accrued on such amount (as determined under subparagraph (D)).</text></clause><clause id="H40A5339950D14240A13BB1A8D929BEE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Distributed to taxpayers</header><text>The amounts described in clause (i) shall be distributed to the account identified by the participating taxpayer under paragraph (4)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EA8EBDC37354200A6AAD6332910A504"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interest accrued</header><text>The amount of interest accrued on the amount deferred by a participating taxpayer under subsection (a) shall be determined by the Secretary based upon the return on the investment of such amounts under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E4D2F4AB06A4071A94241AD6883B1B8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Early withdrawal</header><clause id="HBC7D55F036D949EB8324BA45BE10488C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as possible after receipt by the Secretary of the individual income tax return of the participating taxpayer and October 15 of the applicable year, such taxpayer may elect to terminate the deferral of the amount described under paragraph (1) and receive a distribution from the Rainy Day Fund equal to such amount and any interest which has accrued on such amount up to that date.</text></clause><clause id="HDD4E8C2E009044FE99F3C8A151C5A183"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Complete withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participating taxpayer making an election under clause (i) must terminate deferral of the full amount described under paragraph (1), and such amount shall be distributed to the bank account identified by the participating taxpayer under paragraph (4)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0717143754EF4C84BFE01CDADA14A587"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Participating taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>participating taxpayer</quote> means a taxpayer who—</text><subparagraph id="HE5E101C507B04C54BD7798B8E026C067" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prior to the due date for filing the return of tax for such taxable year, elects to participate in the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program, in accordance with regulations to be issued by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB832D41966874E83B14B112AE75CDB0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides the Secretary with an account and routing number or any other financial information deemed necessary by the Secretary for purposes of subparagraphs (C)(ii) and (E)(ii) of paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00B4F6DF6BDA4DE89A38F0EA555D8181" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Forms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the election to defer payment of the amount described in paragraph (1) may be claimed on appropriate tax forms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2187C512E704C3BA807EC178A792E02"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Implementation</header><subparagraph id="H60CC8895B4B747C0821026BEC990B5F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Educational materials and outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HCCD0E3EEFB1D41EFBA69D3DAB079DEE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>design educational materials for taxpayers regarding financial savings and the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program,</text></clause><clause id="H3B95A3F153094E51B874683440D369CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publicly disseminate and distribute such materials during the first calendar quarter of each calendar year and following disbursement of amounts described in paragraph (3)(C), and</text></clause><clause id="H1B937A594CC94C8FB1CC33056E1E233E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engage in outreach regarding the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program to the Volunteer Income Tax Assistance program and paid tax preparers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD7D0DDA22DD4009B9193EFD20E61C15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information for participating taxpayers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that a participating taxpayer is able to electronically verify the status of the amount deferred by such taxpayer under paragraph (1), including any interest accrued on such amount and the status of any distribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BFF57E115E499C80291EFDB37B2542"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Federally funded benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts described in paragraph (1) that are distributed to a participating taxpayer, including any interest accrued on such amount, shall be treated in the same manner as any refund made to such taxpayer under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for purposes of determining the eligibility of such taxpayer for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5521066504B46A78F3D3498951B8186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assets for independence innovation demonstration projects</header><paragraph id="H0BCD2AACB1D84A19820B43D7074B833B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reauthorization</header><text>The Assets for Independence Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/604">42 U.S.C. 604</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA7657F0AAA76495686AEAF3EF2546978"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 416, by inserting <quote>, and, subject to section 417, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, 2026, 2027, and 2028, to remain available until expended</quote>at the end before the period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE226F6A325045DF920F6D9B64C8101F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H6A64B95BD484487F8C73B2A93D5DAA6E" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="H30BCF6A4276D4D199E084D139DC4FCCE"><enum>417.</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><subsection id="HD8ED5A640E9C4D41BF21F159C5FAE240"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), from the funds appropriated for each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, 2026, 2027, and 2028 under section 416, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><paragraph id="HEB461D3B450B4B4EA018D17775364E7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for general research and evaluation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2040820DE3304814A3B3AC08A878B3D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amounts remaining after application of paragraph (1) to fund Assets for Independence innovation projects under section 418.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC1FEC6BCCEA4BEB911419538883AB74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program funding</header><text>From the amounts reserved under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, and 2026, the Secretary shall make available for operating the pilot program established under section 7(c) of the Protecting America’s Retirement Security Act of 2022—</text><paragraph id="H41A0CE12981E4515AC34A39AA4EBE7BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>50 percent of the amount reserved for the relevant fiscal year under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) (after any adjustment under subsection (c)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H041FEFAD22904F9CB4E18A17E1AF7516"><enum>(2)</enum><text>25 percent of the amount reserved for the relevant fiscal year under paragraph (2) of subsection (a) (after any adjustment under subsection (c)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H905488756E004383AD50E2B0E5449457"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proportional adjustment</header><text>In any of fiscal years 2024, 2025, 2026, 2027, and 2028, if the amount appropriated for such fiscal year is greater or less than the amount authorized for such fiscal year under section 416, the amounts reserved under subsection (a) shall be increased or decreased for such fiscal year so that each such amount bears the same proportion to the amount appropriated as each of the amounts reserved under such subsection bears to the amount authorized.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14F51C533E3B4A03892B59AC09A031F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of innovation program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assets for Independence Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/604">42 U.S.C. 604</external-xref> note), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H3C99D15BF75442CDA4624B3BD80A52B2" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="H06AA57388BEF4E2BBA52D6DA21BC935E"><enum>418.</enum><header>Assets for Independence innovation projects</header><subsection id="HA697681610FF428CAB966CA6438D98DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to make grants to qualified entities to conduct Assets for Independence innovation projects under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H05104D90967045D4AF141DAB9D23DF1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H953347A3273645878857AB3522F3036F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assets for Independence innovation project</header><text>The term <quote>Assets for Independence innovation project</quote> means a demonstration project carried out by a qualified entity under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB89DF2C549C446EEA4AC4A54E2A644F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Innovation development account</header><text>The term <quote>innovation development account</quote> means an account that is established in a federally insured financial institution or a State insured financial institution and meets such other requirements as are established by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA67E6AA92BEB40528159E98A779567A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H045C761C86194EE69161B792F7B528ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria and preferences</header><subparagraph id="H960C7A00F5274CC290D9216DA70993DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in considering an application to conduct an Assets for Independence innovation project, the Secretary shall apply subsections (c) and (d) of section 405 to the application in the same manner that such subsections apply to an application to conduct a demonstration project under section 405.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB65F96E25014B2A82BD037D135831DF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, paragraph (1) of section 405(c) shall be applied without regard to the phrase <quote>through activities requiring one or more qualified expenses</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBEDC4456F34FE99A251C5351F0FD10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of Assets for Independence innovation projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, on a competitive basis, approve such applications to conduct Assets for Independence innovation projects as the Secretary considers to be appropriate, taking into account the considerations required by paragraph (1). The Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the applications that are approved involve a range of communities (spread out both geographically and in rural and urban areas) and diverse populations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DA65D3EFC96486E8F5A33911DAF5E7A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project duration and grant amount</header><paragraph id="HFEB80B37AED24890BD74318404442967"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this section for a period not to exceed 5 project years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A817874CA314330B4E84AC1A1526002"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>For each project year of an Assets for Independence innovation project approved under this section, the Secretary may make a grant to the qualified entity authorized to conduct the project. In making such a grant, the Secretary shall make the grant on the first day of the project year in an amount not to exceed the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="H8A2F1FCEEB7A403F9E864CC0EB3175E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of funds committed as matching contributions from non-Federal public or private sector sources; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D5A960BDF764D46AAD967A2F5A73B42"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06D7121FECF4420DBF7BBBA9A36261BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligibility and selection of individuals to participate in an Assets for Independence innovation project</header><paragraph id="HA364E4E4A7EC459F99D92FA7A2BDE494"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header><text>Subject to the approval of the Secretary, each qualified entity conducting an Assets for Independence innovation project shall establish eligibility requirements for participants in the project. Such requirements shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1D9E5F489302441CB2CE14658B088D67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be more expansive than the requirements established under section 408; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H647922A2C92044F6835164FF2F6291FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that eligibility is limited to low-income individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0423F5F3A5AF4C3881631CCDD38DBE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of individuals to participate</header><text>Each qualified entity conducting an Assets for Independence innovation project shall select, from among the individuals that meet the eligibility requirements established by the entity under paragraph (1), the individuals—</text><subparagraph id="HBD2A2F8DD0CA4493AC84220D1A83302A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the qualified entity determines to be most appropriate to participate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9C2B32277E94CD0BA8A828A59E79455"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to whom the qualified entity will make disbursements or deposits in accordance with subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB98DB44751D4497BB8116DBCF919999B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Disbursements by qualified entities</header><paragraph id="H536969C20AC942B682596C2F6E0CFFC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each qualified entity conducting an Assets for Independence innovation project shall, in a manner consistent with the program requirements established by such entity, disburse to a third-party or deposit into the innovation development account of each individual participating in the project from the funds described in subsection (d)(2), a matching contribution of not less than $0.50 and not more than $8 for every $1 deposited in the account by a project participant, except that the rate of matching shall be equal for all individuals participating in the project conducted by such qualified entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC5C175E5F4B43D1AE4A4A2ECBA12F7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on disbursements for an individual</header><text>Not more than $5,000 from a grant made under subsection (d)(1) shall be provided to any one individual over the course of the Assets for Independence innovation project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4539BDF0162141129AAA781A9D58F8AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on disbursements for a household</header><text>Not more than $10,000 from a grant made under subsection (d)(1) shall be provided to any one household over the course of the Assets for Independence innovation project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B52A60EE3E4368A47895BC630EDE3B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><subparagraph id="HF7BFDD8BF5BC431BAAA1F3406B17D063"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each calendar year after 2023, the dollar amounts in paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be increased by an amount equal to the product of—</text><clause id="H8B8A10AFC62E464B8CDEF611E665BA29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, and</text></clause><clause id="H2A80E19F2C794CAB8435881EA5FB2D3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1">section 1(f)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>2022</quote> for <quote>2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE56996E17B2A43AE8073722976772CDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase determined under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $50, such increase shall be rounded up to the next lowest multiple of $50.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F56E39D103A4F10A286D51BFB504CE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assets for Independence Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/604">42 U.S.C. 604</external-xref> note), as amended by paragraphs (1) and (2), is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="HE47D7D4B026A475587E689C1295E4E3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 404(2), by inserting <quote>or section 418</quote> before the period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A60CAF4F9DB47BDA169AAFDC4780403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 406—</text><clause id="HED70AEF83D8443F2A5986E05378CBCD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>to conduct a demonstration project under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>under section 405</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCAF91AD9C37E4A27876E75582502636C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>conducted under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>approved under section 405</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E8474CF2A19411EA4616F6A336481C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 407—</text><clause id="H3133E7DC56EC459CA33BC0D40CC041F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subclause id="HD9D7212321E94BD7952114263FB1A5A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><item id="HF463A79E3D5749F1BDF13E2A9E7A46EE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or, in the case of a participant in a project conducted under section 418, other permitted expenses</quote> after <quote>qualified expenses</quote>; and</text></item><item id="H09A004D54DEA45819858413ADE14B6CE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or subsection (f) of section 418</quote> after <quote>section 410</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HEA35C339FA684719AC1BE135A324D3BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>or section 418(d)(1)</quote>after <quote> section 406(b)</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H84B505E0DCBA4F169BAE4DA4ABCD5751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(A), by inserting <quote>or section 418(d)(1)</quote> after <quote>section 406(b)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB657286F85F243DABD24C1BAC12FF08A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 408, by striking <quote>conducted under this title</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>approved under section 405</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3EDD84367C340508CA9029FF8275A57"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in section 409, by striking <quote>conducted under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>approved under section 405</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98573B7F96BD4AEE92B31046409075C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in section 410, by striking <quote>under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>conducting a demonstration project approved under section 405</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25598CAD60454818BBB5D3D621D14A43"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in section 413(a), by inserting <quote>or section 418(c)</quote> after <quote>under section 405</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H825A6FA8A88844B186A24337BD0A3D4E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>in section 415, by inserting <quote>or innovation development account</quote> after <quote>individual development account</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C49C0554E3A43DF9F839EDA12E92BBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matched refund to rainy day savings pilot program</header><paragraph id="H85A81289DD6348E7A1E820A473F7D74E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and using the funds made available pursuant to section 417(b) of the Assets for Independence Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of Community Services (in this section referred to as <quote>the Secretary</quote>), shall establish under this subsection a matched savings account pilot program to encourage saving by eligible individuals. Under the pilot program, a qualified entity may apply to the Secretary for a grant to conduct a pilot project described in paragraph (2) (in this section referred to as a <quote>pilot project</quote>). The pilot program shall operate for a period of 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B300D3F9B3A4ED7ACC3F3CF0128EB14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pilot project described</header><subparagraph id="H46797502336E47BA9DA7F2EB76392D5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A pilot project is a project in which a qualified entity establishes a matched savings program that meets the requirements of subparagraph (B) for eligible individuals who are selected by the entity to participate in the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A4CB25CF5414CBB85B28FD628D8FA67"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><clause id="H6E8586ED9AF54E45B742B8202472FFED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Deposits into direct deposit accounts</header><subclause id="HAD7ABDEE24F3422DB42245769CD32808"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A matched savings program established as part of a pilot project shall match amounts saved by each eligible individual participating in the pilot project—</text><item id="H5BB216AE754B4E529C7475302B2F8C8D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the amount matched to be equal to or less than the amount of any payment deferred by such individual under the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program established in subsection (a)(1); and</text></item><item id="HE0A690BDCA614AB889C165F35A71C212"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>with the rate of matching to be equal for all eligible individuals participating in the program.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1DF17BBCC9424233B5362BBC63AE2E7B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Any amount described in subclause (I) shall not be distributed to an eligible individual until the amounts described in subparagraphs (C)(ii) or (E)(ii) of subsection (a)(1) have been distributed to the bank account identified by such individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEEE6695F87524C9BBA25BDF55804974B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evaluation of program by independent research organization</header><subclause id="HE63E5666617242009CF465CCBDED8721"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts made available under section 417(b)(2) of the Assets for Independence Act, as added by subsection (b)(1)(B), the Secretary shall enter into a contract with an independent research organization for purposes of evaluating pilot projects conducted under this section.</text></subclause><subclause id="H193074F1D3F94DB18959A2260FF8B652"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Each qualified entity that establishes a matched savings program as part of a pilot project shall collaborate with the independent research organization described in subclause (I) to evaluate the outcomes and impact of the project.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD81CFEDE62CE42378D0A262B7FF0D197"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Impact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The evaluation described in subclause (I) shall include an examination of the demographic characteristics of the individuals participating in the pilot project, such as gender, race, age, geographic location, and family makeup, and how the impacts of the project vary among different demographic groups and the effects of the pilot program on retirement savings for eligible individuals.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE7810BEF54F24150841B5BBEBFBB6513"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Program features</header><text>The program features to be evaluated through the pilot projects conducted under this section may include—</text><item id="H9958C819FB7D4E52A60DC382518D419B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>different levels of matching contributions by qualified entities;</text></item><item id="H538DDF198EF844C4A1A9FE980661C8EE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>lock-out periods during which an eligible individual may not make withdrawals from their account; and</text></item><item id="H96C3513350E44F6E9FE6714A8187D1D5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>educational materials intended to promote savings.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HA0158857A15E47DCA80B1DA9558509AC"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Safeguarding privacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any contract entered into under this clause shall require the selected independent research organization to take all necessary and proper precautions to protect eligible individuals’ privacy and personally identifiable information when conducting the evaluation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7848BD6E1C6244EAB47D31EE5485BC1A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A pilot project shall be for a duration of not more than 3 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B9359EAD29C4BB59A17BC73877E7E07"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Federally funded benefits</header><text>Any amounts described in subparagraph (B)(i) which are distributed to an eligible individual shall be treated in the same manner as any refund made to such taxpayer under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for purposes of determining the eligibility of such taxpayer for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08E5A608AD2B44CA89B1FC2F50564349"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategic communications plan</header><text>The Secretary shall devise a strategic communications plan to ensure a successful pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42D743C5218B469196486A1FF9EBDBB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual report to congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit an annual report to Congress on the progress and outcomes of the pilot program established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF519ACBC8EB24FD198A681BE54B075B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HF293E0AAA2DC4556953BA8B8CE192F6A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means an individual who—</text><clause id="H8E5582A646B64870A176DE3087A86818"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has deferred payment of the amount described in subsection (a)(1) under the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program established in such subsection, and</text></clause><clause id="H50EBC0C8FFB541AA8E01448A6C75DF48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the eligibility requirements under section 408 of the Assets for Independence Act, except that subsection (a)(2) of such section shall not apply.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1488E837054D4B2E962A4B7553844FB4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified entity</header><clause id="H9006372ED34B469D9C7CDBC4DD9760DF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified entity</quote> means—</text><subclause id="H057B526729324925A6CA338E940F32E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>one or more not-for-profit organizations described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="H50869183E244478EB77581B99DF13106"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a State or local government agency, or a tribal government, submitting an application to conduct a pilot project jointly with an organization described in subclause (I);</text></subclause><subclause id="H97432DCF7BB840139C93313991F7FFA3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a site that offers free tax help to individuals who qualify through the Internal Revenue Service’s Voluntary Income Tax Assistance or Tax Counseling for the Elderly programs; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H63A75EA47B764F429B7B2BD3DAA94131"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an entity that—</text><item id="H861CA4D8979D467A9BBA73DCE7B7DBA2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is—</text><subitem id="HCF14D9D7869543B5BE2222C3B87A8183"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>a credit union designated as a low-income credit union by the National Credit Union Administration; or</text></subitem><subitem id="HA638CFC57D814519822E22D4C3B06EC3"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>an organization designated as a community development financial institution by the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund); and</text></subitem></item><item id="H3553F6BF1F4D48A79531B83545CF172D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>can demonstrate a collaborative relationship with a local community-based organization whose activities are designed to address poverty in the community and the needs of community members for economic independence and stability.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB0DD91751B2E43A8A052C6335A88AF12"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as preventing an organization described in clause (i)(I) from collaborating with a financial institution or for-profit community development corporation to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

