<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39068C309C3F4F65B408B7D1A6528635" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6388 IH: Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001204">Mr. San Nicolas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make updates to the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H690F9CD6452544CC939A1D5BE643A6A4" style="OLC"><section id="H96FC40A1913A4A468D47A792DF69BFB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H416D61F140E84B85A1BADDD200C007A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Including of Tribal Governments and Territories in the High-risk money laundering and related financial crime areas</header><subsection id="H090A5577956D4F09B3F4DBAE6BC724C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H84BCCB18D6104B0B856477F5EF9F607A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Department of Justice, human trafficking is <quote>a crime that involves exploiting a person for labor, services, or commercial sex</quote>, a global illicit trade that is estimated by Global Financial Integrity to be valued at more than $150.2 billion each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB12BE8D00A6A44DE80DA9F1486DB0394"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Polaris, the non-governmental organization which runs the United States National Human Trafficking Hotline, has found that while human trafficking is a nationwide problem, the majority of domestic human trafficking victims are <quote>people who have historically faced discrimination and its political, social and economic consequences: people of color, indigenous communities, immigrants and people who identify as LGBTQ+</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6236A8C9490E483FAA0F3FA31515C947"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For this reason, it is important that law enforcement representing native communities and territories are part of the national dialogue about countering human trafficking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H240EF45D2B9D405EA8618AB44CCB23D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The High Intensity Financial Crime Areas program, which is intended to concentrate law enforcement efforts at the Federal, State, and local level to combat money laundering in designated high-intensity money laundering zones, considers human trafficking among other financial crime issues and actors. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB91C612EFB4303972872047909E6C2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each High Intensity Financial Crime Area, a money-laundering action team, comprised of relevant Federal, State, and local enforcement authorities, prosecutors, and financial regulators, works together to coordinate Federal, State, and local anti-money laundering effort.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE43AE518C714393A096D2ADEB11BC17"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The High Intensity Financial Crime Area program does not currently mandate the inclusion of law enforcement and other agencies from Tribes and territories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C5A64A7DE34A58B2F88298C800D291"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further, the National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing, a valuable report which is scheduled to sunset in January 2022, does not currently mandate the inclusion of law enforcement and other agencies from Tribes and Territories.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0916808F2106470D941C49B936511022"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National strategy for combating terrorist and other illicit financing</header><text>The Countering Russian Influence in Europe and Eurasia Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9501">22 U.S.C. 9501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H523AEAF97E0F4F5A820DF075FAF8C978"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 261(b)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="HD2882BD4FA00494F957B8897B4566A8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2020</quote> and inserting <quote>2024</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCBEFE45A428479CAC60FB987C63BC7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5359BF067014C758B88AC6253B833C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 262—</text><subparagraph id="H59222227342A449DBA7FC9A9AF804588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H091BFE9B2DCF4960BEAFB398F34C9B47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in the documents entitled <quote>2015 National Money Laundering Risk Assessment</quote> and <quote>2015 National Terrorist Financing Risk Assessment</quote>,</quote> and inserting <quote>in the documents entitled <quote>2020 National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing</quote> and <quote>2022 National Strategy for Combating Terrorist and Other Illicit Financing</quote></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H94F8391A092E4C2FA05FB51759723AD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the broader counter terrorism strategy of the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>the broader counter terrorism and national security strategies of the United States</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9721B82800A40B09616C0F70E426808"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text><clause id="HFFB78FAE674D44E1A48E925B67D417A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Prevention of illicit finance</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">prevention, detection, and defeat of illicit finance</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HC18A98E346F24AC0A74F137010FE48E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>private financial sector</quote> and inserting <quote>private sector, including financial and other relevant industries,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H175271483ADF4A8F87E2F7FF3149FFF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>with regard to the prevention and detection of illicit finance</quote> and inserting <quote>with regard to the prevention, detection, and defeat of illicit finance</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H732AFA23BC57449595506F2FDEFDF817"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text><clause id="H8C66598868B844A79AD6CF76A10BD9F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal, State, and local officials</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal, State, local, Tribal, and Territory officials</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H19706F3A3BE0484CBD6BAE621F5A900A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>State and local prosecutors,</quote> the following: <quote>Tribal and Territorial law enforcement</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A332AFECA964DDDB36AD1FBB08E2E7C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>so-called</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB328196628D948148EDB0285E2F4F08A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Law enforcement and other agencies from Tribes and territories</header><text>Section 5342 of title 31, United States Code is amended—</text><paragraph id="H82F0E662EBFC445B94A6FDBE63B18857"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(B), by striking <quote>local, State, national, </quote> and inserting <quote>local, State, national, Tribal, Territorial,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB108F3641ED841F382A77881B38A0101"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(A), by striking <quote>with State</quote> and inserting <quote>with State, Tribal, Territorial,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA14186F39B21408782C7486E90AF67EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(3), by striking <quote>any State or local official or prosecutor</quote> and inserting <quote>any State, local, Tribe, or Territory official or prosecutor</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6558B08EAB34F71BBCBC7DBC3B1DD36"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by striking <quote>State and local governments and State and local law enforcement agencies</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, and Territorial governments and State, local, Tribal, and Territorial agencies</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2435216DF0024F418C3055B512D389E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial Crime-Free Communities Support Program</header><paragraph id="H73BD7120A01E4C9E91CDE3377244AB66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5351 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>to support local law enforcement efforts</quote> and inserting <quote>to support local, Tribal, and Territorial law enforcement efforts</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBFA75C11E74342AE260FE9523FEC09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program authorization</header><text>Section 5352 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H00A842A1FD7D4D7493442ED8CB8B7AA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>State or local</quote> in each place it occurs and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, or Territorial</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FBCE7EAB7B48C0A7ADE7E3F65E3DAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="H006838CF56064611A0AAC34C66BE2C00"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>State or local</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, or Territorial</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H24D0E1BF66D1407A8B0B9100EFCE2104"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>State law</quote> and inserting <quote>State, Tribal, or Territorial law</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3208ACBF3A82478ABC0BA2F4AE525523"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information collection and dissemination</header><text>Section 5353(b)(3)(A) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>State local law enforcement agencies</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, and Territorial law enforcement agencies</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77502C8DC3C4010ABD6315AD0C7E2F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grants for fighting money laundering and related financial crimes</header><text>Section 5354 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H54631100EDA94937B66CBBC16383F0A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>State or local law enforcement</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, or Territorial law enforcement</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC9E6EDC8722467B919ED86F3C0FFD19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>State and local law enforcement</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, Tribal, and Territorial law enforcement</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1769D1449048434091A5FDBBE7DB63D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal, State, and local cooperative law enforcement</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal, State, local, Tribal, and Territorial cooperative law enforcement</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

