<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0027E3CC1A05468AAFDC1EBC6075F210" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8168 IH: Save Our Sequoias Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8168</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001165">Mr. McCarthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000061">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001128">Ms. Conway</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the health and resiliency of giant sequoias, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1A6AA7BD1E3A44F697BFFC85DE8E1203" style="OLC"><section id="H86A07D05CC9C4A6E8AE16745A7EBF152" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H02DF34C5145246189FD6F67494F54F80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save Our Sequoias Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H41E8FE20CD1D4735A752F4080E942612"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H86A07D05CC9C4A6E8AE16745A7EBF152" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB458052BBC7C4561B2C5CA439C5E57DD" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9E036593866047E69E6914EED8F3F0BE" level="section">Sec. 3. Shared stewardship agreement for giant sequoias.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H00697ADE2EE44942BDDF3325F44448B8" level="section">Sec. 4. Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBD663F535F914AB883BE8452A8B1E085" level="section">Sec. 5. Giant Sequoia Health and Resiliency Assessment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9FFCBC3635B34EDC9986C60F41F50D6A" level="section">Sec. 6. Giant sequoia emergency response.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6D9A38F3706F4E99A954C6928C4D134A" level="section">Sec. 7. Giant Sequoia Reforestation and Rehabilitation Strategy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA04AF7CC7CF94E868A133B9B4F37A6B6" level="section">Sec. 8. Giant Sequoia Strike Teams.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H66E6008611944B35B5FE133E6A677414" level="section">Sec. 9. Giant sequoia collaborative restoration grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD7343BE8EBDB484EBDB5090EE69420B0" level="section">Sec. 10. Good neighbor authority for giant sequoias.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDE4D672E63714180ADCE2041912A05C3" level="section">Sec. 11. Stewardship contracting for giant sequoias.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8E225E7BD48C4F20B2F6AA936237D98F" level="section">Sec. 12. Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Program and Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9B0FB2764B6246DBA22AB8F02BEE6BAE" level="section">Sec. 13. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HB458052BBC7C4561B2C5CA439C5E57DD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5C3215C2F33242FE8256F44DD791194B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The term <quote>Assessment</quote> means the Giant Sequoia Health and Resiliency Assessment required by section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD82FDAD4D17941DD9FB55E8721E603B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coalition</header><text>The term <quote>Coalition</quote> means the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition established under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60FEE87FD4184350BFC39DB4A277101D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaborative process</header><text>The term <quote>collaborative process</quote> means a process relating to the management of National Forest System lands or public lands by which a project or forest management activity is developed and implemented by the Secretary concerned through collaboration with multiple interested persons representing diverse interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F1B9813EE2C4BBB8E59361871009964"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered National Forest System lands</header><text>The term <quote>covered National Forest System lands</quote> means the proclaimed National Forest System lands reserved or withdrawn from the public domain of the United States covering the Sequoia National Forest and Giant Sequoia National Monument, Sierra National Forest, and Tahoe National Forest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA2F96D27B6437B821956A75BAC53DB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Giant sequoia</header><text>The term <quote>giant sequoia</quote> means a tree of the species Sequoiadendron giganteum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67DD7E5A6D274E038AF99DA78451D973"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grove-specific hazardous fuels reduction plan</header><text>The term <quote>grove-specific hazardous fuels reduction plan</quote> means a plan developed by the applicable land management agency prior to conducting an analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) to address hazardous fuels in 1 or more giant sequoia groves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB30CE61F37484ED0BCEE19631BE5CFAF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protection project</header><text>The term <quote>Protection Project</quote> means a Giant Sequoia Protection Project carried out under section 6.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE273B44A8D594F8FB26D1A43400B50B8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The term <quote>public lands</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H66E98ADE26FD431FB2BC0DF2382F343F"><enum>(A)</enum><text> the Case Mountain Extensive Recreation Management Area in California managed by the Bureau of Land Management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D9E42C60AA04B0F97EAC1ACF0AB0558"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Kings Canyon National Park, Sequoia National Park, and Yosemite National Park in California managed by the National Park Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC796B5AEB3254A718937E2A948918360"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Reforestation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>reforestation</quote> means the act of renewing tree cover by establishing young trees through natural regeneration, artificial or natural regeneration with site preparation, planting or direct seeding, or vegetation competition control following artificial or natural regeneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B1D9E66BC874758846FFB2EB31F26B9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Rehabilitation</header><text>The term <quote>rehabilitation</quote> means any action taken during the 5-year period beginning on the last day of a wildland fire to repair or improve fire-impacted lands which are unlikely to recover to management-approved conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14BA5859D5DC4A8587E969695FCF0D20"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>relevant Congressional Committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE1B8F4C9A6B84F1383A9466D104BC06A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45095AA0112C417897484CBF3BE58176"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources, Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, and Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24EAB8FEC07342498B1C1F7AFC682748" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Responsible official</header><text>The term <quote>responsible official</quote> means an employee of the Department of the Interior or Forest Service who has the authority to make and implement a decision on a proposed action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CC0C5FF80449D5B6434064A50212E2"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F1E46B371BB493094F9BB9AD572402A"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary concerned</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H12EC5268C6F84747A9332DCC78A9B937"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to covered National Forest System lands, or their designee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CC42B9A0F96476D8C9FF4B72916CAE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands, or their designee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6F6BC34AC594B5DB6E8998A87EA26C2"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <quote>Strategy</quote> means the Giant Sequoia Reforestation and Rehabilitation Strategy established under section 7.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB9990633DF94F1F98531A9F31AAB669"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Strike team</header><text>The term <quote>Strike Team</quote> means a Giant Sequoia Strike Team established under section 8.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD831B78E4C304CA0AD108CA6FEAB815F"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Tribe</quote> means the Tule River Indian Tribe of the Tule River Reservation, California. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9E036593866047E69E6914EED8F3F0BE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Shared stewardship agreement for giant sequoias</header><subsection id="HEB6F82D5F382433D887CD6B4723C6C4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving a request from the Governor of the State of California or the Tribe, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Governor of the State of California, and the Tribe to jointly carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="HD62809F9F6BF412BA7B69228C5A79132"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after entering into the agreement, establish the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition or certify an existing group meeting the requirements of section 4(b) as the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC1A7163A774F7499E52190907734BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 120 days after the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition submits the Assessment under section 5, conduct Protection Projects under section 6.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6A011C1ED964321A96B3F294E00BF65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than 120 days after entering into the agreement, begin implementing the Giant Sequoia Reforestation and Rehabilitation Strategy under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H330E3951E4C24132935513A1D701ADC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation</header><paragraph id="H9CA7884F487E4E46B56C9C6B5353D7D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary has not received a request from the Governor of the State of California or the Tribe under subsection (a) before the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into the agreement under subsection (a) and jointly implement such agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H326932875B974A55BCE91998F53052F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary receives a request from the Governor of the State of California or the Tribe any time after entering into the agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall accept the Governor of the State of California or the Tribe as a party to such agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H00697ADE2EE44942BDDF3325F44448B8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition</header><subsection id="H70B1572395D848A784A146E201D9E455"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H390EA8A9C9404B1C910B1A74225C60C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the timeline and agreement established in section 3(a)(1), the Secretary, in consultation with the parties to such agreement, shall establish, and appoint members to, the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C5C2DF7EE7D4FD2A831DB4119B880D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing coalition</header><text>A previously established group that meets the membership requirements under subsection (b) may be designated by the Secretary as the Coalition under paragraph (1) if the parties to the agreement established under section 3 approve such designation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEB7D8719D484E119838CD13E1DF89C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H594A5FE642E148D58E4F3E736B971410"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint to the Coalition 1 member from each of—</text><subparagraph id="HD074675DF8D24DE6911C23BD6605EC66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Park Service, representing Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEC36A4857444B69A947EEE1A7B8AC3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Park Service, representing Yosemite National Park;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H886AB2546EB048E383DB7B8EBA639A01"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Forest Service, representing Sequoia National Forest and Giant Sequoia National Monument;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H026E7EEC4C21411689F84CBE69C65199"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Forest Service, representing Sierra National Forest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42FB94A61FD3490684BDFD510FC0D9EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Forest Service, representing Tahoe National Forest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0219E50B78DD4D33AB07CD0E5D71FD82"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management, representing Case Mountain Extensive Recreation Management Area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C2F543D79B8419FBBDD0ABB532F06BA"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Tribe, representing the Black Mountain Grove;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB74B3F32D0041F3997C41DCBFB0E33A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the State of California, representing Calaveras Big Trees State Park;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5477B7F2E13848B19F9CC15844B68BF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State of California, representing Mountain Home Demonstration State Forest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BA11250FEF1417DBC5CF1A3828EAF2A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an academic institution with demonstrated experience managing and owning a giant sequoia grove, representing Whitaker’s Research Forest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD093F968D244D43AEAC15DA16C756FB"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the County of Tulare, California, representing Balch Park.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA8711A6D8AE44D79CA1C9D18A34B5B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affiliate partners</header><text>The Coalition may designate organizations or agencies with demonstrated experience and knowledge on giant sequoia management and resiliency as affiliate partners of the Coalition to enhance the work of the Coalition under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9774C92D2F01430A817F90CEA49E1406"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local government participation</header><text>Upon the written request of a local government in California whose jurisdictional boundaries encompass at least 1 giant sequoia grove, the Secretary shall appoint 1 member from such government to serve as a member of the Coalition, subject to the same requirements outlined in this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F77DDC706E34C6798CCDD572DAB237D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term</header><subparagraph id="HC6175111B3EC4138B3C956449BA5C057"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Length</header><text>The term of an appointment as a member of the Coalition shall be 5 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BEA58F0CC54449EA5A849D4AAC1974A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limit</header><text>Members of the Coalition may serve no more than 2 terms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDB08D8664D401982AED961C28A7C82"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a new member to fill a vacancy on the Coalition not later than 6 months after the date on which such vacancy occurs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H783C5639404144FE8CD9881B3246931D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Decisions</header><text>Decisions of the Coalition shall be made by majority vote, a quorum of 6 members of the Coalition being present.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAF69D8C19C74BD5A3E57E35682C8E46"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="H7B9877ECEA7A420D8FC3D21056E1DD9D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after all members of the Coalition are appointed under subsection (a), the Coalition shall hold its first meeting.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86CE3AA95D2F4F7887788DF9CFB3454D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regular meetings</header><text>The Coalition shall meet not less than twice per year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H452701C1AA224373940320255ED5FDB6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint members under subsection (b)(1) who have a demonstrated experience and knowledge on managing giant sequoia groves.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H303CF505F50A4E6DBB849E9C61C671EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Coalition are to—</text><paragraph id="HD3B1608FE6AC44AB85DF5EF89859C80E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out the Assessment under section 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE1B68C850F4D4E9DBBE003D7F376D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>observe implementation, and provide policy recommendations to the Secretary, with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H5C7F2045C87B4DD584925C1BC6BE9980"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Protection Projects carried out under section 6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A72A282C602467D8713F34AF91BE6BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Strategy established under section 7;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC46D94E40D4F76AF8633ADEE288C6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate collaboration and coordination on Protection Projects, particularly projects that cross jurisdictional boundaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFA9CF44C66549619188FD074A3182A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate information sharing, including best available science as described in section 5(c) and mapping resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H003B836E81984D4CB941BAFDD35E533E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the development and dissemination of educational materials and programs that inform the public about the threats to the health and resiliency of giant sequoia groves and actions being taken to reduce the risk to such groves from high-severity wildfire, insects, and drought.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2288EAF37C444C2B844D7C51643F642"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pay and expenses</header><paragraph id="H5205AC4129314CC4A6413BF75F3919E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph id="H3721FCE2592D48E198711F80EB4F48E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal employee members</header><text>All members of the Coalition who are officers or employees of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their services as officers or employees of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DEF311A0882490D9524EBA3FC2365DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-federal employee members</header><text>All members of the Coalition not described in subparagraph (A) shall serve without compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB1A507EB13435FBFFA8538F0B546F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>A member of the Coalition may be reimbursed for travel and lodging expenses incurred while attending a meeting of the Coalition or any other meeting of members approved for reimbursement by the Coalition in the same amounts and under the same conditions as Federal employees under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D7D825540645498AA20DB827375B0A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>The Secretary may pay the expenses of the Coalition that the Secretary determines to be reasonable and appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA261BC95B14262ADE39AF296B87CE9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative support, technical services, and staff support</header><text>The Secretary shall make personnel of the Department of the Interior available to the Coalition for administrative support, technical services, development and dissemination of educational materials, and staff support that the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50F116E7438B436E88F21AB1FFE82558"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Coalition.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBD663F535F914AB883BE8452A8B1E085"><enum>5.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Health and Resiliency Assessment</header><subsection id="HEB869631D88E4D8EBE59CD016E537C57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the first meeting of the Coalition, the Coalition shall submit to the relevant Congressional Committees a Giant Sequoia Health and Resiliency Assessment that, based on the best available science—</text><paragraph id="HDF86CD7D169C4E91A9AAC2A512470D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies—</text><subparagraph id="HACD2528885C8491FB40947E3533F8F03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each giant sequoia grove that has experienced a—</text><clause id="H22E8087473564B5B8567F3058DF37200"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stand-replacing disturbance; or </text></clause><clause id="HE867C9212A284EF3A6E59AB07910FD76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disturbance but continues to have living giant sequoias within the grove, including identifying the tree mortality and regeneration of giant sequoias within such grove;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21C10F92C0B74345A850BCA9D2DB7C94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each giant sequoia grove that is at high risk of experiencing a stand-replacing disturbance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E1BDD8CB7404E0EB3200B580667CAB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lands located near giant sequoia groves that are at risk of experiencing high-severity wildfires that could adversely impact such giant sequoia groves; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEB27821C26C44728803452E8B8D5298"><enum>(D)</enum><text>each giant sequoia grove that has experienced a disturbance and is unlikely to naturally regenerate and is in need of reforestation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84FA173D6E73490D8CA4B1CD3BCDEC6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzes the resiliency of each giant sequoia grove to threats, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H8125F222B2464F2795A2844772DB8848"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-severity wildfire;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C916DBDCE0143B7A787DD92D1A5C1C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>insects, including beetle kill; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A015C32DEFE411C9E059BB8EDB72EA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>drought;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D5AFA13F2864495BE1A8F6C2FE014DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to Protection Projects, proposes a list of highest priority Protection Projects to be carried out under section 6, giving priority to projects located on lands identified under subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (a)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2699851B8974B9B90B68D39C2E5FA42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examines how historical, Tribal, or current approaches to wildland fire suppression and forest management activities across various jurisdictions have impacted the health and resiliency of giant sequoia groves with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HFD9206A528834238A0F2BAF1D6902307"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-severity wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC428A93040B84C318657B7E9B214F644"><enum>(B)</enum><text>insects, including beetle kill; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A4099338A78470CB4B08D558C2700BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>drought; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403AFDDDEE9A459094D4F74EFF0AADA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes program and policy recommendations that address—</text><subparagraph id="H37D373968B7A470D9A1CF4B7EA48B9A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal and State policies that impede activities to improve the health and resiliency of giant sequoias and proposed policy changes to address such impediments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BFB928507B045C3BB8D50D0C824B61A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>new Federal and State policies necessary to increase the pace and scale of treatments that improve the health and resiliency of giant sequoias;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H003DE9AD5FB04423B5695028D2928CF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>options to enhance communication, coordination, and collaboration, particularly for cross-boundary projects, to improve the health and resiliency of giant sequoias; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D95B760984F4714B1A381E7DE917AD7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>research gaps that should be addressed to improve the best available science on the giant sequoias.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DDA30720968461AB125F0C82016A1CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the submission of the Assessment under subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Coalition shall submit an updated Assessment to the relevant Congressional Committees that—</text><paragraph id="HC47E1662F8014B6DAB7A9D0B17E4F5F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes any new data, information, or best available science that has changed or become available since the previous Assessment was submitted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE15142678E604530803F55466173BBD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to Protection Projects—</text><subparagraph id="HEE1F209AD8A64108A4D77B0F40233E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes information on the number of Protection Projects initiated the previous year and the estimated timeline for completing those projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86C526435EE144F998D9AEA0CBEFAF57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes information on the number of Protection Projects planned in the upcoming year and the estimated timeline for completing those projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H804210F6D4A54DC3ADAAACA67743709B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides status updates and long-term monitoring reports on giant sequoia groves after the completion of Protection Projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA7368791CCE4E2E963F6FBB1E84987A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the Secretary concerned failed to initiate at least 1 Protection Project each in the previous year, a written explanation that includes—</text><clause id="HA9F80F61EBFA4CFB850DA9B2F5CB0530"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of what impediments resulted in failing to initiate at least 1 Protection Project;</text></clause><clause id="HF4A0F1C488334A5A9213F80456081557"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of what actions the Secretary concerned is taking to ensure that at least 1 Protection Project is initiated the following year; and</text></clause><clause id="HC38C5DA8B38440D3A28BAF21858590B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recommendations to Congress on any policies that need to be changed to assist the Secretary concerned in initiating Protection Projects; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE825FBDEB45B473B9FE351832FB29957"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to reforestation and rehabilitation of giant sequoias—</text><subparagraph id="H1F0D0B1E8F404B32AF165646BB17D45E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains updates on the implementation of the Strategy under section 7, including grove-level data on reforestation and rehabilitation activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB246B64A5EE947369740BDE5451E7130"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides status updates and monitoring reports on giant sequoia groves that have experienced natural or artificial regeneration as part of the Strategy under section 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D274FF051D040928589675C86F58F5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dashboard</header><paragraph id="HAE24B7A59E184879A7E9CD80AC4C1672"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to maintain</header><text>The Coalition shall create and maintain a website that—</text><subparagraph id="HE62E4CE3D2BD4642BC3F59C1A3E0E196"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishes the Assessment, annual updates to the Assessment, and other educational materials developed by the Coalition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H633B348DDC7E469D84A1688A79D8746C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains searchable information about individual giant sequoia groves, including the—</text><clause id="HF23DE97E834144B7A10D180B0D0C305D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>resiliency of such groves to threats described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a); </text></clause><clause id="HD07D7861F4B947A0A4755A542D451EAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Protection Projects that have been proposed, initiated, or completed in such groves; and</text></clause><clause id="H2B26611EC0324948A78B2A58ED7BCB5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reforestation and rehabilitation activities that have been proposed, initiated, or completed in such groves; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2D12DEE5D3142DB883B5EC494E97117"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintains a searchable database to track—</text><clause id="HA38B6E2BB68C4BC2A2F22C8B90C181B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the status of Federal environmental reviews and authorizations for specific Protection Projects and reforestation and rehabilitation activities; and</text></clause><clause id="H9D1E64E5B6EC402AA5E2D7701ECCCF6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the projected cost of Protection Projects and reforestation and rehabilitation activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4819EC62080C48EB9870CBFE4415FF6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Searchable database</header><text>The Coalition shall include information on the status of Protection Projects in the searchable database created under paragraph (1)(C), including—</text><subparagraph id="H54E3E1EFD678492990DD941F293DFA92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a comprehensive permitting timetable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D59289E86342B4913AF836C5989DD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of the compliance of each lead agency, cooperating agency, and participating agency with the permitting timetable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9542DDCE22A4139BECDBB97374ECEC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any modifications of the permitting timetable required under subparagraph (A), including an explanation as to why the permitting timetable was modified; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5F3D65D025B441F9701CF2B67C6DDA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information about project-related public meetings, public hearings, and public comment periods, which shall be presented in English and the predominant language of the community or communities most affected by the project, as that information becomes available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3CE169A659749AE90A85E8E08BDCF24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best available science</header><text>In utilizing the best available science for the Assessment, the Coalition shall include—</text><paragraph id="HD8591E0979BD47E0B371C9B4A0E8C4E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data and peer-reviewed research from academic institutions with a demonstrated history of studying giant sequoias and with experience analyzing distinct management strategies to improve giant sequoia resiliency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D30C6F57A794869BF38A729234FA2C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>traditional ecological knowledge from the Tribe related to improving the health and resiliency of giant sequoia groves; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9AF16BA62C84CA1A4EDA047241B583E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data from Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments or agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6D1B390E05940249A08555AA874B96B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technology improvements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into memorandums of understanding or agreements with other Federal agencies or departments, State or local governments, Tribal governments, private entities, or academic institutions to improve, with respect to the Assessment, the use and integration of—</text><paragraph id="HD3AFEEBCC59C45DB9BAF7C77F6658D2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advanced remote sensing and geospatial technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC10DFFC25CBF4CC797E6F39821DC45D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>statistical modeling and analysis; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF7C8729D1A49B9A76818B8876D6E97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other technology the Secretary determines will benefit the quality of information used in the Assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H286166F7FF9F4B279E5586664D7AFC45"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Planning</header><text>The Coalition shall make information from this Assessment available to the Secretary concerned and State of California to integrate into the—</text><paragraph id="HDFA5FEF398734DFF816D0D03FD6BC324"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State of California’s Wildfire and Forest Resilience Action Plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F9516CD6144DC29AE030140A458D19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Forest Service’s 10-year Wildfire Crisis Strategy (or successor plan).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8042AF507F06416FAAFD7E07731F5CAD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Relation to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</header><text>The development and submission of the Assessment under subsection (a) shall not be subject to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H9FFCBC3635B34EDC9986C60F41F50D6A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Giant sequoia emergency response</header><subsection id="H2222184802674E3AAEAF124F22224B21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency response To protect giant sequoias</header><paragraph id="HFB0709D045E348E0A574422440F4C6D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H31DDFCEFFA174542A53D3E1AE3389C72"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Emergency determination</header><text>Congress determines that—</text><clause id="H90A85C5B4C3C4D988AE73FFF915EF99D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an emergency exists on public lands and covered National Forest System lands that makes it necessary to carry out Protection Projects that take needed actions to respond to the threat of wildfires, insects, and drought to giant sequoias; and</text></clause><clause id="HD1C590B8A1624112ABADEADF43466E87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Protection Projects are necessary to control the immediate impacts of the emergency described in subparagraph (i) and are needed to mitigate harm to life, property, or important natural or cultural resources on public lands and covered National Forest System lands.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC5DE84694CA4BE3B2B0DB2E12FFAFDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The emergency determination established under subparagraph (A) shall apply to all public lands and covered National Forest System lands.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A1DF890C8C3404F948710652AE63ED6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The emergency determination established under subparagraph (A) shall go into effect on the date the Giant Sequoia Lands Coalition submits the Assessment under section 5.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD80A25805764E018008DCA9DFB690C2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The emergency determination established under subparagraph (A) shall expire on the date that is 10 years after the effective date of the emergency determination established in paragraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA37122914B26451A941B9E4AA69B211F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>While the emergency determination established under subsection (a) is in effect—</text><subparagraph id="H533DC231FFE449E588A560B33937FD11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a responsible official may carry out a Protection Project described by paragraph (4) before initiating—</text><clause id="HD2C362803651408196BF27AF8300EE71" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an analysis under section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HD6EBA31C86524D3A96FE8AA10E88B99E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consultation under section 7 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H5194B1C8D1A04D50A110D9E6F23D8DFA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consultation under section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470">16 U.S.C. 470(f)</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4EEC5EA2B774023B50DF98A370B8C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rules established under subsections (d) and (e) section 40807 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6592c">16 U.S.C. 6592c(d)</external-xref> and (e)) shall apply with respect to Protection Projects by substituting <quote>Protection Projects</quote> for <quote>authorized emergency action under this section</quote> each place it appears in such subsections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4700E7C5A6749E5B2250A09BAB3AB65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Protection Projects shall be subject to the requirements of section 106 of title I of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C3D3BB08C7F4553BD5E2B75B3E5ABBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protection Projects</header><text>The responsible official shall carry out the following forest management activities as Protection Projects under the emergency determination under this section:</text><subparagraph id="H050C7FBE844B441291CBD3EF2D5A9CE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Activities recommended by the Assessment under section 5.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75047F01C2DA4B3BA10E9728FECCA012"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conducting hazardous fuels management, including mechanical thinning, mastication, and prescribed burning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB54F37EAF12E418AAE6446F6C1C4CA4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Removing hazard trees, dead trees, dying trees, or trees at risk of dying, as determined by the responsible official.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EDAE4E80E404E27B893F64A7DF3DA8E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Removing trees to address overstocking or crowding in a forest stand, consistent with the appropriate basal area of the forest stand as determined by the responsible official.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A9F87C5FED4FF0A826FA1B3DCC44A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Activities included in the applicable grove-specific hazardous fuels reduction plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644E1AC15F464FE6A928481B5B2E68C6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using chemical treatments to address insects and disease and control vegetation competition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2BF4B6C697848C39C618CDADA992318"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any combination of activities described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2784FA32650C4C1CB2D4C3C00A113FCB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="HACC2D7700DEC4EB095AF00D9FD605F32"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection Projects carried out under paragraph (3) and reforestation and rehabilitation activities carried out under this Act that are described by subparagraph (D) are a category of actions hereby designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AE91E450F3E44FD8E4A51D54CAAB685"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall use the categorical exclusion established under subparagraph (A) in accordance with this section. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F9F1DE23E3D426789130B89A4D905AF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interagency cooperation</header><clause id="HB274FA525C7D4A778216D5045F8152F6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that Protection Projects carried out under this section are consistent with improving the health and resiliency of critical habitat for threatened and endangered species, including the pacific fisher and California spotted owl.</text></clause><clause id="H126EE4DCEB0147079AA4D17AC2CB4647"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The informal consultation requirements in sections 402.05 of title 50 and 800.12 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), shall apply to Protection Projects.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DD670E260254987A87DE181A64652AD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A Protection Project or reforestation or rehabilitation activity is described by this subparagraph if such Protection Project or reforestation or rehabilitation activity—</text><clause id="HCC1C358F76F54DA698CBBFCF184FDEBB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covers an area of no more than—</text><subclause id="H145D485E31E54514B48AB2E21AAB4E70" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2,000 acres within giant sequoia groves where a grove-specific hazardous fuels reduction plan has been developed by the relevant land management agency or on lands identified under section 5(a)(1)(B); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF93A7F3EDAD84983B978FC3BD4BEA60D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>3,000 acres on lands identified under section 5(a)(1)(C); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H45742488827E424B88F334608AAB1BEC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was—</text><subclause id="H76C282711CF649ECA534B1EFC0B92BDE" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>proposed by the Assessment under section 5(a)(3);</text></subclause><subclause id="H311A4E22A5BE42FB89E30AB7DD389736" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>developed through a collaborative process; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H61B061B8EAA246438ED3E016C7FF808F" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>proposed by a resource advisory committee (as defined in section 201 of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7121">16 U.S.C. 7121</external-xref>)); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4458CB7E75224C6797032BFFCF859CE8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>occurs on Federal land or non-Federal land with the consent of the non-Federal landowner.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B674EB3DFF3467CA806F1B184F2B759"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of other authorities</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary concerned shall use the authorities provided under this section in combination with other authorities to carry out Protection Projects, including—</text><clause id="H8DC2D9D201D94DDDB605D271ADC484E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>good neighbor agreements entered into under section 8206 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H38CF0AA2145A485BBA22E53A7D2C57E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stewardship contracting projects entered into under section 604 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H237EDCE981CD421993A3B0446A56A08D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>With respect to joint Protection Projects and reforestation and rehabilitation activities involving the Tribe, nothing in this section shall be construed to add any additional regulatory requirements onto the Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H131C7E801C9544B3A8344FEDEC18EB10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary concerned shall initiate no fewer than 1 Protection Project each year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6D9A38F3706F4E99A954C6928C4D134A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Reforestation and Rehabilitation Strategy</header><subsection id="H530DFF84EDA342BB84068E26A27810EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reforestation and rehabilitation strategy</header><paragraph id="H2C49B52EFEF0464E98E90D4EB8065522"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the timeline and agreement established in section 3(a)(3), the Secretary, in consultation with the parties to such agreement, shall develop and implement a strategy, to be known as the Giant Sequoia Reforestation and Rehabilitation Strategy, to enhance the reforestation and rehabilitation of giant sequoia groves that—</text><subparagraph id="H2951D7E5881E4C22977C8630C8BD7852"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies giant sequoia groves in need of natural or artificial regeneration, giving highest priority to groves identified under section 5(a)(1)(A)(i);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E229A65A0764B86BBDA809E5137CD23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creates a priority list of reforestation and rehabilitation activities; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83CFACE2D79D45F4AA9AC65B016F4906"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies and addresses—</text><clause id="H13A019778E2E4969AFF04A00CF0C8651"><enum>(i)</enum><text>barriers to reforestation or rehabilitation including—</text><subclause id="H8036CE677647480C90F165F41B432080"><enum>(I)</enum><text>regulatory barriers;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCFEEFE4DA548476A95D9290E2121AD08"><enum>(II)</enum><text>seedling shortages or related nursery infrastructure capacity constraints;</text></subclause><subclause id="H89D8C4270D8942F0A6168862C936ABDD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>labor and workforce shortages;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEE8CA681E20945A1ABC647737D2DBD0B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>technology and science gaps; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEA8B7F3F27EE46ADB5D16173E7611DBA"><enum>(V)</enum><text>site preparation challenges;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C02EDEEED424B0496B298BF2583AF68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>potential public-private partnership opportunities to complete high-priority reforestation or rehabilitation projects;</text></clause><clause id="HA21D4FF2849F413891F858BCADD3F516"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a timeline for addressing the backlog of reforestation for giant sequoias in the 10-year period after the agreement is entered into under section 3; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD7B3880AB3B488281B6063D85A8EAC3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>strategies to ensure genetic diversity across giant sequoia groves; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0613F4514EF7445B8569344B504F9C38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes program and policy recommendations needed to improve the efficiency or effectiveness of the Strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H602C265112A948639B466C9CDEEDDCBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Secretary may incorporate the Strategy into the Assessment under section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67AC4CEA50FB4D4B92C4660CEBED0905"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority reforestation projects amendment</header><text>Section 3(e)(4)(C)(ii)(I) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1601">16 U.S.C. 1601(e)(4)(C)(ii)(I)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H363CEAB89A824BA2973C5DE876CB5F96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in item (bb), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2771007A1B65474F84505FE3DA2E9DBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in item (cc), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC474D21AFF304FA9ADEDD52648446E99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H59487A78952C4D1A9AA6487FECEF4844" style="OLC"><item id="H17B10C353FB540D29C36315C30F58860"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>shall include reforestation and rehabilitation activities conducted under section 7 of the Save Our Sequoias Act.</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3D5770F5F0647AF8EB5F36983A82C4C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>Nothing in this Act shall restrict or prohibit the Secretary of the Interior or Secretary of Agriculture from conducting reforestation (as such term is defined in section 2 of the Save Our Sequoias Act) activities to reestablish giant sequoias following a wildfire.</quote> after the period at the end.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA04AF7CC7CF94E868A133B9B4F37A6B6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Strike Teams</header><subsection id="HD34A88C581C6493496C655FCDC258CB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Giant sequoia strike teams</header><paragraph id="H23DDF1E9FC604ACFAF3953D20C085518"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall each establish a Giant Sequoia Strike Team to assist the Secretary concerned with the implementation of—</text><subparagraph id="H3E7E50A7FB5C4D32B06A0CE274E06BF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primarily, section 6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321280067FBF4E87A15A03C5FF40C890"><enum>(B)</enum><text>secondarily, section 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79739F3D20124B598BEBAAD0F8B5CD62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each Strike Team shall—</text><subparagraph id="HBFC75745588743588C0E15A16F991669"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assist the Secretary concerned with any reviews, including analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), consultations under the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470">16 U.S.C. 470 et seq.</external-xref>), and consultations under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C41ACD850EE4E2AAC099266FF393D71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement any necessary site preparation work in advance of or as part of a Protection Project or reforestation or rehabilitation activity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B08E38E1B80452D80CA6BDDE49A50BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>implement Protection Projects under section 6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3324AE6DD174AED91382A000D28A598"><enum>(D)</enum><text>implement reforestation or rehabilitation activities under section 7.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D8B87F339DC427EA0CE214BFC6E37B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Secretary concerned may appoint no more than 10 individuals each to serve on a Strike Team comprised of—</text><subparagraph id="HFF553107BB82454FB245FD4F26FA14A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90310EA9D66549D1827CF203F3612CC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employees of the Forest Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28AA091EFFC646B5B1C2BB360561E2A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">private contractors from any nonprofit organization, State government, Tribal Government, local government, academic institution, or private organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9688A1A34E44F190AE5D4531D90C7F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">volunteers from any nonprofit organization, State government, Tribal Government, local government, academic institution, or private organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H66E6008611944B35B5FE133E6A677414"><enum>9.</enum><header>Giant sequoia collaborative restoration grants</header><subsection id="H8CD124D4EA524C608448649613976507"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the parties to the agreement under section 3, shall establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to advance, facilitate, or improve giant sequoia health and resiliency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB55F4F3A91A146CA84426A62E7FC39D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants under this section to any nonprofit organization, Tribal Government, local government, academic institution, or private organization to help advance, facilitate, or improve giant sequoia health and resiliency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA372A2FFC6DF411D8978E8CDAC0D553B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text><paragraph id="H4A73F1C534A7479EB1046F33DC0F1D63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>primarily, are likely to have the greatest impact on giant sequoia health and resiliency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0411B0E39678412D98DDA7EEED0FB7C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>secondarily—</text><subparagraph id="H77518A5BA2534F03B1650A722D9FD4B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are small businesses, particularly in rural areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D93CB2D43544F49545A8DA6E6E351F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create or support jobs, particularly in rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AF6DDDD1E4445C0BBFA7036556DFDF7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text>Funds from grants awarded under this section shall be used to—</text><paragraph id="H14973D7D72874D83AEF7AFDC731EC301"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create, expand, or develop markets for hazardous fuels removed under section 6, including markets for biomass and biochar;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB34FBADFF3CE4E26A48CC75BC0800758"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate hazardous fuel removal under section 6, including by reducing the cost of transporting hazardous fuels removed as part of a Protection Project;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BBFC0DF69604B6FA9493A234358040C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expand, enhance, develop, or create permanent or temporary facilities or land that can store or process hazardous fuels removed under section 6; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H393FDAC41EA247C793EEFCD379C8EFE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish, develop, expand, enhance, or improve nursery capacity or infrastructure necessary to facilitate the Strategy established under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD7343BE8EBDB484EBDB5090EE69420B0"><enum>10.</enum><header>Good Neighbor Authority for giant sequoias</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8206 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8DA9D8531C294D9CA72B8C9F1E4E3E3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H4586F10830D84EE2AA5E057C2FE55420"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)—</text><clause id="H478C6EB90A3948FD873120D6A4EA2253"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HD5AB9256EDFA4898B50DC41DCE74DD8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (iv);</text></clause><clause id="H004F39F6537B445E8CEC27B5035622C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H41D899E754C047B8BAE0047DA3AD7CD2" style="OLC"><clause id="HAF2DFD59E3C94B70A5CBDAA8DA3F0687"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities conducted under section 6 of the Save Our Sequoias Act;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H31BA397500D445D1940EAC62C94F8653"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in clause (iv), as so redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H8DDEC8E27019471B816E374BD3FA0E70" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD3DCF24B1E574418B1AD2BAEABFB7247" style="OLC"><clause id="HB60A9F3532F24625827B24F3F21B6B69" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any combination of activities specified in clauses (i) through (iv). </text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC532E274F3428D99199D1582FD81B3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (10)(B) by striking <quote>land.</quote> and inserting <quote>land, Kings Canyon National Park, Sequoia National Park, and Yosemite National Park.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA0A9C0174C045A994BE890B3F60A47F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows—</text><quoted-block id="H363B21929C8A4082ABEFCBDD6E7675E5" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HDBA1D0900D5F4CA6BDE4BFA8060BC00C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of revenue</header><text>Funds received from the sale of timber by a Governor of a State under a good neighbor agreement shall be retained and used by the Governor—</text><clause id="H80D0BD894FD643B2AD4C52C9ACCD8E58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to carry out authorized restoration services under such good neighbor agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="HF22BADC659F748D78C5255E27FEE4A4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if there are funds remaining after carrying out the services under clause (i), to carry out authorized restoration services within the State under other good neighbor agreements.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HDE4D672E63714180ADCE2041912A05C3"><enum>11.</enum><header>Stewardship contracting for giant sequoias</header><subsection id="H31DE0115406E43B98A2B1A5D6DF721F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National park service</header><text>Section 604(a)(2) of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read—</text><quoted-block id="H876746AC129D4CF58EBBE1887DA4A45F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HD38298B8101B45E192B9EA7F9CD9F88D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Bureau of Land Management with respect to Bureau of Land Management lands and the Director of the National Park Service with respect to lands within Kings Canyon National Park, Sequoia National Park, and Yosemite National Park.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H561EDE6CEDA44762875F6507F3CF3802"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Giant sequoia stewardship contracts</header><text>Section 604(c) of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFDD519BBB8424304B047DEC7A0078341" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HFAFAF7A268E143C8BA6EBCE82EF50C1F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Promoting the health and resiliency of giant sequoias.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8E225E7BD48C4F20B2F6AA936237D98F"><enum>12.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Program and Fund</header><subsection id="H95D7CC8EB1E541938F36192081F07D21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1011">Chapter 1011</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H35BB6AEA9198430A96F81A8048F9A697" style="USC"><section id="HFB7A1EE1D2A746BD92F943D9A8E6263F"><enum>101123.</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Program and Fund</header><subsection id="HD27202E6EFEE4726ABFC468194268A39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Giant sequoia emergency protection program</header><text>The National Park Foundation, in coordination with the National Forest Foundation, shall design and implement a comprehensive program to assist and promote philanthropic programs of support that benefit—</text><paragraph id="HA4CB5C25AD6B4DA7A6EC2F41EA6DEEF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>primarily, the management and conservation of giant sequoias on National Park Service and covered National Forest System lands to promote resiliency to wildfires, insects, and drought; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8101201475A8449CB96D6809A1AB564A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">secondarily, the reforestation of giant sequoias on National Park Service and covered National Forest System lands impacted by wildfire.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60E6FC751F80438C93A7FF05A5343585"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Fund</header><text>The National Park Foundation, in coordination with the National Forest Foundation, shall establish a joint special account to be known as the Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Fund (referred to as <quote>the Fund</quote> in this section), to be administered in support of the program established under subsection (a).</text><paragraph id="H598F80B26F784AA4B7878923127906B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Funds for giant sequoia emergency protection</header><text>The following shall apply to the Fund:</text><subparagraph id="H01183CF543BF486AA29AC2094F4440CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Fund shall consist of any gifts, devises, or bequests that are provided to the National Park Foundation or National Forest Foundation for such purpose.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H362A31030EDE4BDE8C97B6EFEF6DF4CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Park Foundation and National Forest Foundation shall deposit any funds received for the Fund in a federally insured interest-bearing account or may invest funds in appropriate security obligations, as mutually agreed upon.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7D58C35A5AC42FE87861D3C03870C47"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any accrued interest or dividends earned on funds received for the Fund shall be added to the principal and form a part of the Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD970C6C7DC08420593B09F31CB7DE723"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds shall be available to the National Park Foundation and National Forest Foundation without further appropriation for projects and activities approved by the Chief of the Forest Service or the Director of the National Park Service as appropriate, or their designees, to—</text><subparagraph id="HA0D057EB29144E2C8A3C7F5344947EED" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primarily, support the management and conservation of giant sequoias on National Park Service and covered National Forest System lands to promote resiliency to wildfires, insects, and drought; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BD8C80C17C14B1AB195703C48BDBD95"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">secondarily, support the reforestation of giant sequoias on National Park Service and covered National Forest System lands impacted by wildfire.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC43B38240C34749B990CDC09AD432CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Summary</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Park Foundation and National Forest Foundation shall include with their annual reports a summary of the status of the program and Fund created under this section that includes—</text><paragraph id="H3BAC06045453448499627EE91500E6BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the amounts deposited in the Fund during the fiscal year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC18386ECC5F24287B8F7B8D63037B7E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21717AEF45E04B2EB81042B97102DC8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the program and projects funded during the fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H657821D5CCE84D3EAA61B9546D0A2F9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered National Forest System lands defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered National Forest System lands</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the <short-title>Save Our Sequoias Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA462318C26DB4D55AB6BFE5A30A3E40C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter of title 54, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H912C9B12F72E4133A436C09C9643C95A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H35BB6AEA9198430A96F81A8048F9A697" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HFB7A1EE1D2A746BD92F943D9A8E6263F" level="section">Sec. 101123. Giant Sequoia Emergency Protection Program and Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H9B0FB2764B6246DBA22AB8F02BEE6BAE"><enum>13.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HAE04A9AA37D1498BBE002399254ECB92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph id="H729A94ECBBC34A5D92CACD1FE2F1EBC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2024, $10,000,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBFE9A03620D4E4FB5DD374E25A0F38D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2025, $25,000,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D1869E76B548F5854D6F31A7057185"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028, $30,000,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63C6C854BBB544BDB24AA29D8005E46E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2029 through 2033, $40,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13813F9D68704E69A7C7321C456AAF5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Of the amounts authorized under subsection (a), not less than 90 percent of funds shall be used to carry out section 6 and section 9 of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

