<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD4436FBF102467BB42F6C7155BE6621" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9381 IH: Holding Accountable Russian Mercenaries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9381</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To designate the Russian-based PMC Wagner Group as a foreign terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HD19A1429B8034665B17E143406CED083" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1045CB80D1524E2FB933262FE1DD966E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Holding Accountable Russian Mercenaries Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HARM Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H8BC8CC6A2CF04E9E95A22268AD2F224C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H74C31807F0DA47AFB7A83986DEF06AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of State's designation of an entity as a foreign terrorist organization results from a determination that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEDD63E38EFAF48429F8E3B40AA36ACC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the entity is foreign and engages in terrorism or terrorist activity; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BE1C6AA001841A1B546F20273A981D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terrorist activity threatens the security of the United States or its nationals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF293521B5664419DA7AA49D85CC21F52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The activities of the PMC Wagner Group and affiliated entities of Russian national Yevgeniy Prigozhin pose a threat to the national interests and national security of the United States and allies and partners of the United States, including with respect to Russia’s war on Ukraine, which President Biden declared, on March 2, 2022, <quote>pose[s] an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAAB4B0E9504425FBB7880DE0E73687D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On June 20, 2017, the Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control designated PMC Wagner and its military leader, Dmitry Utkin, pursuant to Executive Order 13660 (titled <quote>Blocking Property of Additional Certain Persons Contributing to the Situation in Ukraine</quote>) <quote>for being responsible for or complicit in, or having engaged in, directly or indirectly, actions or policies that threaten the peace, security, stability, sovereignty or territorial integrity of Ukraine</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB01583621A494CA9A5AD5FE26366DF1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On September 20, 2018, the Department of State added Yevgeniy Prigozhin and his affiliated entities, including the PMC Wagner Group, to the list of persons identified as part of, or operating for or on behalf of, the defense or intelligence sectors of the Government of the Russian Federation under section 231 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9525">22 U.S.C. 9525</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E29C799E5CA42FF9028AC5A8B2605D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The PMC Wagner Group, a self-described private actor that undertakes military action and subversive operations at the behest of the Government of the Russian Federation, is a <quote>terrorist group</quote> that engages in <quote>terrorism</quote> (as defined in section 140(d) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1988 and 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656f">22 U.S.C. 2656f(d)</external-xref>)), which is <quote>premeditated, politically motivated violence perpetrated against noncombatant targets by subnational groups or clandestine agents</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFA0BDE261214753B178ED91F4CF4CE4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The PMC Wagner Group and its affiliated entities have committed, or are credibly accused of committing, terrorist activity (as defined in section 212(a)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>), through their involvement in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22B5EA6B5B9C44C5880453544475B06E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the massacres, rape, and torture of civilians in Bucha, Ukraine, in March 2022;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB510346DF6F4CE5813F82CA2A40E3F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the massacres in Moura, Mali, in March 2022;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5213B1CBAEC44A4EB8BF2F084AB314C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the massacres of migrant workers and civilians in mining regions along the Sudan- Central African Republic border in 2022;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2ADBCD346EE4A0D8DC86DB698BAFA4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the murder of Russian journalists in the Central African Republic in June 2018 as well as threats against United States journalists investigating such incident;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1930F4BAF514C5C8C89316621381912"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the kidnapping of children in the Central African Republic in 2022 to work in mines;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1D5B6AFB3384A40AED06E662B8EA51E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the rape and sex trafficking of women and children in the Central African Republic between 2018 and 2022;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52EAC0549BC14478A82C6207E488D697"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the sabotage and lethal suppression of civilian protestors in Sudan in 2019;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5300E424F06E44E5B590F1CBB6A803CE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the use of nerve agents against Libya’s Government of National Accord and deployment of illegal landmines and booby-traps in civilian areas of Tripoli between 2019 and 2020;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95574A2198A240A79776A75D641B1A7A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the torture and execution of a Syrian national in June 2017; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BF7F967FCCD4D89B930A7CE70746950"><enum>(J)</enum><text>efforts to assassinate Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky in March 2022.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCF73EF7D8A9546FC881DF225E5B828A4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HF12EAAFE59D349538DA747306EF48560"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Russian-based PMC Wagner Group meets the criteria for designation by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H066410C77BE444D2BEB76705DC536669" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State should designate the PMC Wagner Group as a foreign terrorist organization under such section 219. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H7F12E66882CE4532A1DB25A151D59970"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of PMC Wagner Group as a foreign terrorist organization</header> <subsection id="H1A4EB50727EF4983971CB0018FDFB337"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall designate the PMC Wagner Group as a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H729E882C0748487C936786ACBAB19604"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The designation required under subsection (a) shall equally apply to any affiliated and successor entities to the PMC Wagner Group undertaking malign activities against the United States and its allies and partners, including activities taking place in Ukraine, Africa, and the Middle East.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7297D1C0B55D4664A4BF548597813DC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that such a waiver is in the national security interest of the United States. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDAA6A18DF0BB4B6B8976DF3E0CFB9EB5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H0B232845334046E39C5ABAB1D609A3CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F66BE41679243DA96025FEC2EAA6F4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC57FDF84B0FA4AB8A73F244BD06B9626"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1383C3F579F04E319DE380D73BBBE331"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H915D503383C3448C9667451D72A12C79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B107CCC5A274949B2A4EDE2B686ECEE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54CB2252264349D6A8BB28C2E1D2274C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


