<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C53A85F3BDD41C998839B82D00EE07F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7220 IH: Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7220</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a business credit for gain from the sale of real property for use as a manufactured home community, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC45DDB7860CD41CB8176B57B7B694916" style="OLC">
<section id="HF6195804FE8B4342AD2F2A38B477019A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1DB2ED88F1EE47CEBE5606D535407A43"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H9390D038388D4AFFBD2B46F929687141"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 17 million people live in manufactured homes, benefiting from high-quality affordable homes that can provide them stability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5AB81B7F5E940AA8BE02F6762DC6861"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of manufactured homes are disproportionately low-income households: in 2013, the median annual household income for those living in manufactured housing was $28,400;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H01B6909CBEFE4811B5FFBFD6C8E6588A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>about 75 percent of manufactured home households earn less than $50,000;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E79DEBBE6914CB2A137E2F6B5CB6A26"><enum>(4)</enum><text>over 10 percent of United States veterans live in manufactured homes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C2BF3E306D74C7D92F574F1EB8B891E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the late 1990s, manufactured housing represented two-thirds of the new affordable housing produced in the United States, and it remains the largest source of unsubsidized affordable housing in the country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2C2172095014E8CA1FAA1A4D03250B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>as of 2015, the average cost per square foot for a new manufactured home was $48, less than half the $101 per square foot of the structure-only cost of a new site-built home;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H87B8B1F94FBE4CD6A2CBF33E4DD15BB5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in 2009, 43 percent of all new homes that sold for less than $150,000 were manufactured homes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F5F37B1E7BA4B71B8F88137B4EB6E51"><enum>(8)</enum><text>manufactured homes account for 23 percent of new home sales under $200,000;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F0BD3E7E01C4F3193CDCC8B59F7CF53"><enum>(9)</enum><text>more than 50,000 manufactured home communities, or <quote>mobile home parks</quote>, exist throughout the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA32DE0FC49C4F9B8D33549DDFB3B4B8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>more than 2.9 million manufactured homes are placed in manufactured home communities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2F9162F93ED4019B20483B768A00EB3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>manufactured home communities provide critical affordable housing but receive very little local, State, or Federal funds subsidizing the cost of these homes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCADD4FC0D37947509DD33957EDFD2DA8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>manufactured home owners in communities may own the home, but they do not own the land under their homes, leaving them vulnerable to rent increases, arbitrary rule enforcement, and even closure of the community if the community owner decides to convert the land to some other use;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC607E01EC4C467B8182419C8946F9AD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>eviction or closure of manufactured home communities is very disruptive to residents who may be unable to pay the thousands of dollars it takes to move their home or even find a new location for their home;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71B2A5A9158044EAB13B86EC3AFAD856"><enum>(14)</enum><text>in the past two decades, a national network of housing providers has helped residents purchase and own the land and manage the community in order to preserve a crucial source of affordable housing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H913BCBC21E4146A1AC1449D86B61D8C4"><enum>(15)</enum><text>nationwide, there are more than 1,000 of these stable, permanent ownership cooperatives or nonprofit-owned developments in more than a dozen States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H602CD1D14D2248EF891AEDE6B3A611E3"><enum>(16)</enum><text>members continue to own their own homes individually and an equal share of the land beneath the entire neighborhood where everyone has a say in the way the resident-owned community is run, and major decisions are made by democratic vote by a member-elected board of directors;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA789478974644347952559FDA57A744A"><enum>(17)</enum><text>in New Hampshire, more than 20 percent of manufactured home communities are owned by residents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9ED2E21660944D09E29363E28FEB1EB"><enum>(18)</enum><text>in Vermont, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Washington, Oregon, and Minnesota, resident-owned cooperatives and nonprofit ownership have flourished;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1947A7790B994F299C359AA587B9F9CD"><enum>(19)</enum><text>nationwide, only 2 percent of all manufactured home communities are resident- or nonprofit-owned;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54B1DF921B284644B0B03DA089F112EB"><enum>(20)</enum><text>owners are frequently reluctant to sell the community because they would prefer to pass the property on to their heirs tax free and avoid capital gains taxes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C0E273C8E1A4E1C9743DBD6AA2691AF"><enum>(21)</enum><text>when the owner dies, the heirs frequently sell the community to the highest bidder resulting in displacement for dozens and sometimes hundreds of families; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCB0A1951737490C8BC4196AD03688D0"><enum>(22)</enum><text>a Federal tax benefit needs to be established to induce owners to sell to residents they have known for decades or to nonprofit organizations in order to preserve the community for years to come.</text></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE5237BB42D9462C8CDC944036C1CC3C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tax credit for manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBD4623E91454C899E8DCC8FD247A796"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to business related credits) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16263AFC04654F1A94019098F0E6D9C6" style="OLC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFF463286D75428E8203A965D9FB4FF0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>45U.</enum><header>Manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76A09BAEA315470CB2CF2B1F5CB60E7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the manufactured home community sale credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 75 percent of the qualified gain received by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA78B34D9B46849349CCACDCABF0FDA8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HADF6D7C74F5B4FE4AEDCA2CE39449742"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified gain</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified gain</term> means gain from the sale or exchange of real property to a qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation if—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0CA080B96979425496581CECF8CC8F17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the real property is acquired for use as a manufactured home community, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA64DE56D80A84B36BE7C26AEE6525A2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements of paragraph (2) are met.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E6036420C8A4A208091B268E0A8233E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements of this paragraph are met if—</text> <subparagraph id="H28332F66C7354F5D98D447EF7ACB91EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the seller (or any related person) owned the property for not less than the 2-year period ending before the sale or exchange, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6B19D39740D04D33A5F8873D9A7254B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the property is transferred subject to a binding covenant that the property will be used as a manufactured home community for a term of not less than 50 years (or, in the case of a manufactured home community located in a State the laws of which restrict such covenant to a lesser term, the maximum permissible term allowed under such State laws).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9E76F75CA58248AF92062028232599DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Manufactured home community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufactured home community</term> means a community composed primarily of manufactured homes used solely for residential purposes and owned by a manufactured home community cooperative or corporation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45397FD997FB4762B57723F37FE6BAC7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Manufactured home community cooperative or corporation</header>
<subparagraph id="H4D14F0EC614F433D84BA10DF60C30EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation</term> means a cooperative or a nonprofit corporation established pursuant to the laws of the State in which the property used as a manufactured home community is located and which—</text> <clause id="H368AA17A8F0D42B8BDC0AA800B75B718"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a community owned by a nonprofit corporation whose membership interests are sold on a nonappreciating basis, has only one class of membership consisting of residents, and</text></clause>
<clause id="H6AA86A9A9C784504B74B5C1212482093"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a community owned by a cooperative, has no more than two classes of membership, which includes both members and a tax-exempt organization actively engaged in supporting affordable housing and resident-owned manufactured home communities.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F117A9FAE094DD6A013DB5A2D8843D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Governance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall not be treated as a qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation for purposes of subparagraph (A) unless governance of the entity is carried out by members elected to a board of directors with voting structured equitably among all members.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C05834F08654A3EBCEB9077E3272375"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Member</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>member</term> means—</text> <clause id="HC61A749A22634D5EBDF06215AB879D5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who—</text>
<subclause id="H3E9B898655944FA6B4C8E5E757D7B85E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has attained the age of 18,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB587601BE2AA46CF9A32F2A2632FACD9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is entitled by reason of the individual’s membership interest to execute an occupancy agreement with the manufactured home community cooperative nonprofit with respect to one site in the manufactured home community for the purposes of situating a manufactured home owned by the member or, as permitted by the manufactured community cooperative or corporation, the member’s trust or other entity, and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H907FD4EE124841648A387F337ADE03FA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a resident of the manufactured home community, and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4B611A1B65F24E139688B022B3A61259"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a tax exempt organization.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8E94A0C57BAC43CEBAB19D334FD8254F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Membership interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>membership interest</term> means an ownership interest in a manufactured home community cooperative or corporation or a membership interest in a manufactured home community nonprofit corporation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H15D191A3E8D7402CAA631FC895F57991"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Manufactured home</header><text>The term <term>manufactured home</term> means a structure, transportable in one or more sections, which—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC6CB73E4C48F43E3A8E25B5FC6C59772"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the traveling mode, is 8 body feet or more in width and 40 body feet or more in length, or when erected on site, is 320 square feet or more,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91093E1244A442AF9522371C85E0A25B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is built on a permanent chassis and designed to be used as a dwelling (with or without a permanent foundation when connected to required utilities) and includes plumbing, heating, and electrical heating systems, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0ED00B172604CA398944F44722B288D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a structure manufactured after June 15, 1976, is certified as meeting the Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards issued under the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5401">42 U.S.C. 5401–5426</external-xref>) by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and displays a label of such certification on the exterior of each transportable section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C017FB60A034816BDF94863E30BBEB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <paragraph id="HA9943936873341E3B629F8F3B3405D3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(A), a person (hereafter in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>related person</quote>) is related to the seller if—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB41A745F7B8F44A5AA0D654FFA1CE0F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the related person bears a relationship to the seller specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H869F26133A9343C993ABD4E7B4536BF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the related person and the seller are engaged in trades or businesses under common control (within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2D12D8B7D3B042E29323366D361D1E9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election by both seller and buyer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The credit is allowable under this section only if—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4B202E1B6D7417397B5404F0DCCCF16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>elected by both the seller and the buyer of the real property and evidenced by an affidavit executed by both parties, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H49F5A957F1564D039011C898DB5F6217"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the buyer of the real property records the affidavit and the affidavit is referenced in its deed to the real property.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The seller shall elect the credit under this section on its return of tax. </continuation-text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H2BCE6FB2C31F44738654E0B45E49F7E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax upon violation of covenant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is imposed a tax on the buyer for a violation of the covenant specified in subsection (b)(2)(B). The amount of such tax shall be 20 percent of the net proceeds after settlement for the sale or exchange of the real property referred to in subsection (b)(2). For purposes of section 501(a), the tax imposed by this subsection shall not be treated as a tax imposed by this subtitle.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HED30CF24880D4C14A50BFDD6E0B1967A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section, including the recapture of the tax benefit under this section in any case in which the real property described in subsection (b) is not used as a manufactured home community for at least 50 years.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE03D5F9C6ECF4FC08FB666ADA7FDCF03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (32), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (33) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1753F01112C24D4EBBE821264D253AA0" style="OLC">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5919B2E8FF144E7FA93AEAC940D65968"><enum>(34)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufactured home community sale credit determined under section 45T(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H696F0824A4494454B960628465EE1429"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD64C052638640819110DCCA87329F74"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 196 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (13), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (14) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DEE0BD3488843CC8C264D37FD9897B0" style="OLC">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3338E7A2FD14CC3843D91EAAB3BBE2D"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufactured home community sale credit determined under section 45U(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7C31D7D4E774476ABEAA1100521A1FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48E54AA3881A495B9FB036C96632384F" style="OLC">
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H16263AFC04654F1A94019098F0E6D9C6" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
<toc-entry idref="HFFF463286D75428E8203A965D9FB4FF0" level="section">Sec. 45U. Manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C23091581FF4C6A87D114ECF4BD5292"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2021.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

