<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H3D572734287F437A8FB1010E98F97176" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 3326 RH: Public Land Renewable Energy Development Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 459</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3326</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–636, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210519">May 19, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote the development of renewable energy on public lands, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H273F3BC6E84E42FEA68F73D45EF57E3F" style="OLC"><section id="HDDE095A4890B426395270080FB2A855F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Land Renewable Energy Development Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAC37D25130344203B5BA1D1CFEA59250"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HDDE095A4890B426395270080FB2A855F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAC37D25130344203B5BA1D1CFEA59250" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCD18C0D201134C06A9576ECD2584438E" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE1D097D3211C423DA55DE11406A7683F" level="section">Sec. 4. Land use planning; updates to programmatic environmental impact statements.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFC66B6C2DBCA47839ADDD974E000213B" level="section">Sec. 5. Limited grandfathering.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H14F447FF25E64A879AE8E36BDC90BAAD" level="section">Sec. 6. Disposition of revenues.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H252BB842D40043ECB2F38390F5E1C47F" level="section">Sec. 7. Savings.</toc-entry></toc></section><section id="HCD18C0D201134C06A9576ECD2584438E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H30A7CC0C69D74ECF936DEADFE7869B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered land</header><text>The term <term>covered land</term> means land that is—</text><subparagraph id="H0AF64381B6CB4223AF7BF88C471EE80B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal lands administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AD4BD4D2C0242D0AC424630E5BF1F0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not excluded from the development of geothermal, solar, or wind energy under—</text><clause id="HB74A38AD808C4C48AAEA9A1E97B740CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a land use plan; or</text></clause><clause id="HCF000272EF2D4D5F8D57115440D3FE13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other Federal law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46AF0183586A443AB60109FB60B42D60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion area</header><text>The term <term>exclusion area</term> means covered land that is identified by the Bureau of Land Management as not suitable for development of renewable energy projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70D2393A7D2B4241ADB29A5CEA3F899E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H96014BB0E1084616B637C1FF60107B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public lands; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB20A0FB56EE04B7E8166A2B9D8514169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lands of the National Forest System as described in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H333DF515F3E844CCA14E9BBBD734052E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund established by section 6(c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12B0F676B0CF4F3DBD2506EF57029760"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Land use plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>land use plan</term> means— </text><subparagraph id="H6050E65322A34C76A3D526393FA1B648"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in regard to Federal land, a land use plan established under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB898CC88DD8480FB62F79FE21D5C657"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in regard to National Forest System lands, a land management plan approved, amended, or revised under section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H788A3AA821B24718AB325E217B454CE9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Priority area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>priority area</term> means covered land identified by the land use planning process of the Bureau of Land Management as being a preferred location for a renewable energy project, including a designated leasing area (as defined in section 2801.5(b) of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) that is identified under the rule of the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Competitive Processes, Terms, and Conditions for Leasing Public Lands for Solar and Wind Energy Development and Technical Changes and Corrections</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 92122 (December 19, 2016)) (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AB5412F6B1347FE9A6735DFAA911104"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The term <term>public lands</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86279DE661DA43E2AF1D74429DA340F1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Renewable energy project</header><text>The term <term>renewable energy project</term> means a project carried out on covered land that uses wind, solar, or geothermal energy to generate energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EFB6B63239F42B0A3E0BC5F0173FF2D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H907DDB7ADD49456E8D422F0B6AE1FDB9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Variance area</header><text>The term <term>variance area</term> means covered land that is—</text><subparagraph id="H9CD1A303F9694292BE9BB378299AC50D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not an exclusion area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H126CF776572F43C782F816D064280BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not a priority area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86AF675D1C11443F9CC8ED8E6B510B43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identified by the Secretary as potentially available for renewable energy development and could be approved without a plan amendment, consistent with the principles of multiple use (as defined in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HE1D097D3211C423DA55DE11406A7683F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Land use planning; updates to programmatic environmental impact statements</header><subsection id="H0E14547A97EE45CEA644DD7B109E34C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Priority areas</header><paragraph id="H1FC14662A72741ABA7BCF1D46E099D30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish priority areas on covered land for geothermal, solar, and wind energy projects, consistent with the principles of multiple use (as defined in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)) and the renewable energy permitting goal enacted by the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>). Among applications for a given renewable energy source, proposed projects located in priority areas for that renewable energy source shall—</text><subparagraph id="H626B111FC6014EEC8FC1259740C3DDC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be given the highest priority for incentivizing deployment thereon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7078C75DB17543508528A0874A944C1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be offered the opportunity to participate in any regional mitigation plan developed for the relevant priority areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7E0798ED0240FCA89C7593EA86DC81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishing priority areas</header><subparagraph id="HC885518932954F27A3453001EE5D3834"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Geothermal energy</header><text>For geothermal energy, the Secretary shall establish priority areas as soon as practicable, but not later than 5 years, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AAF2E8C9121448E9346D5B993919C3A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Solar energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For solar energy—</text><clause id="H2D6CF0D9366E4F5AA8039D3C0E8B9F5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solar designated leasing areas (including the solar energy zones established by Bureau of Land Management Solar Energy Program, established in October 2012), and any subsequent land use plan amendments, shall be considered to be priority areas for solar energy projects; and</text></clause><clause id="H64139C1255B94745B639D48AC6E48DD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary shall complete a process to consider establishing additional solar priority areas as soon as practicable, but not later than 3 years, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA48737DFA9014F7CB1867375D298BDA3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Wind energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For wind energy, the Secretary shall complete a process to consider establishing additional wind priority areas as soon as practicable, but not later than 3 years, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE9DA58FBA274D69B424C9DE287996FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Variance areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Variance areas shall be considered for renewable energy project development, consistent with the principles of multiple use (as defined in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)) and the renewable energy permitting goal enacted by the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>), and applications for a given renewable energy source located in those variance areas shall be timely processed in order to assist in meeting that goal.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBDE2D660CAAE4C3DB28EB5BBC6CA096C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review and modification</header><paragraph id="HB0FE14EB366543A6BD7EBB04BA95FA28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less than once every 10 years, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H645C34C813184924BB24EF5D8335F530"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the adequacy of land allocations for geothermal, solar, and wind energy priority, exclusion, and variance areas for the purpose of encouraging and facilitating new renewable energy development opportunities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7468BB870A7449C926FA3274E0D92CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>based on the review carried out under subparagraph (A), add, modify, or eliminate priority, variance, and exclusion areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H467C35D334574C17BB7F1272E1D2B7EE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the renewable energy land use planning published in the Desert Renewable Energy Conservation Plan developed by the California Energy Commission, the California Department of Fish and Wildlife, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service until January 1, 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5F619579A6E4C06871BCE24CCACE797"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act</header><text>For purposes of this section, compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be accomplished—</text><paragraph id="HB80E4C2F15474C5B9265C31B1D208FC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for geothermal energy, by updating the document entitled <quote>Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Geothermal Leasing in the Western United States</quote>, dated October 2008, and incorporating any additional regional analyses that have been completed by Federal agencies since that programmatic environmental impact statement was finalized;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H811297D187394A54B90F1756713CF6A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for solar energy, by updating the document entitled <quote>Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement (PEIS) for Solar Energy Development in Six Southwestern States</quote>, dated July 2012, and incorporating any additional regional analyses that have been completed by Federal agencies since that programmatic environmental impact statement was finalized; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E586E499BB34FD2AAE97834A8C8B7A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for wind energy, by updating the document entitled <quote>Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement on Wind Energy Development on BLM–Administered Lands in the Western United States</quote>, dated July 2005, and incorporating any additional regional analyses that have been completed by Federal agencies since the programmatic environmental impact statement was finalized.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC1DE170054A4D3C9CA29C99A4DCF9E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No effect on processing site specific applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Site specific environmental review and processing of permits for proposed projects shall proceed during preparation of an updated programmatic environmental impact statement, resource management plan, or resource management plan amendment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFF8A0CB2E76F4CAFA2874481D8EE926A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In developing updates required by this section, the Secretary shall coordinate, on an ongoing basis, with appropriate State, Tribal, and local governments, transmission infrastructure owners and operators, developers, and other appropriate entities to ensure that priority areas identified by the Secretary are—</text><paragraph id="HF8C345AB43404D50A7BA70007459F492"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">economically viable (including having access to existing and planned transmission lines);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0995141AB7B5434FBDFFC54A43A5F6B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">likely to avoid or minimize impacts to habitat for animals and plants, recreation, cultural resources, and other uses of covered land; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8720D862B3C444C94F6FB275A4F282D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consistent with section 202 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>), including subsection (c)(9) of that section (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712(c)(9)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HFC66B6C2DBCA47839ADDD974E000213B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limited grandfathering</header><subsection commented="no" id="HB9C2798D35C8417C8EA3E16F42C676C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of project</header><text>In this section, the term <term>project</term> means a system described in section 2801.9(a)(4) of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF0A879C278A045F79BF0D28051D06384"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To pay rents and fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise agreed to by the owner of a project, the owner of a project that applied for a right-of-way under section 501 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1761">43 U.S.C. 1761</external-xref>) on or before December 19, 2016, shall be obligated to pay with respect to the right-of-way all rents and fees in effect before the effective date of the rule of the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Competitive Processes, Terms, and Conditions for Leasing Public Lands for Solar and Wind Energy Development and Technical Changes and Corrections</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 92122 (December 19, 2016)).</text></subsection></section><section id="H14F447FF25E64A879AE8E36BDC90BAAD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disposition of revenues</header><subsection id="H7C701163F33D460987B014AF64745F0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disposition of revenues</header><paragraph id="HD4363AB82C864FCEA9120405C62E25A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), beginning on January 1, 2022, of amounts collected from a wind or solar project as bonus bids, rentals, fees, or other payments under a right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization the following shall be made available, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HFB1A0071327D4E04A9F581CF2C2DF5D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Twenty-five percent shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the State within the boundaries of which the revenue is derived.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD846A2D14F924F81BF26C7558E649BC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Twenty-five percent shall be paid by the Secretary of the Treasury to the one or more counties within the boundaries of which the revenue is derived, to be allocated among the counties based on the percentage of land from which the revenue is derived.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE57E9755BF4773BE1584D4DBDA3B58"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Twenty-five percent shall be deposited in the Treasury and be made available to the Secretary to carry out the program established under this Act, including the transfer of the funds by the Bureau of Land Management to other Federal agencies and State agencies to facilitate the processing of renewable energy permits on Federal land, with priority given to using the amounts, to the maximum extent practicable without detrimental impacts to emerging markets, to expediting the issuance of permits required for the development of renewable energy projects in the States from which the revenues are derived.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H158E04F6E14B4AED828CA25723BC627A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Twenty-five percent shall be deposited in the Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund established by subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9626BA6F9D3740B9B56342CA9A7E9F72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7028AB509AF843738936A9EFE9CDB36D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Amounts collected under section 504(g) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1764">43 U.S.C. 1764(g)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8291F21F8084483A8528A59DC5E8A0C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts deposited into the National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund under section 200402(b) of title 54, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7136E1C541CA4A46950F5A3BB810E655"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments to States and counties</header><paragraph id="H41AF9EBFF99A4126BECDF154D4DC49E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts paid to States and counties under subsection (a)(1) shall be used consistent with section 35 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/191">30 U.S.C. 191</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5CA8E34EC204C70BC57785EA3471F74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payments in lieu of taxes</header><text>A payment to a county under paragraph (1) shall be in addition to a payment in lieu of taxes received by the county under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/69">chapter 69</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DCCB66B4DB346EAB3EBC90C638EB7C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund</header><paragraph id="H1D1B664EB0FA49BAAA01935CCFF0A45F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund, which shall be administered by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55F2913549FA4D27A9C1233E39C65A6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Secretary may make amounts in the Fund available to Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies to be distributed in regions in which renewable energy projects are located on Federal land. Such amounts may be used to—</text><subparagraph id="H068DE5EB26B4497680C4B32C928572AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restore and protect—</text><clause id="H3DA3B2280B334E9F9AC828323854E635"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fish and wildlife habitat for affected species;</text></clause><clause id="H8C4C1B7043214F44B63C3B3C7AE4EA71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fish and wildlife corridors for affected species; and</text></clause><clause id="HAE998D3797EB43AC8A6A95F748B43926"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wetlands, streams, rivers, and other natural water bodies in areas affected by wind, geothermal, or solar energy development; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E1737C744A646A3AF2D597C30C900A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preserve and improve recreational access to Federal land and water in an affected region through an easement, right-of-way, or other instrument from willing landowners for the purpose of enhancing public access to existing Federal land and water that is inaccessible or restricted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF04D936B08EC41FD864F5D92F7CB13DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State and Tribal agencies, nonprofit organizations, and other appropriate entities to carry out the activities described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86424DBE58A04FC6B730C7AEF09E6525"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investment of Fund</header><subparagraph id="H456770DDF54F4CA78ECABE573DB8AAB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts deposited in the Fund shall earn interest in an amount determined by the Secretary of the Treasury on the basis of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC2792366D0148E6A949DDB8814E5366"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Interest earned under subparagraph (A) may be expended in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H108BBC8EB7874C3CA901609C6436C05E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate that includes a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H350F72B0FFBD436B9001AC172996124D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount collected as described in subsection (a), by source, during that fiscal year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BD00F1FB9B541E7A95D6A4E72284B5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount and purpose of payments during that fiscal year to each Federal, State, local, and Tribal agency under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7487544451BD4750B75248A157DC6F06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B58C39EA0FC4626A2F12651A51D1C2C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intent of Congress</header><text>It is the intent of Congress that the revenues deposited and used in the Fund shall supplement (and not supplant) annual appropriations for activities described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H252BB842D40043ECB2F38390F5E1C47F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Savings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall continue to manage public lands under the principles of multiple use and sustained yield in accordance with title I of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), as applicable, including due consideration of mineral and nonrenewable energy-related projects and other nonrenewable energy uses, for the purposes of land use planning, permit processing, and conducting environmental reviews.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

