<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0DD4333679A44FB88DFC4B54ABEF423D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4009 RH: Enslaved Voyages Memorial Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 363</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4009</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–467]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210617">June 17, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 17, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour to establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H6E09402397A348878A42A0F635CDEEF6"><section id="H650D537845904379863416F8CC20A3EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enslaved Voyages Memorial Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE432B882CBA04A7D825D6DB9687E1CA2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization to establish commemorative work</header><subsection id="H0733E508A3A34564A6ADCEA05DA04DB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour may establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District of Columbia and its environs to commemorate the enslaved individuals, whose identities may be known or unknown, who endured the Middle Passage.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDCFE35D00F3411E950F78E2A5EEA1EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance with standards for commemorative works</header><text>The establishment of the commemorative work under this section shall be in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Commemorative Works Act</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E47DC68F99948BEBCF56EE659BADF63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of Federal funds</header><paragraph id="H76FF6E045E2E41B7B615866BFD55A43B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal funds may not be used to pay any expense of the establishment of the commemorative work under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2276A5342B54048A1878EDD022D67F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibility of the Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour shall be solely responsible for acceptance of contributions for, and payment of the expenses of, the establishment of the commemorative work under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H090D773285634BCD97D0EF024538DB16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit of excess funds</header><paragraph id="H62174BDBE8A3491EBC9BEC0834EAEF19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If upon payment of all expenses for the establishment of the memorial (including the maintenance and preservation amount required by section 8906(b)(1) of title 40, United States Code), there remains a balance of funds received for the establishment of the commemorative work, the Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour shall transmit the amount of the balance to the Secretary of the Interior for deposit in the account provided for in section 8906(b)(3) of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3683FE6143940F48AD4D684DF2A7793"><enum>(2)</enum><header>On expiration of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If upon expiration of the authority for the commemorative work under section 8903(e) of title 40, United States Code, there remains a balance of funds received for the establishment of the commemorative work, the Georgetown African American Historic Landmark Project and Tour shall transmit the amount of the balance to a separate account with the National Park Foundation for memorials, to be available to the Secretary of the Interior or Administrator (as appropriate) following the process provided in section 8906(b)(4) of title 40, United States Code, for accounts established under section 8906(b)(2) or (3) of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

