<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD34722AD55614FF5AA9625CF191F0A07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9487 IH: Advancing Safe Medications for Moms and Babies Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9487</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221212">December 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement certain recommendations to promote the inclusion of pregnant and lactating women in clinical research, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1D8B3A3EFD1946BB8C712AACA642DDC4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H91C4B0204400403E8DBD3F05815D73FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Safe Medications for Moms and Babies Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HAA1127A9DA6D470FB3E65EE3E2DAF956"><enum>2.</enum><header>Updating FDA regulations to remove pregnant women as a vulnerable research population</header> <subsection id="H61D797CBD9D74A6B9096D5A5DB06C969"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B803834CA7F48378AF5D451938579BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to facilitate compliance with applicable Federal regulations relating to the protection of pregnant women participating in research as subjects; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H408EFD5850D34A7D978890E86B3FF624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote the inclusion of pregnant women in clinical research.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0705DD3D1BC4DD1B26A1DC8DBBF0D81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Harmonization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes specified in subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with other applicable statutes, issue such regulations as may be appropriate to harmonize the regulations of the Food and Drug Administration relating to the protection of human subjects, including parts 50 and 56 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, with the latest regulations of the Department of Health and Human Services relating to the inclusion of pregnant women as subjects in clinical research.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H90F1011014AD4FA68CEE083985597692"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall finalize the regulations required by subsection (b) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HB639B5977CCB48799389E0F4BF346BB5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clearinghouse of clinical trials and registries</header> 
<subsection id="H6701530F1984433B85376E4229CF2907"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, and in consultation with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall establish and maintain a national clearinghouse of educational materials and current information on registries and clinical trials that enroll pregnant and lactating women in order to—</text> <paragraph id="H103BD719CC284C878035BCC71147B6C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable pregnant and lactating women, their families, and health care professionals to easily identify and enroll in registries and clinical trials;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AE95EBF550640C790E12DF3D405E6A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educate pregnant and lactating women, their families, and health care professionals on the importance of enrolling in registries and clinical trials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DF51C2FCAFF4D71812B6DBDBD04F622"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform pregnant and lactating women, their families, and health care professionals about the general requirements, commitments, and benefits associated with participating in a registry or clinical trial.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D0F4455926E47BC8CB9D12B9CA6BC26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, and in consultation with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall ensure that the clearinghouse under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H8E9D10BC1E6F4ED19D7EDE27A6E6E1CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is accessible by means of the internet;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CB55BA61A514E0EB28CC916B1B04A19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is updated on a regular basis, not less than quarterly;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39717345DE0343CE825EE088B690BACC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is designed for consumers, incorporates a user-friendly interface, and is searchable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83D2E80231004236863A682CA0273C6D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes links to related public and private sector resources on registries and clinical trials described in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08D327ECE6B74D368F6F15DAA2B179E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is available to the public by October 1, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF1C1224571542118843B406A372EC38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Planning</header> 
<paragraph id="H096E1B34F50E415BB58780B66860D419"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the clearinghouse under subsection (a), the Secretary, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E3205E824774BC99F040A4A4FC4B31E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop criteria for which registries and clinical trials are eligible for listing in the clearinghouse under subsection (a); </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBB11B9B06CA4003B4874976DDD39A17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a procedure for archiving closed registries and clinical trials; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6AD838D83C148A29B1792937D5C8B11"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify educational resources needed for the clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EADFE7EAC0E4F8DBF859CC46DE6025C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>The Secretary shall solicit public input on content to be included in the clearinghouse under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6474D453B0CA42FAA886C47B0D9832AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9184A75E1D404918BE5851B545403F97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$4,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2024; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DE24465BA594986840E675AE4B203DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBA1E70026F0D4129AD820787FF347D08"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordinating Committee on Research Specific to Pregnant and Lactating Women</header> 
<subsection id="HC28147348E7843E191A4B133A64964AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a committee, in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), to be known as the Committee on Research Specific to Pregnant and Lactating Women or the PRGLAC Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to advise on coordinating Federal activities to address gaps in knowledge and research regarding safe and effective therapies for pregnant and lactating women.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE4AB738E6886486D823460210F042B57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC338D674529B45A99E45020BAFC68FBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advise on coordinating Federal activities to promote the inclusion of pregnant and lactating women in clinical research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB82AF82E41AA43759F14704FFD391C3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote opportunities for Federal agencies and private actors to advance the inclusion of pregnant and lactating women in clinical research;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3AF1ED99BE8466687AF5D4D95BA57D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and annually update a summary of Federal agency progress toward implementing recommendations included in the September 2018 Report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the August 2020 Report Implementation Plan to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, prepared by the Task Force on Research Specific to Pregnant Women and Lactating Women; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30BEA91FD0714EE0A58339B2A246D2D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify new recommendations for the Secretary regarding Federal activities to address gaps in knowledge and research regarding safe and effective therapies for pregnant and lactating women; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF369E0B9FBB7473ABD28C0D390394EC8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive updates on private sector and international efforts to include pregnant and lactating women in clinical research.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7D98F2E53ACE4EC490565F0B7F304615"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H61CEE3711ABC49F68A2A22090CDF9789"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC9ED72F870274092B658A2D93A5D7BCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal members listed in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF1D5630BC8243AFAF11D7682BE9016E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the non-Federal members appointed pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2746552899B74E628C086E2ABC3631A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal members</header><text>The Federal members of the Committee shall consist of the following Federal officials (or their designees):</text> <subparagraph id="HFEED50355E1D42869C98CFA96F6A7700"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD83E823F209A44C5ADD10BF9283866FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, the Director of the Office of Research on Women’s Health of the National Institutes of Health, and the directors of such other national research institutes and national centers of the National Institutes of Health as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5880E28D1B9C46E08C07F70E3BF0A6AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3B16AF9F62649D2A03C9A80E2D389C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89D3AB45B8B8486D968C13D40A67BE8C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Director of the Office on Women’s Health of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18B92A992E6E456DA462C2CBB7946102"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Director of the National Vaccine Program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99C88D9CEAE4425783A36AA5452AC7D7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Director of the Office for Human Research Protections of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B0D98B1490A46A5982D3780DA2837B0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Administrator of Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7A20B6D1C7D4F9FBDED1BC541CC8103"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The head of any other research-related agency or department not described in subparagraphs (A) through (H) as the Secretary determines appropriate, which may include the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF74259CD7E7E463CA6E3F3ED121C4260"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal members</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3371DADE497944159C9CE759B4522A59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Federal members of the Committee shall consist of—</text> <clause id="HA7C3BC0C2C224FF2A280711CCBAE0916"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from relevant medical societies with subject matter expertise on pregnant women, lactating women, or children;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDD15FD9379224F38A75615879724940D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>representatives from nonprofit organizations with expertise related to the health of women and children;</text></clause> <clause id="H5211C2315FD0494D9007EE7A839153F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relevant industry representatives;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H752572DDFC0E49068FF76CDCDF913CB0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>individuals with ethical and legal expertise in clinical trials and research;</text></clause> <clause id="H1FA17DFEFB584D7F8731ED48AF3050B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from relevant nonprofit organizations with expertise in clinical research; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA04C50B83CF3434E9D0046C32F26F402"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other representatives, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1406380648D1416BAF0E0B21C30845D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The non-Federal members of the Committee shall compose not more than one-half, and not less than one-third, of the total membership of the Committee.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6A683663F8E44F190591184E7A0B0D8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint the non-Federal members of the Committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21DD933ED1F74461A77D0610B008FB1B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal members of the Committee shall serve for a term of 4 years, and may be reappointed for 1 additional 4-year term. Any non-Federal member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. A non-Federal member may serve after the expiration of the member’s term until a successor has taken office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H30FFDAD7A8CF4DAF8A56CB9771E41A19"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide the Committee such administrative support as the Secretary determines to be necessary for carrying out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HECC81451B3394D6B8538F78E950A3800"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Committee shall meet at least 2 times each year and shall convene public meetings, as appropriate, to fulfill its duties under subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A55A68E977C4C49A78020C855E0413D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> 
<paragraph id="H2315FE2C0A564669960413DC2A6A47D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every other year thereafter, the Committee shall prepare and submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="H81063437FF194A529CF00D5B1E185E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress of Federal agencies in implementing the recommendations and implementation plan described in subsection (b)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA72A90A0BFEC424B999E39AFE87E3796"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal activities undertaken to advance the inclusion of pregnant and lactating women in clinical research; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DE141176E75423CB7AAADAFA8E211D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional recommendations for the Secretary regarding Federal activities to address gaps in knowledge and research regarding safe and effective therapies for pregnant and lactating women.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H653CC98C0E384EA0B3A0023F2614A261"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the reports required by paragraph (1) available on a public website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF4432E49F3204F12905216B6598ACA80"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Supplemental report on Department guidance</header> <paragraph id="H544441EB693541579987915938B9A216"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Committee shall prepare and submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report to inform guidance of the Department of Health and Human Services to facilitate the conduct of clinical research involving pregnant and lactating women.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D86C17E2A7441A399DDBA15079F2C67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H1718A9A0B7BB4BAD96C8CC3F88B5D0D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on which clinical studies require consent from both biological parents, including information quantifying how requiring consent from both biological parents limits participation in such clinical studies;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DD8F90F915E4395B1E072BFC018C977"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices and recommendations for institutional review boards related to the inclusion of pregnant and lactating women in clinical research, including information on successes and challenges of using a centralized institutional review board; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H991E0806B05A46B483C1C59356EE9330"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of statutory programs enacted to spur pediatric-specific information in Food and Drug Administration-approved therapies, such as the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/109">Public Law 107–109</external-xref>) and the Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/155">Public Law 108–155</external-xref>), and how approaches taken in such programs can be applied to clinical research including pregnant and lactating women.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6155B381F75443590ED51B8AA73E293"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make the report required by paragraph (1) available on a public website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2E5D4709F0EF4D398FB1673311AAC5C1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header> <paragraph id="HB66803DCF3204BD1A0C0F1B34CD74A19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Committee is established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAEB0A8AFD354860B0640806216DFB02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Secretary may extend the operation of the Committee for up to 3 additional 2-year periods following the 5-year period described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that the extension is appropriate to monitor the implementation of the recommendations and implementation plan described in subsection (b)(3) or any additional recommendations made by the Committee.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HCCE38F5008A34946BADF42E3AEB437D3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Raising awareness of research that includes pregnant and lactating women in clinical research</header> <subsection id="H3B8FFC0E6518461C896FCAB468F084F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall establish and implement an education campaign designed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9AC2122C7604E5D8C47C286C0503357"><enum>(1)</enum><text>educate the public on the importance of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2E16BDA0D3144AD96A687593DA41C2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including pregnant and lactating women in clinical research to better inform health care decisions on the safety and effectiveness of medications for pregnant and lactating women before, during, and after pregnancy; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13770777FA21462C88C1E2047C1093C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">registries and clinical trials that include pregnant and lactating women;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AC7C50AEEBB4B7B8DADFC16FEF0C0C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage and facilitate participation by pregnant and lactating women in clinical research;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86C46B487BFE4F3BA002AB661A74FF6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the general understanding of the critical role registries and other postmarket surveillance activities have in collecting data related to the use of medications by pregnant and lactating women;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD496D4B522345F38448F4304EBAE35C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the understanding of available clinical trials and registries that enroll pregnant and lactating women;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45B317A89FF4434680187B2038C47266"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage pregnant and lactating women to seek additional information about such opportunities to participate in clinical research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40266E24BE8148BBA5FDF12A966F4AEA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage health care providers to make information on clinical research available to pregnant and lactating women; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F5E7A5226E54F8F85B7B95F80258EF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate access to and enrollment in such research by pregnant and lactating women.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H03AAB642B70D434CA027331BA052D89F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H92709D858B2D45D3800558CC725B1D33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations with expertise related to the health of women and children, including those representing populations with high rates of maternal mortality and morbidity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06525B49FF1C418CAC1557FB920443CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from relevant medical societies with subject matter expertise on pregnant women, lactating women, or children;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H036A2743806D48189D79289BC8529AC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>relevant industry representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B03295D0DCD4CD6A1B3C82FBC8EAA9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other representatives, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CE0DA14B64B42B7BB6DE68F593A96FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HBFF89F26E7B34CF8A5CD4BB033537274"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a needs assessment to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCC9DC7BA86E44BF8879C161758C16078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate existing resources; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F2BE9726CC24B72BECB199E60D1DEE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify barriers to awareness and opportunities to fill gaps and address barriers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF65C307D4A9A41EBBB0D68907992CF75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify target audiences for the campaign;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59074D2CFD2A4CC5B5581A78880718DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify best practices to reach each such target audience;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97EA2371A1914CE2B7AC42B9F125256A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>test appropriate messaging strategies, including risk communication messaging, for each target audience; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H792A7706B15D45C6A35652F74EC5B24F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the clearinghouse established under section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CDDDD0E83C549439CAB232BDB8A4B2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFF12C450162C495B8EBBD62F0023347B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Research prioritization process for pregnant and lactating women at the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development</header> <subsection id="H41897073AF384018AECD986CEBAB3C56" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health, acting through the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (referred to in this section as <quote>NICHD</quote>), shall carry out priority research projects on existing and new medications prescribed for pregnant and lactating women.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA94A290C88CE45BA9A6CB9F07852EA6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research prioritization process</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall establish a research prioritization process to determine which proposed research projects should receive priority funding under this section. Such research prioritization process shall take into account the following factors:</text> <paragraph id="HBDBA0B6707C1481E84C06FA210DD6685"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The available evidence, including whether there is an unmet medical need or gap in scientific information relevant to treatment of pregnant and lactating women with specific diseases or conditions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF96F952D593D41C2A8CDD844DDFCA288"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The feasibility of research, including the prevalence of a disease or condition in pregnant and lactating women and the availability of investigators with expertise in studying such disease or condition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A5AEDD0A823478B9B6B257B50097269"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The potential impact of research, including the severity of the disease or condition in pregnant and lactating women, the current cost of treating the disease or condition in pregnant and lactating women, the frequency of use of the drug in pregnant and lactating women, and the availability of alternative treatments for the disease or condition in pregnant and lactating women.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC05CE4AF247C45B4A3C7D9315EA2F06B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the research prioritization process described in subsection (b), the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall seek feedback from—</text> <paragraph id="H7AA30FC707CF4494BE39CEB53C089E64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the existing research networks of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development with expertise in clinical research involving pregnant and lactating women;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30C831874427443B9EE7751184E8A056"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant medical societies with subject matter expertise on pregnant women, lactating women, or children; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD645E8D4EB9450B9D0B696ED63C6304"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations with expertise related to the health of pregnant women, lactating women, or children, including those representing populations with high rates of maternal mortality and morbidity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9AE8BE01973455DAFF083A550586D43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment on the program under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6985E679ABBF42298C33398AF7FE1C55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Accountability and oversight</header> <paragraph id="H271A2955936A4838A63DAA0E44D71BD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a work plan for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9AB4A6231EBD4BE593225DB8CA835320"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funding priority research projects under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04F55FC2EE904D66904681094AA14C34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing the research prioritization process under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40B0BF7B26BE48A8B8D97EA7378F9C4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1 of each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the program under this section, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4EF90CE94A8B427D9EDBE7F38283411B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of money obligated or expended in the prior fiscal year for each priority research project under subsection (a); </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1CBF9F9A1B047F0BA83D3B5399DBDF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of each such project; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6C88546FA75434FA0FB96FEDDA14DE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the rationale for prioritizing each such project according to the process under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8849135B42648078ADA489D57AAF4A0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for the period of fiscals year 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

