<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAADDB829F3D0443C9D3955897675C362" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7114 IH: Stop China’s Financing of Russia’s Invasion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose retaliatory tariffs on Chinese goods for financially supporting Russia through the increased purchases of Russian agricultural products during Russia’s ongoing invasion of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD870EBDD9BBE4961B019ECF9ACFDBADA" style="OLC"><section id="HFEFC37BCC9554A45818DDCE3BA1D1E86" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop China’s Financing of Russia’s Invasion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4BAAEECD22684982BCAF0E04EF33623B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification by United States Trade Representative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative shall certify to the President whether China has increased the volume of wheat and barley imported from Russia relative to the volume imported on February 1, 2022.</text></section><section id="H9A12B3D784AB4D26865278300C6AF8B5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of additional tariffs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon an affirmative certification under section 2, the President shall, using all authorities granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) relating to the regulation of imports, impose on each article classifiable under section I, II, or III of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States that originates from China and is imported into the customs territory of the United States (as such term is defined in General Note 2 to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States) an additional tariff of 20 percent of the value of such article.</text></section><section id="HD1EE56FD3D324668A9F8728F7EE8D517"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relaxation of additional tariffs</header><subsection id="HF335A711F61741C0BE270E6F7432B560"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The additional tariffs imposed pursuant to section 3 shall be removed beginning on the day after the date described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F9E3644D805472D82E9F45F3A33D0D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Date described</header><text>The date described in this subsection is the first date on which each of the following has occurred:</text><paragraph id="HDBD642C500FC4B188D8BA7FFA69A4A70" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Either—</text><subparagraph id="H7DF3D5D75EE24A36A76FD99A5333D422" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States Trade Representative certifies to the President that the volume of Chinese imports of Russian wheat and barley has returned to or fallen below the volume imported on February 1, 2022; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA90C27AD88EB452CBA7A9990EECA2DE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of State certifies to the President that the Russian invasion of Ukraine has ceased.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H340670BE0BA2488583DA1CA5EDAB475A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President transmits to Congress the applicable certification described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB8388264E44B748385E18B89B22D83"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is enacted statutory approval of such certification and for the removal of the additional tariffs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H66B97B9675494192A4C8285E57FE6334"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cooperation and accountability at the World Trade Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative shall use the voice and influence of the United States at the World Trade Organization to—</text><paragraph id="H7EC6024598D345DA8F4F5C02B44E4511"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemn the recent aggression, human rights abuses, and war crimes by Russia;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72B183F7DFB747EFB6F7B2527B29FCBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage China and all other countries to not economically help the Russian Federation pay for its war by increasing the volume of their trading relationships with the Russian Federation while the violent and unprovoked invasion transpires; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE20F6B87E0E44880B41202FCB2BA2148"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider further steps with the view to suspend the Russian Federation’s participation in the World Trade Organization.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

