<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H951E3E1AD4A940FCA045135D46A697A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6591 IH: Protecting Infrastructure and Promoting Environmental Stewardship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish a rule that establishes standards for the flushability of disposable nonwoven wipes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8CF36282DC994517896D5F32FA4F918D" style="OLC"><section id="H163E7F9490E34994A625CD23BBBC293B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Infrastructure and Promoting Environmental Stewardship Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PIPES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2E38C916153B42A1B72EA485871FD660"><enum>2.</enum><header>Flushability of disposable nonwoven products</header><subsection id="HFE9A3B46FB684701A33C97620C06F51F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall publish a rule in the Federal Register that—</text><paragraph id="HA8029C5491C9452C9688424B49AB2747"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes standards for flushability with respect to disposable nonwoven products, based on—</text><subparagraph id="HD99B9E207D074527938EBC043F08CA8C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the criteria set forth in the document entitled <quote>Publicly Available Specification (PAS) 1: 2020 Criteria for Recognition as a Flushable Product</quote>, published by the International Water Services Flushability Group and dated December 2020 (or any appropriate successor criteria, as determined by the Administrator), and any relevant voluntary consensus standards, or other standards, determined appropriate by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H626E146095EC458E9C1632B25074D612" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consideration of—</text><clause id="HCA7C35C1EED940D287400CC5C61663EE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the environmental impact of flushing the product, based on the composition of the materials in the product;</text></clause><clause id="HCD09A44FE8BC417FA89911DEB4C866EA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the toilet and drain clearance ability of the product;</text></clause><clause id="HA15C471FD78C47589B12F586288D3347" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the disintegration of the product;</text></clause><clause id="HA5B46FD63E5C4728AC71C42B3E045F5D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how the product settles in the waste system; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A007B451AEE493EAACA64892C3B4BB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the biodegradation of the product; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5777A35DBF943B8BB9B3B0AD8E5922E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes a process to assess whether a disposable nonwoven product conforms to the standards established under paragraph (1), including a requirement that in order for a disposable nonwoven product to be designated or marked <quote>flushable</quote> or <quote>sewer and septic safe</quote>, or with any other representation that depicts the disposable nonwoven product as suitable for toilet disposal, the manufacturer of the disposable nonwoven product shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFCD475FD7AC64DD390161B472D1FF137"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator—</text><clause id="HFCC105945DEA46DF8BBEDC35EB8AB174" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documentation demonstrating that the disposable nonwoven product conforms to such standards; and</text></clause><clause id="H5122D66CE8004D76838664AA18FC8F6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a fee in an amount determined appropriate by the Administrator to cover the costs of administering this section; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C87D3690ECC42228FCE231EA51B2D6D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make public the documentation submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92029782A6764C948934E8EE73CB8ABB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Product designation or marking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the effective date of the rule published under subsection (a), a covered entity may use the terms <term>flushable</term> or <term>sewer and septic safe</term>, or any other representation that depicts a disposable nonwoven product as suitable for toilet disposal, to designate or mark a disposable nonwoven product only if—</text><paragraph id="H57CD439E5EA7461890FA654DE3A08BE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disposable nonwoven product conforms to the standards established under subsection (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A9B0258076B4ED2953FFFEED4C98A30" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturer of the disposable nonwoven product is in compliance with the process established under subsection (a)(2) with respect to the disposable nonwoven product.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H701F214837AC43888AAB6082A0DB7D5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance</header><paragraph id="HFCF6D31622934B2CB1414BC282D6B7FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may, in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission, develop a process to determine whether a covered entity is in compliance with this section, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HB2714B96C42144F6A8D2A0709E884679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a requirement to submit a third-party verification that a disposable nonwoven product conforms to the standards established under subsection (a)(1) if the Administrator determines that the documentation submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(2) is insufficient, or further information is otherwise necessary, to verify such compliance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C05F41BA35348198FD5B4167E48003D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a requirement to submit to the Administrator, upon request, such other information as the Administrator determines necessary to determine such compliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4FBF53017749B983D7627A893AACCA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header><subparagraph id="H0379B1052C7648E68234A8B84A8BCE8C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Monetary civil penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall impose a monetary civil penalty on any covered entity that violates subsection (b) in an amount that does not exceed—</text><clause id="H3C32C10C82FF4C4EB4384694761EE4AC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$25,000 for each day a disposable nonwoven product designated or marked by the covered entity in violation of such subsection is for sale at retail; and </text></clause><clause id="HBCB9AD6787764FE19008B680A05ACADA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$500,000 for a single such violation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762F52821CF0488AAFB590FC98306F3B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Orders; injunctive relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may, with respect to any covered entity that violates subsection (b), issue an order to comply, or bring an action in an appropriate United States district court for appropriate injunctive relief.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14B993DBDB674C7D8ADC8EAB146A5640"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Website</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H0E924C2AAEFF4C48BFA91956078233C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish a website to educate the public about the proper use and disposal of disposable nonwoven products, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9C78189CAFA04FF9A1175C25914C9459"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effects of flushing nonflushable wipes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF73E48A4178C49EDBC8A2B8B594242DE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78A4E777FDED45EBBC471A713C49B513"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a quick response code to advertise such website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H306F054EEDFF402C94E18FB466A731FD" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator—</text><paragraph id="HBDE8A6FE80BE46CF93E53746A4C9BFB9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (a), such sums as may be necessary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51BA2E13A0A14FECB25082BAD8AEB420" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to administer this section, an amount equal to any amounts collected by the Administrator pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H095FE07739CF47518EE112EC44A2A5FC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the effective date of the rule published under subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section, which may include recommendations for any changes necessary to improve such implementation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB19BEB3881F4460EB0AC577B8730A22C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9F27321BE5D5471AA2FD6D9B44D7C8E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C1EFD32BF5E4FA5AFF21816E8E03162"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a manufacturer, wholesaler, supplier, or retailer that is responsible for the labeling or retail packaging of a disposable nonwoven product that is sold or offered for sale in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA869AA09D7794D38ABE0B5B491BA02C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disposable nonwoven product</header><text>The term <term>disposable nonwoven product</term> means a premoistened, nonwoven disposable wipe that has significant potential to be flushed, as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

