<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2CEA8DFFED2432CB7C3A9A042602191" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7680 IH: Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a joint task force to improve the collection of restitution and improve oversight of the Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts for the purpose of deterring illicit financial activity, money laundering, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E2BEEC087FD4BEF8F7DEEDB2FAD301D" style="OLC"><section id="HC3AE61B78973439994D4F62B90AA2DF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBB8A2D63FF3B4B74906A381D3E561045"><enum>2.</enum><header>Task force</header><subsection id="HF5FBBA2C3A43443CBBFE6EFFCF7CC5C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General (in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the Executive Office for United States Attorneys), the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in consultation with the Commissioner of the Office of Child Support Enforcement), the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Director of the United States Marshals Service, shall establish a joint task force (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force</quote>)—</text><paragraph id="H513332C8BF844672A96A192349809178"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop a strategic plan to improve the criminal and civil debt collection process and establish an effective coordination mechanism among each entity involved in such process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D7505154EAE4DD48803615B893D80E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop a strategic plan to improve oversight of Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts for detecting and deterring illicit financial activity and money laundering.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC65CC9CCA37F41138334580A0D496583"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required review of procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force shall—</text><paragraph id="H748DC648DF324DD29478FDC83332F326"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the long-standing problems in the collection of outstanding criminal and civil debt, including fragmented processes and lack of coordination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H439EB4E6CDC34220B65E481B237DA798"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review and enhance training and examination procedures to improve the capabilities of criminal and civil debt reporting and collection by Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AFC502BA256496584BA065831B2D649"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommend the proper accounting, reporting, collecting, and managing of criminal and civil debt eligible for referral to Treasury for collection actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H999D1077C31A49D781068702F10B0AE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and enhance training and examinations procedures to improve the capabilities of anti-money laundering to detect financial transactions relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCD91805CE3E4CFD9EBF41E6679E0B5F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>review and enhance procedures for referring potential cases relating to money laundering and illicit financial activity to the appropriate law enforcement agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABEAE8C399804C408810331F5C8E8394"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine, as appropriate, whether requirements for Bureau of Prisons are sufficient to detect and deter money laundering relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5660836BAE6B4DC5BC155086CAC2C973"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H792DF594E5F54916A9132A49304449ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal and civil debt collection report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H15557AF9EF124F00991413D0BE7E943B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of criminal and civil debt collection efforts of the United States Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD91B979C48D440AC9AA48B51F4030093"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate legislative, administrative, and other recommendations to strengthen criminal and civil debt collection processes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB7855D8E6F64508B82084A3ABFBFFD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>required recommendations, including—</text><clause id="H10AABDF12D054E8AB6F520AC3BE48A4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">feedback from stakeholders, including victims of crime advocacy groups, such as the National Association of Victim Assistance Administrators, National Association of Victim Compensation Board Administrators, National Child Support Enforcement Association, National Tribal Child Support Association, National Attorney General Association, Council of Prison Locals 33, and financial institutions, on policy proposals derived from the analysis conducted by the Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force that would enhance the efforts and programs of Federal and State agencies to improve criminal and civil debt reporting and collection, including any recommended changes to internal policies, procedures, and controls;</text></clause><clause id="HFF8E533BFBE54F899C4F2D7F2F2C1117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any recommended changes to expand information sharing relating to criminal and civil debt reporting and collection between financial institutions, appropriate law enforcement agencies, appropriate State agencies, and appropriate Federal agencies; </text></clause><clause id="HCAFEAC6C834B4BD8A0B7FF91CA5C17B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any recommended changes to enhance the efforts and programs of Federal and State agencies to improve criminal and civil debt reporting and collection and expand information sharing of the Bureau of Prison Trust Fund Inmate Trust Fund Accounts with appropriate law enforcement agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="HA841D08534004F77AFEED7C5D166BA2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any recommended changes, if necessary, to existing statutes to more effectively report and collect criminal and civil debt.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10D72DE665754A0BA457EE89A82C251D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anti-money laundering report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H90996499DB954CDAB067B90B2D5A0080"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of anti-money laundering efforts of the United States Government and United States financial institutions relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E86F072BF2F480DBD330464FE0D945A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriate legislative, administrative, and other recommendations to improve anti-money laundering efforts relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCBA8FF5B0F94D0890A424D7926C9CCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>required recommendations, including—</text><clause id="H821100C07252473491E91A293F9F479D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>feedback from Federal agencies on best practices of successful programs related to anti-money laundering efforts in place that may be suitable for broader adoption by the Director of the Bureau of Prison;</text></clause><clause id="HE0E57CB6DF2E4A0593CBBD997A8EF949"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">feedback from stakeholders, including law enforcement agencies and financial institutions, on policy proposals derived from the analysis conducted by the Inmate Financial Accountability Task Force that would enhance anti-money laundering efforts and oversight of Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts, including any recommended changes to internal policies, procedures, and controls to improve anti-money laundering efforts; </text></clause><clause id="HFD0E7E5440C44D79802E7B3777DC5EEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommended changes to training programs at the Bureau of Prisons to better equip employees to deter and detect money laundering relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts; and</text></clause><clause id="HD2D3EE447ED2454BBDA35ED98663F9D2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommended changes, if necessary, to existing statute to more effectively detect and deter money laundering relating to Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6024F85AE044892996630400F3776A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to grant rulemaking authority to the Task Force.</text></subsection><subsection id="H97086D15E8EA429992C888617CB4E352"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Bureau of Prison Inmate Trust Fund Accounts</quote> refers to the following trust funds:</text><paragraph id="H8798A6EE0F4C4EFBAB8D15EA4EA642FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Funds of Federal prisoners.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1969CECC23C4DCB8B740E016B33AF57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Commissary funds, Federal prisons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

