<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB0C4A44DD1B4C11A518B8BFA0851C17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8609 IH: Surging Prosecutors to Expedite Alien Removals Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish and maintain a ratio of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement prosecutors to immigration judges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE794F59D962C4ABA86189EA151A8A95E" style="OLC"><section id="H5AE9E000B42B41B684769E159088DB27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surging Prosecutors to Expedite Alien Removals Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEBBD5808768A4564A580A1FEA3A85D2D"><enum>2.</enum><header>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement prosecutor to judge ratio</header><subsection id="H8BB09C006F4F4CD9BAF21D13065C22D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish and maintain a four to one ratio of four U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement Office of Principle Legal Advisor prosecutors to each immigration judge (as defined by section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)) for the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H57B00EEE5F1A4541B068323BEA5CDBA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prosecutors described in subsection (a) shall represent the Department of Homeland Security during removal proceedings before the Executive Office of Immigration Review of the Department of Justice. </text></subsection><subsection id="H53DE14A802904A1CBFF208DBE97784F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H2A07E93175EC48C3A664D151385FC2CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of achieving the ratio described under subsection (a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADCBFF9376414E27950BB84BA6A1C469"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the initial report under paragraph (1) identifies a ratio less than the ratio under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees including a plan to achieve such ratio. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B9C3F41C8EE407C864DC933A7916B2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8B070094BE034E55820916F94821D94B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H660A882E9AF94301A4B50B168AA913BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA3CE8C329C44633A5F784B7671BE393"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E14D2C931D48D582D3DBB76041DAED"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H547933569F46485AAB7A91F5DD96546C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $35,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available through September 30, 2024, for the purpose described under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

