<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H6C795A198FD54FDDAD0D754092B5F37F" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 310 : To posthumously award the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith, in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 310</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To posthumously award the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith, in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H119B3B4A7624495C813A753AEBEAAFAE" style="OLC"><section id="HECAB315B3F2B4CEDA038ED7FF44FE431" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H7A1B43FE47194075B6B9A6051AA2952C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On September 11, 2012, the United States consulate, and its personnel in Benghazi, Libya, were attacked by militants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F47C5F0CDC4724A0E5AF709441E9B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Four Americans were killed in the attack, including Ambassador J. Christopher Stevens, Sean Smith, Glen Doherty, and Tyrone Woods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE374F4B8AD9451DB739AF3CB61CB300"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Glen Doherty and Tyrone Woods were former Navy SEALs who served as security personnel in Libya. As the attack unfolded, they bravely attempted to defend American property and protect United States diplomatic personnel. In so doing, they selflessly sacrificed their own lives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67E82ED633AF4549A6118CE5BFA9559D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Glen Doherty was a Navy SEAL for 12 years and served in Iraq and Afghanistan. He attained the rank of Petty Officer First Class and earned the Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal. After leaving the Navy, Glen Doherty worked with the Department of State to protect American diplomats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8707DC85A40545EE9058C0B768D24CA1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Tyrone Woods served for 20 years as a Navy SEAL including tours in Iraq and Afghanistan. In Iraq he led multiple raids and reconnaissance missions and earned the Bronze Star. After retiring from the Navy as a Senior Chief Petty Officer, Tyrone Woods worked with the Department of State to protect American diplomats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E83C1C2C91D49A28B4E644948A8D091"><enum>(6)</enum><text>J. Christopher Stevens served for 21 years in the U.S. Foreign Service. He was serving as U.S. Ambassador to Libya and previously served twice in the country, as both Special Representative to the Libyan Transitional National Council and as the Deputy Chief of Mission. Earlier in his life, he also served as a Peace Corps volunteer teaching English in Morocco.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16287236A2347F099D7A0D23A03944F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Sean Smith served for 6 years in the U.S. Air Force. He attained the rank of Staff Sergeant and was awarded the Air Force Commendation Medal. After leaving the Air Force, Sean Smith served for 10 years in the State Department on various assignments, which took him to places such as Baghdad, Brussels, Pretoria, and The Hague.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F2C0A6FF98F4573A91BEA099275C8BA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As their careers attest, all four men served their country honorably.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H37B467AD3E3544069FC8D241BD47F274"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="HD90C479C05CF4DF6AFFE34000404254A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous award, on behalf of the Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design collectively in commemoration of Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith, in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1CB0D7F94214088A3B869D82243D038"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary. The Secretary is authorized to create designs for the medal that, if the Secretary deems it appropriate, include images of, and inscriptions of the names of, Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8AB81B19FCC7442993E320DA9DBDD0F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Central intelligence agency museum</header><paragraph id="H7A1088FCE8014AED9BB709B697843479"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Central Intelligence Agency Museum, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8CB00A152A48B0ADCD8164EC199D3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Central Intelligence Agency Museum should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26B20C4514FD4F529482411B631086D8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 2, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H4D00DD6BD7D84B1890F0A44FB85A839F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H1E4B02702A924C1BBBB95ED26AFF6478"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BF31276DB7048419B31D6011320A119"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5548B9DEAA1048A08904013D2E0D5C88"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="HE9E22B34159543A5BD071FE48D84470A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5DA736CA56A94E4BA8907393F6D12E7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC5C010FF8499427B8A4BAE54F90929A6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220726" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 26, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

