<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E3ED213B8904519A67936555ED69612" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7475 IH: Mamas First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide coverage under the Medicaid program for services provided by doulas and midwives, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9016E8AA2D5B4C50976D093E01378A1C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86E3ECC27EE145B58626EB6687D416E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mamas First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4538085FF4D0417BBC98F56A952D0C8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2599E1D710942BBA2E908E26C7DD29F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the maternal mortality rate varies drastically for women by race and ethnicity. On average, there are 12.7 deaths per 100,000 live births for White women, 43.5 deaths per 100,000 live births for African-American women, 32.5 deaths for American Indian and Alaskan Native women, and 14.4 deaths per 100,000 live births for women of other ethnicities. While maternal mortality disparately impacts African-American women and indigenous women, this urgent public health crisis traverses race, ethnicity, socioeconomic status, educational background, and geography.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB63E61AAFD4A442D92A0A15D1B098007"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States maternal mortality rates are the highest in the developed world and are increasing rapidly.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64E13B731C844515AD79950950C517C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many of these maternal deaths are likely preventable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD30A9BFD18B4E54AD82F398EF5144DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the National Institutes of Health, doula-assisted mothers are four times less likely to have a low-birth-weight baby, two times less likely to experience a birth complication involving themselves or their baby, and significantly more likely to initiate breastfeeding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B6AE43D51154819AC9461D4ED9D87EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Midwife-led care is associated with cost savings, decreased rates of intervention, lower cesarean rates, lower preterm birth rates, and healthier outcomes for mothers and babies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BEBE7E58C2F463DB13101FD6162B364"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Midwives may practice in any setting, including the home, community, hospitals, birth centers, clinics, or health units.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB9200DD5DCF54EBC81489620C7D32B06"><enum>3.</enum><header>Medicaid coverage of services provided by doulas and midwives</header> 
<subsection id="H7A11437F67A34A71A9D0BDC16EFB1756"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H701376EC01A44B8F897A0DB7ECD4B199"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC56D361897E54A5DB7388DF33BC8DAEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (30), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C04F1AD473C4FF2A742B0B9DDD5E144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (31) as paragraph (32); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H143011119EFF4810B008530D5A321CE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (30) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H95542A3B0EF5402F8F9EB69DDEB15C04" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H511FD2A2D8234BDFBE3EFA6BDCEB87B9" commented="no"><enum>(31)</enum><text>services and care, including prenatal, delivery, and postpartum care, that is provided in a culturally congruent manner (as defined in subsection (kk)) by doulas, midwives, and tribal midwives (as those terms are defined in subsection (jj)), that is provided in the home, community, a hospital, birth center, clinic, health unit, or is furnished via telehealth to the extent authorized under State law; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9C8C4607BFF4BE8AC054446E65B934F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD38B4D29E5554589B0A1D2956A1C2F69" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H30B95BDF84BD4DD2AD9D01CAF4A717AA"><enum>(jj)</enum><header>Doulas, midwives, and tribal midwife defined</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(31):</text> 
<paragraph id="HD3404C499D71444EAB8C020670AFD9A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Doulas defined</header><text>The term <quote>doula</quote> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HB60D5ECA90674FA2A85E1A7817CED750"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has completed 60 hours of foundational training;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B97B07B82124655AB7D2B4AA395391A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certified by an organization, which has been established for not less than five years and which requires the completion of continuing education to maintain such certification, to provide non-medical advice, information, emotional support, and physical comfort to an individual during such individual’s pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B0D08A7E8AD4D95915CC80CECCB3ECF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintains such certification by completing such required continuing education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD00D23E6A36D4F3388FD7FBB909836B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Midwives defined</header><text>The term <quote>midwife</quote> means a midwife who meets at a minimum the international definition of the midwife and global standards for midwifery education as established by the International Confederation of Midwives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D285F2E429F44CB9B0704AAEEA67831"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal midwife defined</header><text>The term <quote>tribal midwife</quote> means an individual who is recognized by an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)) to practice midwifery for such tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H32A87D99B800452DAF2B6AC5D1D59460"><enum>(kk)</enum><header>Culturally congruent care defined</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(31), the term <quote>culturally congruent care</quote>, with respect to maternity care, means care that is provided in agreement with the preferred cultural values, beliefs, worldview, language, and practices of the health care consumer and other stakeholders.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE9AD9B416246447BBCB39F60D41A87F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring mandatory coverage under State plan</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and (30)</quote> and inserting <quote>(30), and (31)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE1A78263094461182530A79B83DF5DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="HDD9D2496FDA043FF94040A7841F75531"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to medical assistance furnished on or after January 1, 2022.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD69DA4ED0246DC9A11FE9F6186647B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for State legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet any requirement imposed by amendments made by this section, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

