<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85F44BC9EBCA4106BADFF4312C4E4286" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9579 IH: Reducing Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Juvenile Justice System Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Program assistance be used to reduce racial and ethnic disparities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E2144C382A84F5C9E8826098D7C4B2B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF4E6546C86CF4310B1CC0044D721A222" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Juvenile Justice System Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC7B9D302A26749D48022A02AFDED290F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA32357758FE64B788F5D8155BAA213E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color are overrepresented in the juvenile justice system and receive harsher consequences than White youth.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABB6F43DA3404712A16B89FE1DFA628B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reducing reliance on incarceration and providing evidence-based, trauma-informed, and linguistically and culturally responsive support and services to youth who come in contact with the juvenile justice system is a key goal of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11101">34 U.S.C. 11101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA33E4823CB284F9688AD6D4523A1CF5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Addressing racial and ethnic disparities in the juvenile justice system requires accurate data regarding youth of color who come into contact with the juvenile justice system, including data that can be disaggregated by race, and ethnicity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H102D11CACB09444ABF7B3978AA3EE47C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Youth of color and their families with lived experience interacting with the juvenile justice system can provide important insight, analysis, and solutions regarding how to recognize and address racial disparities in the juvenile justice system. </text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDD234892D3C143E5906C5642A56464C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition of racial and ethnic disparity</header>
<subsection id="H21196D90673241CF978CBCE89BD331A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11103">34 U.S.C. 11103</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (41) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA919DC96D1A04EBB84286D9ADD9C70F1"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77F9FD3C592C4067B386783611395B58"><enum>(41)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>racial and ethnic disparity</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07F04C03EB4A499185F2B5EE3947FF45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color are involved at a decision point in the juvenile justice system at disproportionately higher rates than White youth at that decision point;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD0A86F84168479D8F7FEE5F16B2D4EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the percentage of Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color at any decision point is higher than the percentage of youth of color in the general population;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H98D387F0022D40C1AA8EAF956905F0B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color experience more severe outcomes at any decision point than similarly situated White youth; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC051B7F7866449EC8F18A098755E2DF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color are detained and removed from their homes when less restrictive alternatives would be more effective;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H6500031DF66F4CD0A27D9A0FBBFCFDFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 251(a)(1)(B)(viii) of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11161">34 U.S.C. 11161(a)(1)(B)(viii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>members of minority groups</quote> and inserting <quote>Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, and other youth of color</quote>. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H12CAFB4EA5A64EB395CFC6E57D3A6CF4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Program State plans</header> <subsection id="H87DB2A27D6DD4B339363687E6899D6FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 223(a) of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11133">34 U.S.C. 11133(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HCC121A593A144EA7B8973C2D2BC9D28A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A)(v), by striking <quote>of someone</quote> and inserting <quote>of a youth representative of the population in detention and secure confinement</quote>; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFF86FC1F01C41F68642817FCDB025E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(B)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H633BC4F2C0E74702B1C866E8D7B478A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E6A19EF797C4BF9A538B2A51F36CBC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ix) as clause (x); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B50130470004E23B5BD5B3A998C2DF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (viii) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19B3FDDE728C4BEBBECA44D72A381E8C"> <clause id="HBA2F6B9950D445B8A511C9D6B55B4DFD" indent="up1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a plan to implement systems for identifying and recording youth data disaggregated by race and ethnicity; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA644C95243DD4A7BB5C2BBF2DB8F74AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6EAA8FBB6C374EF5802FAA3249711182"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (V), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3269728AC80A49488ADDE77C4DFD8D16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (W), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE375E94CB54D42769FC785D338848FBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (W) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB6F485690CE4585A9A7FFC989CD8929">
<subparagraph id="HDDDF15C0859D454CBDA6F28B4342AE25"><enum>(X)</enum><text>programs seeking to reduce racial and ethnic disparities at any decision point, such as at the point of arrest, referral to court, diversion, secure detention, judicial waiver to adult criminal court, case petitioning, delinquency finding or adjudication, probation, or residential placement, including secure confinement, including prevention, diversion, and community supervision, and other programs that provide linguistically and culturally responsive support and services to youth;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8323E4073C94747984A1278C43FD926"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (15)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H68A69EB56ACF4C1D8FDC026907547415"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and youth representative of the population in detention and secure confinement who have been or are currently under the jurisdiction of the juvenile justice system or, if not feasible and in appropriate circumstances, parents or guardians of a Black, Indigenous, Hispanic, or other youth of color who has been or is currently under the jurisdiction of the juvenile justice system</quote> after <quote>educational system</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33270D730F8F4AF7BF8B44DD719819DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B79F9F272944C1C9DAEAED36556843B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H975C51E984D340A6B484FE72B1C8678D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52EAAF4DEBBC4A899333D97ED8EA2A02">
<subparagraph id="H8D16611AB880458FB3E390D233F3B5BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reporting on measurable progress on the work plan described in subparagraph (C) for the prior year;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6136B32C19224628A3A4FA59AE6667F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (22)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H00BCCB91DDE648BF82895101F0BE4ACB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H006911109FD34D2ABC0E00078B8C2F4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4ACB4BDE1FD44EE8E9A3805E071C623"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FD7F2BB436043FF915A7CE356284D7E"> <subparagraph id="H15F45AA0A409453FB48EB3F510DD4020"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote opportunity for community-based providers serving youth in communities with higher than average racial and ethnic disparities at any decision point in the juvenile justice system in the State, compared with other communities in the same State;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF32BCC36530F44CD88B5D3D8AD6335FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance for collection of data</header><text>Section 223 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/11133">34 U.S.C. 11133</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91B1195EC3C9465D807180A9D332B413"> <subsection id="H9F2846ADB4B745078F84F62543478939"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Guidance for collection of data</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reducing Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Juvenile Justice System Act of 2022</short-title>, the Administrator shall, in consultation with the United States Commission on Civil Rights and the Director of the Census Bureau, develop guidance for States with respect to a uniform standard for the collection and reporting of disaggregated and cross-referenced data on race and ethnicity under this section to assist States in implementing subsection (a)(15).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

