<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H46AAD01EE28F41C390ED3D3A656855DB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8992 IH: Methane Super-Emitter Strategy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8992</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a Federal methane super-emitter detection strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5F56B0352EF24912B5536153D369F565" style="OLC"><section id="H8DEDDDFAF1F347248AD509F7ABE55323" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Super-Emitter Strategy Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0543733FC54D4DA3BDF0FA66710C116D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal methane super-emitter detection strategy</header><subsection id="H4020E67C7C9A4272A3870C3FBA9AAD65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph id="H9C5B0E0381C24F20997E566F8CEA6AF6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and other relevant agencies, shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to develop a science-based strategy to assess, evaluate, and make recommendations regarding the use of present and future greenhouse gas monitoring and detection capabilities, including ground-based, airborne, and space-based sensors and integration of data relating to such monitoring and detection from other indicators, with a focus on the ability to detect large methane emission events (commonly referred to as <quote>methane super-emitters</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AE22F1C2F17431A848E143E70A07E83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The strategy described in subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="H12BA7A2975C44A78A114D8D938BE64AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Development of a consensus definition for the term <quote>methane super-emitter</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F51255035D548C6BAA3C3D4EC008B76" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Examination of whether and how current and planned Federal greenhouse gas monitoring and detection capabilities may be leveraged to monitor and detect methane super-emitters, and identify key gaps in such capabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE886CD88706D48299CD8FF262B4AC29E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Consideration of a means to facilitate effective interagency collaboration for greenhouse gas monitoring and detection, data standards, stewardship, and data integration, to monitor and detect methane super-emitters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF605FF0C28C4DE098EACBB150AFF25C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Consideration regarding how agencies that conduct greenhouse gas monitoring and detection can enhance the scientific and operational value and enable the broader application of information regarding methane super-emitters, including by operationalizing methane super-emitter data to support the rapid mitigation of methane sources and integrating such data from multiple sources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A7AFEA0467A41918508DE397080DB01" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Consideration of options for the Federal Government to partner with non-governmental entities, including State and local governments, academia, non-profit organizations, commercial industry, and international organizations, to effectively leverage present and future greenhouse gas monitoring and detection capabilities to monitor and detect methane super-emitters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AE5DEEBFE5746CC9B96207C740A6A8C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Recommendations regarding the activities under subparagraphs (A) through (E), as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF8E53EAED784D13BA28056DCFD27A13" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may use the strategy described in subsection (a) to inform the planning of research and development activities regarding greenhouse gas monitoring and detection and the monitoring and detection of methane super-emitters.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC321C08C7AB2408DB4C3868F7A935B5C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the execution of the agreement between the Administrator and the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine under subsection (a), the National Academies shall submit to the Administrator, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the strategy described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF35BA64291444053A1E073BA3D0DA711"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD02E7830AA804B12B6D4EB33222FDA81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61C6B30BE6224C73A53BD4CBEBAEB82B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas monitoring and detection</header><text>The term <quote>greenhouse gas monitoring and detection</quote> means the direct observation, from space or in-situ, or collection of measurement data pertaining to, greenhouse gas emissions and levels.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBA37609C2734051BF534C0370F209CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $1,200,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

