<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDC0956CC1635469DB295AF98C2ACB995" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6442 RH: Partnership Agreements Creating Tangible Savings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 434</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6442</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–601]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on January 20, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 101703 of title 54, United States Code, to include Tribal Governments and quasi-governmental entities, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HDD0945354F264083879465D7A55CEF05"><section id="HDE76149A89A348FDA2E341AC50C6E284" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnership Agreements Creating Tangible Savings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PACTS Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HA09E65CE941E4A1795CC853E13DBC7E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cooperative management agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101703 of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H99B4BCC2308645219F4F0D75A690FFCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H201A0C3B610449808ABB069D7D221B8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>agreement with a State or local government agency to provide for the cooperative management of the Federal and State or local park areas where a System unit is located adjacent to or near a State or local park area, and</quote> and inserting <quote>agreement with a State or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity to provide for the cooperative management of Federal, State, local, or Tribal park areas where</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF58DEBEEB9C4338A6A50FF151652DD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>between the Service and a State or local government agency of a portion of either the System unit or State or local park will allow for more effective and efficient management of the System unit and State or local park</quote> and inserting <quote>between the Service and a State or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity of a portion of either the System unit or State, local, Tribal, or quasi-governmental entity land will allow for more effective and efficient management of such System unit or such land</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D7E1FCF0F26453EA1C357A2246DD75D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>provide to a State</quote> and all that follows through <quote>land</quote> and inserting <quote>provide to a State or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity goods and services to be used by the Secretary and the State or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity in the cooperative management of lands and waters</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF63C24278EF4A679C43BAFF3EE66FF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HDFF59FB6ED0D46EEBC63FA54A72ED403"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a Federal, State, or local employee for work on any Federal, State, or local</quote> and inserting <quote>an employee of a Federal, State, or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity, for work on any Federal, State, local, Tribal, or quasi-governmental entity</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57F458A6EE3C48968A153B78498F0757"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by the Secretary and the State or local agency</quote> and inserting <quote>by the Secretary and the State or local agency, Tribal Government, public university, public utility, or quasi-governmental entity</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

