<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HD78FD1183D4E407295B29344D6FDD787" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 7311 : Countering Malign Russian Activities in Africa Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to develop and submit to Congress a strategy and implementation plan outlining United States efforts to counter the malign influence and activities of the Russian Federation and its proxies in Africa, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3800FBF7DAEC42B191833F1B41CC0F72" style="OLC"><section id="H41E60019E73E4170B4A762AFA9E09308" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Malign Russian Activities in Africa Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4EDDB66DE1D34BB781CB16A33457C0A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States—</text><paragraph id="HC3A4564DDC4946468385611D18391D21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>should regularly assess the scale and scope of the Russian Federation’s influence and activities in Africa that undermine United States objectives and interests; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0600AFABB2144FA9AF5087B0FF4AF990"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine how—</text><subparagraph id="HC478965F5017429887EB551F87CD5300"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address and counter such influence and activities effectively, including through appropriate United States foreign assistance programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H755ABC188DFE4C279DD0381AD16D7CBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to hold accountable the Russian Federation and African governments and their officials who are complicit in aiding such malign influence and activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3112C215269D40E3ADE97A4DD40D4073"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy and implementation plan; report</header><subsection id="H72394BCC41F04D8D9F11AD9276D58C18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy and implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy and implementation plan outlining United States efforts to counter the malign influence and activities of the Russian Federation and its proxies in Africa, including programs and other initiatives designed to—</text><paragraph id="H3EC782CABF7B4AA58DAD0DD1DAFEB4A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen democratic institutions, improve government transparency and accountability, improve standards related to human rights, labor, anti-corruption initiatives, fiscal transparency, monitor natural resources and extractive industries, and other tenets of good governance; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B1993DD86A4260A1D2D89B17605F7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>monitor and report on Russian political influence and disinformation operations and the activities of Russian, Russia-connected, or Russian-funded private military contractors in Africa. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C73E5DFFDD24B539E7ADBDD4987873B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H80AE69918DC040C3ABF7FEFF6D32944B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the strategy and implementation plan required by subsection (a) and related efforts to counter the malign influence and activities of the Russian Federation and its proxies in Africa. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDCFAB77C2C421E9C05640AD61374C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following: </text><subparagraph id="HDAD814D1DD124F48BB51985508FEFFC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the scope and nature of the Russian Federation’s malign influence and activities and related diplomatic, economic, and security priorities and strategic objectives of such engagement in Africa, including influence and activities that involve Russian proxies, such as Russian oligarchs, Russian-funded private military contractors, and other individuals and entities directly or indirectly employed by or financially or politically associated with Russia and its officials, who are involved in or aid activities to, among other things—</text><clause id="HEFD7E86CC7E94D8E8EB64B1B7CEB9E1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>manipulate African governments and their policies, as well as the public opinions and voting preferences of African populations and diaspora groups, including those in the United States; and </text></clause><clause id="H085755A1D9CB4DD5B21656A09EEC5D5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>invest in, engage, or otherwise control strategic sectors in Africa, such as mining and other forms of natural resource extraction and exploitation, military basing and other security cooperation agreements, and information and communications technology.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF05ECE8C51477781D031BD09F12BB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A detailed account of United States foreign assistance and other initiatives developed and implemented during the preceding 3 fiscal years to address Russia’s malign influence and activities in Africa, including the objectives and details of planned programs and initiatives set out in the strategy required by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85AB88AF8E1848B1BCE12116F409B01E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of policy and programmatic limitations, gaps, and resource requirements to effectively counter Russia’s malign influence and activities in Africa.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC90353A67344427D87A8A49A6110495C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An overview of other initiatives and assistance programs funded by other international donors and partner countries to counter Russia’s malign influence and activities in Africa.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15C0B3DFC1914F4C9E28048FDCF10EA5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of African governments and government officials, Russian government officials, and other individuals and entities that have facilitated payments and other prohibited activities that benefit United States-sanctioned individuals and entities tied to Russia, including in violation of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note), the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/44">Public Law 115–44</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9401">22 U.S.C. 9401 et seq.</external-xref>), Executive Order 14024 (86 Fed. Reg. 20249; relating to blocking property with respect to specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation), and Executive Order 13848 (83 Fed. Reg. 46843; relating to imposing certain sanctions in the event of foreign interference in a United States election), and a detailed overview of United States efforts to hold such governments, officials, and other individuals and entities complicit in violating or facilitating the evasion of United States sanctions against Russia and its proxies accountable through sanctions or other restrictions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C218F4822154BDE821B798D051FFCCA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of foreign companies and persons that have provided transportation, logistical, administrative, border crossing, or money transfer services to Russian mercenaries or armed forces operating on behalf of the Russian Government in Libya, and an analysis of whether such entities meet the criteria for imposition of sanctions under section 1(a) of Executive Order 13726 (81 Fed. Reg. 23559; relating to blocking property and suspending entry into the United States of persons contributing to the situation in Libya).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8894A02497D4E08856C04EA3CD46B48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7F638890343A427B98C0DD479A0B482D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HB5B93730C6924CB182D6E7D7926AA51B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H434CF2843BD14516A800557580EF94FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

