<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F70A9185D72485CAA0B7CADF0D8EE51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7826 IH: Pathways to Policing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7826</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220518">May 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a grant to encourage recruitment of law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1D00106CA7584264981948582E38BD7F" style="OLC"><section id="HD167A94599F745A3A64DFF7B07868BE2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pathways to Policing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA69AC4171BB04E44A0D5C588CB159B6B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF9FC93347FDF46AF82D231E48A77C6EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><part id="H5D69FB65BBE24D0DBE1E762A8DDB2F0C"><enum>PP</enum><header>Law Enforcement Hiring Support Grant</header><section id="HA4F88BA28ED94439AF15B5E7F7EBE636"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><subsection id="H7D6FC462BD8D44A5A5130307AB089FC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this part, the COPS Director is authorized to make grants, on a competitive basis, to States, units of local government, and law enforcement agencies for the purposes described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A934E1302CE4386AC45E9680DC48838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a State, unit of local government, or law enforcement agency shall submit an application to the COPS Director at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the COPS Director may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H05EB319A048A448E8991C853954D6DFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under this part may use the grant funds for the following:</text><paragraph id="HB8064F23087B4242AC9ECE41375A4624"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Marketing and Recruitment campaigns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 50 percent of the grant funds awarded to a recipient under this part may be used to develop, implement, or expand marketing and recruitment campaigns for the purpose of encouraging candidates to seek careers in law enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CF9C2BBBBE94E27814CD8A17FE4273E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pathways to policing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Not more than 50 percent of the grant funds awarded to a recipient under this part may be used to develop, operate, or expand Pathways to Policing programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB65030FF7D9E41A38DD2C96B26C65E50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>For each fiscal year in which a grant is awarded under this part, each recipient of such grant shall submit to the COPS Director a report containing a summary of each activity carried out using such grant and such other information as the COPS Director may require.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3D442E8265044A64B56B52E9CCAAD87E"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Priority</header><subsection id="H1E2F1015CD624318A8B02644E7270688"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Underrepresented and nontraditional groups</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding a grant under this part, priority shall be given to applicants that seek to recruit candidates who are members of communities traditionally underrepresented in the field of law enforcement or who have nontraditional educational or career backgrounds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC5EC447631D346E8970752FC70033ED6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Community policing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding a grant under this part, priority shall be given to applicants that seek to recruit candidates who reside in or who are willing to relocate to the communities that the candidates will serve, or that are in close proximity to the communities that the candidates will serve.</text></subsection></section><section id="H07BE2151FA104D5187F879DA1ACE2C83"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text><paragraph id="H8471C8A31E744A49AD642817278DD3B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>COPS Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>COPS Director</quote> means the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA82EA59B9ECE4CC3A6C3FF8A88DABC9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pathways to Policing programs</header><text>The term <quote>Pathways to Policing programs</quote> refers to any program that—</text><subparagraph id="H7725B9EB5A2345199A918A8D6BE6E6B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitates the entry into full-time law enforcement positions for candidates that—</text><clause id="HEA38E4515B8F49878B085E0ADC6341A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>face barriers in obtaining the education and training necessary to pursue a law enforcement career; and</text></clause><clause id="HB4115CCB205F49CEB0AD87C8A369B13A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have no prior law enforcement experience;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FF4FEC4B16F4CFFAF08734DCE941452"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides candidates with financial support, including tuition, compensation, or benefits, while attending a law enforcement officer education and training program, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0CF080BCFF24F988CD23A81AB1830C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include service in part-time, uniformed positions that further a candidate’s training to be a full-time law enforcement officer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H086A3E4C76F94B6A880F40745A05AD26"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 to carry out sections 3061, 3062, and 3063 for each of fiscal years 2023 to 2027.</text></section><section id="H2167041371E74FEFA2C9D5273EADA338"><enum>3065.</enum><header>Nationwide law enforcement marketing and recruitment campaign</header><subsection id="HF5BB15BF9FE04564BC0283CB3DF3AF70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Marketing and recruitment campaigns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Attorney General shall develop and implement nationwide marketing and recruitment campaigns for the purpose of encouraging candidates, including candidates who are members of communities traditionally underrepresented in the field of law enforcement or who have nontraditional educational or career backgrounds, to seek careers in law enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H66FDE3A45E884B7B90071BF5A3906655"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and implementing the marketing and recruitment campaigns under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall consult with State attorneys general, State and local law enforcement entities, professional law enforcement associations, community-based organizations, and academic researchers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H74B3A2D700E84EB7AD70515ED37EED65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>States, units of local government, and law enforcement agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and implementing the marketing and recruitment campaigns under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall create educational materials and related resources for States, units of local government, and law enforcement agencies to operate a marketing and recruitment campaign under section 3061.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA3B1CCE34F44EF6B7690274E82A2F24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 to 2027.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

