<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA670C02E59554B758C41F1E2952093C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7141 IH: College Completion Fund Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7141</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to States to empower public institutions of higher education in the States to provide student support services to students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4CD6206C48D74DDBB9AB83C3AFB8F193" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF3B52B37DE4944FB8062132537F3AA95"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Completion Fund Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCABB9157490E4158B80B6BFEB12A3DA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Higher education college completion fund program</header><subsection id="H560CB92089E04532B2BE922B17B7F93C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to support completion and retention activities designed to ensure the postsecondary success of students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans in public institutions of higher education serving a significant number of such students. </text></subsection><subsection id="H3E01C2954A664FA4AA83D0B021025AC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H99A8389D836048F5B717059897100C29" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Completion rate</header><text>The term <term>completion rate</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE821FDCD88DE420B819756499E8BB403"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the percentage of students from an initial cohort enrolled at a public institution of higher education in the State that is a 2-year institution who have graduated from the institution or transferred to a 4-year institution of higher education; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H438264716BA24CCCB53E95489F4AD86E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage of students from an initial cohort enrolled at a public institution of higher education in the State that is a 4-year institution who have graduated from the institution. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCAA5465C834048F5A07AADFB1D6BF25C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible indian entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible Indian entity</term> means the entity responsible for the governance, operation, or control of a Tribal College or University.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19CDD7BFB77B4C9085A5293D11CE7B64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A1A40D62B441BC855E8F2CBFFA0570"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B59BA28F8D2407993B34EB96446B5C4" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State service provider</header><text>The term <term>State service provider</term> means a nonprofit organization that receives Federal funding or State funding to provide services commensurate with guidelines for those services and is in good standing with regard to such funding. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D3A961DC51A4152ADF785747BB5A1F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text>The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> has the meaning given the term in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H592570D78155451D8619F8F0A48780DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of completion fund</header><paragraph id="H9DD48ECBBB054AAEA8FE5D908861C322"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservation of funds for eligible indian entities</header><text>From the total amount appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve 2 percent for grants to eligible Indian entities to increase participation and completion rates of students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE6182D0781E4D1697A958066C15E008"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make grants, from allotments under paragraph (3), to States to enable the States to distribute funds to participating public institutions of higher education in the State to provide student support services to increase participation, retention, and completion rates of students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78872FD8A3474F5C91EE46CDA3C55AA9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of allotment</header><subparagraph id="HC654BC53601340B8A3F13CBC1080488E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount of allotment</header><text>From the total amount appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year and not reserved under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall allot to each State having an application approved under this section an amount, subject to subparagraph (B), that shall be equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="HBBD94EB30CC84DFF909C8CC1A019B303"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount that bears the same relation to 50 percent of the amount appropriated and not reserved for such fiscal year as the number of residents in the State aged 5 through 17 who are living below the poverty line applicable to the resident’s family size (as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)) bears to the total number of such residents in all States; and</text></clause><clause id="H645785529AE84D1388BD56EB062C51B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount that bears the same relation to 50 percent of the amount appropriated and not reserved for such fiscal year as the number of residents in the State aged 15 through 44 who are living below the poverty line applicable to the individual’s family size (as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)) bears to the total number of such residents in all States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ADA6F3D62A3488BB1D90975C99825FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum amount</header><text>The allotment for each State under this section for a fiscal year shall not be an amount that is less than 1.0 percent of the total amount appropriated to carry out this section for the fiscal year and not reserved under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D42C578E7FB4860B0326ED5C4301A86" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Set asides</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E043533B47E414F8197D2527D3BB6B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evidence-based student success programs</header><text>Each State that receives a grant under this section shall set aside not less than 20 percent of grant funds for evidence-based student success programs, which are programs designed to improve persistence, credit accumulation, completion, or career success, carried out by an institution and that—</text><clause commented="no" id="H28682465698943699A872957AB2458C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H29BB59B9453D472D8383526317575833"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the requirements for evaluation as described in subsection (a)(2)(B) of section 4611 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7261">20 U.S.C. 7261(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>); or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H99D89963B9814893A9599EAB0E7F835C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the requirements for evaluation as described in subsection (a)(2)(C) of section 4611 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7261">20 U.S.C. 7261(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBAD1FECC96594606853DFE3C59F85C9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide students with a program advisor to each eligible student participating in such program who provides comprehensive academic and personal advising to the eligible student, including monitoring of academic progress of the eligible student, and may provide each eligible student with financial incentives, such as tuition assistance, transportation assistance or a gas card, free tutoring and career services (which can include benefit counseling) to eligible students in order to create a community with eligible student participating in such program. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9DF71E941F9A45C3BC6C00949FB8FFBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Permissive</header><text>Each State that receives a grant under this section may set aside—</text><clause commented="no" id="H6C299D580CD94887A0936974C04A10B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent of grant funds for administration, capacity building, research, evaluation, and reporting; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBA45241BC5B94FF38D04423383379DA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent of grant funds for technical assistance to State service providers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88F81C1AB2F7431B9A46BDA35181DAB7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State strategic plans</header><paragraph id="HEBB6799BBAD2415DA277F1652DBF3205"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a State strategic plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DF2264A48A6427FBBEB9054F119240D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of state strategic plan</header><text>Each State strategic plan shall be developed with input from each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1D5B2EFA1EF64B4CA4F4B81AC6AAB304"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2-year public institutions of higher education in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AB3871974004DB4AF7BBFB25E714B32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>4-year public institutions of higher education in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D81D151385D4F1599D770B2123BC9AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The State workforce development board established under section 101 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B73B066E72B424D805438B4E2455F5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A Tribal College or University with a campus located in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEFAC7F466C04F7080CCBFBE45F405E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>State service providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DA84F9B714A45058DCC714D3757EFFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The State department with jurisdiction over children, youth, and family services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF623FE41964E21BD5B05597527B592"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content of state strategic plan</header><text>Each State strategic plan shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB4585E05021B4564A3151789112B3C0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information on the state of the public institutions of higher education in the State, including the following:</text><clause id="H548DF8C9FB0446BB9B74B301A5F75C78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of the distribution of funds to be provided from the grant to participating public institutions of higher education in the State.</text></clause><clause id="HF604FD0A2BEB42B5803EB3AF1C84D1CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A strategy for adopting a diverse portfolio of promising and evidence-based practices.</text></clause><clause id="HD1F683D95869456F80FF26CA1089A62D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Annual benchmarks for student outcomes.</text></clause><clause id="H5AA85A77A8234D5C899879F6BB5BE4E9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Information about the evaluation of interventions proposed to be funded by the grant. </text></clause><clause id="HBD9B3B40F164439B9FC6A59C2EAB8FB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of the State’s plan for an equity audit of higher education financing.</text></clause><clause id="HCC65BCF54BA74B0C97A86E51C1BD8E17"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Rates of enrolled students who received a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H58B7DEFC36114BA88F4CC3572A02F4CF"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Demographics of enrolled students, including students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC8ECA23116F4523BFDF94D480071CC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A plan to increase student attainment and completion rates or graduation rates of all students enrolled at public institutions of higher education in the State, with a particular focus on students from students from low-income backgrounds, historically underrepresented students, first-generation college enrollees, parenting students, students with disabilities, and student veterans through student support services, cross-agency engagement, and collaboration among 2-year programs, 4-year programs, and workforce systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA2895C9BDB0481395B949A3C92C8142"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Institutional participation</header><paragraph id="HA62245E801D243668E9BED0FF27CF9F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A public institution of higher education that desires to receive assistance under a grant made under this section shall submit to the State in which the institution is located a notification that the institution desires to opt into participation under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5581B7F61329455C897E21E993D41D67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of strategic plan</header><text>A State that desires to receive a grant under this section shall solicit input from public institutions of higher education in the State in the development of the State strategic plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF78E5CCCF6BF4D419FC0FC3982023958" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institutional support</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall not limit student support services to students enrolled at public institutions of higher education in the State that participated in the development of the State strategic plan, but shall provide student support services to students enrolled in participating public institutions of higher education in the State. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H338CAB241A6F4379ADCB5B69A82AF9BD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall distribute funds to participating institutions of higher education in the State for evidence-based and promising practices in improving retention and completion rates, including the following: </text><paragraph id="HA7A4254961F34D09A7AFB81A2FC105E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Student support services to support retention, completion, and success, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA24787002FF74D57ABE8BA73A5F28A79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>faculty and peer counseling;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE0E1C66734C43A7A52E97D4B0B7994A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use of real-time data on student progress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34E6261D54AB4A43BC0E509BE47278E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incentives for students to stay on track.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7615B4A27FFE4BD28A5F9105352CFBEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Direct student support services, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEB664C1A232C45D49D5CEEA0529C5B1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transportation accessibility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB66206149A2F4C2B943A686888CCBECF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>room and board or assistance to address housing instability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BAD1B58C21F4375B973843AA728E8B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>addressing food instability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB57D8B8665F4431A8D0F1F04E75A18C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>remedial education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C73438E945C4EFCACF0BC3EAD5A852A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>tutoring, academic supports, and enrichment services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1385547A79D949B6A7FE4C810591003C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>emergency financial assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0551E602F37D4335BDFD6AD6E2252631"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Access to health care and mental health services on or near campus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A7100005A5341A68FC84721258E857F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support helping students enroll in public benefits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H104EC275CBF34AC6AFC54D84DA38FA39"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Issues with respect to dependents of students, including—</text><subparagraph id="H855B0484E27745CB8FCE8AE6878C3E16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-quality daycare and prekindergarten access during traditional school hours;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H554450D727B945B58FFA7B23967E3874"><enum>(B)</enum><text>childcare access during non-traditional hours; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B6FD61539B64AF396F0D3EEB22B1355"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prenatal and early childhood education classes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDCFDA381102472AA4CB5D57FEEC53DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Development of soft skills.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5993ECE68CAB41C9A95B17740C01EA73"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Career coaching, career counseling and planning services, and efforts to lower student to advisor ratios, including—</text><subparagraph id="H71DDB92BAF8B418DB053378FD4A9EA2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>networking and work-based learning opportunities to support the development of skills and relationships; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92694BF7C3894922A77178880CEC2122"><enum>(B)</enum><text>boosting experiences necessary to obtain and succeed in high-quality jobs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11DA7F0DA0AD450C850DA748BB766F52"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Reforms to developmental education, including—</text><subparagraph id="H50A753AB346F45FF9F6A9D135C9D0B15" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilizing career pathways; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9CEE0926024A71B2D8A8170777B83B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving transfer student success.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E1AB1C04C4040138E1D509FEBE5B0D3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Efforts to recruit, retain, and develop diverse faculty and other instructional staff.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27A04DD92E6D4ED88D716F0490DD8DBA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation and reporting</header><paragraph id="HD1855C95DF5841AA8096EA6B2F3BF6C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of independent agency</header><text>The State department with jurisdiction over higher education in each State that receives a grant under this section shall designate an independent agency to compile and evaluate data linked to institutional programs and student outcomes funded with grant funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABFD72419917446FB54840E5285838AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compilation of information</header><text>Each independent agency designated under paragraph (1) shall compile longitudinal data tracking student participant outcomes, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4A03C05954C74DF2976275E9D192A553"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Graduation rates, disaggregated by age (25 years of age and younger, and older than 25 years of age), gender, income, race and ethnicity, and first-generation college status—</text><clause id="H697825CE897B4FE28CBF78956DD46133"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at 100 percent of the normal time for graduation;</text></clause><clause id="H25907B378FE34118A4CA0785F55642C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at 150 percent of the normal time for graduation; and</text></clause><clause id="HAC75047705C24756BAD55012A5480FC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at 200 percent of the normal time for graduation. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41107F19350A4A4F9D7BA73669D0B803"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Transfer out rates, disaggregated by age (25 years of age and younger, and older than 25 years of age), gender, income, race and ethnicity, and first-generation college status. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12FF4D96DA884A79925AF5C694599053"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Withdrawal rates, including rates of students who withdraw to seek employment in a related field of study.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE19A3334C5E246829D042770EE4B2AC7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The percentage of students who continue enrollment at the institution after the first year of enrollment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE22CF848AB644AE7BF623E739026B5C8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The median time to degree completion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC167EFE709744DCF9DF38AAACD2DEB21"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Career outcomes and employment data, which may include earnings, within 1 year of completion, within 3 years of completion, and within 5 years of completion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H196BFE3A8A2D489CB5EB23174BC97015"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Career outcomes and employment data for student participants who did not complete the program in which the student was enrolled within 1 year of leaving the program, within 3 years of leaving the program, and within 5 years of leaving the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B6A9D7DB84F49968CCCD7C4DCE1CC08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Techniques</header><text>Each independent agency designated under paragraph (1) shall evaluate the academic outcomes using quasi-experimental techniques.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6AD5D52D5247AD977218E074E2BC7C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Each independent agency designated under paragraph (1) shall submit to the State department with jurisdiction over higher education a report that includes findings of the data compiled under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21967B3605BC4989B6115F2034D456CB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Each State department with jurisdiction over higher education that receives a report under paragraph (4) shall submit the report to the Department of Education and the authorizing committees, as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>), at such time and in such matter as the Secretary of Education determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD06151CBD9E4CEE9042DA43CAEFF241"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Each independent agency designated under paragraph (1) shall not track data with respect to individuals who transfer, move, or seek employment outside of the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6F79B79C97842AB92808FD14772F2A9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Maintaining net State operating support for higher education</header><paragraph id="H862DFA771517488C86CA945AD61F5207"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall maintain net State operating support for higher education for each fiscal year for which the State receives a grant under this section at a level that is not less than the level that is equal to the average of such net State operating support for higher education for the 3 fiscal years preceding such fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5744D11030E4F0CA160157732722740"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waivers</header><subparagraph id="H0C094DA0882C49A1B8072F113FBE595D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may grant a waiver to a State from the requirement under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year if the State demonstrates that—</text><clause id="H16BAB57B99E247C1BE011E4223D9E2DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the net State operating support for higher education for such fiscal year as a percentage of total revenue available to the State that will fund higher education for such fiscal year is not less than such percentage for the previous fiscal year; and</text></clause><clause id="HE6F5DE40E0484A76B67A210065D22641"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>unexpected or uncontrollable circumstances prevent the State from maintaining such State support.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF900003E31C4F738221B0CD876CA68C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No reduction for subsequent fiscal year</header><text>If the Secretary grants a State a waiver under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, a determination of the required level of net State operating support for higher education for subsequent fiscal years shall exclude the fiscal year for which the waiver was granted. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCA25928A07844E18BBA3D148B3ED325" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $62,000,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2032. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

