<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD4972F1DFF924EA2A119D99E914B9270" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7860 IH: Financial Freedom Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7860</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220520">May 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Labor from constraining the range or type of investments that may be offered to participants and beneficiaries of individual retirement accounts who exercise control over the assets in such accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD09CE446B3134FAB93B01E6DB9311DE0" style="OLC">
<section id="H0AC46959FDB247A19FA0416F1CCFBCA1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Freedom Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H343C692262914B598E3E148600F2D79C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fiduciary duties with respect to pension plan investments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1104">29 U.S.C. 1104(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H86E80F1F6C7046C1A0537D44781776B4" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H75EB0FFEAE794D469051699F67D56754"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph id="H411D0AFCF317463DBCDA4BC5BB731B91" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of a pension plan that provides for individual accounts and permits a participant or beneficiary to exercise control over the assets in the participant’s or beneficiary’s account, nothing in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H8053E6848E80409093B30CDE9C112DD0" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>requires a fiduciary to select, or prohibits a fiduciary from selecting, any particular type of investment alternative, provided that a fiduciary provides the participant or beneficiary an opportunity to choose, from a broad range of investment alternatives, the manner in which some or all of the assets of the participant’s or beneficiary’s account are invested, according to regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HF24540FFF38443108A5537FEF2082608" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requires that any particular type of investment be either favored or disfavored, other than on the basis of the investment’s risk-return characteristics, in the context of the plan fiduciary’s objective of providing investment alternatives suitable for providing benefits for participants and beneficiaries.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA467C76D76394560A0E51C33063E0944" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the event that a fiduciary selects a self-directed brokerage window as an investment alternative for a plan described in subparagraph (A)—</text>
<clause id="HF49D72A06BAB4919BE1F0CDB235AAFA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall not issue any regulations or subregulatory guidance constraining or prohibiting the range or type of investments that may be offered through such brokerage window;</text></clause> <clause id="HE500A726F63D4039880F35713521EE46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subsection (c) shall apply to such self-directed brokerage window; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H85AFF91A0DCA4F7FBDA36B221A0B9B00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the diversification requirement of paragraph (1)(C) and the prudence requirement of paragraph (1)(B) are not violated by the fiduciary’s selection of a self-directed brokerage window as an investment alternative or as a result of the exercise of a participant or beneficiary’s control over the assets in such self-directed brokerage window.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

