<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE5F3FC5B18CD4BDCA39F75590C461B81" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9046 IH: Industrial Efficiency Incentive Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a program to issue rebates for energy efficiency improvements at industrial facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4050CE868AD44838ABCDAA2A4638042C" style="OLC"><section id="H6CDC322AE9AC42A68E1F6FBC2E00DED6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; definitions<editorial></editorial><editorial></editorial></header><subsection id="HC08C1A1CA0414090A8D2D8FA6C6E7CA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Industrial Efficiency Incentive Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C23DDFB7EF843BC82067082BBBC17D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H55F0AB97FE9546248F94FB1DD3CCB8E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certified energy expert</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>certified energy expert</term> means an expert that has been identified, through testing and review by an independent, accredited certification body that has been approved by the Secretary of Energy, as meeting the Department of Energy’s criteria for providing energy efficiency and carbon reducing services to an eligible facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FE5535449ED41DC8732A0C1F871C521" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible facility</term> means a nonpower industrial facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF29E9659E0F44A3B19BEF69648BB077" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industrial Assessment Centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Industrial Assessment Centers</term> means the Industrial Assessment Centers of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1296DB4877B3470083A803DC5D52E2A0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified entity</header><text>The term <term>qualified entity</term> means the owner or operator of an eligible facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H382B58EF62CA4144AD49FB26219A6C4A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified technology</header><text>The term <term>qualified technology</term> means any technology—</text><subparagraph id="H80035FE7EA534A33A5771BB3EB0734FE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is used at an eligible facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B6AAB73E68649F7B7DB3F73B660B407"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="HB4A17F5BF99A4D4397A39DE46F24A13A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of which can be demonstrated to result in energy efficiency improvements of at least 20 percent over an eligible facility’s existing technology and does not increase scope 1 greenhouse gas emissions or scope 2 greenhouse gas emissions, as such terms are defined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, of the eligible facility;</text></clause><clause id="HC4AB7190AC154916931F98846FB85F09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of which can be demonstrated to reduce the amount of water used by at least 20 percent over an eligible facility’s existing technology; or</text></clause><clause id="H332325D849234B41A5F02F0BD7AB5EB1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replaces fossil fuel-fired technology at an eligible facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81133911A33944D097442A410BFE32EB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>utility</term> means a regulated entity that provides electricity, natural gas, or water service to an eligible facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H244D6F45239D4DFBAD20060F09ECB029" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Working Group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Working Group</term> means the Industrial Efficiency Working Group established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H84831EA31FEA44C4A44F13BFC31C8163" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="H7B48A85D6FD946BAA01D9606C6774AC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the industrial sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CAE4914D78641A8B6D70F1D24C01168"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maximize the energy efficiency and water use efficiency of United States industrial facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35CB1FC1477744CEBF05212679929E97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make industrial facilities more financially viable by making energy efficiency improvements at such facilities that lower energy costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE50CC7210CC343BD9025CE528D9E2BA6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>create opportunities for energy efficiency manufacturing and installation jobs across the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E61DFD843E45D29BE75CC22E034899"><enum>(5)</enum><text>make the United States industrial sector the cleanest in the world.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBFD234D2236642A0AA412E7D833FDF85"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sustainable industry rebate program</header><subsection id="H7C57097C6401479DBCC095E67DE47B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Sustainable Industry Rebate Program</quote>, under which the Secretary of Energy shall issue rebates to qualified entities for purchases of qualified technology.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4DE5A47601F342BFAA0A3BE95A9DE941"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process</header><paragraph id="H0841EA2E05DA4AF2A8389E8C569F07CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H20E18E536E944452ADDB26DF15C6D200"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and make available rebate forms which qualified entities shall use to request a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5961874349C546BAA2A1672B0B427A21" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a database and information technology system, to be known as the <quote>Federal Rebate Processing System</quote>, which shall be used by qualified entities to submit forms made available under subparagraph (A) for the purpose of requesting a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70CA91FFB0544405B722C0B624B5F74E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program, a qualified entity shall submit to the Secretary of Energy a completed form made available under paragraph (1)(A) at such time and containing such information as the Secretary of Energy may require, which at a minimum such form shall—</text><subparagraph id="H83D31FE0EAC5458F95F32062A1F9F551"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate—</text><clause id="HB1604D5EC9714F34B3B6A1066F9F064F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the qualified entity purchased a qualified technology;</text></clause><clause id="HCE90ACEAC5DD45E5A4F1D8172D4BAAD5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that such qualified technology is eligible for the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program;</text></clause><clause id="HA2AB3E6DBFFF4BA1851601E82CC5D8C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such qualified technology is eligible for any of the additional rebate amounts provided in subsection (d)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="HD76991BABF974729A07489D5DB916DA7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applicable, whether any technology replaced by the qualified technology has been permanently decommissioned; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6773CFA33184BB684B09C90AABEB859"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include information on—</text><clause id="H8BBADF53E1324A1CB41316559AF2DEA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of the reduction in energy or water use to be achieved by implementation of the qualified technology; and</text></clause><clause id="HD9F418C02FBE4A04921185691E567462"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of any reduction in greenhouse gas emissions that results from replacing an existing technology with the qualified technology.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD88CB303A9934A2497569700736A204E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sustainable Industry Database</header><paragraph id="H6E8FAF91595045A5B4AB9EF66C3B49AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall establish and maintain on the website of the Department of Energy a national database, to be known as the <quote>Sustainable Industry Database</quote>, to provide information on the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D68EFB70514CD096555DF858A66465"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The Sustainable Industry Database shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H7865AA8724464B9CA5D2E221C70ED7E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the technologies that the Working Group determines are qualified technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB748838801D471C9624EFF8DC4033B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of the qualified technologies that are eligible for the Made in America additional rebate amounts provided in subsection (d)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC223E2817AD49C494FF2F724C50449C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instructions for how a qualified entity may apply for a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AFAAF824D3F418D9F8DB920C21465DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>instructions for how to petition the Working Group to request an addition to a list of qualified technologies included by subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A71250373D54D40AE97F45E6A6328C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructions for how to petition the Working Group to recognize technologies that individually do not qualify for the rebate but can be combined and used to provide a benefit equal to or greater than a qualified technology, such as pumps and pipes used together; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AC4C51085D9468FBE6DC10BBB8F7BA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional information determined appropriate by the Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA2B1C0D88274FE087DB460744EEE573"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorized amount of rebate</header><paragraph id="HE41578B7877A436A8C1F57319500C21D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Base rebates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The base amount of a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program shall be equal to the amount that is—</text><subparagraph id="H4F9CF245A026495FB359692760141ED8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a qualified entity with more than 500 employees, 25 percent of the total cost to purchase the qualified technology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44432D89A1A841A18401AABC448B3B5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a qualified entity with fewer than 500 employees, 40 percent of the total cost to purchase the qualified technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD04393376BB2403A94E848FF0C187B6F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional rebate amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the base amount described in paragraph (1), the total amount of a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program may be increased by—</text><subparagraph id="H1D0A09F7B7F64FD08A77630342926608" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the majority of the components of the purchased qualified technology were manufactured in the United States, the amount that is equal to 15 percent of the total cost to purchase the qualified technology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F4DDFCE7A6E47399214FA51C18CC292" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the qualified technology facilitates a switch from a fossil fuel-fired energy source to a zero-carbon energy source, the amount that is equal to 10 percent of the total cost to purchase the qualified technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81BE3C2CD7894DCF9ADCC19A251B9FE2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost to purchase qualified technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of determining the amount of a rebate issued under the Sustainable Industry Rebate Program, the total cost to purchase the qualified technology shall include all costs associated with—</text><subparagraph id="H33D37E1CADED4F4183F98C26786FDCF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purchase and installation of the qualified technology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9850CCE17E14AB6A1A5B8750D1C0116"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the removal of any existing technology as a result of such purchase and installation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD17544767E4843E8BB8110FAB946D2E7" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2031, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5C96CCEEEF07493D8CEAFC5A693675DA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Industrial efficiency working group</header><subsection id="H41CAEE0928B24E40B883130F7741239A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall establish the Industrial Efficiency Working Group.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB93356707E049A6BC51FD6A86658155"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H6C3DC0680C064E83AA565A81B8398B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group shall be comprised of members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Directors of the Advanced Manufacturing Office, the Building Technology Office, and the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7567A0950EB747E4AE2EA49CAE1D3C8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>Members of the Working group shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H27BBC7D89FF74942846525C7F8E8C9FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one representative from each relevant Federal agency, as determined by the Secretary of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2021E162BEA45D99ACF04CD9049E5BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one representative from each relevant office of the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA87FD07973146A0A850D9DCFAE2D029"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one representative from labor groups;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38A1A2D24234448CA2105921DB677D19"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from the research community, which shall include at least one representative from academia and at least one representative from any relevant National Laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B3B80F74484E1BB967FA85C8A78CE1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one representative from nongovernmental organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDDA3C5C871A45D7AB61479B5EE15B73"><enum>(F)</enum><text>representatives from energy efficiency program administrators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE762194A52344E1B00EE4286835D868"><enum>(G)</enum><text>representatives from industry and trade associations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9FF5720C324339BADFA6FADBB1C8B1"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other individual whom the Secretary of Energy determines to be necessary to ensure that the Working Group is comprised of a diverse group of representatives from industry, academia, independent researchers, and public and private entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H286116E4E57B4492881988BB08DBAAF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall designate a member of the Working Group to serve as the Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D2B9BC718D44422ADD588F6138BA705"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Working Group shall—</text><paragraph id="H4DA8431943864920AF3ECD13ED097B16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop the list of qualified technologies to be included in the Sustainable Industry Database under section 3(c)(2)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF71B50E9CDC446799C5337297B258793" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop the list of the qualified technologies that meet the Made in America requirements for additional rebate amounts to be included in the Sustainable Industry Database under section 3(c)(2)(B);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDF6B05E24D04EB6A0F63F2BE7CCACAD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determine if any technologies for which a petition is submitted pursuant to section 3(c)(2)(D) should be added to the applicable list;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5BF46229BA84CAEBD3E4BF98CF73008"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">periodically revise the lists developed under paragraphs (1) and (2), which includes revising such lists to remove, as necessary, any technology that is no longer determined to be a qualified technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB85988EB95A440D6846C5C2D0F946DDB" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify technology gaps in industrial efficiency, and make recommendations to address such gaps.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52CD172428774CE7ACE11FF114815007"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="H784C1F7D26854CCC8DA04210F0A8A2CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Working Group shall meet not less frequently than twice per year, at the call of the Chair.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC87A5962E5CC41A6B1981C328EC960E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the members are appointed under subsection (b), the Working Group shall hold its first meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8881B519AED74DE9AE5FCDFE678B5E06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every year thereafter, the Working Group shall submit to the Secretary of Energy a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HF45F56FF194A41EDA3845D6EE10A1386"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the list of qualified technologies developed under subsection (c)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2439F979E773469AB66F223B54C44B79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the list of the qualified technologies developed under subsection (c)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C0D9A7877994040881EC813E99AB70E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an identification of which technologies were added or removed from the lists described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A45B853744F4582A033BDE495288AD8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Energy shall, to the maximum extent possible—</text><paragraph id="HA7073EA061584FEEB23CEDB234457713"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate and seek to avoid duplication with other programs of the Department of Energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF6CEF5CDC464DBA8E1C6BF35D084812"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate and collaborate with the Industrial Technology Innovation Advisory Committee (established under section 455 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17114">42 U.S.C. 17114</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDD0B69C3129461CBB72E2740B052F8C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leverage existing resources and programs of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB251117B04244C2F9B05D45B8B3CDC34"><enum>5.</enum><header>Save carbon now program</header><subsection id="H44BA3CCA01F143D7807BDF12592B9FB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HAD6011A826734C79ABD61A53205F9345"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall, after consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, identify the 3,000 eligible facilities in the United States that emit the most greenhouse gases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE5E80A11D74EFBA159C2D0AF85EB1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessments and technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each facility identified in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Energy shall offer to—</text><subparagraph id="H588C044EE15048748D12F833DDDD5EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out an assessment of such facility in accordance with subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3278206292C499182F378329C38946D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to such facility to assist with developing and carrying out a plan, in accordance with subsection (c), to implement recommendations provided by the assessment carried out under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3C2E320635341BEA019832293789F19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessments</header><paragraph id="H0ACC50C8CDC34882AC960FB83353DCC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments carried out under subsection (a)(2)(A) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H480C2530152948F395E227DB356EE01A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze the energy use and costs of the facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2C198BB275D4C5E9A616F03BACCE0C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide recommendations to—</text><clause id="HA71E951393654CAA83C4E0851BC98E8A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maximize the energy efficiency of industrial processes and cross-cutting systems at the facility;</text></clause><clause id="HE9E6BAB9B8184F0F9DAB6D755A8BFC17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce greenhouse gas emissions of the facility;</text></clause><clause id="H38F92FC2C5BA48EAA68B5C19462B3CA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the efficient use of water in manufacturing or industrial processes at the facility;</text></clause><clause id="H3C204C4CFF1B4C9BB0474D2913D6EEF8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent air and water pollution and minimize waste from the facility; and</text></clause><clause id="H5AF34C736C9F4B58970E506AE6C1D3A6"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce energy and water use, and greenhouse gas emissions, of the facility, including by making—</text><subclause id="H7ED6BDB16E2A49E08AD4CF49DC1A8E88"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">motor system improvements, including to fan, pump, compressed air, and other motor-driven equipment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB17E16F5002D40D69C5295868F9D37CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>steam system improvements;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF27A613D90CA4B44AD8BD6B66753F326"><enum>(III)</enum><text>heating, ventilating, and air-conditioning system improvements;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1C7CAE4A93B248078BA627DE2FFF4370"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>lighting system improvements;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDD4CE819F66542F1934688503F52FB06"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">process equipment or operational improvements; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7B1BD775BCB744458C9FEAAD3EBBEE04"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>water system improvements.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60041B318FA04648BF584CC7C6AC995D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment teams</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessments carried out under subsection (a)(2)(A) shall be conducted by teams of experts made up of—</text><subparagraph id="H0266146AD5E44AD49559B5157C5F97EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>staff of the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49A184B994047B6B8DFF2F435C0533F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experts from the National Laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08BB71F960D04827BE0463EA75D7F8C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>experts from the Manufacturing USA Program established under section 34 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECC0F686CD9A43959EFC9905BB86AF3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>faculty and staff from the Industrial Assessment Centers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CEDCD9E0F4D4664AF8EB7991CD8CED4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other certified energy experts contracted by the Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE53923D9AE22474FBF5DB19DAA98D8EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation plans</header><paragraph id="H0E9FA7AFB5F044D9B91C326E9830A28F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Implementation plans developed pursuant to subsection (a)(2)(B) shall, with respect to the recommendations included in the assessment—</text><subparagraph id="HA9988DA7C881455ABCA41A16748A2336"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include information on any assistance or training needs necessary to implement such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF6507DAC6114E48BC00BBB6E68FC1E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include information on any new or upgraded equipment necessary to implement such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072476597BE245BCB3DE8915F7B7E2A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include information on research and development activities that would assist with implementing such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA29CDB8B8234C4FAE6DDE4D73ACC376"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify local partners that can be leveraged to implement such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BCB1DE7C89A43378727B9EBB9A7BCC0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify steps needed to implement a strategic energy management program at the facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2CF75227B914A55A5E4F6B1865724A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify Federal, State, and utility assistance programs that may be used to implement such recommendations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8B0EAA561AA4667A8B6412594718E1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In providing technical assistance to carry out an implementation plan under this section, the Secretary of Energy shall coordinate, as appropriate, with—</text><subparagraph id="HC5BA0FE0A7314CA5A477C96CFBBAF961"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7CAC633650F435B8EA74E200FCA60E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private and public sector entities, including State energy offices, utility regulatory agencies, Indian Tribes, economic development authorities, and utilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAA793AD80614D28AEDA2A859D37ACA1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Secretary of Energy may not, with respect to a facility identified under subsection (a)(1), expend more than $500,000 in carrying out an assessment and providing technical assistance to such facility under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H503F33F6B9064AD6B7B531052B81A986"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H8AF91CC8ED0046028A6955EAD38D9CA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report on the assessments carried out and the technical assistance provided under this section by not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every two years thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA8FC40498349318083909119840E70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include information on—</text><subparagraph id="H00FE2186331A41F2A747FF74D8FCAF18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of facilities assessed under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE54A7C1AC12542AF88E920F6102C6665" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of recommendations provided pursuant to this section and the expected effect of such recommendations, if implemented, on energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions of such facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB70BBB01D34B3FAA577CC611152371"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any reductions in energy use of such facilities achieved by implementing such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5DE007256FA4CD0B4DA10991C04868E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any reductions in greenhouse gas emissions of such facilities achieved by implementing such recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A2756F437240DCAE9E03F6A1BE211F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any reductions in water use of such facilities achieved by implementing such recommendations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70578418C9794255A24FB9502C842539"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any reductions in costs to such facilities achieved by implementing such recommendations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9051ABEDF340C9B645C12CA9EBA116"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidential information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy may not include any confidential information relating to such facilities in any report under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CE02DFC0B034D1BB9682BE9A83FCC96" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $750,000,000 for fiscal years 2022 through 2026, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

