<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E192C306F584CF386EEC685DF2AED2B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7215 IH: Ravi Thackurdeen Safe Students Study Abroad Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7215</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional reporting on crime and harm that occurs during student participation in programs of study abroad, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE28C81CF0E1F470D823C588609FAC79A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEE6D4C35698947EEB407B0AD30A241B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ravi Thackurdeen Safe Students Study Abroad Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1B214F5D1E124E1BB6F47EE19FDF153E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of Clery Act to programs of study abroad</header> <subsection id="H252DB898CD10492D8CCEB9C758DB5B93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting of crime statistics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (12) of section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HCBF0F6EEA03448539A9AF6AF61CA3758"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFA69938F5DD45108B17E678827DEDF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (D) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54A77E697C2949F5836BA871F99F8511"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4912913590B4BADB112C91CA29709E9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H4F295681EE0743C3A5C8A136C943271F" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while a student is participating in a program of study abroad approved for credit by an institution of higher education, distinguished by whether the criminal offense occurred at a location described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D), or at another location, without regard to whether the institution owns or controls a building or property at such location.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2E6248294FCF4B169641F14921C74E04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional reporting for programs of study abroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2B2E6405457C4127B64573FEE4A8BCF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (18) as paragraph (19); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB836355472B4467BAC670D4E951CF6B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (17), the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28F9F2B27C1A4AC0B61A423F7F29B506" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC837BC75A3C94E5588E3F9DF001AB34E" indent="up1"><enum>(18)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2926181B19DB40FEBCDC53E226122606"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each institution of higher education participating in any program under this title, other than a foreign institution of higher education, shall develop and distribute as part of the report described in paragraph (1), a statement that the institution has adopted and implemented a program to protect students participating in a program of study abroad approved for credit by the institution from crime and harm while participating in such program of study abroad that, at a minimum, includes the following:</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H120B9C7388BE42D08027193712C303D4" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A biennial review by the institution of the programs of study abroad approved for credit by the institution to determine—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H394A6C51AD384DE08028E72AC4DE50EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the programs at protecting students from crime and harm, and whether changes to the programs are needed (based on the most recent guidance or other assistance from the Secretary) and will be implemented;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H4B99940020A94B60876220974E1DC759"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the 10 years preceding the date of the report, the number (in the aggregate for all programs of study abroad approved for credit by the institution) of—</text> <item commented="no" id="H27EF0953959941838BDE1A451C6CB463"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deaths of program participants occurring during program participation or during any other activities during the study abroad period;</text></item>
<item commented="no" id="H5755C23D19A041D9A42D2F7EEB06FC23"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>accidents and illnesses occurring during program participation that resulted in hospitalization;</text></item> <item commented="no" id="H8E4B699EA4CB4213A0D03CC223835DA6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>sexual assaults against program participants occurring during program participation; and</text></item>
<item commented="no" id="H88F4289EBB3F4F29837EF09E2D6B983E"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>incidents involving program participants during the program participation that resulted in police involvement or a police report; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H62373D2664E94A298C6D9455178EF441"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the incidents described in items (aa) through (dd) of subclause (II), whether the incidents occurred—</text>
<item id="HB07C9913A6F64BE7B26D037070D3B4BE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on campus;</text></item> <item id="HF300B01B3EE345738FC94F703661BE5F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in or on a noncampus building or property;</text></item>
<item id="H5BB84FDFC2C3440292C7CB15518F9264"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>on public property;</text></item> <item id="H1BBDD5D824364A8CAC2097CA283D8AB8"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in dormitories or other residential facilities for students; or</text></item>
<item id="H0C26628E5651499DA5F82350B7745CF3"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>at a location not described in items (aa) through (dd) of this subclause, without regard to whether the institution owns or controls a building or property at the location.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF99DA84F2A7249CE8CDDDD02AA72A141" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The crime statistics described in paragraph (12)(E).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DE1454312EB4C80B0C1BF11AE41A40C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An institution of higher education described in subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="H642836C4FFA445A097F2E7C1EAB33752"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide each student who is interested in participating in a program of study abroad approved for credit by the institution, with a pre-trip orientation session and advising that includes—</text>
<subclause id="HE6A47E2A7A9645CE9F6FFD2127A13C71"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of countries in which such programs of study abroad are located;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8130B41901CC49CDA11D84A8BDDFD286"><enum>(II)</enum><text>all current travel information, including all travel warnings and travel alerts, issued by the Bureau of Consular Affairs of the Department of State for such countries; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H96724EA57E164EB18B870732C06E165E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the information described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A), provided specifically for each program of study abroad approved for credit by the institution in which the student is considering participation; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF8E805CE816041DCBF8584E492D20F47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide each student who returns from such a program of study abroad with a post-trip orientation session, including an exit interview that assists the institution in carrying out subparagraph (A) and clause (i) of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFFD5DE3EE3D14BB79EC51C393D50BE2D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education shall not disaggregate or otherwise distinguish information for purposes of subparagraph (A) or (B) in a case in which the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H372FE9EC08E14F9B87610CA2F97B7B63" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall periodically review a representative sample of the programs described in subparagraph (A) that have been adopted and implemented by institutions of higher education to protect students participating in a program of study abroad described in subparagraph (A) from crime and harm while participating in such program of study abroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

