<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2367306C556447E838A2B619786523D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8804 IH: Air Force Rated Officer Retention Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Air Force to establish a demonstration program to assess and improve the retention of certain officers serving on active duty in the Air Force.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC9E2A590D48C41A799025E60C66EBA54" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B340196284C4F5B8B2F82B06FD84D07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Air Force Rated Officer Retention Program Act</short-title></quote>. </text> </section> <section id="H99A5FEAD354C4E24AD53C6D46C99D526"><enum>2.</enum><header>Air Force rated officer retention demonstration program</header> <subsection id="HFA61483A30994A2F841504E2971616A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and carry out within the Department of the Air Force a demonstration program to assess and improve retention on active duty in the Air Force of rated officers described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA3AF6D0DDDB44F039367148B418B9CF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rated officers described</header><text>Rated officers described in this subsection are rated officers serving on active duty in the Air Force, excluding rated officers with a reserve appointment in the Air National Guard or Air Force Reserve—</text> <paragraph id="HEC78CBC711A24E0D90B1C3B42F6EC270"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whose continued service on active duty would be in the best interest of the Department of the Air Force, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H537EEC77C5B74B9BBBC8D2A527C8A989"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who have not more than three years and not less than one year remaining on an active duty service obligation under section 653 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCB905D4538DC4A50B542C1A812EE2D62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Written agreement</header> <paragraph id="HB89A1B4D01F64AA9A550D70AC295F854"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the demonstration program required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall offer retention incentives under subsection (d) to a rated officer described in subsection (b) who executes a written agreement to remain on active duty in a regular component of the Air Force for not less than four years after the completion of the active duty service obligation of the officer under section 653 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB48C11C76A6B486AB617AEF76F4C4331"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Secretary of the Air Force determines that an assignment previously guaranteed under subsection (d)(1) to a rated officer described in subsection (b) cannot be fulfilled, the agreement of the officer under paragraph (1) to remain on active duty shall expire not later than one year after that determination.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27CA101B6603468BAEDCDF00300207A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Retention incentives</header> <paragraph id="H926D04B3B73C4570B957AAB6311A6F74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guarantee of future assignment location</header><text>Under the demonstration program required under subsection (a), the Secretary may offer to a rated officer described in subsection (b) a guarantee of future assignment locations based on the preference of the officer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H69B449615B794487AE4B32CF2D9A4BC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aviation bonus</header><text>Under the demonstration program required under subsection (a), notwithstanding section 334(c) of title 37, United States Code, the Secretary may pay to a rated officer described in subsection (b) an aviation bonus not to exceed an average annual amount of $50,000 (subject to paragraph (3)(B)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9677A6CD256A4002AC53DC54D90B5C7B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Combination of incentives</header><text>The Secretary may offer to a rated officer described in subsection (b) a combination of incentives under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6DD8B0402D134539BED85F61FEBF2269"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Variations; limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may vary or limit the total number of available contracts and the combination of incentives within such contracts to target certain Air Force specialty codes, ensure required assignments locations are filled, and readiness is not negatively affected. The Secretary shall determine the criteria for such variations or limitations and include such criteria in the annual briefing under subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF1C080C10ED4914AD111DE4F735DC8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2023, and annually thereafter until the termination of the demonstration program required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing describing the use of such demonstration program and its effects on the retention on active duty in the Air Force of rated officers described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFBAB3107ECBC459AAE73202866E375EE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDEC25124BFE242579EE55726A60312FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rated officer</header><text>The term <term>rated officer</term> means an officer specified in section 9253 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59269267A50C41588D0C984E07AEB7B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA6FBED2192614BE891EF26BC65716E5C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall terminate on December 31, 2028.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

