<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDA04EB4B940437281E663D6CB55FCE4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6777 IH: Supplying Ukraine with Provisions to Protect against Ongoing Russian Threats Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6777</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish the policy of the United States with respect to supporting an insurgency in Ukraine in the event of an invasion of Ukraine by Russia, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3F630FCD854D42DDBD419BC66DB11BD5" style="OLC">
<section id="HC3157C87FBB94C02ACCD65CEEAFE3C04" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supplying Ukraine with Provisions to Protect against Ongoing Russian Threats Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUPPORT Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H08A7E4576081414F846499A78758FFCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ukraine anti-Russian insurgency</header> <subsection id="H80AEBCB21FA447B792D80F03A520A2A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H68FEFC57A3FD4A52A587F50469948954"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is in the national security interests of the United States to support the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, and to continue and deepen the security partnership between the United States and Ukraine;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4427D37414254EEEAFA151D698A93D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aggression and malign influence by Russia and its proxies in Ukraine are a threat to the sovereignty and democratic government of Ukraine;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C7E8E9165444F338B2895B962945C22"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordination by the United States with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, and members of the international community can help strengthen the opposition to the efforts of Russia to further encroach on the territorial sovereignty and right to self-determination of Ukraine;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2CB6D6526CD44C8A5CCFD36A0064939"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress supports efforts to resolve the crisis diplomatically, without compromising on the principles on which the NATO alliance and European security rest; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22E5CF3CEED544089E8DCD45095ED4D7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress believes that the principle that nations may not change borders by force is central to the post-World War II international order.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6B2A140A007C4D67BD382207987A3967"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that, in the event of an invasion of Ukraine by Russia, the United States will take necessary and appropriate steps to support Ukrainian efforts to reassert control of its territory, expel an invading foreign force, and defend its sovereignty. These steps include supporting a Ukrainian insurgency with lethal and nonlethal assistance, and intelligence sharing, with the aim of imposing grave costs on Russia for actions threatening international peace and security. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA1325A181D946898AC097F1EB99F888"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
<paragraph id="HB7BA0F09A5F64E70A0E2507A5B8593F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict, in coordination with any other official the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a plan for providing support described in subsection (b) to a Ukrainian insurgency, including with respect to funding, weapons, partner contributions, intelligence sharing, and type of systems to be deployed, and means of insertion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H329F3AAA67C74AC6AE7F689967813F51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) may be submitted in classified form, but if so submitted shall include an unclassified executive summary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H562B3BBBCB454E239EE6838A26FA64FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Intelligence community assessment regarding Russian gray zone assets</header>
<paragraph id="H90A3204095F5445B85310F77012DCDCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intelligence community assessment</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence, acting through the National Intelligence Council, shall produce an intelligence community assessment that contains—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F4238A53B9C4C2FBD385028788C95E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the gray zone assets of Russia;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB20E6735CEC480097F17D6D33F1283F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of any opportunities to hold such gray zone assets at risk, as a method of influencing the behavior of Russia; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76010DC9C9D341EEA822CDC7412F8DA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the risks and potential benefits, with respect to the interests of the United States, that may result from the seizure of such gray zone assets to hold the assets at risk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A3769487E7D4A5180F193A48DFFD2FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In identifying opportunities to hold a gray zone asset of Russia at risk under paragraph (1)(B), the National Intelligence Council shall consider the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0A3E91C76D624480B73DDFEB9D5C44BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The effect on civilians of holding the gray zone asset at risk.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEA69D49AF5444A3CBDC24AB09EFF0584"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the gray zone asset is substantially State-owned or substantially controlled by Russia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50E0A8C805F94E0BBBC3FADD2FA84B3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The likelihood that holding the gray zone asset at risk will influence the behavior of Russia.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA7405D8A60674A90B7AA9DC3B78E6CF2" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The likelihood that holding the gray asset at risk, or degrading the asset, will affect any attempt of Russia to use force to change existing borders or undermine the political independence or territorial integrity of any State, including Ukraine.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC419169830E44D6838BF5C91CFEF82D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other factors as the National Intelligence Council may determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F383FE1F8844CC0B1F8D88619EB10A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appendix</header><text>The intelligence community assessment under paragraph (1) shall include an appendix that contains a list of the categories of gray zone assets of Russia, with specific examples of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC55FCEADBD9947F193C018E1CA78A01C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gray zone assets in each category; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE461E356DA0E4876822C7245433C6731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each such gray zone asset listed, the ways in which Russia uses the asset to advance its gray zone activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAFE9DDE563E4DC6B516ACDACDBFD684"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, consistent with the protection of sources and methods, shall submit to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate the intelligence community assessment under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D98CACECD2F4DD3B902B500936E74E3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intelligence community assessment under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD41ECFF7843F4750B38E6CC62BCFC75A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H7370EBCDE92D4AFFB2C1F29D30CD44E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H4453CC42454642BF9ED3D6A173A04EDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H81483E20EE164B48B7BB656DD163C39B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H149B18FBD8034B418772AD9F84F08800"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gray zone activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gray zone activity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 708(b) of H.R. 5412 of the 117th Congress, as reported by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives on October 28, 2021.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DA96E93EC064EF4BF276327913822F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gray zone asset</header><text>The term <term>gray zone asset</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAC625147E2B454588FFCC7F1A91AAA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an entity or proxy that is controlled, in whole or in part, by a foreign adversary of the United States and is used by such foreign adversary in connection with a gray zone activity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA62EF320284A42A0ADB829003C7FB0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a State-owned enterprise of a foreign adversary that is so used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H520D7F35B8E64EA0AD5D8C4948DD1567"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


