<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16A62A37DBA1438E8602A655D2574D2F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7876 IH: Connecting Rural Telehealth to the Future Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7876</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000377">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to protect access to telehealth services under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4CB3ABF9C2D2417DAC26A94F7B6062A0" style="OLC"><section id="H962AFDC624374D48860D0479F877AA43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Connecting Rural Telehealth to the Future Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAB66E2F4588A4827903658310CF9F9D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removing geographic requirements and expanding originating sites for telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8914571D380D47E6A1285E8BA63580D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C)(iii), by striking <quote>during the 151-day period beginning on the first day after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>before January 1, 2025</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H647CC44CC58B43F6908442E12DDC1D45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(iii), by striking <quote>during the 151-day period beginning on the first day after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>before January 1, 2025</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB34D020F7C0C48FF897EF0D80F4BC48C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expanding practitioners eligible to furnish telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended in paragraph (4)(E), by striking <quote>151-day</quote> and inserting <quote>and ending on December 31, 2024</quote> after <quote>described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></section><section id="HF565257B08B940F881122941F2F401D7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extending telehealth services for federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)(8)</external-xref>) is amended in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>151-day</quote> and inserting <quote>and ending on December 31, 2024</quote> after <quote>described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E6B0F551E5D44FFB17E7DAF8CF82D35"><enum>5.</enum><header>Delaying the in-person requirements under medicare for mental health services furnished through telehealth and telecommunications technology</header><subsection id="HDAD1FA27793B4974B5F8BFBBCEFFFF21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(m)(7)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)(7)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>the day that is the 152nd day after the end of the emergency period</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 2025</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A4B84F100634A55ACC8BDD3B5CB6B54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>Section 1834(y) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(y)</external-xref>) is amended in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the day that is the 152nd day after the end of the emergency period</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 2025</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF92D11188A1741B6870A5BA0D8F9F5C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1834(o)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(o)(4)</external-xref>) is amended in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>the day that is the 152nd day after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 2025</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEAEFAEAE77D04B82B9E3EDCAFE3DB188"><enum>6.</enum><header>Allowing for the furnishing of audio-only telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H29DDFF4C77CE4FB292003C381938FEFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (8)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H614923D87A944D20BD83D0C45FAAC839"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (9); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD3148B8440947538B8F384AE0654EFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HDD9C980CF8274D51BB7F6DF301A0DAEB" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HD522F927B14649139F06727BCFC5D1AF"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Telecommunications system</header><clause id="H1A9B7BB6691B4EACB4D52BA2C2B98DB9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) and section 410.78(a)(3) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), subject to clause (v), the term <quote>telecommunications system</quote> includes, in the case of the furnishing of a specified telehealth service (as defined in clause (ii)) a communications system that uses audio-only technology.</text></clause><clause id="H5907AAD8315F40828A7B4D6C740F5ACF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specified telehealth service</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>specified telehealth service</quote> means a telehealth service described in clause (iii) that is furnished by a qualified provider (as defined in clause (iv)).</text></clause><clause id="H9BE7DC1049F34593BCD50C6167088862"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Telehealth service described</header><text>A telehealth service as defined in subparagraph (F)(i).</text></clause><clause id="H15DA17B2E66D4C8FA8B8F0ABAE2927DD"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualified provider defined</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii), the term <quote>qualified provider</quote> means, with respect to a specified telehealth service that is furnished to an eligible telehealth individual—</text><subclause id="H1018E1B78D7C41E1AE30B50920531EC0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a physician or practitioner who has an established patient relationship with such individual as defined by the State in which the individual is located; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H36E78CCEA3D54CE68EF447DAE8CCAF3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1)), a rural health clinic (as defined in section 1861(aa)(2)), a federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa)(4)), a hospital (as defined in section 1861(e)), a hospital-based or critical access hospital-based renal dialysis center (including satellites), a skilled nursing facility (as defined in section 1819(a)), a community mental health center (as defined in section 1861(ff)(3)(B)), or a rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2)).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H690B46411C994086ADF98A287FB82BFD"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the Secretary may determine whether it is clinically appropriate to furnish a specified telehealth service via a communications system that uses audio-only technology and whether an in-person initial visit (in addition to any requirement with respect to the furnishing of an item or service in person pursuant to clause (iv)(I)) is required prior to the furnishing of such service using such technology.</text></clause><clause id="H9AA93FF06B2E449DB1CFBCD4306EF696"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Clarification regarding payment</header><text>The amount of payment for a specified telehealth service that is furnished using audio-only technology shall be equal to the amount that would have been paid for such service under this subsection had such service been furnished via any other telecommunications system authorized under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HF8C270BFDAFD443982DED418B3ED26FA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Use of telehealth to conduct face-to-face encounter prior to recertification of eligibility for hospice care during emergency period</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1814(a)(7)(D)(i)(II) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(a)(7)(D)(i)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>151-day</quote> and inserting <quote>and ending on December 31, 2024</quote> after <quote>described in section 1135(g)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></section><section id="HC71AF5DA5918442AA3CBB000B3570931"><enum>8.</enum><header>Extension of exemption for telehealth services</header><subsection id="H3565B37D519741279C67AF8A0CD1BC6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (E) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>2023</quote>and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FE5856D271041E99F181A6878F6030F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain coverage disregarded</header><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD84BB10BFB3949849160C43CAC40BAF0"><enum>9.</enum><header>Federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended in paragraph (8), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE6370C674F974F4783B0143E2DB38A16" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HDB9ADA89BF9F45648C0E057BCCF1DF28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><clause id="HA0138B5AEDF0405A9C224C8563E3A053"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A telehealth service furnished by a federally qualified health center or a rural health clinic to an individual pursuant to this paragraph on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph shall be deemed to be so furnished to such individual as an outpatient of such clinic or facility (as applicable) for purposes of paragraph (1) or (3), respectively, of section 1861(aa) and payable as a federally qualified health center service or rural health clinic service (as applicable) under the prospective payment system established under section 1834(o) or under section 1833(a)(3), respectively.</text></clause><clause id="H12D1AA9FE7C14095AFA2A914A7446CE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of costs for fqhc pps calculations and rhc air calculations</header><text>Costs associated with the delivery of telehealth services by a federally qualified health center or rural health clinic serving as a distant site pursuant to this paragraph shall be considered allowable costs for purposes of the prospective payment system established under section 1834(o) and any payment methodologies developed under section 1833(a)(3), as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H54EED797C4C844838F6EDB3DF036A57D"><enum>10.</enum><header>Telehealth flexibilities for critical access hospitals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB26CCCFD2F5F4DC0873AC85DC1142866"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA04AE7130889443AA8A58F9838367799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD4595D2B43A4D5786E362EBBDDB276C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H8ACC683395E746DDB577A49B9661825A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2954D7B181474583C1EBEEADD10006"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)(i), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97FF519A28E0438EA32DF31F36D4D9D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H69708286A8EA494DA18304C9CE402772" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HDCC0C0DCBA3F44318A2EBBE0585B2D7B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Telehealth flexibilities for critical access hospitals</header><subparagraph id="H75369F0FB15041AC9C0C96A362E4466F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph—</text><clause id="H258976A0D0AF47B5B8C2FF8F7F7EA182"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall pay for telehealth services that are furnished between the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) and January 1, 2025, via a telecommunications system by a critical access hospital, including any practitioner authorized to provide such services within the facility, that is a qualified provider (as defined in subparagraph (B)) to an eligible telehealth individual enrolled under this part notwithstanding that the critical access hospital providing the telehealth service is not at the same location as the beneficiary, if such services complement a plan of care that includes in-person care at some point, as may be appropriate;</text></clause><clause id="H16E6E00EC2DC4A77BAF62B0D08BDA172"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of payment to a critical access hospital that serves as a distant site for such a telehealth service shall be determined under subparagraph (C); and</text></clause><clause id="HAF84E198E6AD4BAB830363FE921105C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for purposes of this subsection—</text><subclause id="HDE7F782B829A4C9DB4E6E2497F2D2A3A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the term <quote>distant site</quote> includes a critical access hospital that furnishes a telehealth service to an eligible telehealth individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4A873CC2FD444DEC8AE6EEDF84F377C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the term <quote>telehealth services</quote> includes behavioral health services and any other outpatient critical access hospital service that is furnished using telehealth to the extent that payment codes corresponding to services identified by the Secretary under clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (4)(F) are listed on the corresponding claim for such critical access hospital service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAE3A9500A094F8680899AD45BBA69FE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition of qualified provider</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified provider</quote> means, with respect to a telehealth service described in subparagraph (A)(i) that is furnished to an eligible telehealth individual, a critical access hospital that has an established patient relationship with such individual as defined by the State in which the individual is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H192805473B9C40248DD8CF9BD318DCC5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>The amount of payment to a critical access hospital that serves as a distant site that furnishes a telehealth service to an eligible telehealth individual under this paragraph shall be equal to 101 percent of the reasonable costs of the hospital in providing such services, unless the hospital makes an election under paragraph (2) of section 1834(g) to be paid for such services based on the methodology described in such paragraph. Telehealth services furnished by a critical access hospital shall be counted for purposes of determining the provider productivity rate of the critical access hospital for purposes of payment under such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9CC3F554AFD4DB6A22B320B209A7178"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph through program instruction, interim final rule, or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HDF44660B6A9748E89644F950049390B7"><enum>11.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

