<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9216359575F4A68A9883B2D1E2CFFAE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7138 IH: Protecting Against Compromised Internet of Things Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7138</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish procedures to include certain foreign persons that pose a threat to the security of supply chains of Internet of Things devices on the Department of Commerce’s Entity List, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09E10A5A5D16448091AFBBB07B99BBC7" style="OLC"><section id="H1D1CD98FBB76432C84C0EA381A841B1E" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Against Compromised Internet of Things Technology Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H811EE3C929854891B170C557243E0994"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recommendations to include covered foreign persons on the Entity List</header><subsection id="H22DCB8B3EDC44654AADFB8E306FD8EB1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Bureau of Industry and Security, shall submit to the End-User Review Committee—</text><paragraph id="HE27E23A0D84F462780AFCFCCAB583DA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of covered foreign persons, if any, that the Secretary determines pose a threat to the security of supply chains of Internet of Things devices; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE575CF187B1B4FD2A526520DA9982305"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recommendation of whether or not to include each such covered foreign person on the Entity List or make other modifications to the Entity List as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F8F344F8E244D3CA057F13ED1F61DFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates of list</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the End-User Review Committee an updated list and corresponding recommendations under paragraph (1)—</text><paragraph id="H0D2B693F7099483E90FF3815ACCEC016"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H001E6A8E232C46B183241CA50EDA857A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as new information becomes available.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0ED49864C961419C980778E90E3CE4FC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consideration and vote to include covered foreign persons on the Entity List</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receiving a list of covered foreign persons and corresponding recommendations required by section 2, the End-User Review Committee shall convene a meeting—</text><paragraph id="HEF1CF5E8568A4122B311873074DAE7F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to consider such list of covered foreign persons and corresponding recommendations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE26E9F108ED44BEB827AA970F41A9900"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hold a vote with respect to including each such covered foreign person on the Entity List or make other modifications to the Entity List as appropriate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H316C7AD3C1884ECC81840AF35C4CDEAA" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal financial assistance prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the event that any company is on the list described under section 3—</text><paragraph id="HB739183EB10A498593F86DB7842EF354"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that company may not receive any Federal financial assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H753AAB1494B04F0CA62823D559F3463B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Government may not enter into any contract with such company for any Internet of Things device.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF887C5582BEA461FB0F6A1D43DA944D1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB944C983F32C4D65A1BFCE5D2FFA3A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered foreign person</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HCB9188C182194EF6934CB4C49451568D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a foreign person that produces an Internet of Things device; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H168DC2C53FEE4E808776C990921C9B47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a parent company, subsidiary, or relevant senior officer or other official of such foreign person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6CD288112C94921B8BFB228E192F390"><enum>(2)</enum><header>End-User Review Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>End-User Review Committee</quote> means the End-User Review Committee described in Supplement No. 9 to part 748 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD80CD916F7B1424ABC2BD7BE159B48D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Entity List</quote> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H649C0E77E4234514AB6EBE936E05D42B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Export Administration Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Export Administration Regulations</quote> means subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD772504FEBC04D7F841F92AF5F2F4B36"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal financial assistance</quote> means any form of loan, grant, guarantee, insurance, payment, rebate, subsidy, or any other form of direct or indirect Federal assistance (including general or special revenue sharing or formula grants made to States) approved by any Federal officer or agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8661B51FB8044D52975747EDF3A31E48"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means a person that is not a United States person. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3A33AF9B6B42199742133324C304AB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Internet of Things device</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Internet of Things device</quote> means a device described in section 2(4) of the Internet of Things Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020 (15 U.S.C. 278g–3a note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H522976155C1D42D293EE069D90387C8F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4C54AD7A7FCD4534BEC86CC1DF845527"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7C3A389FCCC44FAB5669E568E6BF75E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

