<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF4D9E78A9CB44469C3FB2BE474136F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8499 IH: Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission from considering, in taking any action, the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, the social cost of nitrous oxide, or the social cost of any other greenhouse gas, unless compliant with Office of Management and Budget guidance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HED7DEEA1BA0B4078B0ACE0D0899D6116" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H14982BC8477C412895D76C0F7D8AC2EC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1E2AD16AAB1A47C8942FC7A779C0F053"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H8DE9477E05EF4FC8854BE44E055984FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a tool to justify Federal actions by the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Chair of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to address greenhouse gas emissions, including the regulation or prohibition of the exploration, mining, production, and use of coal and other fossil fuels as energy sources, the social cost of greenhouse gases, specifically the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide, represents the hypothetical cost of 1 incremental ton of carbon dioxide, methane, or nitrous oxide emissions in a given year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25FA869BC5DD4D5690206BA0E1AD4014"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003—</text><subparagraph id="H5321423DAF6341B3809015B6F2335744"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guides Federal agencies on the development of regulatory impact analysis required under Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review) and other authorities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C470FFCF7534E69A261C62EBC06240E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructs Federal agencies to include discount rates of 3 and 7 percent and evaluate the costs and benefits of the regulatory action that accrue to citizens and residents of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65524FA7E76344629EAE3A2CCCB26C40"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">first developed in 2009 by an interagency working group that included the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Transportation, and the Council on Environmental Quality, the estimates for the social cost of carbon and the subsequently developed social cost of methane and social cost of nitrous oxide fail to comply with the 3- and 7-percent discount rates prescribed by the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95ABC6154C2A4798B36CD306042AA058"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while the document of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Circular A–4</quote> and dated September 17, 2003, specifies that, in carrying out an evaluation of the global effects of a rule, regulation, or action, the evaluation shall be reported separately from domestic costs and benefits of that rule, regulation, or action, the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide instead calculates the global benefits in lieu of, not in addition to, the domestic costs of a rule, regulation, or action;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A9AA7A7B2CE4D95BBCD0588B431A9AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the use of the estimates of the social cost of greenhouse gases, including the estimates for the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide, in the rulemakings and other actions of the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Transportation, and the Council on Environmental Quality was without—</text><subparagraph id="H8792DFABAD344830B2A486FABEFA8652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an adequate opportunity for public notice and comment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94198013C2174E7F8D34A8631C0FD9F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rigorous scientific peer review;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF70C9BC188BC4066B723F0DF406FC035"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by Executive order, the interagency working group described in paragraph (3) was disbanded in March 2017, and the related estimates were withdrawn;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5009441828C0486E8A7C9948E6E34A13" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency developed new estimates in line with the document described in paragraph (4) in EPA–452/R–18–006, dated August 2018, and entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis for the Proposed Emissions Guidelines for Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Existing Electric Utility Generating Units; Revisions to Emission Guideline Implementing Regulations; Revisions to New Source Review Program</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A05352E46C348EE8AD4D603DCE0EF55"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Executive Order 13990 (86 Fed. Reg. 7037; relating to protecting public health and the environment and restoring science to tackle the climate crisis), issued on January 20, 2021—</text><subparagraph id="H1AD9B766902742CCB425AAC6DF0BCF62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reconvened the interagency working group described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DC67EC0FA154C2B951E827FE8B73DEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directed the head of each Federal agency to include an interim figure for the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide in any consideration of the effect of greenhouse gas emissions in any regulations and other relevant agency actions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC0106AF9C8A4048AFFE9E14EB5621B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>directed the reconvened interagency working group to review and update the methodology and estimates for the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9045E028BDD242489A9DCA0FD7D2FA03"><enum>(9)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H969308883DCE41CE9B3D98A2E95896A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of the interim social cost of greenhouse gas figures was challenged in court and a preliminary injunction was granted by the United States District Court for the Western District of Louisiana on February 11, 2022; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC05F17BA826A4139A3CCBBF3E97F618A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals stayed the preliminary injunction on March 16, 2022; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA785A532BE1F42138527D9C8CA1AF758"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency relied on the interagency working group interim estimate of the social cost of methane, without appropriate peer review or opportunity for public notice and comment, in attempting to justify the costs and benefits of the proposed rule entitled <quote>Standards of Performance for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources and Emissions Guidelines for Existing Sources: Oil and Natural Gas Sector Climate Review</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 63110 (November 15, 2021));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H539E95C7D24940F3AC803EC79CFFD842"><enum>(11)</enum><text>prior to the 2017 disbandment of the interagency working group described in paragraph (3), the Department of the Interior used the social cost of methane estimate to justify the costs and benefits of the final rule entitled <quote>Waste Prevention, Production Subject to Royalties, and Resource Conservation</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 83008 (November 18, 2016));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A2676E6B4424E27A5195197695EA4C9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>court filings note that various agencies have 38 pending regulatory actions that rely on the interim social cost of greenhouse gases figures; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CCDB3F79434D929377ED39BA40A06D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>continued use of the social cost of greenhouse gases, including the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide by the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Transportation, the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission ignores sound science.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFB4EA98F15AE473E974CBE46E49DEB9A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H948BC3F9B69741A8B6F4744CFA20D25C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94243D2B958E435A962CF982C72090C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social cost of carbon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social cost of carbon</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H7B0E66BE97FB4E1E8D69018DDFC3A408"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of carbon described in—</text><clause id="HF863618A5842476BAD7819FFC5107A2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in February 2010; </text></clause><clause id="HA39C3961A2BE4C74A07125F1EA203BD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in February 2021;</text></clause><clause id="H674CB3A19CFE4978805928FDD3E0A97E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in May 2013 and revised in November 2013 and July 2015, and published and revised by the Interagency Working Group on the Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016; or</text></clause><clause id="HD6FEA3A2F4044CE396A3DAC5A6454767"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DFA14FD95E14656B51E8B9362193860"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in carbon dioxide emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D6081B17054FCBA211F69E84ADC296"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Social cost of greenhouse gas</header><text>The term <term>social cost of greenhouse gas</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF7A949C8A19B49058A3EE10BA5249BF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of any greenhouse gas that is described in any successor document to—</text><clause id="H547DDD7C7C754ED995A085AAE627E8D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in February 2010;</text></clause><clause id="H7C462CB0772144FFB372CEEEAFC4A386"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in May 2013 and revised in November 2013 and July 2015, and published and revised by the Interagency Working Group on the Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="H2D9949266BF1467590396B37289D8737"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016; </text></clause><clause id="H19F511345BAD498885400C4DF7BBEC32"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in February 2021; or</text></clause><clause id="H684850BD5205465A9091E9BBE94501A9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CF1D150EAD546F6BFB095D37635B9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in greenhouse gas emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3155EF6D548F46BA9B581763D225FCEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social cost of methane</header><text>The term <term>social cost of methane</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6B128AA0C07F44029D8E18CCBA4714CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of methane described in—</text><clause commented="no" id="HDB4DA549248E4647996E5C9DF1091CE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed rule entitled <quote>Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New and Modified Sources</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 56593 (September 18, 2015));</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1B288FF241204A7987AE3230729D860B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the final rule entitled <quote>Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 35824 (June 3, 2016));</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19F355F02AF14615A6445BF709208FF1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulatory impact analysis entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis of the Final Oil and Natural Gas Sector: Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources</quote>, prepared by the Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Air and Radiation, in May 2016 and identified by docket ID number EPA–HQ–OAR–2010–0505–7630; </text></clause><clause id="HDCAEA15A4E9249E68C20D88731D803B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="H5BCE1C3C18E94517A3F1C52525BC5823"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in February 2021; or</text></clause><clause id="H68C248C607394A3D8034A69A408D237E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51FC54685507420095154945DD29032D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in methane emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23FB2D10C1D945D1971DC008147BA3B9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Social cost of nitrous oxide</header><text>The term <term>social cost of nitrous oxide</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1E3DEF993E2843A396F8B41CD4A70501"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of nitrous oxide described in—</text><clause id="H83B4B7F9BC5F432882AE7AB2E1062574"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="HE6E1D7C2C4A343F29C0A0140636D83BA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, in February 2021; or </text></clause><clause id="HCC61C66CB69A42BB940918D3A573208E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D6ACC728E244822900722041C620CFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in nitrous oxide emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3897298EB4784259A80F22D5B83A6C4F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on considering the social cost of greenhouse gas, including the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, under any authority, the Administrator, under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary of the Interior, under any authority, the Secretary of Transportation, under any authority, the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, under the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Chair of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission may not consider the social cost of carbon, social cost of methane, social cost of nitrous oxide, or social cost of greenhouse gas— </text><paragraph id="H35D1624ECD824D0BAB1803B16345B610"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as part of any cost-benefit analysis required under—</text><subparagraph id="HD6E1A929DC13423FB22C0955627727FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H776AA13CC39848938E8CAF3C0223C44F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0197166949BB4C4DB37442DDEDFBB3B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13563 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to improving regulation and regulatory review);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D08DB83C9D4481C8211EEF635322D3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any rulemaking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8F4742FE5364DA3916B26D38CEBB801"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the issuance of any guidance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H380C0FB88DC340EA8CAB563D44609FB5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in taking any other agency action; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE28D119B7454F838BCFFAF142958461"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a justification for any rulemaking, guidance document, or agency action.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9E11A1FFD25A4B3CB79F447A7C68E1F0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report of the Administrator</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination and consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Chair of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall submit to the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report describing the number of proposed and final rulemakings, guidance documents, and agency actions that, since January 2009, have used the social cost of carbon, the social cost of greenhouse gases, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide, including the use of the social cost of carbon, the social cost of greenhouse gases, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide as part of any cost-benefit analysis required under Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review) or other relevant authority.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

