<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" dms-id="HD393659BF3074165904476420029C8BD" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2250 : Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the management of information technology projects and investments of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7A15840C6013427B8379D7CDD44681C2" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H35744BCEACC544F58D2C2AF1CAEA17A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H00ECB190EE8448EFB2AFE9983C6C7EB4" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information technology projects and activities</header><subsection id="H52909559DAAB41C2B44C15C4F2D19C19" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/81">Chapter 81</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H389ACE95E62247A292273BD4F9BACEC3" changed="not-changed"><subchapter id="HF4AF8F87484F4E5F9EC5EA9EA8E746B9" changed="not-changed"><enum>VI</enum><header>Information technology projects and activities</header><section id="H2A2E6B30C38D497F83BC1D4BCB613FE7" changed="not-changed"><enum>8171.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="H23E2CC24AD1C4400838760973A371D35" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H61261CD637A24E00A0F7F717E940F42D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A6CF4658EC244538763091508C429A1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0960C79F7C34DF1B484E90673C19D45" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>information technology</term> has the meaning given that term in section 11101 of title 40.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC48435B5E3C40FBAFD6494D6FFB5E7C" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H212E84FC1C4A437AB3CF3908E2673810" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>information technology project</term> means a project or program of the Department (including a project or program of any element of the Department) for, or including, the acquisition or implementation of information technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA39D2911107443E783F358B3127F019B" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In cases where the Secretary transmits to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget information regarding information technology investments, which may consist of individual or multiple projects, the term <quote>information technology project</quote> refers to an individual project or program or a grouping of multiple projects or programs resulting in the acquisition or implementation of discrete information technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8BBC179C0C746309D77EB5147E879A6" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>life cycle costs</term> means all direct and indirect costs to acquire, implement, operate, and maintain information technology, including with respect to costs of any element of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCF8F0629AEA4040AF1493389B1E66E2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>major information technology project</term> means an information technology project if—</text><subparagraph id="H40FA93AA065B42EBB314B2DE58320FF3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the project is designated by the Secretary, the Chief Information Officer of the Department, or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget as a major information technology investment, as defined in section 11302 of title 40; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF524F71F07FC41EDA9C917CAF37E99EA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the dollar value of the project is estimated by the Secretary to exceed—</text><clause id="H07267280BF6A4F18AF9F3C61B9B5DFFC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000,000 (as adjusted for inflation pursuant to section 1908 of title 41) for the total life cycle costs of the project; or</text></clause><clause id="H3A03226FB3EC4C89B7F174A1CE535E9F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$200,000,000 (as adjusted for inflation pursuant to section 1908 of title 41) annually.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67DBE57E36C646C4947AA177F6B43F9B" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>business owner</term> means, with respect to an information technology project, the program manager, project manager, or other supervisory official of the Department responsible for the project.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDF5C2DA7F97046CC8E62C564C7BD5765" changed="not-changed"><enum>8172.</enum><header>Management of major information technology projects</header><subsection id="H83E7D66E34674C148C29642E4D5C46C2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cost, schedule, and performance information</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H510B227DD2C3441AB43A9FA55760A25F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Chief Information Officer of the Department, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing information on the cost, schedule, and performance of each major information technology project that begins after the date of the enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2022, as generated by the business owner of the project, prior to the commencement of such project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B92AAE0AD2C463FAEC1EFD80E9D8C7F" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under paragraph (1) for a project shall include, with respect to such project, the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD9624B42A78F49399EF959B490A7AF5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An estimate of acquisition costs, implementation costs, and life cycle costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B5A2E6DECAD4DAC920D66D914008FBE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An intended implementation schedule indicating significant milestones, initial operating capability, and full operating capability or completion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8584FCCC3824A2680137EB85C09BB8B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Key business, functional, and performance objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08C82D7978B4B589AC3BBB943873714" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Baseline</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAB78A0BEFDC043C39E149D1B20CC6193" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall use the information on the cost, schedule, and performance of a major information technology project included in the report under subsection (a) as the baseline against which changes or variances are measured during the life cycle of such project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1A64548EB324726B59EA2A633889755" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8586010FED9A4428AA9B1B82703FF3B3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annually update the baseline of a major information technology project pursuant to subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H714F0306F0334A1BA424DC21CD8DFEC2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include such updated baseline in the documents providing detailed information on the budget for the Department that the Secretary submits to Congress in conjunction with the President's budget submission pursuant to section 1105 of title 31.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF32415788A0495E8CB81A593D44E947" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Changes and variances</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE52D661470E8469897E4CC61AD6F50C2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary identifies a change or variance described in paragraph (2) in the cost, schedule, or performance of a major information technology project, the Secretary, acting through the Chief Information Officer, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of such change or variance, including a description and explanation for such change or variance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA82BE1714BB4278A8899E5CC0898A49" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A change or variance in the cost, schedule, or performance of a major information technology project described in this paragraph is—</text><subparagraph id="HFCD7E9CCBA454ADB8D2C2D5041CC3CC2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the acquisition, implementation, or life cycle cost of the project, or development increment therein, a change or variance that is 10 percent or greater compared to the baseline; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEDC382B26334C85805F0C1056646529" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the schedule for a development increment or for achieving a significant milestone, initial operating capability, or full operating capability, or for the final completion of the project, a change or variance that is 180 days or greater compared to the baseline; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD66E47BA24148C3BF6B65F2BB4D1512" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the performance, an instance where a key business, functional, or performance objective is not attained, or is not anticipated to be attained, in whole or in part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52ECFC13BF9843BDB14A4BE8367587B9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each major information technology project is managed by an interdisciplinary team consisting of the following:</text><paragraph id="HD0F7D215552A4572A728C5882D3B7449" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A project manager who—</text><subparagraph id="HBBD16A1BF6294A81BBDB4C1D632FBFAA" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE6C77029E76D487FA6C1EC296536D93A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is certified in project management at level three by—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H4A591AD12C9E41BCA81F701952741117" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" indent="up1" id="H59006348CC52440FBB5759EAC9A1662C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Acquisition Institute pursuant to section 1201 of title 41; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" indent="up1" id="HA40D915D082345849A65C2F64D7475BA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Defense pursuant to section 1701a of title 10; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB5BAA245A3A04B06A5C3B72F51767859" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holds an equivalent certification by a private sector project management certification organization, as determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1C3DE5B1D26406EA2E0EAB133830612" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an employee of the Office of Information and Technology of the Department or an employee of an element of the Department at which the project originates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A660FCE1EA42E2B485671AAF26E589" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A functional lead who is an employee of the element of the Department at which the project originates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81760CF6B0344E10A5D8951332BC3DA5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A technical lead who is an employee of the Office of Information and Technology of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3F153A76A8E4E778AA31332DDD4085E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A contracting officer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96A0AD32B37446A9A8C3EB002B385F88" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Sufficient other project management, functional, technical, and procurement personnel as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5DA58FB02D734FA887FC24BFB59214A9" changed="not-changed"><enum>8173.</enum><header>Information technology activities of the Financial Services Center</header><subsection id="H5C4E3E50C20742678409FA69FCA98766" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Consistent with sections 11302 and 11319 of title 40—</text><paragraph id="HA1270041E2784690A9D1DBCA14103AD0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Chief Information Officer of the Department shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5D146590F13D453FAA5D661D7EA86475" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exercise authority over the management, governance, and oversight processes relating to existing or proposed information technology of the Financial Services Center of the Department, or such successor office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1F6F4E3671D44AFB0304CCA45445A48" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supervise the information technology employees and contractors of the Financial Services Center; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE9C989B98648AAA9263C7403802C71" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the Financial Services Center of the Department, or the head of such successor office, may not enter into a contract or other agreement for information technology or information technology services unless the contract or other agreement has been reviewed and approved by the Chief Information Officer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB57FBB47C8A44799BA6FAC1A24ED7E8E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Chief Information Officer shall have oversight and operational authority over all information security practices of the Financial Services Center of the Department.</text></subsection></section><section id="H52F6DB429D1B4FE988996F12C7B46AEE" changed="not-changed"><enum>8174.</enum><header>Submission of annual reviews of information technology</header><subsection id="H140EA9257CE74B6D9C7CD348D6766DF3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Chief Information Officer of the Department, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees each annual review of the information technology portfolio of the Department conducted pursuant to section 11319(d)(3) of title 40.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB712AE217224AB4928FF836E2D17D8D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>First submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first annual review submitted under subsection (a) shall include a copy of each previous annual review conducted under section 11319(d)(3) of title 40.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD6268714950A46F6B67F61C8A385402A" changed="not-changed"><enum>8175.</enum><header>Information technology matters to be included in budget justification materials for the Department</header><subsection id="H604E18BD45CF481C8C90D254868BAA5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of information technology projects in effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that whenever the budget justification materials are submitted to Congress in support of the Department budget for a fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President for such fiscal year under section 1105(a) of title 31), such budget justification materials include a list of every information technology project currently in effect at the Department (including not only congressional projects and subprojects as determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget or the Secretary).</text></subsection><subsection id="HFBC6B978659A4919A0680291A79E6B63" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritized list of unfunded projects</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0E704C9352B64B69B4CE56BB03A80187" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the list included in the budget justification materials required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that the budget justification materials described in such subsection also include summary descriptions and a prioritized list, in rank order, of every information technology project of the Department, proposed or intended to be proposed for the following one, two, or three fiscal years, that is unfunded as of the time of the inclusion of the list under this paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E1CCC5A82D46B6AC681798749EF8D7" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In producing the list required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H267B0CDA76354B8AA39980A6A624CE39" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure such list represents a ranking of all proposed information technology projects that reflects the needs of all elements of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87518D0BD7984C5AB8C1D40791F9131C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produce one unified list for the entire Department demonstrating how the various proposed information technology projects of each of the elements of the Department rank in priority with the information technology projects of the other elements of the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B5388760A04B0191DBF52199B25F50" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the list—</text><clause id="HF838FF006EE948899CCF5ED37F657AD3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not disaggregate and rank information technology projects based on element of the Department; and</text></clause><clause id="H45299D7C6CAE4FB2942CE763AC5F3948" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does identify the element of the Department requesting the information technology project. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0383BE89FA2945F9A413F8E3BF8D38EC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H40CC50AB3D2C4BE8835CD531066676D8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In producing each list under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize and rank each information technology project based on an assessment of each of the following factors:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H3563AF08645B4B96BC8ADA0FCF702970" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Degree of collaboration between business owners and the Chief Information Officer with respect to joint functional-technical planning, requirements, and management.</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" indent="up1" id="HDBFA313057F34CC0988C0E2AEA729AEB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Operational or efficiency benefits to employees of the Department created or produced by the information technology project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H10143714039B438B90A0BE5FD2CBA99F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The life cycle cost of the information technology project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HC6D14DC79A5540E8A68164286EE9C15E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost savings or cost avoidance yielded by the information technology project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H664FAD72DF91457F96C297F4892879FA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Time to completion of the information technology project. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H51DE08D2AEBC46C6808F5D075E800C5C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The difficulty of the information technology project, the likelihood the information technology project will be completed, or the risks associated with undertaking the information technology project.</text></clause><clause id="HFC77EA89D9D74077BF9F8A731D602629" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tangible benefits to veterans created or produced by the information technology project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HC88C61292E204B26A2E7C4A46B881FD0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H602A8F4784C34BC5995B4B38A595151E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that each list produced under paragraph (1) includes, for each information technology project included in the list, a brief description of the findings of the Secretary with respect to each assessment carried out by the Secretary for each factor for the information technology project under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E37C22D126246AD92D8D02FD54C19DC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Projected funding needs</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6A48AABF1A324AA6A067D4A4DC4AC273" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the matters included under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall ensure that the budget justification materials described in subsection (a) also include a projection of the one-year, two-year, and three-year funding needs of the Department for information technology, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="H56F820F9D63C4D55A6CAF8F70FBB1506" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">portfolio; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H95A225B659064D69969DA2DFB9DC2FAB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the product line of the Department that requires the funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B8E03B223EE4F3D92671481C5DA683B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In addition to the projections under paragraph (1), with respect to each of the periods set forth in such paragraph, the Secretary shall include a description of the funding required for each technology business management category used by the Office of Information Technology of the Department (commonly referred to as <quote>cost pools</quote> and <quote>towers</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6692177AE4524967A187C9ABDC1304E7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H552C0F972C0340C899E0C1EC1CE0CCB0" changed="not-changed"><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry level="subchapter" idref="HF4AF8F87484F4E5F9EC5EA9EA8E746B9" changed="not-changed">SUBCHAPTER VI—Information technology projects and activities </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2A2E6B30C38D497F83BC1D4BCB613FE7" changed="not-changed">Sec. 8171. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HDF5C2DA7F97046CC8E62C564C7BD5765" changed="not-changed">Sec. 8172. Management of major information technology projects. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5DA58FB02D734FA887FC24BFB59214A9" changed="not-changed">Sec. 8173. Information technology activities of the Financial Services Center. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H52F6DB429D1B4FE988996F12C7B46AEE" changed="not-changed">Sec. 8174. Submission of annual reviews of information technology. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD6268714950A46F6B67F61C8A385402A" changed="not-changed">Sec. 8175. Information technology matters to be included in budget justification materials for the Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H33C497DA5D964F23AABD631FB9DD447F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application and report regarding management of major information technology projects</header><paragraph id="H33E80B973C36466BA4A06414D89B2EEB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Current and new major projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as specifically provided in subsection (a) of section 8172 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section, such section 8172 shall apply with respect to major information technology projects that begin before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6DCE9FD7430D42EBA54DB7EDEE5EC47B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on current projects</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD6E11A41A6E437BA64CEC708B1EC3ED" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on each major information technology project that the Secretary is carrying out as of the date of the report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC056BEFAC7C7485C9B779B917A3493BD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall contain, with respect to each project described in such subparagraph, information on the cost, schedule, and performance of the project as described in subsection (a) of section 8172 of such title, as so added.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE00A39EC007A494EBA049BB54444D272" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the terms <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> and <term>major information technology project</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8171 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7F685DF742D4556B563AF1072547AD4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information technology activities of the Financial Services Center</header><paragraph id="H4918A2CD0E344F2584A43D14BAAE8A95" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 8173 of such title, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94800DB53B434AA1BA6D96FD2E87CFFE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (a)(2) of such section shall apply with respect to contracts and agreements entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9A83718C03A548848CD4D7C5525A5A2B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date of requirement for projects in budget justification materials</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 8175 of such title, as added by subsection (a) of this section, shall take effect on the first<pagebreak></pagebreak> Monday in the second January beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20221115" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 17, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

