<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B20FF2DCAC542128BD877D35067E298" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8320 IH: U.S.-Albania Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on improving the diplomatic and defense relationship with Albania, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26E9A7E369DF427D90A5808CF1658F91" style="OLC"><section id="H8375528C90CB42C4982A2E35C48AA68D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S.-Albania Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H032821FA7F0D4F609C1192A98D85176C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on improved diplomatic relations and defense relationship with Albania</header><subsection id="H5DC0FE00F1E945A09AFDD0BC14CBD971"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H407A364AE760486AB71C0C9DE9F1864C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4489B1E971B446979B4A4E8519CB6FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H120A5CA50DC34B448929254A9928D452"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, jointly with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of the viability of military infrastructure in Durrës, Albania, and Vlorë, Albania, as locations for cooperative security activities, including NATO activities and exercises that advance NATO and shared security objectives and enhance interoperability. The report shall also include a description of—</text><paragraph id="HE2DFBB499D664694A517A717885A4FA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>opportunities for the United States to support training for Albania’s military forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53F1CA9910204B8CBA9B19440AD2F0EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the current status of such training activities with Albania, including the level of progress toward interoperability, absorption of assistance, ability to sustain equipment provided, and other relevant factors that enhance Albania’s ability to contribute to NATO objectives and maritime security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1306C4F1AF748CFA66EBD912C715001"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cost estimate for any potential U.S. investments and activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

