<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H716E6820F13D4ECA9085893227363E9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8945 IH: Restoring Academic Freedom on Campus Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8945</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220921">September 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit the use of political tests in the selection, hiring, or promotion of students or faculty at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF752D120C3C413A9C3840F0EF6B3098" style="OLC"><section id="H99C0F0AA2D8A4CAFAC235EDBB32DAA07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Academic Freedom on Campus Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA36E93F5B22E4506A6C39485C66181E6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header><subsection id="H6D6DCA101FE54AA5918C7616599C8D81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of political tests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0FE91129A7DA464C9576447A9EEED49B"><section id="H4A8AB371E87549A5973CFD5BB071E37A"><enum>124.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of political tests</header><subsection id="H49F2F017270E42359070CC29F73DD12C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on political tests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education that receives funds under this Act, including through participation in a program authorized under title IV, may not consider, require, or discriminate on the basis of a political test in the admission, appointment, or promotion of, or granting of tenure to, any covered individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDC34BDF3D454FBEA084E7B487E10E7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H121DD6E101E54EF2B2CC66C1306B9E52" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><subparagraph id="HA1A75D092C2143458520D97BEFC5490F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual that applies to, attends, or works at an institution of higher education claiming that the institution maintains a policy or practice that is a political test in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a) may bring an action in a Federal court of competent jurisdiction to—</text><clause id="H14BCA5B9AA5844B9AC343D408BB7AD85" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin a violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a); or</text></clause><clause id="H79C9996C29834285912E0EB2260EA408" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recover compensatory damages, reasonable court costs, or reasonable attorney fees.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17C94FD6D43540F5B63EC27F5BB67D23" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action brought under this paragraph, if the court finds a violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a), the court may—</text><clause id="H1403C1A9567C40C5A18A09D043E7AEE6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enjoin the violation; or</text></clause><clause id="H9D8C1F0F25C549BFB4009D92247C360C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>award a prevailing plaintiff—</text><subclause id="H530E2981FB254030B9B8E25F00C116E2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D4FF4B347EE41318C979752E7ABE90A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>reasonable court costs; or </text></subclause><subclause id="H444AB580A62C4D6D8A8B19ECA01BAE33" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>reasonable attorney fees.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E679F184BF0416398FD074CB0679844" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver of immunity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall not be immune under the Eleventh Amendment to the Constitution of the United States from an action under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C771653510F42A48E53A49685F12716" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action under this paragraph may not be brought later than 2 years after the date of the violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C2286BABF22452B83FC7D4A5FB00FCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court finds under paragraph (1) that an institution of higher education maintains a policy or practice that is a political test in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a), such institution shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF89298D6D27E451E8C342114F237B675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the date on which the court makes such finding, notify the Secretary of such finding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2CF0CBF3D2B4DC6A067746DCEE60851"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after the date on which the court makes such finding, submit to the Secretary a report that—</text><clause id="H4713292D130A4F5AAC08A6A420AFE370"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies that the policy or practice that is a political test in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a) is no longer in use; and</text></clause><clause id="H93705EEB72C645D3B7805BE7FE7F27FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides evidence to support such certification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H679BC360B78C4267B10CCA56ACC57E8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revocation of eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that does not submit the report required under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary shall revoke, beginning the academic year immediately following the conclusion of the academic year in which the institution is found by a court to be in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a), the eligibility of such institution to receive funds under this Act, including through participation in a program authorized under title IV.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20B76C18437140DD82FCFF44334A895C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restoration of eligibility</header><subparagraph id="H2A46A4B3B87C4F60A9FEBA2254DB503A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education that loses eligibility under paragraph (3) to receive funds under this Act may seek to restore such eligibility by submitting to the Secretary the report described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1848E21F80CF4480BD8A0747F48CD2A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after an institution submits a report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall review such report and make a determination with respect to whether such report contained sufficient evidence to demonstrate that such institution is no longer in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD87F51CBBF249A688122A4FEB5E7B7B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary makes a determination under subparagraph (B) that the institution is no longer in violation of the prohibition described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall restore, at the beginning of the academic year immediately following the conclusion of the academic year in which such determination is made, the eligibility of such institution to receive funds under this Act, including through participation in a program authorized under title IV.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H553D8939954A4555BCAB2EA27CD82DF3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HF9E15A5153704634B4BF2823C3F982A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit an institution of higher education from requiring an applicant, student, or employee to take an oath to uphold the Constitution of the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF81BA4D11040A1820F80B2FD687FC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit an institution of higher education which is controlled by a religious organization from requiring an applicant, student, or employee to—</text><subparagraph id="H834F98FEE4574484A31E3DB70C008CD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide a statement of faith; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34C2D230562E4C05A4EE946CE1C114CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adhere to a code of conduct consistent with the stated religious mission of such institution or the religious tenets of such organization; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB05CFEB67B774A95875E603F9E13C0A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>infringe upon or otherwise impact the protections of an institution of higher education under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>) and title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97D4AAF68E3A4A1EA3776AA49B717CAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Academic Freedom on Campus Act of 2022</short-title> and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H1822AD5816FA4F1D99C3591C9E0F51BE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a compilation of—</text><subparagraph id="H7456D9D0ED16469FB10822037A143283" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the notifications of violation received by the Secretary under subsection (b)(2)(A) in the year for which such report is being submitted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD74764CD65D54A5E84233CF2E686344F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reports submitted to the Secretary under subsection (b)(2)(B) for such year; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A5F8C2D92E4260BC144F4DA2BD8365"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any action taken by the Secretary revoke or restore eligibility under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b) for such year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B141580C72C4CF7BC1A30DD9EECACD9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H928E4A0F572049CDB1DAEC57985579B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means, with respect to an institution of higher education—</text><subparagraph id="H2BD39AD5C5194DAF9A82C7FDD9B533CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a prospective student who has submitted an application to attend such institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57DB8C93692A45CD8E8AAA388C88DF87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a student who attends such institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H051662D7D0AB46DA8305BB91CDF558AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a prospective employee who has submitted an application to work at such institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FB2021B5E9B414E996EE609CC439439"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an employee who works at such institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H707E0F20530443CE9F64F473D772F479"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a prospective faculty member who has submitted an application to work at such institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D9EA64DD2D44A9B87E53D13C1912558"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a faculty member who works at such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87470A6E9E554545A1B2A7193189ED02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Political test</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>political test</term> means a method of compelling or soliciting an applicant for enrollment or employment, student, or employee of an institution of higher education to identify commitment to or make a statement of personal belief in support of any ideology or movement that—</text><subparagraph id="H5E5F4A5416A24D40BCA37369B90B1350"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes a specific partisan or political set of beliefs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC2A5EB713D9426387387006E1843AE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes a particular viewpoint on an issue of public controversy; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36E0498FECE4479798864E7C3C7A6AB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promotes the disparate treatment of any individual or group of individuals on the basis of race or ethnicity, including—</text><clause id="H408EC264B5854D9089FFF40502A621FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any initiative or formulation of diversity, equity, and inclusion beyond upholding existing Federal law; or</text></clause><clause id="H72E3680BF8E648E5A3180222C2699285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any theory or practice that holds that systems or institutions upholding existing Federal law are racist, oppressive, or otherwise unjust.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8A19D3F6B3584B568BDFD6EF61BEA389"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEDD28F9F104446F88A375728E733B590" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HF16034356FF64622BD1A2E626CE76976"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will comply with the requirements of section 124.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

