<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF4E12E32B7564C22BD833EFF2DECD5AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8419 IH: To amend title 1, United States Code, to direct the Archivist of the United States to authenticate, count, and publish applications of States calling for a Convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution of the United States, to publish a certification when two-thirds of the States submit applications calling for such a Convention, and to notify Congress of the requirement under Article V of the Constitution to call such a Convention when such a certification is published, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8419</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220719">July 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001084">Ms. Herrell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 1, United States Code, to direct the Archivist of the United States to authenticate, count, and publish applications of States calling for a Convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution of the United States, to publish a certification when two-thirds of the States submit applications calling for such a Convention, and to notify Congress of the requirement under Article V of the Constitution to call such a Convention when such a certification is published, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H825091BD63BD4545B3CFB2DBD070458E" style="OLC"><section id="H93314BBFBBEB410B88A088866CED3DCD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Duties of Archivist relating to State applications for calling for Conventions of States for proposing Constitutional amendments</header><subsection id="H5BCA228801CB4296B6140394121B0A94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title 1, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 106b the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA4852F5EC4824C979027B675D09C0D2F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H956E15BEFB0047D38DC6D7569480B346"><enum>106c.</enum><header>Duties relating to State applications calling for Article V Conventions</header><subsection id="HF1075E95C9F040CE907FC593C258D28C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applications by States; rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist of the United States shall authenticate, count, and publish all applications of States calling for a Convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution of the United States pursuant to Article V of the Constitution, together with resolutions of States to rescind previous applications.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E09F8FAFFB44D3F81899DA0C7720949"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification and notification requirements</header><text>Upon the receipt by the Archivist of non-rescinded applications calling for a Convention for proposing amendments to the Constitution from two-thirds of the several States, as provided under Article V of the Constitution, the Archivist shall—</text><paragraph id="H7622D9FD6C374AF491EFED107C7B2D6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish a certification that two-thirds of the several States have called for the Convention, together with a list of the States submitting applications calling for the Convention; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09705EB5CBA549F8AD4C3A177D339671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify Congress that it is required under the Constitution to call the Convention and set its date and place forthwith, as set forth in Article V.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCC65B0828CE74755A39B33693517AB59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/1/2">chapter 2</external-xref> of title 1, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/1/106b">section 106b</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H090B54CCCB384029A63C6D0919796662" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">106c. Duties relating to State applications calling for Article V Conventions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

