<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H562C93E45B4649D296A03B8AB1E88349" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8470 IH: Investing in American Defense Technologies Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8470</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a public-private partnership technology investment pilot program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H72674D100E124C5CA948777B7733EAFA" style="OLC"><section id="H0C3BD7C8695C41DBAAE1790D06D86164" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in American Defense Technologies Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H24B35EB942A34C17B9A45EE00F05B678"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public-private partnership technology investment pilot program</header><subsection id="H76FBF9ADB2B54D30890015E389C038E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H7E73B8A0139841A59895F98CA0F3A061"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations for this purpose, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a pilot program, for no less than five years, to accelerate the development of advanced technology for national security by creating incentives for trusted private capital to invest in domestic small businesses or nontraditional businesses that are developing technology that the Secretary considers necessary to support the modernization of the Department of Defense and national security priorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92F6204919F1452DA308E8767AB75D1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the program required by paragraph (1) are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H0988499A555548CA98CBCBBB303294D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To promote the global superiority of the United States in advanced technologies of importance to national security, which are not adequately supported by private sector investment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0C42751A2A24405B868128ECDEDA85D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To accelerate the transition and deployment of advanced technologies into the Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6658BDCCA3E4C9594A45B6E7371606A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To support Department investment through a loan guarantee to accelerate acquisition, procurement, and the transition of advance technology described in paragraph (1), as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA68C2E0ECEF547699969EC45C77AA54B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public-Private partnership</header><paragraph id="H5E4219439F50441392856D3B522EB8BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into a public-private partnership with one or more persons using criteria that the Secretary shall establish for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB650790958A4ECAAB9C9EFBF5B01D42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The criteria established under paragraph (1) for entering into a public-private partnership with a person shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB0200C82B059429789CBAFADF65CAAB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The person shall be independent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95369E751901404697B842F8CC021127"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The person shall be free from foreign oversight, control, influence, or beneficial ownership. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H211A7D40F9A34C5DA0A719CE38F63EB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The person shall have commercial private capital fund experience with technology development in the defense and commercial sectors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38BDF5E05D764FBAB9CAAAA0A9F4CB78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The person shall be eligible for access to classified information (as defined in the procedures established pursuant to section 801(a) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3161">50 U.S.C. 3161(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H643FA334AEFF4B93AA010705FA3E07F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Operating agreement</header><text>The Secretary and a person with whom the Secretary enters a partnership under paragraph (1) shall enter into an operating agreement that sets forth the roles, responsibilities, authorities, reporting requirements, and governance framework for the partnership and its operations. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H658FA9617B734479BF7FDBD7D0B65A30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment and raising of capital</header><paragraph id="H7F36F4DA655649FAB79540E9003029F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investment</header><subparagraph id="H63BB90F15F7245829D7EB1799EB67593"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to a public-private partnership entered into under subsection (b), a person with whom the Secretary has entered the partnership shall invest equity in domestic small businesses or nontraditional businesses consistent with subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF61C82530E2547F19D001295077C4491"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>Investments under subparagraph (A) shall be selected based on their technical merit, economic considerations, and ability to support modernization goals of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE74211637AEF49A58FBF246755D0281C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of trusted capital sources</header><text>Pursuant to a public-private partnership entered into under subsection (b), a person described in paragraph (1)(A) shall, in order to support investment of equity under paragraph (1), raise private capital only from trusted capital sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB722BE920353441D8B4CE68E2438237E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sole authority</header><text>A person described in paragraph (1)(A) shall have sole authority to raise funds for, operate, manage, and invest capital raised under such subparagraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E865631D8F4EDFA86D4987CA1325C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loan guarantee</header><subparagraph id="H27E252399710447BA3622AFC2185F28A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a loan guarantee for up to 80 percent of the principal capital amount of the funds raised under paragraph (2), pursuant to the public-private partnership entered into under subsection (b), with investment of equity that qualifies under paragraph (1) and consistent with the purposes set forth under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D9EF3D3E5D9483C81247A0F62F4A0BC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subject to operating agreement</header><text>The loan guarantee under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the operating agreement entered into under subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B94C4EEF6534A998AB980516A2DB601"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obligations incurred by the Secretary under this paragraph shall be subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB23BB25F3246441DB7B2C38E2A4E67AA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefings</header><paragraph id="H13E997F16F5A454199BDD13DF8B6BE85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H963BE67954E54CD48BDEE27A5EE31922"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of outcomes and feasibility</header><text>Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall provide the congressional defense committees a briefing on the outcomes of the pilot program and the feasibility and advisability of making it permanent. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD70633C9DC77422AB5ADA4188680D862"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF0D48749B593418ABBB7CEEB5466161D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3486F4D3DA432BB17D922D2A0D9C2A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>domestic business</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>U.S. business</quote> in section 800.252 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFFFCDBF276E243E4B8088CDA3CC68E83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>domestic small businesses or nontraditional businesses</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBFD0DE813DCA45E4925C0CED59900DE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a small businesses that is a domestic business; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E4997C928C1409D95109B164F799859"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nontraditional business that is a domestic business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6551F6795B634483A17901B6169AC1F6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>free from foreign oversight, control, influence, or beneficial ownership</term>, with respect to a person, means a person who has not raised and managed capital from a person or entity that is not trusted and is otherwise free from foreign oversight, control, influence, or beneficial ownership. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51ACD92BC3049BD845DDF30EC55ED43" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>independent</term>, with respect to a person, means a person who lacks a conflict of interest accomplished by not having entity or manager affiliation or ownership with an existing fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H110279F0245E41F29CCA431D5B446DD2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>nontraditional business</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>nontraditional defense contractors</quote> in section 3014 of title 10, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2520802812F34857BA991CA98716390B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>small business</term> has the meaning given the term <term>small business concern</term> in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

