<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2572D198FB7F4529B6564C7DC5EC7E53" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9127 IH: Mandating Exclusive Review of Individual Treatments (MERIT) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221004">October 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to clarify the use of the national coverage determination process under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD55F5D5446B64350BDBE2CE84330C909" style="OLC"><section id="H08C4165C33114508B13EC3F9804C44F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mandating Exclusive Review of Individual Treatments (MERIT) Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H09BEFBAD4F8F4581956C17E835F64BC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification on Medicare national coverage determination process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1862(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of paragraph (1)(E), in the case of research conducted pursuant to section 1142, the determination of whether a drug or biological is reasonable and necessary to carry out the purposes of section 1142 shall be made with respect to each drug or biological involved and not with respect to a class of drugs or biologicals.</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

