<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H20A48C0A930041A6A88A8BC2D2D950AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 7364 IH: Stop Flood Insurance Rate Hikes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7364</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220401">April 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permit policyholders under the National Flood Insurance Program to elect to have previous premium rates remain in effect until the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency satisfies certain conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H243C7A6F93B646AFA3C46A028CD42F26" style="OLC"><section id="H750B2BAEF5264FDD80EFFA5F074B3E5B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Flood Insurance Rate Hikes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2CB1559A03F74E878BE5D541B0AC2D9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chargeable premium rates</header><subsection id="H0B2306583FB74E56BD8532C63FE7AA31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="HFE624F596F7F4B74AC4AD613F39453CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2956407A26C408FA6E2928532C7D792"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>National Flood Insurance Program</term> means the program established under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF80CBB8CA1F54D75AD9AE5847AA72647"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Option for policyholders</header><paragraph id="HFFDBFB5C00324C5EA0ACA994CD8ECF2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1308 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015</external-xref>), a policyholder under the National Flood Insurance Program may elect to have the chargeable premium rate for the applicable property of the policyholder, as in effect on April 1, 2020, apply and remain in effect during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the Administrator completes all of the actions described in subsection (c), without regard to the chargeable premium rate that is in effect for that property, as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31F3E5DDFB9047DEA3A25995C548DD70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>The Administrator shall provide each policyholder under the National Flood Insurance Program a notification regarding the right of the policyholder under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7033294B85AA4DA7B52E249F0ED982A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Refund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide for a refund to each policyholder making the election pursuant to paragraph (1) in the amount of any chargeable premiums paid in excess of the chargeable premium rate for the property as in effect on April 1, 2020, and attributable to coverage during the period beginning on such date and ending upon the date that such election takes effect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD26052919122416C9964F213C81B4F77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required actions</header><text>The actions of the Administrator described in this subsection are as follows:</text><paragraph id="H82CA23EEFECB4D7385B2A83B93D069E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Makes available to the public all data and methods used to prescribe chargeable premium rates for types and classes of properties for which insurance coverage is available under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this subsection as <quote>chargeable premium rates</quote>) under Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H966ACD764AB04FF3974A7E5756058EC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Creates an online database that is available to policyholders under the National Flood Insurance Program that provides each such policyholder with information regarding what the chargeable premium rate for the applicable property of the policyholder would be—</text><subparagraph id="HEB8988B9E84D491E825D304CBCA9AC26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF21EE8B42FA949339C5AD3C0C7CAF97F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assuming that the limitation under section 1308(e) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(e)</external-xref>) were not in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03DBC713F2F644F681C9A5F6919BD1F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Completes and publishes a comprehensive assessment of the economic, social, and environmental impacts of implementing Risk Rating 2.0 (or any substantially similar methodology) during the 20-year period beginning in the year in which the assessment is made, which shall include an evaluation of the effect that such implementation will have, during that 20-year period, on— </text><subparagraph id="HD432D62DFB6F467F92EAF29FE6BD4498"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the affordability and availability of flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H048CFFBED4AB4B32B75EFF9D95133B1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>property values;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1D754E52C8046A48D8A74CDE26268C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>non-Federal Government revenues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AD89ABB54E7407B926BCFD5B1B788AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the expected cost increases and exacerbation of inequality for low- and moderate-income policy holders, particularly year-over-year policy rate changes under the 18 percent limitation under section 1308(e)(1) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(e)(1)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64100CE598F943ED84E25C9D03F0D892"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how modifications to the National Flood Insurance Program on implementing Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology, including any modifications under the Administrator’s notice of availability of the record of decision for the final nationwide programmatic environmental impact statement (83 Fed. Reg. 24328), will impact climate resiliency of policy holders and communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187707830B0B40998DBBDFE4728429BD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how specific premium savings can be accessed by mitigation measures, including how home builders can determine the offset of increased cost of construction imposed by implementing such measures, the regional development of community flood risk measures, and updating building codes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7106C688F14D999C9979E91BE8BAC6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Supplements (and revises, as appropriate) the Record of Decision for the final nationwide programmatic environmental impact statement evaluating the environmental impacts of proposed modifications to the National Flood Insurance Program (83 Fed. Reg. 24328) to include the impacts of implementing Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEAFE1E2C4E14DA7BACCBAC37E81A6AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Demonstrates that the data and methods used to prescribe chargeable premium rates under Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology, satisfy the requirements under section 515 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>; 114 Stat. 2763A–153), including that, in implementing that methodology, the Administrator ensures and maximizes the quality, objectivity, utility, and integrity of information disseminated by the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF2634FB57B4AF693A87545BB7C9926"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Conducts public notice and comment rulemaking under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, regarding Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology, which shall include the development of a fair, transparent, and streamlined process to manage— </text><subparagraph id="HB68CBD60B01D48279945EEC4A1BF6344"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disputes over chargeable premium rates; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H659CB6592CD0423381260A477FB459F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other factors with respect to the implementation of that methodology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8462CC24CDAE4088AD6F38B0FF3CCC28"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For each county in the United States, publishes the distribution of chargeable premium rates showing the median, mean, lower and upper quartiles, maximum amount, and minimum amount of chargeable premium rates under each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H07FCF36E6C22452AA5C65DF10EF030E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The method used to prescribe chargeable premium rates, as of September 30, 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58F564B8D56A427A831393E64782C623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The methodology projected to be used to prescribe chargeable premium rates, as of April 1, 2022, assuming that the limitations under section 1308(e) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(e)</external-xref>) are applied.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB07498FBD482400DA4600ED2FCA0800F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The methodology described in subparagraph (B), assuming that the limitations described in that subparagraph are not applied.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A6C1AA82E7B48B398C6C45345AC53A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The methodology described in subparagraph (B), assuming that—</text><clause id="HDC833EB19B1F4276BE21A8186A703BAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the limitations described in that subparagraph are applied; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E8404134C404706A82D3E38E774518B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the administrative costs of the National Flood Insurance Program are allocated on a uniform, per contract basis rather than as allocated under Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1D689E7E86741C191974BA61B860B84"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The methodology described in subparagraph (B), assuming that—</text><clause id="H0CF8E1EC7D5345F1B58C49587777E717"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the limitations described in that subparagraph are not applied; and</text></clause><clause id="H8DB74747E66C42A2BE883629A217C6B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the administrative costs of the National Flood Insurance Program are allocated on a uniform, per contract basis rather than as allocated under Risk Rating 2.0, or any substantially similar methodology.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA662333E82453888BB3ACB9A489239"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Submits to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report detailing the satisfaction of the requirements under paragraphs (1) through (7).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

