<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB12324DB1054324B4B7AFF21DD2AE1B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8161 IH: Fair Pricing with Cost Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220621">June 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10 and 41, United States Code, to strengthen requirements for Government contractors to submit certified and uncertified cost or pricing data and information supporting commercial product determinations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA1A0473E6C684A9DBF8FD1D5FD3911E3" style="OLC"><section id="HF56DC62EA7314DD1B8320D0803F24897" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Pricing with Cost Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H28C13F02490B4244A258C520F2378E80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Submission of uncertified cost data to contracting officers</header><subsection id="H5D46843DB2B14C3D96EC4E8E1CB2A697"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of uncertified cost data to civilian agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3505 of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD51936A26FB2417BAA1BD650B5731599"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9EF43441F79C4F91AF9CC15290422242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>data other than certified</quote> and inserting <quote>uncertified</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EB496FD66E441148A8C96B442F837CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>the procurement.</quote> the following: <quote>If the contracting officer determines that the uncertified pricing data submitted by the offeror, contractor, or subcontractor is not adequate for evaluating the reasonableness of the price of the contract, subcontract, or modification of the contract or subcontract, the offeror, contractor, or subcontractor shall submit to the contracting officer uncertified cost data to the extent necessary to determine the reasonableness of such price.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EEF81168B94B7AB2D58901D3845425"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6408470947094AB99E155F731F781548"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H97EC482576AC4AA791424153E94C700D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HB7D62127C7A64196B2F14737F542E6BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for award</header><paragraph id="HD96CECD20D104A7391EF162782FCCCB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the event the contracting officer is unable to determine proposed prices are fair and reasonable by any other means, an offeror who fails to make a good faith effort to comply with a reasonable request to submit data in accordance with subsection (a) is ineligible for award unless the head of the contracting activity, or the designee of the head of the contracting activity, determines that it is in the best interest of the Government to make the award to that offeror, based on consideration of pertinent factors, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H116AA93F0FC1412C949247B51EDFC097"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The effort to obtain the data. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91B056D9F4854D5D9C9DF26BF0B8B0A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Availability of other sources of supply of the item or service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C96EB983022467B844205AF38208C2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The urgency or criticality of the Government’s need for the product or service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE66A5AD700D14C41BC0649ED3F87E782"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Reasonableness of the price of the contract, subcontract, or modification of the contract or subcontract based on information available to the contracting officer. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF7910FDC4E54E44B918DD85DA086EEB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Rationale or justification made by the offeror for not providing the requested data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2022B88672444486E239166C644700"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Risk to the Government if award is not made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB0E40B8266543A4BBEF9B8D973B0B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H87864ADF10994D3BA7735E184104EFFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any new determination made by the head of the contracting activity under paragraph (1) shall be reported to the senior procurement executive on a periodic basis. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H442F323B96BA4477AAAAC8CD00EA321A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HB624C6CDCE5647C9B808551AA6CAB97D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The senior procurement executive, or a designee, shall submit an annual report to the Administrator of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy identifying offerors that have denied multiple requests for submission of uncertified cost or pricing data over the preceding three-year period, but nevertheless received an award. The report shall identify products or services offered by such offerors that should undergo should-cost analysis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15679638740E4977A31B7E7DF39B369F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notation</header><text>The contracting officer may include a notation on such offerors in the system used by the Federal Government to monitor or record contractor past performance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9644302A82C74A0DB6D1EDC38B904F36"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The senior procurement executive shall—</text><clause id="H9431BE9EE6194811BB389D527136CF9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess the extent to which these offerors are sole source providers; and</text></clause><clause id="H4806028FD22A43D3A6AA60701761F32C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop strategies to incentivize new entrants to increase the availability of other sources of supply for the product or service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DD90DA487E546A8B1FFA84820826511" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of uncertified cost data to contracting officers</header><text>Section 3705 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H54C8F842775B4CDC8C197F33B28C9379"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H1BD4AA1B9D7C43BCA0B9B1DEEE3812FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>data other than certified</quote> and inserting <quote>uncertified</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C51DE06FEE44AF1A792CE1290141C38" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>a fair and reasonable price.</quote> the following: <quote>If the contracting officer determines that the uncertified pricing data submitted by the offeror, contractor, or subcontractor is not adequate for evaluating the reasonableness of the price of the contract, subcontract, or modification of the contract or subcontract, the offeror, contractor, or subcontractor shall submit to the contracting officer uncertified cost data to the extent necessary to determine the reasonableness of such price.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8D3F2AC0A4946F19A57C8CAF8E8A091"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HCC240A7A524B47BEAFE02B576A478981"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>head of contracting</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the contracting</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11B4C8C7242D45A4A2903B6A1C191F13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>item</quote> and inserting <quote>product</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H707CE51AA7DF483B89288FE9D30C9A09" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply with respect to contracts awarded on or after the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE790CC4D4899465AAB903BA8F8454B88" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discretion to Require Certified Cost or Pricing Data on Below-Threshold Contracts</header><subsection id="H8962245482C04028A92421E630C26024" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3504(a) of title 41, United States Code, is amended by inserting before <quote>In any case</quote> the following: <quote>The head of the procuring activity should consider making such a determination when a contractor, offeror, or subcontractor has previously failed to provide adequate uncertified cost or pricing data when requested or required, or other significant risk factors impede the Government’s ability to determine the reasonableness of price.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7971AE20CA1D4FCCA1BF207737551C53" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cost or pricing data on below-Threshold contracts</header><text>Section 3704(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting before <quote>In any case</quote> the following: <quote>The head of the procuring activity may consider making such a determination when a contractor, offeror, or subcontractor has previously failed to provide adequate uncertified cost or pricing data when requested or required, or other significant risk factors impede the ability of the Government to determine the reasonableness of price.</quote>. </text></subsection></section><section id="H06BF93D9CD3D41ACA09265DDB20821E2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Data requirements for commercial product pricing not based on adequate price competition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3705 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFCAF374CEA79447C82A059736512595A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H952CE29185174A0B831749E62301A6A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection (b):</text><quoted-block id="HCCF4691BB6094CA59176D2BAB73CCC5D" style="OLC"><subsection id="H1E4703B2021141CEB89C30A870D908A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To require submission of information for commercial products of a type customarily used by general public or nongovernmental entities</header><paragraph id="H4B3C6EDAA0B14A5A895C809A05D40859"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data to support commercial product determination</header><text>For products proposed as commercial as defined in section 103(1) of title 41, and that have not previously been determined commercial in accordance with section 3703(d) of this title, or to the extent necessary to perform a periodic review of a commercial product determination in accordance with section 3703(e) of this title, the offeror shall be required to identify the comparable commercial product that is customarily used by the general public or nongovernmental entities that serves as the basis for the <quote>of a type</quote> assertion. The offeror shall submit a comparison of the essential physical characteristics and functionality between the proposed <quote>of a type</quote> product and the comparable commercial product in support of the <quote>of a type</quote> assertion. The offeror shall also provide the National Stock Numbers for both the comparable commercial product used by the general public, if one is assigned, and the product proposed to meet the Government’s requirement, if one is assigned.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACCF21714E3C4165811F7AFA3AFE7451"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data to support price reasonableness</header><text>When procurements that include products proposed as commercial as defined in 103(1) of title 41 and are not covered by the exceptions in section 3703(a)(1) of this title, and the contracting officer determines data available from within the Government and outside sources are insufficient to determine price reasonableness or the contracting officer determines the proposed price is not reasonable, the offeror shall be required to provide data to support price reasonableness for a contract, subcontract, or modification of a contract or subcontract as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HDE6C82F358DF457C8877A745244D1BF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the offeror sells the commercial product that is customarily used by the general public or nongovernmental entities, the offeror shall provide the contracting officer access to all unredacted sales data or purchase order history for the commercial product so the contracting officer can review unredacted sales to the general public or nongovernmental entities. If the contracting officer determines the proposed price is not reasonable after evaluating the sales data, the offeror shall be required to provide the contracting officer with cost data, including information on labor cost, material cost, and overhead rates, for the purpose of establishing price reasonableness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A3CCA33288D425696755ED013B43D8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the offeror does not sell the commercial product that is customarily used by the general public or nongovernmental entities for purposes other than governmental purposes that serves as the basis for its <quote>of a type</quote> assertion for the proposed product, the offeror shall provide the contracting officer with cost data, including information on labor cost, material cost, and overhead rates, for the purpose of establishing price reasonableness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE8567408B8BB403C82B11C17B9E563A2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Periodic review of commercial product determinations</header><subsection id="H4FAE83D4EDE14028B8785EBE17929771"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3703 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE1819B4705974E2BA03EAB497365082A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by inserting after <quote>such product or service</quote> the following: <quote>, subject to the limitation in subsection (e)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B43885263CE402585A3A0C3361CD5C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0149319605164B5F89CF9540C362C798"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H41FA986B235B4AFB949E720FB5801BDE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H4E1C4BCB98A44D868C6D8185251A9556"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic review of certain commercial product determinations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2A64996338074F6395E7E98ED0EC3F15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Commercial product determinations shall be periodically reviewed, no less frequently than every five years, to ensure that the initial decision was appropriate and that the market conditions continue to support the designation, if—</text><subparagraph id="H22727E6F3E5F458D89F2CCB05C9DD4A2" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the product is not regularly sold in substantial quantities in the commercial marketplace in essentially the same form; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F648BA2C38143EE8F779B2C1182A13D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the product has not been subject to adequate competition, as defined in subsection (a)(1)(A), from a different product or products since the determination was made, unless the procurement is subject to the exception in subsection (a)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF423C1DF63ED40C786B5EB518FDCFC78" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reviews of commercial product determinations shall be approved at a level above the contracting officer. The Director of the Defense Contract Management Agency, the Director of the Defense Contract Audit Agency, or other appropriate experts in the Department may support such reviews upon request, consistent with section 3456(b)(1)(A) of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38F6AC8C83B946AC804BC84ED369EEEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commercial product and commercial service determinations by Department of Defense</header><text>Section 3456(c) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6AA895BEC7634597B44957780272F9A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>this chapter</quote> the following: <quote>subject to periodic reviews of certain commercial product determinations as set forth in section 3703(e) of this title, or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF85BA29CC314308ACFD5F2E1B66A634"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H23C5FBFCC0D144A09056180BDCFD7936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Limitation</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Limitations</header-in-text></quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3560B784BE174CCC8B2A847524ACD2C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and (C)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H453815B2603245E588DD534ACF03214E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H48FEB55CBBBA46A1926CAA99F23B807C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H3E86510F77AD4D3F94DA64251345AA80"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limitation under subparagraph (A) does not apply to the periodic review of commercial product determinations as set forth in 3703(e) of this title. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1377CE3DDA894FCB812C322801F4BB45"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO review and report on Government contractors using distributors to avoid scrutiny</header><subsection id="H291D429DD0414A8AACD9915F14BA4D6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><paragraph id="H416B842778DE4EFFA1E43A86378E1403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the prevalence and trends of contractors of executive agencies using distributors or other intermediaries as a means of avoiding legal or regulatory requirements, such as requirements to provide certified or uncertified cost or pricing data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB552CCD7895E4206B5A0676DDE1FADC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional contents of review</header><text>In conducting the review under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="HEE67ACC40A2B42859F799A7495E07B29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any effects of this practice on the ability of the Government to—</text><clause id="H7AAB1254ED9D4045A0C912994A40AFD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>acquire needed goods at reasonable prices; and</text></clause><clause id="HD386AFEE105D4A06A53743686A340F6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>avoid waste, fraud, and abuse in the procurement process; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABB9E09FB71344F5B6CC9AC334698A9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how executive agencies may differentiate between the legitimate business purposes for the use of distributor relationships, compared to situations where the distributors largely serve to avoid legal and regulatory requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H035BF77251834226B472156390545F05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report containing the results of the review required by subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph id="H6FD5A9556D994E29BC4E4399D8875A24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D50F44BC1DD4E3D95384345877F4A56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E0F6AD46154EECABEEA1A274CA478D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H659B8374FE3B446BB8AE2F12A5B58A1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Executive agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>executive agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

