<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3239068B85C24DAE8E1AB90500BA215B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6602 IH: Affordable Housing Resident Services Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. C&#225;rdenas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize funding of enriched resident services in federally assisted affordable housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H06F809162BCC42AEB0E3B355CA29EE35" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4FC1B079B029425783427CC0457FD2F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Housing Resident Services Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEF0800F500004F1FA5A80F17AD65990F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Affordable housing resident services grant program</header> <subsection id="H9112E24DA6F74CAD9EA84DBA9A92CA1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall annually award grants on a competitive basis to owners of qualified properties for use for eligible activities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC333D428F2A49EC8215DC408CAF294E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms of grant</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be funded for a term of 5 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC896DB756C4C46B1896B65C278AED8D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>Grants shall be used for activities that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H431925D425274102BDE27A43D7E3A1C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist residents in obtaining health services and other community services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3F8A34F69BA44A399950E3F5E1F6321"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide after-school programs for children and teenage students, including mentoring, tutoring, college and career readiness, and life skills training;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB33C570C4994E62BE69A46D05D429B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance educational opportunities for youth and adult residents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4870E7893E094ACEAD6DDB805C82DBA6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide access to programs to assist residents with mental health or alcohol or addiction problems;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78421E8B8B554B7F812D97E13EED9CB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>enhance residents’ economic self-sufficiency and empowerment, including providing employment resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B9FCDB6FDB343F78CBD14AD73A8693D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prepare residents for home ownership;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0151243A83A43CE8BDEB5BC90F8EF91"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide residents assistance with financial literacy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EE5ACC75E674A919E2423355138CFBC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>assist older adults to enable them to age in place; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65E383E931A94015BF54F8015F4099A7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assist residents with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D336822E7A44BC9869245EEECA420D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified properties</header><text>The term <term>qualified properties</term> means a property assisted under—</text> 
<paragraph id="H59B47A71B3BE4B1CB36CD701494D6A83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the low-income housing tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA75F003899E84ABC93A367ED3ACEB2A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the project-based rental assistance programs under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, including units assisted by project-based vouchers under section 8(o)(13) of such Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE17C16AAC5E74716A06FE543E14C13B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the program under section 236 of the National Housing Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBA96A2F8A44450A9E292B170D13C6D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the below-market interest rate mortgage program under section 22(d)(3) of the National Housing Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78B4113E73F8496D9B009106578D9ECF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the rural rental housing program under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD17D1D0D6A2488DAF2706BDF830DACC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a program under title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11361">42 U.S.C. 11361 et seq.</external-xref>), but only permanent supportive housing projects subsidized under such programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6B47E67FB4941FC8A21B2D73E8D3C25"><enum>(7)</enum><text>section 1131 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/289">Public Law 110–289</external-xref>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06436C7B09C440A193DBB37043B86D6A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the supportive housing for the elderly program under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA80F3C3D043A4B2D9C2D19C08F0D9CE3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the supportive housing program for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABC6151EB90F497AA0A81D54AEB53E02"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affordable housing units owned by public housing agencies that are not assisted under the Housing Act of 1937.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34FB18A608A54CBBAD840113D5292EC5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>Grants shall be awarded on a competitive basis, based on the following selection criteria:</text> <paragraph id="H2621539B8FD64267A898A7294B921A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The extent to which a grant may enable an applicant to provide new types of enriched services, to provide services to more residents, or provide more effective services to residents.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DCADD63FDD54E498016F9D9B99A9C30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which an applicant can demonstrate the likelihood of achieving objective outcomes for its residents that are described in the application.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H848F2AC7CC0846B0B229F5F80F231F4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent of experience with respect to eligible activities and a demonstrable track record in providing resident services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H108F15F648D34EFE8058021124CC9F71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent of relationships and partnerships an applicant has with localities, non-profits, and health care providers that provide services or facilitate the provision of services that improve outcomes for residents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10A4EBEC2D4A4BB184A7E4EB82014B67"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any experience the applicant has with respect to development, ownership, and management of qualified properties for low-income families, seniors, and disabled persons.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C3D801BE448417F96C968304DC78E13"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The selection of a diverse range of grantees, including minority business enterprises and owners of properties located in rural areas and other underserved areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45E0F1ED765140159ECB8FF10DF03BED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Economies of scale associated with providing services to residents in a number of different qualified properties that enhance the efficiency of providing resident services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H406033099F104462A97C5BA2D2856EA2"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which an applicant can supplement the grant with matching funds from other sources to fund additional services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59FF69311A9345CDBB56E33FBF39EE8C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services as the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H89F6695575EF49998965CCFB9DF82432"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="HFBB4635528E343C7A672E2EC768EBE0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the appropriation of additional amounts for use in association with the grant program established under this section the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, for each of fiscal years 2022, 2023, 2024, 2025, and 2026, transfer, to the grant program established under this section, such amounts as the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines appropriate from the Social Services Block Grant program and the Community Services Block Grant program.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H45FC668F536142AFB9F375D42DC1415D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum</header><text>The sum of the amounts transferred by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in a fiscal year under this section shall not exceed 300,000,000 dollars. </text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

