<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D8B56E7F0ED405196A993748CB38F27" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9501 IH: Developing Alternative Mitigation Systems for Beavers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9501</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to assist projects that use nonlethal coexistence measures to reduce property damage caused by beavers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3AD0C0F2452F46428FD77E53E0E319B1" style="OLC"><section id="H17E1194C8D4D4019B25DD210A033354C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing Alternative Mitigation Systems for Beavers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DAMS for Beavers Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0AA419E7CA1F461EAAC51E1CBF244496"><enum>2.</enum><header>Beaver damage mitigation grant program</header><subsection id="H983DB4B4CBD049A4ADC9AF62CB218483"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a grant program under which the Secretary may award grants on a competitive basis to assist projects that use nonlethal coexistence measures to—</text><paragraph id="H5CBB6A7BA86541E5B9F4F5B7DC43C595"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce property damage caused by beavers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8122E1E8AFCA4AF28B9C9E9CAD0B7B61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain or enhance habitat for beavers and other wildlife.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC8A99F934994AE7AC1AEAEBDD763EB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H68A14701119A4AE6AC6808C1B6F851F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the experience, qualifications, and training (including planned training) of the applicant with respect to the use of nonlethal coexistence measures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71E6BFADCD644ED7BF92E16C3C1479BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of an application submitted by an applicant other than a State or Tribal wildlife or natural resources management agency (or equivalent), a certification that the applicant has consulted with such an agency (or equivalent).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D5FB29B7B94AEE9B7EC960F1F948A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an application submitted by an applicant other than the owner of the property on which a relevant proposed project will be located, a certification from such owner that such owner—</text><subparagraph id="H1F7646EABABA4B28BAA7AD12743C68A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approves the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A0DF2FE835F48B6B4855BDE45CC012A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the duration of the project, will only allow the use of nonlethal coexistence measures on the property for purposes of reducing property damage caused by beavers (except in the case of a circumstance subject to an exclusion under subsection (d)(2)(A)(i)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCE8260E67F14AA2B14A2EEF3BF93076" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary may give priority to a project that—</text><paragraph id="H1A9674AD0EEC4F3AA21EC17951882667"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes monitoring and research that facilitates evaluation of the project and identification of best practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H797BB3BC6FB94ADA89AFC60B0C06B73F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes educational and outreach activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD290833FE1A9403BBF4091D3297D396D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is located in an area that ensures grant recipients under the Program represent diverse geographic areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H744645EA701B46D6A9FA7B3F00D39D01"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">satisfies any other criteria the Secretary determines relevant to effectively reducing damage to property and maintaining or enhancing habitat for beavers and other wildlife.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E25C7EEC1674B4A905441294F47344A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions</header><paragraph id="H5578197D863E44E885D529F8AF473233" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under the Program, for the duration of the project facilitated with grant funds a grant recipient may only use nonlethal coexistence measures for purposes of reducing property damage caused by beavers on the property on which the project will be carried out.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7BB11058C6D40A4BAB151A48FDA9CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><subparagraph id="HCB567E9CC1174642B2DCE8AEB1E6682A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the Secretary determines that—</text><clause id="H972AA0454F1E4F6FA826CE67B3903DA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an activity other than a nonlethal coexistence measure is necessary to protect human health or safety; or</text></clause><clause id="HCA88F5C0AE084ABF988287FF6D8932ED" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the project assisted with grant funds has been implemented for not less than 1 year and such project has not sufficiently reduced the damage caused by beavers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58667F8E56F8428189000D14F1D3F71C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain a record of each determination made under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3A031C8EC164D1A8FBEB8763B83765E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project for which a grant is awarded under the Program may not exceed 75 percent.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC470579993CA4403AE84A93867D1666E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which grants are awarded under the Program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HE44B8288C0C942A8B71D68C14D388F0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of the projects funded by grants under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C2D76D3116544AF898F07AC5E288263"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the Program in selecting projects according to the priorities described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A27B62F4D3D4FB58BAAE017876D5378"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the effectiveness of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97E2A3E023064B5B8B2BDC6299CB6D8F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H6859880BD63847A58502CFAD0109EE66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonlethal coexistence measure</header><subparagraph id="HA7FC4BEF2B254A3FB9FD3B9C35C0BE7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>nonlethal coexistence measure</quote> means a measure that does not incorporate—</text><clause id="H0A02F506F92C40DB9EC34262D2AD7982"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the gripping, trapping, injuring, or killing of a beaver;</text></clause><clause id="H629F64801C5945E7A5B7F905F6190D89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the destruction or removal of a beaver dam or lodge;</text></clause><clause id="H11D3207C5AF5401F82A99A4083C67FB0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the relocation of a beaver; or</text></clause><clause id="HC957531781FA4F808A93FA6EFC4FFE45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the installation of beaver dam analogues.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54AB5B3B7567455FBE7E151F9ECA5B76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonlethal coexistence measure</quote> may include fencing used to protect culverts, fencing and paint-sand mixtures used to protect trees, and flow management devices used to control water levels in beaver ponds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC65C0F514B4E4DA1CF679B1F5FAD34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>Program</quote> means the grant program established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C5EA4B204543E893D4936A3BD0DFB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDC976BDF4D74306A9B1FDA025DDD9D9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H5980358701474FAFAC8A59C7E266B459"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H860BC70EF0F8412ABC6833C044214219"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of the funds made available each fiscal year under paragraph (1) may be used for administrative expenses of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

