<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34159EFCAA2444D2A727B0BFC3E71963" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7992 IH: Sustaining Our Democracy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7992</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001312">Ms. Bourdeaux</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000376">Mr. Allred</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a democracy advancement and innovation program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H673E01407BAF4AAE8F0C60C56F75B682" style="OLC"><section id="HDD4D949BE96B457B9EF614D8BF2E502D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HA76FC4ED62764948BC81F527CCD0F675"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sustaining Our Democracy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36C424F195B7428EBE7109C0D203C413"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HDD4D949BE96B457B9EF614D8BF2E502D">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HFB789597FA774B75B748F2ACC42BB7FC">TITLE I—Payments and Allocations to States</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA1EDEA5CA6E24355ABEBB66E5C35C663">Sec. 101. Democracy Advancement and Innovation Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC2E5D8506E4446D2B18EE8C30B1836C8">Sec. 102. State plan.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HCE4B1AF050ED4035BDC5DCE23F75373D">Sec. 103. Prohibitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H8A9A0841D29D4770A47C9354ACD7088B">Sec. 104. Amount of State allocation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE9B841E17CA84F3598578CCBFF3D7D4F">Sec. 105. Procedures for disbursements of payments and allocations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7F47504417034A59B9CB88FBB71C2381">Sec. 106. Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H830E315721F549F68921FAA3E9F0980D">TITLE II—State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5FB1E06A81F14E41818198B580425185">Sec. 201. State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H5AF38B99E4484129AF3650B2BF73DB98">TITLE III—General Provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE96155E6EA824902B8C415B590F19C70">Sec. 301. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H1DFDCD438A2044AFBB21D686442432D5">Sec. 302. Rule of construction regarding calculation of deadlines.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD6576FEA6AFE43DF8A6CE612F52CBEBE">Sec. 303. Severability.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="HFB789597FA774B75B748F2ACC42BB7FC"><enum>I</enum><header>Payments and Allocations to States</header><section id="HA1EDEA5CA6E24355ABEBB66E5C35C663"><enum>101.</enum><header>Democracy Advancement and Innovation Program</header><subsection id="HE932E78F43F84F7A81D428C9035D5677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a program to be known as the <quote>Democracy Advancement and Innovation Program</quote> under which the Director of the Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation shall make allocations to each State for each fiscal year to carry out democracy promotion activities described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF15AE8648322424FB75D1F41E5A75017"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Democracy promotion activities described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The democracy promotion activities described in this subsection are as follows:</text><paragraph id="HAFC6750AC812431AA92514F68130AEFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities to promote innovation to improve efficiency and smooth functioning in the administration of elections for Federal office and to secure the infrastructure used in the administration of such elections, including making upgrades to voting equipment and voter registration systems, voter registration and nonpartisan voter outreach activities, securing voting locations, expanding polling places and the availability of early and mail voting, and promoting cybersecurity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H389EEF7EBC6241FDBD1F553FD0103FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Activities to recruit, train, and retain nonpartisan election officials and poll workers and to protect election officials (both nonpartisan and those elected or appointed to their position) from threats against them in the course of their work administering Federal elections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA85FAB251D64AD2BCCB57472402A53F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Activities to increase access to voting in elections for Federal office by underserved communities, individuals with disabilities, racial and language minority groups, individuals entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, and voters residing in Indian lands. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08288F1802AB4F0183AF27A231F25096"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitting States To retain and reserve allocations for future use</header><text>A State may retain and reserve an allocation received for a fiscal year to carry out democracy promotion activities in any subsequent fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0AB8266E12D943AF80B1A7AB45B15D0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requiring submission and approval of State plan</header><paragraph id="H9186639BCB074E99B3C422A5DF47FFA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State shall receive an allocation under the Program for a fiscal year if—</text><subparagraph id="HCB2B638A6CE1401699EDCF1EB1E9A718"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 90 days before the first day of the fiscal year, the chief State election official of the State submits to the Director the State plan described in section 102; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C7F54587DC94B82B484B7A4FEDDCB07"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 45 days before the first day of the fiscal year, the Director, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission as described in paragraph (3), determines that the State plan will enable the State to carry out democracy promotion activities and approves the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFE940D71624FF4B03E9BE12875FC4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission and approval of revised plan</header><text>If the Director does not approve the State plan as submitted by the State under paragraph (1) with respect to a fiscal year, the State shall receive a payment under the Program for the fiscal year if, at any time prior to the end of the fiscal year—</text><subparagraph id="H11930F081E2D47329BB949EFEAC51C97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chief State election official of the State submits a revised version of the State plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E3DBEBC9A9548F9A73E13A108D62A5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission as described in paragraph (3), determines that the revised version of the State plan will enable the State to carry out democracy promotion activities and approves the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD759AA3DB434FB5AFE485AA941B7BFE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Election Assistance Commission consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a State plan submitted under paragraph (1) or a revised plan submitted under paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H4DC0FFBC7CD44714908477F1D07EE002"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director shall, prior to making a determination on approval of the plan, consult with the Election Assistance Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF744A8072446E887997134D9B7A238"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Election Assistance Commission shall submit to the Director a written assessment with respect to whether the proposed activities of the plan satisfy the requirements of this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H497F76C10F9D4BA49D4447FFC580FDF7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation with legislature</header><text>The chief State election official of the State shall develop the State plan submitted under paragraph (1) and any revised plan submitted under paragraph (2) in consultation with the majority party and minority party leaders of each house of the State legislature.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H693F243AEF2A4AD0B5F4301AEE9F235B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules for States that do not submit a State plan</header><text>If a State fails to submit a State plan described in section 102 before the date required under paragraph (1)(A), under rules established by the Director—</text><subparagraph id="H60E28AB1AFDE4570B039FD3C880F8FBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for purposes of this title (other than section 104)—</text><clause id="HC0AE62E1651542E0B9E2768DB2736D43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each political subdivision within the State shall be treated as a State for purposes of this title (other than section 104); and </text></clause><clause id="H6F585DC59E14427FBBD5343FD15B0E0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in applying this title to such political subdivision, any duties required of the chief State election official shall be undertaken by the executive official of such political subdivision charged with the administration of elections; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA72C702D56CA4991A19DED520B6163D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in applying this subsection to any political subdivision of the State—</text><clause id="H5DE5502C989D4F45904B0E650F14F704"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (1)(A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>the first day of the fiscal year</quote> for <quote>90 days before the first day of the fiscal year</quote>; </text></clause><clause id="H8CB0F367E87C4745B8450FAFA8F0BB3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>paragraph (1)(B) shall be applied by substituting <quote>30 days after the first day of the fiscal year</quote> for <quote>45 days before the first day of the fiscal year</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H45EC6B28CF924304BB87E905C2FFA949"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>paragraph (4) shall not apply; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDDDB69051B44BEA994B5A672A211E7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of the allocation made to each such political subdivision under the Program shall be the sum of—</text><clause id="H525C050355424F0CB9601984913A1216"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount which bears the same proportion to the amount determined under section 104 with respect to the State in which the political subdivision is located as—</text><subclause id="H5CF2383AC3AE447AAF8621EE3301A894"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the population of the political subdivision; bears to</text></subclause><subclause id="HBEC905C730ED4B1D837E51B132CD7262"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the population of such State; plus</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEB6782740268498A835C2586C7B4175D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount (not to exceed 100 percent of the amount determined with respect to the political subdivision under clause (i)) which bears the same proportion to the unsubscribed funds of the State as—</text><subclause id="H745305BB1E2041B7B51BFB953C00E4B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the population of the political subdivision; bears to</text></subclause><subclause id="HB27AF13CDD6F49C2AA5A40B9B216DBDE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the population of the number of political subdivisions within the State that submitted a plan under section 102 before the date required under paragraph (1)(A) (after application of subparagraph (B)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of subparagraph (C)(ii), the unsubscribed funds of any State is the sum of the amounts described in subparagraph (C)(i) with respect to political subdivisions in the State which did not submit a plan under this subsection before the date required under paragraph (1)(A) (after application of subparagraph (B)). </continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3414F8D84EFF4099951DBB16E08227F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State report on use of allocations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the last day of a fiscal year for which an allocation was made to the State under the Program, the chief State election official of the State shall submit a report to the Director describing how the State used the allocation, including a description of the democracy promotion activities the State carried out with the allocation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1AE0F6AEB8EE4FEBB33DC264E7E7EE10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><paragraph id="HE604B93945C34BF7B6BB40A7FBCC4E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publicly available website</header><text>The Director shall make available on a publicly accessible website the following:</text><subparagraph id="H55E772E587534D48BA2A988EB2B4FD2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State plans submitted under paragraph (1) of subsection (d) and revised plans submitted under paragraph (2) of subsection (d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38493561E6294DBA8C93DD3C1BD19D57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director’s notifications of determinations with respect to such plans under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D85873E15094F0FBC4010F17105974F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Reports submitted by States under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H277F9C50AE5D4F3EA6CC314853524FDC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redaction</header><text>The Director may redact information required to be made available under paragraph (1) if the information would be properly withheld from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or if the public disclosure of the information is otherwise prohibited by law. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D3C4EA871F64DFCBA03759074520CD8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC2E5D8506E4446D2B18EE8C30B1836C8"><enum>102.</enum><header>State plan</header><subsection id="HDEA68939725243C4A6CE6AF925B7F3C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State plan under this section with respect to a State is a plan containing each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HB9A100B74C5A4947B03EBF6FCC684B7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the democracy promotion activities the State will carry out with the payment made under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2BEA1753324EC988140B63922D8212"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A statement of whether or not the State intends to retain and reserve the payment for future democracy promotion activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H789D6744EC1C4759921BD4E0339FE5E1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A statement of how the State intends to distribute resources under the plan, including how the distribution of resources will address geographic and racial disparities within the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC38ED8C91647FBB9157AD37D8C3B2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of how the State intends to allocate funds to carry out the proposed activities, which shall include the amount the State intends to allocate to each such activity, including (if applicable) a specific allocation for—</text><subparagraph id="H3B9DC344CF8B47F9B170C6260197B5C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>activities described in subsection 101(b)(1) (relating to election administration);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE20054A1E7A14764B868385BBA8D5969" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities described in section 101(b)(2) (relating to activities to recruit, train, retain, and protect election workers); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0612EC1F6FD643A79C61866F78DEF6FB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities described in section 101(b)(3) (relating to activities to increase access to voting in elections for Federal office by certain communities). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HC123A0D25BEA43F091CDAB9A15609FBF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how funds allocated under paragraph (4) will be allocated to political subdivisions of the State. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E516D1B6794CCDA5378EB5D4BDF527"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the State will establish the fund described in subsection (b) for purposes of administering the democracy promotion activities which the State will carry out with the payment, including information on fund management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF17E7F2501D4330BB937DC3F856FD9C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of the State-based administrative complaint procedures established for purposes of section 103(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF322CE63E74F989EF57D2039B94FB2"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A statement regarding whether the proposed activities to be funded are permitted under State law, or whether the official intends to seek legal authorization for such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82B5C2155B78454686871D455416524A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for fund</header><paragraph id="H4D82EBACD4354DB1B8A729F89B1333EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fund described</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(6), a fund described in this subsection with respect to a State is a fund which is established in the treasury of the State government, which is used in accordance with paragraph (2), and which consists of the following amounts:</text><subparagraph id="H8F819D2B42C5406DA13558E0FF300B4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available by the State for carrying out the democracy promotion activities for which the payment is made to the State under the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8A2F6BC1AED48BEB2E00B6FA804D8FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The payment made to the State under the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB401734707264034880568E00C89C483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2A31734BE0D4F058DBC260B5829C5CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Interest earned on deposits of the fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04706456A61C4EF4A2C68EB9852D78DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of fund</header><text>Amounts in the fund shall be used by the State exclusively to carry out democracy promotion activities for which the payment is made to the State under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84AF0306483C4B0E875AD33A500514D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of States that require changes to state law</header><text>In the case of a State that requires State legislation to establish the fund described in this subsection, the Director shall defer disbursement of the payment to such State under the Program until such time as legislation establishing the fund is enacted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCE4B1AF050ED4035BDC5DCE23F75373D"><enum>103.</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><subsection id="H0EDE41F11FA240B783A99F9DCB349488"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited uses of payments</header><paragraph id="H03A82062808348E8AEB7D358BECFBA18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not use a payment made under the Program to carry out—</text><subparagraph id="H650EE5356E334E859FAC8F2635FD349C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any activity described in paragraph (2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDE8A3F9954F4C4C81550FE801E6E945"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other activity which has the purpose or effect of diminishing the ability of any eligible voter to participate in the electoral process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA09779F084343AE89B014FC9AF328D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibited activities</header><text>The following are activities described in this paragraph:</text><subparagraph id="H01B4F3491F25425BB8080CFA1B09ABED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Activities that intimidate, threaten, or coerce voters, poll workers, or election administrators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAA6DE8B50E6466E8D5D8231BA45ACED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The restriction of the distribution of food or nonalcoholic beverages to voters while waiting at polling places (other than restrictions on distributions made on the basis of the electoral participation or political preference of the recipient).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H365B3CAB5B7548BF988CA8A53836023C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The removal of election administrators from their positions other than for negligence, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB0F4E4CE99C426D848F0FF489BC1BE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Defending against lawsuits alleging voter-suppression practices or proposed practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7F8A71BB00409DBEA82E7C54745E95"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The investigation of claims of voter fraud based on the mere invocation of interests in voter confidence or prevention of fraud.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H317F67E750DD4B1A9DDCA17265599541"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The performance of audits that—</text><clause id="H33459F468E0E4EC18BDE54C779289BB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fail to meet best practices established by the Election Assistance Commission;</text></clause><clause id="H8B849D9766674037B1B7D25A40847F78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fail to meet the requirements for record retention under title III of the Civil Rights Act of 1960 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20701">52 U.S.C. 20701 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="H1886A0E2676D472BB483F0C9417625B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise jeopardize election records, voting equipment, electronic poll books, or election management systems (as defined under the voluntary guidance issued by the Election Assistance Commission under section 311 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21101">52 U.S.C. 21101</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1D848EBEEA44E59ABF777A04FD0147"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The removal of voters from voter rolls based on evidence that is not reliable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2292E33B9964F6E8324566509D5747F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Activities preventing individuals seeking to have their right to vote or register to vote restored.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BDCACACAB1E4F248ACA80B452168DC8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The purchase of voting machines that do not require the use of individual voter-verifiable paper ballots marked through the use of a non-tabulating ballot marking device or system. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CFB85ED03B6483F8834479A4F75FF2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State-Based administrative complaint procedures</header><paragraph id="H57B4508FBE064A2FB2223CEAAE77CCCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>A State receiving a payment under the Program shall establish uniform and nondiscriminatory State-based administrative complaint procedures under which any person who believes that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, is occurring, or is about to occur may file a complaint.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD6F077FAC740D6B94B979F1DCB4C8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to Director</header><text>The State shall transmit to the Director a description of each complaint filed under the procedures, together with—</text><subparagraph id="H0E91EA8EB6EC471AA5ABDB46A5E602E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the State provides a remedy with respect to the complaint, a description of the remedy; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1225FC0BFBEF446281176E48F0AD0D4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the State dismisses the complaint, a statement of the reasons for the dismissal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E250FB87624C479FD2A6BA1C17BB91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review by Director</header><subparagraph id="H4AD7D47431B248B593EA1975744A975D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Request for review</header><text>Any person who is dissatisfied with the final decision under a State-based administrative complaint procedure under this subsection may, not later than 60 days after the decision is made, file a request with the Director to review the decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEC0EE6E831444A5AF8BFF2EBF770E8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Action by Director</header><text>Upon receiving a request under subparagraph (A), the Director shall review the decision and, in accordance with such procedures as the Director may establish, including procedures to provide notice and an opportunity for a hearing, may uphold the decision or reverse the decision and provide an appropriate remedy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CCBCD97C78A4CE6862054B11BFC922B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability of material</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall make available on a publicly accessible website all material relating to a request for review and determination by the Director under this paragraph, except that the Director may redact material required to be made available under this subparagraph if the material would be properly withheld from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or if the public disclosure of the material is otherwise prohibited by law. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5F6C42BD2F94F2580AFF2AE65EEBBC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Right to petition for review</header><subparagraph id="HDFF1471800144EE6B059B39CAE96510A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person aggrieved by an action of the Director under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) may file a petition with the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA40D0B49CD654EE4A3F3D6D1D6CA72E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline to file petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any petition under this subparagraph shall be filed not later than 60 days after the date of the action taken by the Director under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9C3DE6A1D7140DC85045509EFA9B77A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standard of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any proceeding under this paragraph, the court shall determine whether the action of the Director was arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law under section 706 of title 5, United States Code, and may direct the Office to conform with any such determination within 30 days. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13003DFA0E0D4578839D97A2DDB01EFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Action by Attorney General for declaratory and injunctive relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may bring a civil action against any State in an appropriate United States District Court for such declaratory and injunctive relief (including a temporary restraining order, a permanent or temporary injunction, or other order) as may be necessary to enforce subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H8A9A0841D29D4770A47C9354ACD7088B"><enum>104.</enum><header>Amount of State allocation</header><subsection id="H6E4824DB99F54C39824D3FF8B9164734"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State-Specific amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the allocation made to a State under the Program for a fiscal year shall be equal to the product of—</text><paragraph id="HF5735962FFA84E39ABE89767AB92F94A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Congressional district allocation amount (determined under subsection (b)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B30BC35137C407FB797DA74ACBC98D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of Congressional districts in the State for the next regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82581CBEFD7F4A03A16FD30296F914AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional district allocation amount</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the <quote>Congressional district allocation amount</quote> with respect to a fiscal year is equal to the quotient of—</text><paragraph id="H9E699AB1297847D1B4336FC9D8D216C5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the aggregate amount available for allocations to States under the Program for the fiscal year, as determined by the Director under subsection (c); divided by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88050851D63048C9A5C0621C889662D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total number of Congressional districts in all States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H682EE106F36F425197ABE53A7EC4AA3C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of aggregate amount available for allocations; notification to States</header><text>Not later than 120 days before the first day of each fiscal year, the Director—</text><paragraph id="H64861B5D3F43499CA67B50DF7084CE20" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall determine and establish the aggregate amount available for allocations to States under the Program for the fiscal year, taking into account the anticipated balances of the Trust Fund (including any amounts appropriated pursuant to section 106(i)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H039F7E13879C44489CBD12E2056B27C6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall notify each State of the amount of the State’s allocation under the Program for the fiscal year.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In making the determination under paragraph (1), the Director shall consult with the Election Assistance Commission, but shall be solely responsible for making the final determinations under such paragraph.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H507CDEAB5BA64B428C1C4BCAD7060339"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Source of payments</header><text>The amounts used to make allocations and payments under the Program shall be derived solely from the Trust Fund.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE9B841E17CA84F3598578CCBFF3D7D4F"><enum>105.</enum><header>Procedures for disbursements of payments and allocations</header><subsection id="H78F09D9BD7BF4B57B50F10CA4AD9CB38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon approving the State plan under section 102, the Director shall direct the Secretary of the Treasury to allocate to the Election Assistance Commission the amount provided for activities under the plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB1B7C23D2B44C69AB9E12161057027B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment to State</header><text>As soon as practicable after receiving an allocation under subsection (a) with respect to a State, the Election Assistance Commission shall make payments to—</text><paragraph id="H27792641FEF348E69C2EE5DA098EDAB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>local election administrators in the State with respect to amounts related to activities in the State plan carried out directly by such local election administrators; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DFABACFFC3F4F3C9B6E7E3DEAD7DB8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State with respect to any amount not described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7C8A32103DD480385465598BDE08AE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuing availability of funds after appropriation</header><text>A payment made to a State by the Election Assistance Commission under this section shall be available without fiscal year limitation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7F47504417034A59B9CB88FBB71C2381"><enum>106.</enum><header>Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation</header><subsection id="HEE0BC266DCBE47B6B7CAC70A1298AD03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established as an independent establishment in the executive branch the Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H74D3019544634DA3A45263E222BC4310"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph id="H217BE1ED57BF426882EF421CEACF41D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07FCBFB734E74695AA7DC22B935BB21F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term of service</header><text>The Director shall serve for a term of 6 years and may be reappointed to an additional term, and may continue serving as Director until a replacement is appointed. A vacancy in the position of Director shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA46A2E901544C5A959EA9B635C939A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Director shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate in effect for level II of the Executive Schedule.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E13D0B2B7FD41F09CEE7C134F7B63DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may be removed from office by the President. If the President removes the Director, the President shall communicate in writing the reasons for the removal to both Houses of Congress not later than 30 days beforehand. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA662712FF16540D7B20DF5A3F34628DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>General counsel and other staff</header><paragraph id="H57E12EBD67B940549E090469C5151D95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall appoint a general counsel who shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule. In the event of a vacancy in the position of the Director, the General Counsel shall exercise all the responsibilities of the Director until such vacancy is filled.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47FF4C0F5C7A4C15A6AFBD8AB97D955C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Senior staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may appoint and fix the pay of staff designated as Senior staff, such as a Deputy Director, who may be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate in effect for level IV of the Executive Schedule.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H580D48C3ECD246F2B12D98B66B2DA767"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the General Counsel and Senior staff, the Director may appoint and fix the pay of such other staff as the Director considers necessary to carry out the duties of the Office, except that no such staff may be compensated at an annual rate exceeding the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9841D2D59C9944B3A8B30B00B11F19BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Office are as follows:</text><paragraph id="H187D3443E5EF484BBBBAB1F596EE62D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration of Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall administer the Program, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission, including by holding quarterly meetings of representatives from such Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9813FB24B14744CBBFF861F0677774D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight of Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall oversee the operation of the Trust Fund and monitor its balances, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission and the Secretary of the Treasury. The Director may hold funds in reserve to cover the expenses of the Office and to preserve the solvency of the Trust Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H625DA9A8975B4DE08AD445CCFD36A41E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in 2024 and each succeeding regularly scheduled general election for Federal office thereafter, the Director, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission, shall submit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate a report on the activities carried out under the Program and the amounts deposited into and paid from the Trust Fund during the two most recent fiscal years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7D4442A4DBC4D82AB64035981DAA21B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coverage under Inspector General Act of 1978 for conducting audits and investigations</header><paragraph id="HF59C5DB6A8D7427AA826A587F1B42610"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8G(a)(2) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by inserting <quote>the Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation,</quote> after <quote>Election Assistance Commission,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0674E005914CF0AFD548D4AA181908"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect 180 days after the appointment of the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73595E93E39D41B2AF3A347A7297DEAB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coverage under Hatch Act</header><text>Clause (i) of section 7323(b)(2)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDB38E7A252E041FC9C3A134FA98FCF37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (XIII); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF615AF97BC5B46179FB19FFE93549FC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC5914B6709A44D88983DC741D3EBB352" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H2670E9D394AB420DBE4247AF20C37C6F" indent="up2"><enum>(XV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation; or</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H260F70232A1948D0BD7AF6AFBD33CBED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H78B35DCDFD144436A2CC56404AF5D03F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall promulgate such rules and regulations as the Director considers necessary and appropriate to carry out the duties of the Office under this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CFA8EFA69443EDB61A895D8D8215C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State plan submission and approval and distribution of funds</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall promulgate such rules and regulations as the Director considers necessary and appropriate to carry out the requirements of this title and the amendments made by this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3EAD3493D5E4EB8AB3111B5FB3D0287"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comments by the Election Assistance Commission</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission shall timely submit comments with respect to any proposed regulations promulgated by the Director under this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB636630347B42F285ADA49AA8356F88"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Interim authority pending appointment and confirmation of Director</header><paragraph id="H61CBA178067F4EEC803635891A57C0FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority of Director of Office of Management and Budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (b), during the transition period, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget is authorized to perform the functions of the Office under this Act, and shall act for all purposes as, and with the full powers of, the Director. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BA826F0C713418CA4C4A8C1995F6F97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim administrative services</header><subparagraph id="HB13BF99F974E4CF0AE4D3780E469C59C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority of Office of Management and Budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the transition period, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget may provide administrative services necessary to support the Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62014F779D4742C0A8EE32E28756C254"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of authority; permitting extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall cease providing interim administrative services under this paragraph upon the expiration of the transition period, except that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget may continue to provide such services after the expiration of the transition period if the Director and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget jointly transmit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate—</text><clause id="HB29EE11131F14E8C8C409190DA62C50E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a written determination that an orderly implementation of this Act is not feasible by the expiration of the transition period;</text></clause><clause id="HBE3ACFB38C824B6EA19B707C4E825ECA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an explanation of why an extension is necessary for the orderly implementation of this Act;</text></clause><clause id="H4355C10409A5468494AC5A315C741CAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the period during which the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall continue providing services under the authority of this subparagraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H8342D7EA1FC2421AA692FA9A12CE4C5F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the steps that will be taken to ensure an orderly and timely implementation of this Act during the period described in clause (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H574447BE1F9E4EA1B454329D3A2EF500"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition period defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the <term>transition period</term> is the period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act and ends on the date on which the first Director is appointed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10DD9550085542328FD098465DF12CB0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limit on length of period of interim authorities</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget may not exercise any authority under this subsection after the expiration of the 24-month period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77EA7E96CBF64420933E56AD5F9DA47C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated from the Trust Fund such sums as may be necessary to carry out the activities of the Office for fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H830E315721F549F68921FAA3E9F0980D"><enum>II</enum><header>State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund</header><section id="H5FB1E06A81F14E41818198B580425185"><enum>201.</enum><header>State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund</header><subsection id="H6E1F258BC13640E7834B4EDC3A53BBEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H813FE8A854DD4C10B843FF50DC90BA2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>There is hereby appropriated to the Trust Fund $2,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2032. </text></subsection><subsection id="H8F392D0DD3944FFBBDED29E776AC4D90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Trust Fund shall be used to make payments and allocations under the Program and to carry out the activities of the Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H11B9C6D3C3CB4B12AA88D9BFEF5E9086"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acceptance of gifts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office may accept gifts or bequests for deposit into the Trust Fund.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H5AF38B99E4484129AF3650B2BF73DB98"><enum>III</enum><header>General Provisions</header><section id="HE96155E6EA824902B8C415B590F19C70"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H1FAFCBF9AB324FF9854E6091AF367639"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>chief State election official</term> has the meaning given such term in section 253(e) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21003">52 U.S.C. 21003(e)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC311D90665634F45BAA7D39293304540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71572B1661EF4085B208C3CCD0553355"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Indian lands</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HF55AF538C1394DF9BF59B5A3438E4DFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian country, as defined under section 1151 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7C47C16E0A84B5EB04BEC3BD3B55520"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any land in Alaska owned, pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), by an Indian Tribe that is a Native village (as defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)) or by a Village Corporation that is associated with an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H305BB5B293184A23B2697572ECC8F6A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any land on which the seat of the Tribal government is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0466F38F0EB241588AAA0C9B92DD9298"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any land that is part or all of a Tribal designated statistical area associated with an Indian Tribe, or is part or all of an Alaska Native village statistical area associated with an Indian Tribe, as defined by the Census Bureau for the purposes of the most recent decennial census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FA6AA126B96443F83683BD938495073"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Democracy Advancement and Innovation established under section 105.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA273CB76D4413880E1175EB7A2B704" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Democracy Advancement and Innovation Program established under section 101. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA14CEF9B1546DE99EDC2795704B867"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74EDCFA6E702491587D270E3DCF0DD4E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>Trust Fund</term> means the State Election Assistance and Innovation Trust Fund established under section 201.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1DFDCD438A2044AFBB21D686442432D5"><enum>302.</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding calculation of deadlines</header><subsection id="HF73E9D06577E4FA5AC0E244B4EA0AC75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the calculation of any period of time for the purposes of a deadline in this Act, the last day of the period shall be included in such calculation, unless such day is a Saturday, a Sunday, or a legal public holiday, in which case the period of such deadline shall be extended until the end of the next day which is not a Saturday, a Sunday, a legal public holiday.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1249F545D39943C2A61AEF5C7C0DC4B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal public holiday defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the term <quote>legal public holiday</quote> means a day described in section 6103(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD6576FEA6AFE43DF8A6CE612F52CBEBE"><enum>303.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or any amendment made by this Act, or the application of any such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of such Act and amendments made by such Act and the application of such provision or amendment to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding. </text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

