<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A02DB191F304710A5DBC3DFAE00EC1E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8016 IH: Federal Columbia River Power System Certainty Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8016</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220609">June 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. Rodgers of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for operations of the Federal Columbia River Power System pursuant to a certain operation plan for a specified period of time, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC9F9A3B531DF450C9550532A7D4EF88A" style="OLC"><section id="H37034933B7BE4EC2A41E935104D94976" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Columbia River Power System Certainty Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H62FBDF49D3364DC4AEA44253042AAB7D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H612866C767724A59B7A4C42464C122B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FCRPS</header><text>The term <quote>FCRPS</quote> means those portions of the Federal Columbia River Power System that are the subject of the Supplemental Opinion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F2D73310DB54507886F779DD5AB082D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <quote>Secretaries</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H52AA87F28DED4437A404E41B4642BA4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0CA7A6E07794B75BF35BB29E650B368"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Bonneville Power Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8379D8E84A7B43D58AAE929D9BDDD878"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA06A63A666467DB495B1EE6A6D7FBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplemental opinion</header><text>The term <quote>Supplemental Opinion</quote> means the document titled <quote>Columbia River System Operations Environmental Impact Statement Record of Decision</quote>, and dated September 2020.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H39D353E3A40F417A80F87C476B94C8EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Operation of FCRPS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretaries shall operate the FCRPS in a manner consistent with the reasonable and prudent alternative set forth in the Supplemental Opinion.</text></section><section id="HD6EE9505F3ED49CCA81025B88AFCB84B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendments to supplemental opinion</header><subsection id="H440D4C78B1E1430AA671EA48283213E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3, the Secretaries may amend portions of the Supplemental Opinion and operate the FCRPS in accordance with such amendments if all of the Secretaries determine, in the sole discretion of each Secretary, that—</text><paragraph id="H0233825E504F46D885F185DB1B94CAFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amendment is necessary for public safety or transmission and grid reliability; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6CE07BD9A52415E83EC2F1421F707FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the actions, operations, or other requirements that the amendment would remove are no longer warranted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H527943EE009D4935BDF6C7029109D8E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restriction on amendments</header><text>The process described in subsection (a) shall be the only method by which the Secretaries may operate the FCRPS in any way that is not consistent with the reasonable and prudent alternative set forth in the Supplemental Opinion.</text></subsection></section><section id="HAA22FA3BDFC34224BA8535AF68E07DEF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on restricting FCRPS electrical generation; clarification</header><subsection id="H61A3EB10324C4CA3AF0341BF65C5F8C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restricting FCRPS electrical generation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No structural modification, action, study, or engineering plan that restricts electrical generation at any FCRPS hydroelectric dam, or that limits navigation on the Snake River in the State of Washington, Oregon, or Idaho, shall proceed unless such proposal is specifically and expressly authorized by a Federal statute enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6BEE43248C064F7CAD02077EF9517F57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Nothing in this section affects or interferes with the authority of the Secretaries to conduct operation and maintenance activities or make capital improvements necessary to meet authorized project purposes of FCRPS facilities.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

