<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF49A1AC08F9A42C291338CBEF817539C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6831 IH: To require the Commandant of the Coast Guard to issue regulations for amphibious passenger vessels operating in waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6831</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Commandant of the Coast Guard to issue regulations for amphibious passenger vessels operating in waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFEFE86488FD04DFAA2E5C61C6D38A581" style="OLC"><section id="HF943BB9537924A4AA402B2D8815B0B66" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requirements for amphibious passenger vessels</header><subsection id="H5736482EA9854056BA823B59E4C4CB27" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall issue regulations for amphibious passenger vessels operating in waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, as defined in section 2.38 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAA0330A4EA8A4ECD9D744774D723D590" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for compliance</header><text>The regulations issued under subsection (a) shall take effect not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE29F94CB5F204B6482A938ED840F72BC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H7E4016F095DE4CDDB5C9F0D410E91A1D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A requirement that operators of amphibious passenger vessels provide reserve buoyancy for such vessels through passive means, including watertight compartmentalization, built-in flotation, or such other means as determined appropriate by the Commandant, in order to ensure that such vessels remain afloat and upright in the event of flooding, including when carrying a full complement of passengers and crew.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9416F7A15B0D4A218D0DC7941DA9DBA4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A requirement that an operator of an amphibious passenger vessel—</text><subparagraph id="HF22CE1D9D7BD47088A16BF70EC548D2F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review and notate the forecast of the National Weather Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in the logbook of the vessel before getting underway and periodically while underway;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A5F9DE0B57445CD9F59C86604D59B3D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proceed to the nearest harbor or safe refuge in any case in which a watch or warning is issued for wind speeds exceeding the wind speed equivalent used to certify the stability of such amphibious passenger vessel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13C86AAE364742ECBEDFC57EA7EABDFF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain and monitor a weather monitor radio receiver at the operator station of the vessel that is capable of being automatically activated by the warning alarm device of the National Weather Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10FF118ADE77410F87C25C45EE9E34DC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A requirement that—</text><subparagraph id="HAA704B86B75B44529AA2156E04E424E4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operators of amphibious passenger vessels inform passengers that seat belts may not be worn during waterborne operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0872E338B2F040E1B670FB187B000C78" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before the commencement of waterborne operations, a crew member shall visually check that the seatbelt of each passenger is unbuckled; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8AB85CBF874433D87FCA3243ACAC636" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operators or crew maintain a log recording the actions described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43B394D206314B79B0309E3D3988214C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A requirement for annual training for operators and crew of amphibious passengers vessels, including—</text><subparagraph id="H15D5F775ADA14165959C8F1F6566BC7F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training for personal flotation and seat belt requirements, verifying the integrity of the vessel at the onset of each waterborne departure, identification of weather hazards, and use of National Weather Service resources prior to operation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF85A4DB11EF048A7885B2CA9129B3075" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training for crew to respond to emergency situations, including flooding, engine compartment fires, man-overboard situations, and in water emergency egress procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5A296051DF143E6A4B9ADC2D185678E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing the regulations required under subsection (a), the Commandant shall consider whether personal flotation devices should be required for the duration of the waterborne transit of an amphibious passenger vessel.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBDB8CF05DCB64BDCB5EA2E550FC79D20" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interim requirements</header><text>Beginning on the date on which the regulations under subsection (a) are issued, the Commandant shall require that operators of amphibious passenger vessels that are not in compliance with such regulations shall be subject to the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="HE5DB0E924946445B9930AF17A235DECA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Remove the canopies and any window coverings of such vessels for waterborne operations, or install in such vessels a canopy that does not restrict horizontal or vertical escape by passengers in the event of flooding or sinking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FC9B9C303FD4DC48301033191E7A1F2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a canopy and window covering are removed from any such vessel pursuant to paragraph (1), require that all passengers wear a personal flotation device approved by the Coast Guard before the onset of waterborne operations of such vessel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H242C094FCA184F929CC8FE7C8A5C590D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Reengineer such vessels to permanently close all unnecessary access plugs and reduce all through-hull penetrations to the minimum number and size necessary for operation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB605612A89940D8B9D3E1D11CD8FA58" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Install in such vessels independently powered electric bilge pumps that are capable of dewatering such vessels at the volume of the largest remaining penetration in order to supplement an operable Higgins pump or a dewatering pump of equivalent or greater capacity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EEFACBA18644FF2B64E2F5763357D18" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Install in such vessels not fewer than 4 independently powered bilge alarms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC390456BBD439EA9C3C3D1243E442F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Conduct an in-water inspection of any such vessel after each time a through-hull penetration of such vessel has been removed or uncovered.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB030D9C7CB421E82BBBFF0D1D4832D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Verify through an in-water inspection the watertight integrity of any such vessel at the outset of each waterborne departure of such vessel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CDD7B88890E4FD18AB2D90007B014A2" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Install underwater LED lights that activate automatically in an emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E0382A145194C2A9F8EC49480115EAA" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Otherwise comply with any other provisions of the circular titled <quote>Navigation and Vessel Inspection Circular 1–01</quote> in the inspection, configuration, and operation of such vessels.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

