<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57459EF44E174B229FCD301B5F3C029E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7339 IH: Responsible, Better Understanding of Infrastructure Leveraged Dollars Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of the Special Inspector General for Infrastructure Projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6FEC556F48964D43944F53C6F61B35E3" style="OLC"><section id="HC5FB4091B65044138ABEA414C28B0C34" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsible, Better Understanding of Infrastructure Leveraged Dollars Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Responsible BUILD Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA476697E423940808E5C9E3C354B5116"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special Inspector General for infrastructure projects</header><subsection id="HC4610D1EEAD842FE8D7091B84085AED3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB99F4A8D436448279B01376AD647380D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA2AF917B1FDD4944A937CF8548E86528"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations, Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Environment and Public Works, and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H906447672B4A4F85A0B529711B127BEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committees on Appropriations, Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2B4097A36214E01928E3F3A873FD906"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered program</quote> means any program established by the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to the Infrastructure Investments and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), including the amendments made by such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2538350E7A8B4376AD1693A54D0FF34C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text>The term <quote>Inspector General</quote> means the Special Inspector General for Infrastructure Projects established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9E7872B4A6B47B28A47250F6BAC7FA0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <quote>Office</quote> means the Office of the Special Inspector General for Infrastructure Projects established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16EEEB94BB44BD5AF07FAAEB2B1099B" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6926D290A6964F9D9DF2739C4D156011" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any of the several States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3381F9A91BD4EB1B0ABD25E8248C0D8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5C00E9051A7464682E9178895921CEE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72AAB0AA685A4D909A74E70934CACAB6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C27CC11F5E1407B853D233074CF558A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Virgin Islands;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A5E073747414EAEAA3826C9DA0B72B4" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Guam;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABEDEBCA08E149FDBD58AF320BEE3E23" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>American Samoa; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H878A156E563E4EC2B0E7B8B456376FCF" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5D5402F95164DFF9488543B8E721C46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Department of Transportation the Office of the Special Inspector General for Infrastructure Projects to—</text><paragraph id="H1A8D31CCA8194BE998A1A422C4BE0B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for the independent and objective supervision of projects carried out under a covered program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A1F8D2F986409A854D2A8218A57C94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide for the independent and objective leadership and coordination of, and recommendations on, policies designed to—</text><subparagraph id="HA366FD2C9EA54872854D4D9518B0AB23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote economic efficiency and effectiveness in the administration of the covered programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65A880F97E9245268AADF14AE06317E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse in such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1369161E1BFA473D8DDF5F70C959A0C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointment of inspector general; removal</header><paragraph id="H0284700D4C484338B467685EB5BC8597"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Office shall be the Special Inspector General for Infrastructure Projects, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA56BED9DB4A948748E1DAE3AA9696AD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The appointment of the Inspector General shall be made solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CD969DFF73D44259E3E6F54A52B9156"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline for Appointment</header><text>The appointment of an individual as Inspector General shall be made not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB98233C7C4E749B2914A5617CE274881"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The annual rate of basic pay of the Inspector General shall be the annual rate of basic pay provided for positions at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A897315528B4C0594E69B91F5A6B95B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition on political activities</header><text>For purposes of section 7324 of title 5, United States Code, the Inspector General shall not be considered an employee who determines policies to be pursued by the United States in the nationwide administration of Federal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D6913139EA34232A08B023FF2F96535"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Inspector General shall be removable from office in accordance with the provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /3">section 3(b)</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CA0ED3973B34BF19E47C9428709D782"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supervision</header><paragraph id="H26D5976B022C4B80A97060F0BDD4F716"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Inspector General shall report directly to, and be under the general supervision of, the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H145C8A21F8254BCB819682B6F9F054A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independence to conduct investigations and audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No officer of the Department of Transportation shall prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation related to amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out a covered program, or from issuing any subpoena during the course of any such audit or investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E55DDBC98064D0FBA5499E3C97506EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="HC7443F243CDB4E8F8518A303AD93C238"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Oversight of spending by the department and states</header><text>The Inspector General shall conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations of the treatment, handling, and expenditure of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out a covered program, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6E3F952A03AA4026BBB3D54150789263"><enum>(A)</enum><text>audits and investigations with respect to—</text><clause id="HB15BD4AF4BF04914AD14A5267D1262FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the oversight and accounting of the obligation and expenditure of such amounts;</text></clause><clause id="H904AC0EF47064211AC738B90ABC9EBA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the monitoring and review of—</text><subclause id="HF5A75A36F08C4A1B90F8759BD55AB926"><enum>(I)</enum><text>activities funded by such amounts;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD093F880BB874D3EB31EEA498FC489BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>contracts funded by such amounts; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H89FF37F6F22B48C1AC6C1116C735D32F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the transfer of such amounts from States to other entities, including businesses and nongovernmental entities;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE16C2AB0D92A401F98DC5F5B949BE0A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the maintenance of records by States on the use of such amounts to facilitate future audits and investigations;</text></clause><clause id="HBE2EF75A1D1B47D7B62ACFEFEF7FB69B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>overpayments, such as duplicate payments or duplicate billing; and</text></clause><clause id="H96C0AF7F6C5D44F4B65D60F7BEC722CF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any potential unethical or illegal actions of Federal employees or employees of States, contractors, or nongovernmental entities related to the treatment, handling, obligation, or expenditure of such amounts; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB919DE089A4D4082866AD0ECA9CF7E09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the referral of findings of any audits and investigations to the Department of Justice to ensure further investigations, prosecutions, recovery of funds, or other remedies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33CE448FEC94452988928E8111DA44DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other duties related to oversight</header><text>The Inspector General shall establish, maintain, and oversee such systems, procedures, and controls as the Inspector General considers appropriate to carry out the duties under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D35EF683A0456FAA0DFB791CAD6597"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties and responsibilities under Inspector General Act of 1978</header><text>Section 4 of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Office established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65CAEFD195CE4ECB8315997A191DB672"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Powers and authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties specified in subsection (e), the Inspector General shall have the authorities provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /6">section 6</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></subsection><subsection id="H30B2A6D3973448C2A0F33DD334BB0625"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Personnel, facilities, and other resources</header><paragraph id="HA4D13BFC57EA4CF7B9C50812E0D7B0CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>The Inspector General may select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the duties of the Office, subject to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9D4D74FF1B145AB81C4B2E531CC46C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employment of experts and consultants</header><text>The Inspector General may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, at daily rates not to exceed the equivalent rate prescribed for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule by section 5332 of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA09ADC3C3382487384E0DDCAD8881426"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><text>To the extent, and in such amounts, as may be provided in advance by appropriations Acts, the Inspector General may enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private persons, and make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31177E5844A14C93BDB4A0A0C39B4132"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance from federal agencies</header><subparagraph id="H88188D95E4724A17BC6A46FDF902133D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request of the Inspector General for information or assistance from any department, agency, or other entity of a State or the Federal Government, the head of such entity shall, insofar as is practicable and not in contravention of any existing law, furnish such information or assistance to the Inspector General, or a designee of the Inspector General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0963B80818654C67913FAFCFEFB7B6D8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting of refused assistance</header><text>Whenever information or assistance requested by the Inspector General is, in the judgment of the Inspector General, unreasonably refused or not provided, the Inspector General shall report the circumstances to the Department of Justice, as appropriate, and to the appropriate congressional committees without delay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90D32EE245224326858416DB10435C50"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HFBEFAFDFD4904AA0A8DD31FB803F298C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><subparagraph id="H4919A2993CB34941B800E1A38E5ECE75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal-year quarter, the Inspector General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Secretary of Transportation a report summarizing, for the period of such quarter and, to the extent possible, the period from the end of such quarter to the time of the submission of the report, the activities during such period of the Inspector General and any activities of States that are carried out pursuant to a covered program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19E4DEF769ED4B3597979DAC509787CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by such report, a detailed statement of all obligations, expenditures, and revenues associated with a covered program, including the following:</text><clause id="H6A9F963257E54700BC9260FEDDBFDBF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Obligations and expenditures of amounts made available to carry out a covered program.</text></clause><clause id="H5F23C3350329438CB1938C9235428AC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Detailed operating expenses of States that are related to the use of such amounts.</text></clause><clause id="HC5BA52CB52C54EC88F02C87BA0DA156D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In the case of any contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism described in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause id="HE5057C2ED5EC44D3945E3A36FFCC431C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism;</text></subclause><subclause id="H733D5DB82A8141CD8717425872F4031B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a brief summary of the scope of the contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D2E803248554B6897FB666E447907EB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a summary of how the State involved in the contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism identified, and solicited offers or applications from, potential individuals or entities to perform the contract or activities under the grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5584A3554A024EEC9CBF796156D026E0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a list of the potential individuals or entities that were issued solicitations for the offers or applications; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H251092D072E14186BE70B0D58B9BF944"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the justification and approval documents on which was based any determination to use procedures other than procedures that provide for full and open competition with respect to the contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4EBA314A764EF5B12DCF3015545333"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered contracts, grants, agreements, and funding mechanisms</header><text>A contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism described in this paragraph is any major contract, grant, agreement, or other funding mechanism with any public or private entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H518EC1FF1ABF43AF8B70B631D79DD19D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entered into by a State—</text><clause id="HC99CE1CE42FB4991A5178D11837E5C3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to build or rebuild physical infrastructure, including infrastructure related to bridges, roads, highways, waterways, ports, rail travel, or air travel of such State; or</text></clause><clause id="H48A775D7328F40F2A5EC6B5E1F8786A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide products or services to the people of such State; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEFA30C696945F3906DB359F4031484"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involves the use of amounts made available to carry out a covered program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA834983198B4E34B8E2DF2A7FE8D2A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of report comments to congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receipt of a report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Transportation may submit to the appropriate congressional committees any comments on the matters covered by the report the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA65EFF6E4CA24902BBF3F27CAF997767"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General and the Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, shall publish on a publicly available website each report required under this subsection and any comments submitted by the Secretary under paragraph (3). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD72E248E0E4F4DE194129C2DA54025DE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under this subsection, including any comments on a report submitted by the Secretary of Transportation under paragraph (3), shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if the Inspector General or the Secretary, as appropriate, considers it necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF90BD5AAA41E4215A345A4006A2AEFA0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the public disclosure of information that is—</text><subparagraph id="H8DD5FF8150D64F3CAE666FB768D5ED3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81CB1D9674CA4807A02365C15209D6A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically required by Executive order to be protected from disclosure in the interest of national defense or national security or in the conduct of foreign affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0085939BC0748CA96035A4C17E528EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a part of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBADBC6B7498442209705A1BDF9F8EBA5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 for each fiscal year to carry out this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="HCC3199FE2F4C4350AD539EA5D0D6E800"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Office of the Special Inspector General shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

