<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00EF9F9CD8FC4CA3B8BA39C34274DAA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6465 IH: Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6465</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001084">Ms. Herrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit discrimination against the unborn on the basis of sex, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H73BCE3B1E7354CA39F04F63BED21C283" style="OLC"><section id="H063D94F3C8D746D5B2E3FD0E12C19787" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRENDA Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H98C78C4399FD4D6DAE4870AEFFE68E87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and constitutional authority</header><subsection id="H03E82BC837464990B50EEA76F94113B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HE5EF416D526F43ACB7697C68EDDA7284"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Women and girls possess the same fundamental human rights and civil rights as men and are essential to the formation of stable, peaceful societies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5774EA6F728144B18D621F1B5297287C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 126,000,000 women and girls are missing from the world population due to systematic violence against women and girls, particularly sex-selection abortions, according to the United Nations Population Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC14E1383DA034C7085ED0DB8E2AA2F2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>United States law prohibits the dissimilar treatment of males and females who are similarly situated and prohibits sex discrimination in various contexts, including the provision of employment, education, housing, health insurance coverage, and athletics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE01E30326664B85BBCF8CEB33FE3E15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A <quote>sex-selection abortion</quote> is an abortion undertaken for purposes of eliminating an unborn child of an undesired sex. Sex-selection abortion is described by scholars and civil rights advocates as an act of sex-based or gender-based violence, predicated on sex discrimination. By definition, sex-selection abortions do not implicate the health of the mother of the unborn, but instead are elective procedures motivated by sex or gender bias.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49F8980886C2437BA0D2A707DDB398B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The targeted victims of sex-selection abortions performed in the United States and worldwide are overwhelmingly female.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H141FB373F2024B8D9A7D7E277AB5D8E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Sex-selection abortions are not expressly prohibited by United States law, and only 7 States ban abortions for reason of sex selection at some point in pregnancy. Sex is an immutable characteristic ascertainable at the earliest stages of human development through existing medical technology and procedures commonly in use, including maternal-fetal bloodstream DNA sampling, am­nio­cen­te­sis, chorionic villus sampling or <term>CVS</term>, and obstetric ultrasound.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB142D51883AF49499BAE28B69C3378A5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Sex-selection abortions have the effect of diminishing the representation of women in the American population, and therefore, the American electorate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9C8C9F4183B4EADB5DEFFC7E04F1A2F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Sex-selection abortions reinforce sex discrimination and have no place in a civilized society.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H441860D408F145B1BCD3ACD71E545CBE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The history of the United States includes many examples of sex discrimination. The people of the United States ultimately responded in the strongest possible legal terms by enacting a constitutional amendment correcting an element of this discrimination. Women, once subjected to sex discrimination that denied them the right to vote, now have suffrage guaranteed by the 19th Amendment. The elimination of discriminatory practices has been and is among the highest priorities and greatest achievements of American history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H035FF6DC8AD6464DBADA549F5EED891F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Implicitly approving the discriminatory practices of sex-selection abortion by choosing not to prohibit them will reinforce sex discrimination, and coarsen society to the value of females. Thus, Congress has a compelling interest in acting—indeed it must act—to prohibit sex-selection abortion.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD60B58ECAA324A649CC4DB74FE31E4AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Constitutional authority</header><text>In accordance with the above findings, Congress enacts the following pursuant to Congress’ power under—</text><paragraph id="H63811DE719B248FD8DAE24FD79503702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Commerce Clause;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9546D3CAAB5C4053A165AF861D8C90CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 5 of the 14th Amendment, including the power to enforce the prohibition on government action denying equal protection of the laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H402371CB44B9487084ED7DF122E26BD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 8 of article I to make all laws necessary and proper for the carrying into execution of powers vested by the Constitution in the Government of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6B058E92CFC146B29870E2EECED53E61"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discrimination against the unborn on the basis of sex</header><subsection id="H71CDA7D0C65E45349DD290F0BB43B4B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF92F3672A2B24C43A542CDC162413C79" style="USC"><section id="HFF8707404F4A4B2091CDB230A9B0BD83"><enum>250.</enum><header>Discrimination against the unborn on the basis of sex</header><subsection id="HDE1AC052E32F44D096F6472AC5818855"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whoever knowingly—</text><paragraph id="H5EA9943CBB4A42E4858BB1C0A7638816"><enum>(1)</enum><text>performs an abortion knowing that such abortion is sought based on the sex or gender of the child;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBCF3B2015CF46D1B11A6734165CF886"><enum>(2)</enum><text>uses force or the threat of force to intentionally injure or intimidate any person for the purpose of coercing a sex-selection abortion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55409655AA6A4835A6183757414AEED4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solicits or accepts funds for the performance of a sex-selection abortion; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E3984E851274049B84FD3E5B270FCFB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>transports a woman into the United States or across a State line for the purpose of obtaining a sex-selection abortion,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">or attempts to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both. </continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HC9C97F38EC4346CDB2179A7114A14B7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header><paragraph id="H33F3AE005814441EB8D05FE3BB0A9737"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action by woman on whom abortion is performed</header><text>A woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted in violation of subsection (a)(2) may in a civil action against any person who engaged in a violation of subsection (a) obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48436BD092D447F4A41A16CF31777E8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action by relatives</header><text>The father of an unborn child who is the subject of an abortion performed or attempted in violation of subsection (a), or a maternal grandparent of the unborn child if the pregnant woman is an unemancipated minor, may in a civil action against any person who engaged in the violation, obtain appropriate relief, unless the pregnancy or abortion resulted from the plaintiff’s criminal conduct or the plaintiff consented to the abortion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75C4EB1AB0C14E5C9A792BA5DC72ED58"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><text>Appropriate relief in a civil action under this subsection includes—</text><subparagraph id="H1F458C5366DC48A1A472FD3FE9918A88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damages for all injuries, psychological and physical, including loss of companionship and support, occasioned by the violation of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AD4708DBF104121B214DD6EFF02AABD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2C1C290B0A41F2AE1379E0B2FE2938"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header><subparagraph id="H0F0967BA094A451F8057CB507605F756"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified plaintiff may in a civil action obtain injunctive relief to prevent an abortion provider from performing or attempting further abortions in violation of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DC62F6B337A4A20907B60D8A55A6F1C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph the term <term>qualified plaintiff</term> means—</text><clause id="HED48839C1C844A03BBD0A2414BCCC8AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a woman upon whom an abortion is performed or attempted in violation of this section;</text></clause><clause id="HD9FF1CFC77574415800D2ACFBF62C0E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a maternal grandparent of the unborn child if the woman upon whom an abortion is performed or attempted in violation of this section is an unemancipated minor;</text></clause><clause id="HF3694A6459194D59978578A37E787EE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the father of an unborn child who is the subject of an abortion performed or attempted in violation of subsection (a); or</text></clause><clause id="H4BDFC7EA03BF49C29D49EDA9C32D0F3A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Attorney General.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64B29B18D65B412FAB8B2D152198DB88"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Attorneys fees for plaintiff</header><text>The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0221F82757404750AC5FFEF3B538CEA8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bar to prosecution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A woman upon whom a sex-selection abortion is performed may not be prosecuted or held civilly liable for any violation of this section, or for a conspiracy to violate under this section, for a conspiracy to violate this section, or for an offense under section 2, 3, or 4 of this title based on a violation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A60270B0EB54DA096E6E71EC8803224"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Loss of Federal funding</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be deemed for the purposes of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to be discrimination prohibited by section 601 of that Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67CA9EEE013345CFA48431AB74E94961"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician, physician’s assistant, nurse, counselor, or other medical or mental health professional shall report known or suspected violations of any of this section to appropriate Federal, State, and local law enforcement authorities. Whoever violates this requirement shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02C72EF6E03F4D8E9BE97950AAA89D47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expedited consideration</header><text>It shall be the duty of the United States district courts, United States courts of appeal, and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H513278CD30DF414598EB9C1C5AC9E07B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Protection of privacy in court proceedings</header><paragraph id="HCFD82DCD919F4883B89D6C241CD841CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except to the extent the Constitution or other similarly compelling reason requires, in every civil or criminal action under this section, the court shall make such orders as are necessary to protect the anonymity of any woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted if she does not give her written consent to such disclosure. Such orders may be made upon motion, but shall be made sua sponte if not otherwise sought by a party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H093D42FFE0C0411CB41BDF7FCCF94E26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Orders to parties, witnesses, and counsel</header><text>The court shall issue appropriate orders to the parties, witnesses, and counsel and shall direct the sealing of the record and exclusion of individuals from courtrooms or hearing rooms to the extent necessary to safeguard the identity of the woman described in paragraph (1) from public disclosure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6732195E85A84B59B3CB1EFD31401928"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pseudonym required</header><text>In the absence of written consent of the woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted, any party, other than a public official, who brings an action under this section shall do so under a pseudonym.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15C630770DC14B3DB7F123AA055AB1B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subsection shall not be construed to conceal the identity of the plaintiff or of witnesses from the defendant or from attorneys for the defendant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0E63127943E4B888CA1F6CC2C0548D4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H6ADE4B4B41024523B66C64CC2BF5055A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>abortion</term> means the act of using or prescribing any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance, device, or means with the intent to—</text><subparagraph id="H59459105DF5C42FDB956171067D2113E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E46B65DE1C640449DC36868DD42A49D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="HEEFF9B91C16045CF9D7DAEC3CD00C9DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text></clause><clause id="H57AE0E9CCF56409EB683A39EDC183A9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7749539408AF4C31AE0F4646B6BCD7EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>sex-selection abortion</term> means an abortion undertaken for purposes of eliminating an unborn child of an undesired sex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H450F479F8ECB4423962B3F6290B793A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 249 the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="HA2F38539A30746CA828117EE64728890" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">250. Discrimination against the unborn on the basis of sex.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H6DBDE27FDFDE4F5D966506CE3D1933E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any portion of this Act or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, such invalidity shall not affect the portions or applications of this Act which can be given effect without the invalid portion or application.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

