<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA8A33CF2E6624FFCA84E7503DD3EC340" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8059 IH: Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8059</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out certain activities to improve recycling and composting programs in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28879BBE4937428A96E244DDF875EC18" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC89FE82215614B96B9F74C08E44860A4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB9456A9D717D4B23960DF024F60C76AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H5E5F8407FD8044ABBFB8D107F89DEA32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H68ED26023E384FD58E4CC73D9325AC9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2870A979CEB4C359362384B83AA2519"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circular market</header><text>The term <term>circular market</term> means a market that utilizes industrial processes and economic activities to enable post-industrial and post-consumer materials used in those processes and activities to maintain their highest values for as long as possible. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C6FF420C626473B88DAA14BB838858F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compost</header><text>The term <term>compost</term> means a product that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB449A2D1EBD94F298DC6EBFF40A5B635"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is manufactured through the controlled aerobic, biological decomposition of biodegradable materials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4FBE09E9B8AD4B18BAEB7F76B14E2031"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been subjected to medium and high temperature organisms, which—</text> <clause id="H621EDAE947D046C6AA8477A52F63DA26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>significantly reduce the viability of pathogens and weed seeds; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H82B2D39937154D589E575E3B0CB02E24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stabilize carbon in the product such that the product is beneficial to plant growth; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB41BA0CA060F40F597E2D4C0E0EF05D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is typically used as a soil amendment, but may also contribute plant nutrients.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44EDF9FA6D0C4CA3AE7F16DDFD678859"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compostable material</header><text>The term <term>compostable material</term> means material that is a feedstock for creating compost, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4827608C67A740D98687F2DAF313C026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wood; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F75D9B285D44D50820C6B9ADD37CDC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agricultural crops; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6794423CF63A456BAF6AFBE58C71F383"><enum>(C)</enum><text>paper;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE3DEBE3D32E4C1C9E33C5956F6B9F34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>certified compostable products associated with organic waste;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02908674B3504D958345ECDA768CAB15"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other organic plant material; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7977CCC3C8D49B9AF3E937FF8800137"><enum>(F)</enum><text>marine products;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8177C2A9A40494AB69B3787BFD24990"><enum>(G)</enum><text>organic waste, including food waste and yard waste; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CE18694DF464BF5B3F26D59DC00CCE6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>such other material that is composed of biomass that can be continually replenished or renewed, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00B90F9C87F94EF6A6A4101F8DB43554"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Composting facility</header><text>The term <term>composting facility</term> means a location, structure, or device that transforms compostable materials into compost.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDD66518E5D24527ADDA83C2DCED2567"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C863953D44B446F93787FCDBD89D3B0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Materials recovery facility</header> <subparagraph id="H538155D7E9364A5CA83896E379479D04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>materials recovery facility</term> means a dedicated facility where primarily residential recyclable materials, which are diverted from disposal by the generator and collected separately from municipal solid waste, are mechanically or manually sorted into commodities for further processing into specification-grade commodities for sale to end users.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84DAE5067F24410D9AC2C6F4DA798819"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>materials recovery facility</term> does not include a solid waste management facility that may process municipal solid waste to remove recyclable materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C9459F59E394F0887DE00CD87325D12"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recyclable material</header><text>The term <term>recyclable material</term> means a material that is obsolete, previously used, off-specification, surplus, or incidentally produced for processing into a specification-grade commodity for which a circular market currently exists or is being developed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2222A2C46954943B17C30B1A0D16171"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Recycling</header><text>The term <term>recycling</term> means the series of activities—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D068A63A5A34873B0B532E16C34EBBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during which recyclable materials are processed into specification-grade commodities, and consumed as raw-material feedstock, in lieu of virgin materials, in the manufacturing of new products;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB255A1DB4F584C188F99ECA13BCE5B50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may include sorting, collection, processing, and brokering; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BA8EBE6460443E584CC34DDF75BF350"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that result in subsequent consumption by a materials manufacturer, including for the manufacturing of new products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F284804C8764F3BA5563B35FC358F9F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1004 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6903">42 U.S.C. 6903</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A58736A25B34C26AC39D50EB4365FB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of processing</header><text>In paragraphs (7), (8), and (9) of subsection (a), the term <term>processing</term> means any mechanical, manual, or other method that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD92A8FC56D2B4410BF3AE0B621FFAA54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transforms a recyclable material into a specification-grade commodity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9B5FF22485E406FA69949371906950E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may occur in multiple steps, with different steps, including sorting, occurring at different locations. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE17300B6B9A94C098D35832B277600D2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HF446B3A5ED034B47B0EC65E166B136C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recycling and composting conserve resources, protect the environment, and are important to the United States economy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H949CF15760534009B3357E52FE7F084F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States recycling and composting infrastructure encompass each of the entities that collect, process, broker, and consume recyclable materials and compostable materials sourced from commercial, industrial, institutional, and residential sources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A22A5BEAAD2414D80BB5932F0B8C4C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the residential segment of the United States recycling and composting infrastructure is facing challenges from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE9DBE665D48B4110BCCBE67290E663F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confusion over what materials are recyclable materials or compostable materials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7A6C6E3934D4D1AAE3E9619D2A4F7F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced export markets; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EAC45754C564EF991D0058965A300B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>growing, but still limited, domestic end markets; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69C0CCDB92194085B06A8279E5AA1740"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an ever-changing and heterogeneous supply stream;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1963ECA08C204FECBCF5A8741231E032"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in some areas, recycling and composting infrastructure is in need of revitalization; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC5AD6FC275A4B35B345FB792829DA40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in an effort to address those challenges, the United States must use a combination of tactics to improve recycling and composting in the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HED5D6E66D1704B4E822D267932E8B58E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on composting infrastructure capabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8D9C2672C169434E8738DAEA7251D983"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare a report describing the capability of the United States to implement a national composting strategy for compostable materials for the purposes of reducing contamination rates for recycling, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2C89057AAF5B4594ABD2B60E5C3A645D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of existing Federal, State, and local laws that may present barriers to implementation of a national composting strategy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BA27CD5F9F04AD0AA8766671F0F647D"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9713EF9272CA436181E7B10041A03679"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an evaluation of existing composting programs of States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1574FC3B29604D8A945FD369F922DA7D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of best practices based on those programs;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H015A0CBF03BE46E8AC608552E4F8D115"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of existing composting infrastructure in States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes for the purposes of estimating cost and approximate land needed to expand composting programs; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49FAE19546E948D1AAA008BA63341D1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a study of the practices of manufacturers and companies that are moving to using compostable packaging and food service ware for the purpose of making the composting process the end-of-life use of those products; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H184B28255049403C9850A2E783FA3DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit the report prepared under paragraph (1) to Congress.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCA36609B64FC4820A4FABE12C35C86CD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on Federal agency recycling practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every two years thereafter until 2032, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Administrator, shall make publicly available a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HE0D72E0EBB2D4848A89A6D9141C409FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides information on the total annual recycling and composting rates reported by all Federal agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF798610ECFC14819B6B8CD69A65F570D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides information on the total annual percentage of products containing recyclable material, compostable material, or recovered materials purchased by all Federal agencies, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H481046EAC1C74A468DF7F26C1B6D695F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total quantity of procured products containing recyclable material or recovered materials listed in the comprehensive procurement guidelines published under section 6002(e) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6962">42 U.S.C. 6962(e)</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56A8D4B56A2C475B9749B8A16F7E285C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total quantity of compostable material purchased; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40AAE999D676459C8311F812360267F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes recommendations, as appropriate, for updating—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75D10622AE31441C87DD3789DC9D1168"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the comprehensive procurement guidelines published under section 6002(e) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6962">42 U.S.C. 6962(e)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6B3F520599C34BD18B7FFC62A801DEB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the environmentally preferable purchasing program established under section 6604(b)(11) of the Pollution Prevention Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13103">42 U.S.C. 13103(b)(11)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C145A6FA10745A8B76EE8E7043F9710"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes the activities of each Federal agency that promote recycling or composting.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEF783EB3F76D47B4B59014A133277AB4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Improving data and reporting</header> <subsection id="H23B3CE2C8AF94FCE957BFBA521577A4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inventory of materials recovery facilities</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Administrator, in consultation with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A198AEE2E8E460BADB39976BAB67B37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare an inventory of public and private materials recovery facilities in the United States, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HA7B632EB01184E91948633E16E39A6C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of materials recovery facilities in each unit of local government in each State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6ED450728C6949CB89BD1A17BF5271FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the materials that each materials recovery facility can process, including—</text> <clause id="H237697FE963A4C8C9E1111A96F4988E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of plastic, a description of—</text> 
<subclause id="H198CCA43218848B386FEADF3BFE0CFE1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the types of accepted resin, if applicable; and </text></subclause> <subclause id="H0B8A952976B941A8BDBBDA9D3FF36084"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the packaging or product format, such as a jug, a carton, or film; </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HA18BC7F47BF84C8492D50371D5179FDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>food packaging and service ware, such as a bottle, cutlery, or a cup;</text></clause> <clause id="HA8BE85A072204C9BAF782C68EB88DF4E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>paper;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA6D4F20C038747DCBF1C7295FAFFB3D8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>aluminum, such as an aluminum beverage can, food can, aerosol can, or foil; </text></clause> <clause id="HC89C34808B6D47F4B311D2FCEAAE3934"><enum>(v)</enum><text>steel, such as a steel food or aerosol can;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3FBDD6F59BA04EFE9FB7175D6FE371CE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other scrap metal;</text></clause> <clause id="HC54C08CD1E9B428487895D38EF2D4F12"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>glass; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9C307BF496E34549B5B6484104439EE6"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other material not described in any of clauses (i) through (vii) that a materials recovery facility can process; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB8040417E7A54F89A7D044FED7DAEC8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit the inventory prepared under paragraph (1) to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H284E0B7817EB464BA7DEE3EC767A39CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of a comprehensive baseline of data for the United States recycling system</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, shall determine, with respect to the United States—</text> <paragraph id="H766794166081498880B3D916044AEEAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of community curbside recycling and composting programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA905FF2238DE43E6A7E4E0EE7FD77789"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of community drop-off recycling and composting programs; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6228FA1E3A99485B854662FE48CAED64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the types and forms of materials accepted by each community curbside recycling, drop-off recycling, or composting program; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2815E3BACB214DC3A2D4A2A52B9E25E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of individuals with access to recycling and composting services to at least the extent of access to disposal services; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1FEC78DC99E496BA960B03E5A0D5A1E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of individuals with barriers to accessing recycling and composting services to at least the extent of access to disposal services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94FB0C6E06F34DDDBBBC3196DD38D688"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the inbound contamination and capture rates of community curbside recycling, drop-off recycling, or composting programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2976140BF714865BBD7AD856C89A54C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>where applicable, other available recycling or composting programs within a community, including store drop-offs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17E79726645A4A0FBAAEF5C0DED48880"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the average cost to States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes of recycling and composting programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BC467DACC6B42D5823BA70C282B31A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standardization of recycling reporting rates</header> <paragraph id="H23A8E566D3534241B5D4E185572D6D01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection of rates</header> <subparagraph id="H8BBA2BBC889247738B51F1A2E32565BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may use amounts made available under section 9 to biannually collect from each State the nationally standardized rate of recyclable materials in that State that have been successfully diverted from the waste stream and brought to a materials recovery facility or composting facility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CFEE59DB2A642D0831AD179A28B6F38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Confidential or proprietary business information</header><text>Information collected under subparagraph (A) shall not include any confidential or proprietary business information, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1B81E9FAC0A4BC48B07F89145C1270D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Using amounts made available under section 9, the Administrator may use the rates collected under paragraph (1) to further assist States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2E720D80C5774FE285D9F349F9B6C5BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reduce the overall waste produced by the States and units of local government; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79DC40EE4D464AAFBB6ABBB1F0C3AD84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to increase recycling and composting rates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C639983E8D54036A0A4D30E23E42F56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on end markets</header> 
<paragraph id="H224117B4D9B24D43B10C074272EB9CB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DDD78C77B8E4DFCBA20D283070AFC1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide an update to the report submitted under section 306 of the Save Our Seas 2.0 Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/224">Public Law 116–224</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 1096) to include an addendum on the end-market sale of all recyclable materials, in addition to recycled plastics as described in that section, from materials recovery facilities that process recyclable materials collected from households and publicly available recyclable materials drop-off centers, including—</text> 
<clause id="HC0E88FF7753F447D954AF78F3CA7E461"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total, in dollars per ton, domestic sales of bales of recyclable materials; and</text></clause> <clause id="H62429DC2397B47A3990CC38AD0414551"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total, in dollars per ton, international sales of bales of recyclable materials;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA1702ED7DF44C6580DA28CC13854B27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare a report on the end-market sale of compost from all compostable materials collected from households and publicly available compost drop-off centers, including the total, in dollars per ton, of domestic sales of compostable materials; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F2B5DB36BC64E8DBB287BEA40B571BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress the update to the report prepared under subparagraph (A) and the report prepared under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD3CD7CF77B347B993DEC75AB0E0F775"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidential or proprietary business information</header><text>Information collected under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) shall not include any confidential or proprietary business information, as determined by the Administrator. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCC4A5AA25D044563AEE6DB1614959D21"><enum>7.</enum><header>Study on the diversion of recyclable materials from a circular market</header> <subsection id="H60DAE14003B94C068D9971A355ED38A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop a metric for determining the proportion of recyclable materials in commercial and municipal waste streams that are being diverted from a circular market.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C4B9B1CDB314FDC806BAB64F99242C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study; report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the development of a metric under subsection (a), the Administrator shall conduct a study of, and submit to Congress a report on, the proportion of recyclable materials in commercial and municipal waste streams that, during each of the 10 calendar years preceding the year of submission of the report, were diverted from a circular market. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F7BE8202C054559A8D0062E2D9FD00F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The report under subsection (b) shall provide data on specific recyclable materials, including aluminum, plastics, paper and paperboard, textiles, and glass, that were prevented from remaining in a circular market through disposal or elimination, and to what use those specific recyclable materials were lost. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C93A289D371415EA9304E43C50EEE38"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The report under subsection (b) shall include an evaluation of whether the establishment or improvement of recycling programs would—</text> <paragraph id="HF1C9173FD12A448F9AEE4FB297C52C5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve recycling rates; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CF8C96066B74776B4DFA2FDDAA49BE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce the quantity of recyclable materials being unutilized in a circular market.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC2FDC2C412474E19A40D30E949AB095A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Voluntary guidelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H92FB131328C74F47B750837346BB943D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes, develop, based on the results of the studies, reports, inventory, and data determined under sections 4 through 7, and provide to States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes best practices that the States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes may use to enhance recycling and composting, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C9DE3D9CB3A40F992C1E56A510DC1C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>labeling techniques for containers of waste, compostable materials, and recycling, with the goal of creating consistent, readily available, and understandable labeling across jurisdictions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3220B5FCAC57443CBCD98CE76947D028"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pamphlets or other literature readily available to constituents;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9AD0D5701C84F2D8EB21171960ED81F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>primary and secondary school educational resources on recycling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67470E96709948A7B26B9AABED710A86"><enum>(D)</enum><text>web and media-based campaigns; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA40965B0FCB478A8CC07E50AF08B106"><enum>(E)</enum><text>guidance for the labeling of recyclable materials and compostable materials that minimizes contamination and diversion of those materials from waste streams toward recycling and composting systems; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07EB8BEF6EA34342BDC805967A39D80F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report describing the best practices developed under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD8AC3D22A86949D7B2AF148E68386FCA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act for each fiscal year.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

