<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB746CFB8DF34C32A4E7DA74CC678AB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8322 IH: Strengthening Tools to Obstruct and Prevent Fraud Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8322</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220711">July 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to establish the Federal Real Anti-fraud Unified Directorate, to require agencies implement anti-fraud controls for programs susceptible to significant improper payments and high-priority programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDE81D129DC84E568986C4F8755D4F1B" style="OLC"><section id="H90E087492E2441EF8699E7CF096A8F23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Tools to Obstruct and Prevent Fraud Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Fraud Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0E469F8EEB254CCEBB0BD2FB313364C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Real Anti-fraud Unified Directorate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDF506EA7FD7D46D7964B0FF956BDBAD7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H41057693CA6C4BB484DCD5C6D7F51D15"><enum>508.</enum><header>Federal Real Anti-fraud Unified Directorate</header><subsection id="HB8D4DEAF6DA7488787728AB68EE70A67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H872580ADFE4E45BBA446EB8C3B64CF39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Office of Management and Budget an office to be known as the Federal Real Anti-fraud Unified Directorate or the FRAUD. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8706E5F07C624E3E90781E3569C77F74" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be at the head of the FRAUD an Administrator who shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H24DE687D1CAD4E5FA38D679F54BC3C5B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appointed by the President; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB656F549F7464980A9A49F23D68530D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compensated at the rate of pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDCA7361C6094BFCAE6A6F7E02CC2007"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Administrator shall do the following:</text><paragraph id="HF5F0059D45E043E6A5D87CA4FD12EAC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Carry out the duties prescribed to the Administrator under section 3360.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45AF1FB08D11485BA6148365591A7A78" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coordinate activities related to reducing and preventing fraud and improper payments—</text><subparagraph id="H4332EAF5F4374804B81A3FFDFA4ADBCC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sharing leading practices and tools with agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6CF8A35DBD3483995AA7DBF286EBC49" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing technical assistance to agencies in implementing the fraud risk management activities described in the GAO Fraud Risk Management Framework; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10BE4B139D6E4C8DA596F006FEF6009B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting agencies in the collection and use of data, including by assisting agencies in—</text><clause id="HA26DA8301085451CBE56531EBA813B28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>working to overcome data sharing barriers; and</text></clause><clause id="HCCF44F175E54476685F304F8E48B72E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing metrics and methodologies to measure the effectiveness of programs and activities employed by agencies to prevent and reduce fraud and improper payments.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91C96B13484844E1A93309C672D39426"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establish an online, publicly accessible dashboard on the implementation of proactive analytics in programs designated as susceptible to significant improper payments under section 3359 that—</text><subparagraph id="H404F0B8BEAEA4117A3AD66839555BC8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes transparency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5731EDA077D0472BBFA4A286653AB2B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assists in the oversight of the implementation of proactive analytics in such programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BEB82C7A1724CCCA76814BCB8A957AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>tracks cost savings, cost avoidance, and the administrative burden attributable to such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7219D5D739740CA9924FF1C0C95E891" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Refer any fraud, waste, or abuse discovered by the Administrator to the appropriate Inspector General. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H261D9D9870174ACEA1C0C6B7F3835C3D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Carry out any additional duties that may be prescribed by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA670759E0F4A461DB627D093A1A7B6E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional authorities</header><text>The Administrator may—</text><paragraph id="HEC603FD206FF4E02B43C459D3CB08B54" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require agencies administering programs susceptible to significant improper payments to submit information as may be necessary to administer the dashboard required to be established by subsection (b)(3), and promulgate regulations that set standards for—</text><subparagraph id="H69831331A797474191C79ADBEAEF5025" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the type of information to be submitted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC39B30234DA242E6BCD8F09BBC7BF18E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the format in which such information is to be submitted;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E9A7C0FD714E09903F0E81E941C476" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to agencies administering a high-priority program, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H3B9EA487BC2C4719ADD20F5CA985E66F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>working on behalf of an agency administering the program to overcome any issues that prevent the agency from receiving or using data from other governmental and non-governmental entities, including by notifying Congress on behalf of the agency of any Federal laws that prevent the agency from receiving or using such data; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C66D783E74849BEA49C921FF9EB1174" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating the collection of real-time data to implement proactive analytics, including by—</text><clause id="H582D21975E8F4825A36B54C90DFC8A0C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying governmental or commercial solutions to facilitate such collection; and</text></clause><clause id="H49790654D580457887546FDB1A199F03" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supporting the agency in identifying potential sources of funding to facilitate such collection;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B4055A685EC478E958582E7B6A8A714" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing non-reimbursable or reimbursable services to agencies administering the programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D52961B22134251808836831EB0FE42" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying strategies that may help the program hire individuals with the requisite skills to implement proactive analytics; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6BA90CA0EF34D118076F0B29F150BEC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refer any fraud, waste, or abuse discovered by the Administrator to the appropriate Inspector General.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28B03DA1556C4555B3883A0709164E72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>administrative burden</term>, <term>agency administering a high-priority program</term>, <term>agency administering a program susceptible to significant improper payments</term>, <term>anti-fraud control</term>, <term>data</term>, and <term>proactive analytics</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3360.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7D86E622DCC74C7384DFC7E63CBFF041"><enum>3.</enum><header>Anti-fraud controls for programs susceptible to significant improper payments and high-priority programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H6DE38029531D40F38A71F636AFB7085F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HD7C97E8B107848C895F9AE0DD09AAA32"><enum>3359.</enum><header>Proactive analytics with respect to programs susceptible to significant improper payments</header><subsection id="H74DB5F95832144B88351B195C5995784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of programs susceptible to significant improper payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1 of each year, for that fiscal year and the next fiscal year, the head of each executive agency shall designate as a program susceptible significant improper payments each program that meets the following criteria: </text><paragraph id="HF5EAB6940B09477E81D688B025DF5A2B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect any program of the agency established during the preceding two fiscal years, any such program making more than $100,000,000 in payments in any one fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H784D5D79597E4290A37140CA6C532AC8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any program of the agency not established during the preceding two fiscal years, any such program that had outlays that exceeded $1,500,000,000 in the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BDB1B6182D4466687A09CD853380544"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of proactive analytics for high-Risk area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency administering a program susceptible to significant improper payments shall implement proactive analytics for one high-risk area of the program. </text></subsection><subsection id="H5A66881D5097455F9FF63CF3886D3E5A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports on Actions To reduce improper payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after a head of an agency has designated a program as susceptible to improper payments, the head of the agency administering the program shall submit a report on efforts of the agency to reduce and prevent improper payments and fraud with respect to the program, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H3E0151ACA0CC4709A89916A0C95EF826" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to a program that is not a high-priority program at the time of the submission of the report, the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA07BE9BEACCA486FAF7619B1410C3A52" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the proactive analytics implemented in the two fiscal years preceding the submission of the report to reduce improper payments and fraud with respect to such program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C36BE1C865649C69C51F7E4157C90C8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Metrics demonstrating the effectiveness of the proactive analytics implemented.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE643F07321E46A891F923CBEAB0854E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of whether the agency anticipates the program will remain <quote>susceptible to improper payments</quote> and require continued designation as such.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H331ADE169ABB443DA519BFDA768FB4DC" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A plan for—</text><clause id="HA17269E0AEEF454E908B7ECB847A6495" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>continuing to use proactive analytics with respect to that program;</text></clause><clause id="HC7787EC4FD5247C293D39687F2BE75C1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the proactive analytics used with respect to that program; and </text></clause><clause id="H781565FC30644CB1961FF59BF260E4AF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying, in consultation with the Administrator of the FRAUD, additional fraud and improper payment mitigation strategies, that could be employed by the agency if the program is redesginated as a program susceptible to significant improper payments. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA96D62F18ED848CDA0C9B3085CB29003" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to a program that is a high-priority program at the time of the submission of the report, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4FE7B8033E154790BACCB1BD9789D77A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A copy of the plan approved under section 3359 for the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FA100DEACDF439EACA5E2CBA6E27C23" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysis of whether implementation of that plan has reduced and prevented improper payments and fraud.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AB228176CC043FF8726EC18E26F18FD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the plan has not reduced or prevented improper payments or fraud—</text><clause id="H2CB268F954054DDFA7625E12F26B56BA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an explanation of why the plan has not reduced or prevented improper payments or fraud; and</text></clause><clause id="H6F546274973F4FAFA6183CE9442655D2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a new plan with a different strategy developed in consultation with the Administrator of the FRAUD, to reduce or prevent improper payments or fraud.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36CB2EB3BC8A4D84A329148D1A6D64D8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A statement of whether the agency has what is needed with respect to internal controls, human capital, and information systems and other infrastructure, to implement the requirements described in sections 3359 and 3360. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ED52A22BE634B00AC19CF1C22D9DB67" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Estimates of—</text><clause id="H65EC884067774F02A366DA9043F8DED8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any costs avoided and dollars saved by the implementation of sections 3359 and 3360;</text></clause><clause id="H7E58880515E44B68869882DB8246CA22" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any change in administrative burden because of the implementation of sections 3359 and 3360; and</text></clause><clause id="H0A4B25E4511D48A0A2C0EF8C90DE44EA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of persons eligible to obtain a thing of value that did not receive such thing of value because of the implementation of sections 3359 and 3360.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93DC169E32924B16ACA979D7CD1C64D6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether the information technology (as defined in section 11101 of title 40) used by the agency with respect to the program is capable of delivering real-time data—</text><subparagraph id="H7C07A93DB6FA49F0AB78B791779BEF0F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Administrator of the FRAUD for inclusion in the dashboard required to be established by section 508(b)(3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1330CD0235D4BF78A4685179747DC64" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the purpose of implementing proactive analytics, as required under section 3359 and 3360.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D464679FE374FAFA96FD8765308F2DB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> A description of the quality of any improper payment estimates and methodology of the agency relating to the program, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9D7BEDC5DFB742F0ACDB617573BA3B24" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">challenges to accurately estimating improper payments for the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8895BF466A32471D85DD177AF13A5472" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plans to improve the quality of the estimates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1BE589769D3A42C6894875B1FFF21567"><enum>3360.</enum><header>Anti-fraud controls for high-priority programs</header><subsection id="H72298A98D60149359BA9721D23946C98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By January 31 of each fiscal year, the Administrator shall designate for the remainder of that fiscal year and the next full fiscal year, any program with outlays in an amount equal to or in excess of $50,000,000,000 with respect to the preceding fiscal year as a high-priority program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB7A4B40012D3413BBB917BD575CB8DE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan To implement anti-Fraud policy for each high-Priority program</header><paragraph id="H363682BE3A0F472EA863281DA36A57BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency administering a high-priority program shall develop a plan to implement anti-fraud controls for that program, that—</text><subparagraph id="HA5E9CFF51E5F4E7891C2F8E8E60FC7B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at a minimum includes a plan to use—</text><clause id="H6A1374CBCE2C4EE2843E6CB8C21E31B3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any solution that verifies and authenticates identity, known as <quote>digital identity-proofing solutions</quote>, if determined necessary by the Administrator to effectively reduce and prevent fraud and improper payments in the high-priority program;</text></clause><clause id="H02288AC13B66496C87D8886DD824F3C3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>threat intelligence, including open source intelligence and intelligence collected from locations on the internet referred to as the <quote>deep web</quote> and <quote>dark web</quote>, to identify and mitigate emerging fraud threats; and</text></clause><clause id="H1428C29B650448DCA985934D78CD7E62" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proactive analytics; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA9FF7D68144B92AAF6470E5D96A533"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">takes into consideration the administrative burden of implementing such anti-fraud controls, including considering the fraud risk profile (as defined in the study of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs</quote>) of the program. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H536A909A53E04C82899C2E68BCE40F99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial submission of plan to Administrator for approval</header><subparagraph id="H05AA50CD9D3B420090B0E7EF6504BEFB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial submission</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a program is designated as a high-priority program under subsection (a), the agency administering the high-priority program shall submit to the Administrator the plan developed under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89C1D0CB00A74E8FB2748E8B68AC82DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval or denial of plan</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the plan is submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall approve or deny such plan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H462B25714F2047ADA29D4FF79AFCB93E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resubmission of plan to Administrator for approval in case of denial</header><subparagraph id="HCC5870B58DD74A5D8D716B0902D23781" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency that submits a plan that is denied by the Administrator under paragraph (2) shall, until such time as the Administrator approves the plan—</text><clause id="H82665865EB71448EBDADAE1C8FB3512D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>revise the plan; and</text></clause><clause id="H06C7DB155E944DCEA7018644F7B7AC0B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit the plan as revised under clause (i) to the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE31408AE61744CB69A2D611FE2E76F30" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval or denial of revised plan</header><text>The Administrator shall approve or deny a plan submitted under subparagraph (A) not later than 60 days after the Administrator receives the plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68732E39FC7947FC8B9B0766E19569C9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Administrator may provide technical assistance to any agency required to revise a plan under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B7CCDA2C0E4801AE49E3F3BF3119CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Criteria for the approval or denial of plan</header><text>Not later than January 31 of each year, the Administrator shall provide to each agency administering a high-priority program criteria on the basis of which the Administrator will approve or deny a plan under this subsection. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6D2850DC5E54C5393F6C981D5080C03"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency required to submit a plan for approval under this subsection with respect a high-priority program, and has such plan denied by the Administrator three times, shall submit a report to Congress on why the plan has not been approved by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6C73681E6DA4792AD4A170043E3F1AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program Integrity Fund</header><paragraph id="H87B6ABCB042A4548AFF6ACCC819C9DDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the Program Integrity Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2463B11C54D447478F4F8A6BD1250C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the fund may be allocated by the Administrator to agencies to implement plans approved by the Administrator under subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38B16DFF3F554433923DB3BD5EFDBF5B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management of the Program Integrity Fund</header><subparagraph id="HA944A75BAD8F4E978E485C3F1744FE01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="H07F1B8122FF142898E836E1AA766B5E9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process through which the head of an agency may request that funds be allocated from the Program Integrity Fund to the agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HB8B15E45AA2443A28AF2B8029AA88B0B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report that describes the process established pursuant to clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1594DA940F4D412CBFB5F21962549A5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Award of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the amount, if any, of funds to be allocated to an agency from the Program Integrity Fund under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall consider the extent to which the plan approved by the Administrator under subsection (b) of the agency—</text><clause id="H92707EE53EAF492F9086142DC3AB1044"><enum>(i)</enum><text>implements the use of proactive analytics;</text></clause><clause id="HEFD3A15BCC9E4FC6A27BA0E14423A61A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is likely to significantly reduce or prevent improper payments and fraud; and</text></clause><clause id="H5D9B4175D8DE40D88A661F58B947A084" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">considers the administrative burden of implementing the plan, including whether there is a clear indication that the agency considered whether there are any anti-fraud controls other than the anti-fraud controls to be implemented under the plan that could be implemented by the agency with less of an administrative burden on individuals who interact with the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8AB6C3A2CA747058E7264A07E966AB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 for the Program Integrity Fund, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F15D9331E2F4F4EBA638579C0E1EBD3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC8A0A826397A48C9B5BC139ED0063818"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the FRAUD. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H207FCAB95C7E440CB1BAC6868BB1F33F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative burden</header><text>The term <term>administrative burden</term> means a cost that a person incurs in interacting with the agency to obtain a thing of value from the agency, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H880D026EF3BE49FE852DAECEFA88115F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The amount of time and effort expended by the person to learn about—</text><clause id="H5F83A6A16CB84BA0BF8F818AC63925DF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature of the thing of value; and</text></clause><clause id="HA38AA3D4D58F40C7B2487C25E9AC4AB0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how to gain access to the thing of value, including—</text><subclause id="H66F160B0011C4E738C17977916C44785" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any program or service of the agency through which the person may obtain the thing of value from the agency; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3E3DFF16DC2B43A0BA280390DFE7910A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any requirement and condition that must be satisfied for the person to obtain and maintain possession of the thing of value from the government program or service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A4AC59F9FF5491A8EAFB974EE63CB98" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of time it takes to—</text><clause id="HE45581BE99D7449DA8A923A2DF14B997" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide information and documentation to satisfy requirements to obtain and maintain possession of the thing of value; and</text></clause><clause id="HFF08343687A54C6BBB2FAB26B444BB35" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>respond to discretionary requests of program administrators for the purpose of obtaining and maintaining possession of the thing of value.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66AA855EF863411C8B1413D07D774F31" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any financial cost to access services that may be necessary to receive the thing of value (such as fees, legal representation, and travel costs).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H051D6AE980C645B391180C2D5B2D3A1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency administering a program susceptible to significant improper payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency administering a program susceptible to significant improper payments</term> means an agency that is responsible for administering at least one program that is designated as susceptible to significant improper payments under section 3359.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5238304D872C4644A0424CDBB440E52B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agency administering a high-priority program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency administering a high-priority program</term> means an agency that is responsible for administering at least one program that is designated as high-priority under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H299818F167594250AC9C3560E7F78C4E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Anti-fraud control</header><text>The term <term>anti-fraud control</term> means a process, system, or technology that can be implemented to prevent fraud and improper payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A2C7B03C7F9426189ACB15A4E768F03"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>data</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63810FF618724A2EAD10DC6B6E6E7EEA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Device metadata</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>device metadata</term> means structural or descriptive data about a connected device (as defined in section 902(a) of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1306">47 U.S.C. 1306(a)</external-xref>)), such as data about the type, model, IP address, and geolocation of the device.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2F36AECC8044C089E773DB092968EC1" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Fraud</header><text>The term <term>fraud</term> means obtaining a thing of value through willful misrepresentation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26210A3EF4064A238CE51B54E281986F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Proactive analytics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>proactive analytics</term> means the collection and analysis of data (including data that is device metadata, administrative data controlled by the agency, and data from other governmental and non-governmental sources) to prevent fraud and improper payments from occurring, including by identifying anomalous or suspicious patterns that might warrant further investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2FA0347B53F4474FA7F8A96C1D4537E7" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendments related to improper payments provisions</header><subsection id="HE8573B4B9E79426F8D1F88CBBE19E1AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 33 of subtitle III of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H49E959D5D17E4DCD9BE2B9A5D8288F64" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3351—</text><subparagraph id="H1B2A927F9578494F8F42B9A4A1E38C1A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDEE3A29EB87048F2A77BA66FF8FA57A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H12ED01525730407892F700BA8B1D258E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has satisfied the requirements of section 3360 with respect to each high-priority program administered by the agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F1CA50DC4C04D7F966B04045E6DA71D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has implemented proactive analytics for one high-risk area in accordance with section 3359(b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7AF550862994ACE81B1D41B73A3D929"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4), (5), (6), (7), and (8) as paragraphs (5), (6), (8), (9), and (10), respectively; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AA361F6CE604E7EBB21B4EB044DDB3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B6155E67BED462FB2CD55D7AAC10BAE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H5747F34B49E04E78989878795AF02F8D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-Priority Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-priority program</term> means a program designated under section 3360(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E1936D4B2B491AA851232C4B60EFAD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6), as so redesignated, the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC94C9CC57E56440790E79BEA14B0F0C5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8BB4F56F71374A7A9F716CB1C56B030A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program susceptible to significant improper payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program susceptible to significant improper payments</term> means a program designated under section 3359(a). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB61AAED8931F4E2789AA0F2ADE56D991"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 3352—</text><subparagraph id="H31E2C9E22E104497A96BD8AF6214CC14" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (a), (b), (d), and (e); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA3E9F3516624F5A8127054ADD94BCDE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (f), (g), (h), and (i) as subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), and (e), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18C84D75B94A4BB8A2986E91743FF32A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(1), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>With respect to each program and activity identified under subsection (a)(1), the head of the relevant executive agency shall</quote> and inserting <quote>With respect to each program or activity with outlays exceeding $1,500,000,000, the head of the relevant executive agency shall<italic>?</italic></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FED78613A6542DFBE6FA13D240A9B36" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(2), as so redesignated—</text><clause id="H4563D596EAEA4B8AAD3AB1D3B2546995" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and recovery actions</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H0214B4C2094044C48F97619D4942A3C7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H0EE7F4ACCE5542358CE89DB73AAC467A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A08932223A84A08B35D247A8AF0C364" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4BDA4DDFBF94C9985A72E39A558BC0F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAFD3108735D84309BDC299F46FE848C4" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Governmentwide—</text><clause id="H86E0290CA86A4BC5BDA56B876D809269" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any cost avoided by implementing sections 3359 and 3360;</text></clause><clause id="HA0778A60EEB84A5191F751A36B6DAC0B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any change in administrative burden by implementing sections 3359 and 3360; and</text></clause><clause id="H982ED16ACEC34C7EA58C918DEE5E537D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of persons eligible to obtain a thing of value that did not receive such thing of value because of the implementation of sections 3359 and 3360.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5714C8BAA43148B7B5F2ADA4C41DE4B5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text><clause id="H88A4A20DB1BE41C9A79CB92E7789B212" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>shall</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>; </text></clause><clause id="H16FC5F274882454A80B31C4E30446116" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (3); </text></clause><clause id="H3F9CD43740074CDCA3F81B68CBE50756"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="H393F996072474401AFF7D07950E186F7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (3)</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9300DB0B8874E1EB1CC2D8FCF001ADE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 3353(a)— </text><subparagraph id="H4F8258A27F2749D09790CBE03E7FFA0E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Annual</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Compliance</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFC7435CE0EE4936AD225BBF78A76F58" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Each fiscal year</quote> and inserting <quote>Not less frequently than once every 3 fiscal years</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0E6AFC35AD4AD481E75A7885CAC912" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking section 3355; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B974838C95E4C639D071224266F3939" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending section 3357(d) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFFBD612D7CB341B6905440BB1B9684AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8815F8E2091146B4A4AD0FCB224464EA" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>For each fiscal year, the head of each agency shall submit to Congress, in the report containing the annual financial statement of the agency, a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="H1229FF9AD32B479590BAD8640BE6F6EB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The progress of the agency in—</text><subparagraph id="H97ADE2B405934A09BB94F5BC5FBE5B90" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing—</text><clause id="HE34F2AE249404BBAB872C7D9B0FB3CE2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the financial and administrative controls required to be established under subsection (c); </text></clause><clause id="H23B970FCB2244521B06FD4BCC2B506D9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fraud risk principles in the standards established by the Government Accountability Office in the Standards for Internal Control in the Federal Government (commonly known as the Green Book); and</text></clause><clause id="H0535D268FA964300A87469B6D4348221" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the requirements in the Office of Management and Budget Circular A–123 with respect to the leading practices for managing fraud risk;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F8CAC395B644280A475F898E476DA7C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying fraud risks and vulnerabilities, including with respect to payroll, beneficiary payments, grants, large contracts, and purchase and travel cards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE79553039DB4F8987F2B7937EDA9F1F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing strategies, procedures, and other steps to curb fraud.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F4EFB8D6C5414D803F615DA4AECE24" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In accordance with the report of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs,</quote>, published on July 28, 2015, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7F651E6C8479403D9B1185D923321E39" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of—</text><clause id="H1A766D8F039D4658910E98F732CDC1CA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity of the agency and the personnel of the entity dedicated to leading the fraud risk management activities of the agency;</text></clause><clause id="H6057F8C64A834680A41E962C9B2D78BF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>roles and responsibilities of the personnel of such entity, including any program or operation for which the personnel is responsible for overseeing; </text></clause><clause id="HB787247BBD434F27983280C7C470FA58" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>capacity, including any limitation, of such entity to strategically manage fraud risks; and</text></clause><clause id="H5A3599D9985840BC9FEA45DF15C77536" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any program or operation for which there is not personnel dedicated to leading fraud risk management activities, along with a detailed justification for why the agency does not have an dedicated personnel to lead fraud risk management activities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4D52284EFEA465EBE82258CCD71C5D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The status of the fraud risk profiles of each program and operation of the agency, including—</text><clause id="H7EB7BAABE5C6443DAFF0D5E18D584012" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the profiles were last updated; and </text></clause><clause id="HFD157A7612B74550B046103513FC9723" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the agency plans to next update the profile.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8C0016931F64CDEA247C8C2A69F20D5" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any program or operation for which there is not a fraud risk profile, along with a detailed justification for why such program or operation does not have a fraud risk profile.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8189B213924B72B5C8E3463460199A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The status of any anti-fraud strategy for each program and operation of the agency, including—</text><clause id="H60B9203F6AB6408293F5A6930F2F5CE6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which any such strategy was last updated; and</text></clause><clause id="H82A4D1E2F24248A8B2A7E21B6386B269" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the agency plans to next update each such strategy.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC71E3B25F20F4FBABF321625BAD83CF5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any program or operation for which there is not any anti-fraud strategy, along with a detailed justification for why there is not any anti-fraud strategy for such program or operation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EF8175407A1490C9EF3E4CD0416A5EF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recovery of costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3806(g)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H467518C4F9DB4EFCBB008A299D2800B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB1E78A04CF8C430A8E5BB1FB1B2CB4D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recovery of costs</header><subparagraph id="H204C92BD70BD4D9AA697F904C97FE0E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H69C04E9A2E414029A022C2E9120556B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount collected under this chapter or chapter 33 shall be used to reimburse any authority that obligated funds in support of efforts of the authority to reduce or prevent improper payments or fraud, including prosecution of the action, any court or hearing costs, investments in information technologies, or the hiring of additional staff related to such efforts; and</text></clause><clause id="HE754B4CBE4A94DAB94B3B4AD2BFEA5A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts reimbursed under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="HBAFD9D6B379E4E71B98F2AFB0CC2E191"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be deposited in—</text><item id="HDCA6C35DB8C947C1859202399798D665"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the appropriations account of the authority from which the funds described in subparagraph (A) were obligated;</text></item><item id="H492302AF55E1434698905DEA72BB8037"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any other similar appropriations account of the authority; or</text></item><item id="H09AE12D5B0B04EC8B3FCEA6B055E8D51"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>if the authority obligated nonappropriated funds, an appropriate account other than any account under item (aa) or (bb); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HC05ED6DB1D324F108642268E6519EEF4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H620DC53462334E57A6F46FF3E0A6EA43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount remaining after reimbursements described in subparagraph (A) shall be deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HED3B592BC2214464AC3B80AAB708081E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delegation to FRAUD</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall delegate to the Administrator of the FRAUD any function of the Director under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, relating to the identification, analysis, and reduction of improper payments and fraud.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB44F049956A847FEB1DDE346A49C5D4B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><subsection id="HCFE6F91D2B034EDA8591198C7E9C8D54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 3351</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3351 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDCB8924E7857440B8F4B9C59B9AEF01E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H5A20C731995242A69132944524EFEF06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>programs and activities identified</quote> and inserting <quote>programs described under</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E2A4752097742658BD88F663019CC7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>section 3352(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3352(a)</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B5295EC05464BF8929AC9998D6E74D6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (B), (D), and (E); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D4A88D5C77C4EB0B175227076E9C856" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (F) as subparagraphs (B) and (C) respectively; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE044FC95AD84973B1035F5C6309B671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>section 3352(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3352(e)</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H210B6DB02E074FE3B919398007B98D76" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for—</text><paragraph id="HD33550A80C3C45F8ACE9D481737C71BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subchapter I of chapter 5 of subtitle I of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H73C169C1536948EABAC0F0AACB855654" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 508. Federal Real Anti-fraud Unified Directorate.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD63744751AF745368BCB9F249DE0AE61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subchapter IV of chapter 33 of subtitle III of title 31, United States Code, is amended by—</text><subparagraph id="H669DF6D4080C46F99B091E834213CEE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>striking the item related to section 3355; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8240EB62FA28425FB54B1854FA7459B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD600C3400F9C450D83D6DC68CAEBCDE8"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3359. Proactive analytics with respect to programs susceptible to significant improper payments.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3360. Anti-fraud controls for high-priority programs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

