<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7278329B44B840EF9AD5A1C4C46AD3CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9089 IH: Consumer Financial Choice and Capital Markets Protection Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9089</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the investment choices of investors in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86BFF71C880E4DDD8EF0C34D84ED6C6E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H474529BF45E74E81A4B477F47650BBC8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Financial Choice and Capital Markets Protection Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF3C05BDA9CF04C34A9F1643D325395EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of money market funds under the Investment Company Act of 1940</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-1">15 U.S.C. 80a–1 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB040E89DB4A942488FDBD3C44C1CB5A3"> 
<section id="H4AB652298AE3401292192A4CE9E8CDEA"><enum>66.</enum><header>Money market funds</header> 
<subsection id="H37EF538449CD4C0CBB6A0E384F341133"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H96D8472711364717AB497EFF619089DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered Federal assistance</term> means Federal assistance used for the purpose of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4DF87E7DAC91498996499AF0B54F8A8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>making any loan to, or purchasing any stock, equity interest, or debt obligation of, any money market fund;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H578456FB32D0413CA5455AF1CA617114"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guaranteeing any loan or debt issuance of any money market fund; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1FA8AAB1BF64126BBD8BF2024DF3400"><enum>(C)</enum><text>entering into any assistance arrangement (including tax breaks), loss sharing, or profit sharing with any money market fund; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE023F85C58F4067AF9EE10C7E55A0D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal assistance</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8E8B97504E9F424B840AA05236029105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>insurance or guarantees by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E04AE9A8E604CA886BA66D96028E48B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transactions involving the Secretary of the Treasury; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15B6FC527EA146BEAED2C5F64983A141"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of any advances from any Federal Reserve credit facility or discount window that is not part of a program or facility with broad-based eligibility established in unusual or exigent circumstances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDBFA15EAE9AC4C9F81B5BF696BFA1BE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election To be a stable value money market fund</header> <paragraph id="HD11A36199ED040AD93BA4637FA264DF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, any open-end investment company (or a separate series thereof) that is a money market fund that relies on section 270.2a–7 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, may, in the prospectus included in its registration statement filed under section 8 state that the company or series has elected to compute the current price per share, for purposes of distribution or redemption and repurchase, of any redeemable security issued by the company or series by using the amortized cost method of valuation, or the penny-rounding method of pricing, regardless of whether its shareholders are limited to natural persons, if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3A8C52F8AB0C4A48A54FE1187B016151"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the objective or principal investment strategy of the company or series is not inconsistent with the generation of income and preservation of capital through investment in short-term, high-quality debt securities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1E4E2D65B9F4FC49358324B93D93564"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the board of directors of the company or series elects, on behalf of the company or series, to maintain a stable net asset value per share or stable price per share, by using the amortized cost valuation method, as defined in section 270.2a–7(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation), or the penny-rounding pricing method, as defined in section 270.2a–7(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation), and the board of directors of the company has determined, in good faith, that—</text> 
<clause id="H35BF3DB0A7F4407FB8CB00DD009B420F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is in the best interests of the company or series, and its shareholders, to do so; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFE63945B565C47A3BED9C8AEE62ADAB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the money market fund will continue to use such method or methods only as long as the board of directors believes that the resulting share price fairly reflects the market-based net asset value per share of the company or series; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EBDB071147B4C4DB32D62302371B81D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the company or series will comply with such quality, maturity, diversification, liquidity, and other requirements, including related procedural and recordkeeping requirements, as the Commission, by rule or regulation or order, may prescribe or has prescribed as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors to the extent that such requirements and provisions are not inconsistent with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D7265C7DDE84E4A96140389183A65D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption from default liquidity fee requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding section 270.2a–7 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation), no company or series that makes the election under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the default liquidity fee requirements of section 270.2a–7(c)(2)(ii) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC13ECC1CDD7D4AC3BEF505363C657101"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition against Federal Government bailouts of money market funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), covered Federal assistance may not be provided directly to any money market fund.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1EEC1D1AF88E4396AF68C34231F4EC85"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disclosure of the prohibition against Federal Government bailouts of money market funds</header> <paragraph id="HE275A2FA732D44B8A66967F91F272E79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No principal underwriter of a redeemable security issued by a money market fund nor any dealer shall offer or sell any such security to any person unless the prospectus of the money market fund and any advertising or sales literature for such fund prominently discloses the prohibition against direct covered Federal assistance as described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E6DF994C0B645C9A489312B79436C4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules, regulations, and orders</header><text>The Commission may, after consultation with and taking into account the views of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Department of the Treasury, adopt rules and regulations and issue orders consistent with the protection of investors, prescribing the manner in which the disclosure under this subsection shall be provided.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7FACE28CD9EE4296A85A994C58EC85D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuing obligation To meet requirements of this title</header><text>A company or series that makes an election under subsection (b)(1) shall remain subject to the provisions of this title and the rules and regulations of the Commission thereunder that would otherwise apply if those provisions do not conflict with the provisions of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

