<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H51FB8907D34843429B42BFCFB27589A7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8307 IH: Steven’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8307</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000020">Mr. Jacobs of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require certain medical information related to donors of reproductive tissue be made available to recipients of such tissue and persons conceived using such tissue, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2501316CA5074ADF9CF6074FBB58FD3B" style="OLC"><section id="H92645F6F1AF947EB8E921824375DD2D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Steven’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC7F16246753041A2A2C72BDC3CC6DF8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reproductive tissue donor information</header><subsection id="H05D02E87382942C59275CD292D2DAAF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 369 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93C61A677D5F42978EA2C91202747E65" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5E237389F1F54B34B175672C00E12352"><enum>369A.</enum><header>Reproductive tissue donor information</header><subsection id="H8F758C920CEF403D9A3BA82A9B757C83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, by regulation, require that a reproductive tissue bank—</text><paragraph id="H52249B9FAE44471D835F9E4A58123C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect and verify medical history information from each donor from whom such bank acquires donor reproductive tissue; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E051E5F582E4E939ABFC2DA3FB4EB28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make available on request such information to—</text><subparagraph id="H62064FE9CA9B41E3982CE42043B8000D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any recipient of such donor reproductive tissue, including before such recipient purchases or otherwise receives such donor reproductive tissue;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H911E30A8B3954F78BEA7BC19317427D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the physician of any such recipient; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H705BD7569E574F8B88879AB4E8256139"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any donor-conceived person conceived with such donor reproductive tissue if such person has attained eighteen years of age or has the consent of such person’s parent or guardian.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58E4A9A2ADEC41EDBD3AD6082AACE129"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Donor disclosure</header><text>Under the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall require a donor to—</text><paragraph id="H8E39B3C0EC92470BAE2F816812EF728B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose to a reproductive tissue bank that acquires donor reproductive tissue from such donor—</text><subparagraph id="H5FD2367F3864487DA35087E4B409D05E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all diagnosed sexually transmitted infectious diseases that the donor has at the time of donation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2406FC655E5F41679C1270A1A2715836"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all diagnosed medical conditions of the donor, including genetic disorders, schizophrenia and other serious mental illnesses (as determined by the Secretary), and intellectual disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H909CF0022CFC475981AED0F481D2D406"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any familial medical conditions (as defined by the Secretary) to the extent such donor has knowledge of or should have knowledge of such conditions, including the conditions referred to in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7DC5A83BD134DE89499F31F42F3FD5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the name and contact information of each medical professional who has examined or treated the donor during the 5 years preceding the date of the donation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46935FDA16C547CFAB6CF7A5C8C5554F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide a waiver of protections of the donor’s medical history and records, including the regulations under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note), necessary to authorize such bank to—</text><subparagraph id="H599AFCF2D24D4281BE7BAB3C34A8A558"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtain donor medical records from each medical professional identified under paragraph (1)(D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9E72692DCCC4998943D4464136CC11F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose the donor’s medical history and records to a recipient, physician, or donor-conceived person in accordance with subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96FFCDDC9D5B4F38939DCE48CF4358C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reproductive tissue bank disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall require a reproductive tissue bank to—</text><paragraph id="H09A8437FE1934ADEB3CB75D9D4C110F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide to a donor from whom reproductive tissue is acquired a statement of the obligations of such donor described in subsection (b) and obtain a signed acknowledgment of such obligations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92A9FCCA789F40C4B540D6B3732AAE37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>verify the medical information provided by a donor in accordance with subsection (b) by comparing such information with donor medical records;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DC1F3D5C220493C9E53FB4F3BEAD8DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review donor medical records for risk factors of genetic disorders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9297E33D5C2C48EA9BAA3E87EACE3403" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>except in the case of a donor known to the recipient, remove any individually identifying information, including the donor’s name, address, and other information that may be used to identify such donor, from donor medical records; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22E16C5B58714B78B0F4A9980FE81F53" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with paragraph (4) and using a standard form prescribed by the Secretary, make available, at no cost, to a recipient, physician, or donor-conceived person in accordance with subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9F6FCDD757B9440485B7695B51239CCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the donor’s medical records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70F710E35806490E8AB1D68B4E8899FE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the information included in such records; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H234F691DFA2E49E38E2FF8BE39C61E80" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any donor medical information that such bank was unable to obtain from donor medical records, including—</text><clause id="HF5CF65794C9F4796A2EC491071B6FD86" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the type of information unable to be obtained; and</text></clause><clause id="H6338562C0B0A400586A17F93E4DADA91" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reason such bank was unable to obtain such information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70BE68C0D3334BB19034F4A4A6143590"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H14C33DAA66DB405390DFFFDC2F5F4307"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Donor</header><text>The term <term>donor</term> means a person who provides donor reproductive tissue for use in an artificial insemination or assisted reproductive procedure performed on recipients other than that person or that person's regular sexual partner, and includes direct and known donors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2E236112FB8425188E2C8C2093893D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Donor-conceived person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>donor-conceived person</term> means a person purposely conceived through the use of donor reproductive tissue.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30F30A99E06F4D0EAC1EE0097BDBDAF9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Donor reproductive tissue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>donor reproductive tissue</term> means any tissue, including semen, oocytes, embryos, spermatozoa, or spermatids, from the reproductive tract intended for use in an artificial insemination or assisted reproductive procedure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9ED88EEEAE4478A0B55B5C0EDED575"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recipient</header><text>The term <term>recipient</term> means a person who receives donor reproductive tissue for the purposes of that person conceiving a child.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0075E8E6F94C19AFD6CC5A9AF169AA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reproductive tissue bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reproductive tissue bank</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H5737A368AE23406B855B7FDE34AB0BBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an entity which acquires, processes, stores, or releases donor reproductive tissue for an insemination implantation site or recipient to use in an artificial insemination or assisted reproductive technology procedure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4748FCCAD989418CA95ADE03705AF9AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a semen bank, oocyte donation program, and embryo bank.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCA0853AAA09143EBBADC26898D4E0C3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate a final rule to carry out section 369A of the Public Health Service Act, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H03A8FA3F6B4C442492B22FBBE57ADF2C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 368(a) of the Public Health Service Act is amended by striking <quote>366 or</quote> and inserting <quote>366 or 369A or</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

