<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1EB07F6A2714438870AFA4F17319C81" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8088 IH: Prioritizing Clean Energy and Climate Cooperation with India Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8088</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership to facilitate clean energy cooperation with India, to enhance cooperation with India on climate mitigation, resilience, and adaptation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B1644DF2BB94FF4B0E292D573999461" style="OLC"><section id="H9CA90E17121147D8BB8FEE0820E3CF08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H89E2C8863606426B8E3DB13C1F72EA09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Clean Energy and Climate Cooperation with India Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H648FC87ABC5F4F96B247EEF2B90FAFB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9CA90E17121147D8BB8FEE0820E3CF08">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD5A47B75F8D14AD0A7964F475B4BC0A8">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H32F84165974B4A929DBFD791ADB9D50F">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7FB6CA86B19E455682EB4FE54651FEB1">Sec. 4. Sense of Congress on climate and clean energy cooperation with India.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HCDA1D08D6A69489C979047546631341F">Sec. 5. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HBD370D95356345E3ADA2A11FF5F6FC59">Sec. 6. Purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7DC6C4AF1E244CBFA40DC70DF3EA0E86">Sec. 7. Establishment of United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HAB0E5C0FD4C3450DBD4C9195C39F8E92">Sec. 8. Strategy for implementation of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC9E55DF6508B4F6EB8A668DCBAA73436">Sec. 9. Partnerships for cooperation on research and innovation for clean energy technologies.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF4D5FDFDEFE549F8A9467AA12F296547">Sec. 10. Initiatives for technical assistance for grid improvement and energy efficiency in India.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HBD7B143CE22F42D09BE704EAA002EF60">Sec. 11. Initiatives for generation of new renewable energy in India.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6B82E6D24101497789230E40A473A217">Sec. 12. Report on promotion of State-State clean energy cooperation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2B5CED1DFED247FABFDCF8A8E4DE3D78">Sec. 13. United States-India climate change risk reduction and resilience cooperation.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HD5A47B75F8D14AD0A7964F475B4BC0A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H9DA69A554B554F3493A68C3E344F5A52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>India is the second most populous country in the world with a population of approximately 1,334,000,000 people and is the fifth largest economy in the world with a nominal gross domestic product of approximately $2,940,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC05D07628F164CECB2597C4B73F824C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>India is among the countries most vulnerable to climate change, with hundreds of millions of people susceptible to events exacerbated by climate change, such as the spread of infectious diseases, sea level rise and extreme flooding, droughts, storms, and landslides triggered by extreme weather.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC2EB12F9E44A59B8FA9EC2CA613048"><enum>(3)</enum><text>India releases approximately 2,500,000,000 tons (carbon dioxide equivalent) of greenhouse gases annually, making it the third largest greenhouse gas emitter after the People's Republic of China and the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07A32A354FAA451A8F1CF888C2FE3DDD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>India is one of the largest energy markets in the world and is projected to be the largest source of global energy demand growth through 2040. Installed power capacity in India more than doubled between 2011 and 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44ABB5B427404BD7B5CCA79EB4897779"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Per capita energy consumption in India is relatively low among emerging economic powers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCB7AC53073A46E2A99A39A1B957ED28"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Reliable access to power is crucial for the storage of vaccines and antiretroviral and other lifesaving medical drugs, as well as for the operation of modern lifesaving medical equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36AFCE0793304FD7B0C5F4C8C77EF5DF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Access to power can also provide improved information and communication technologies that can greatly improve health and education outcomes, as well as economic and commercial opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6965F4A48B74B97B3F324694E305CB5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2000, only 43 percent of the population of India had access to power. That percentage more than doubled between 2000 and 2020, with approximately 700,000,000 people in India gaining access to electricity during that period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0358246EB42B46489D7B21AFB5E912AC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has prioritized improving citizen access to electricity and electrifying every household in India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F5CC33F1AC14FE0A9EDD9E2F6B6B8BD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Power for All initiative of the Government of India aims to provide electricity to all households in India 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC953BB3B7C9144F0BE2B82DAB05E28DB"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Without action, climate change threatens to push millions more people into poverty. Investments in clean energy offer an opportunity to curb climate change while combating poverty and increasing capacity to respond to the impacts of climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD72A1AE4B2CC4345967BA654E7BA9752"><enum>(12)</enum><text>As of June 2020, coal makes up the largest domestic source of energy supply and electricity generation for India. In October 2020, the Ministry of New and Renewable Energy reported that renewable energy comprises approximately 12 percent of energy generation in India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4891CA249614037A3E28F4A85223C62"><enum>(13)</enum><text>India imports 80 percent of its oil needs, and that amount is projected to increase in the coming decades due to aging oil fields and a lack of new oil discoveries in India. India is increasing its oil refining capacity to maintain supply to meet the rising domestic demand for energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E9C48B6AD54941A6B22098D41FF04E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>India is projected to surpass the People’s Republic of China in oil consumption by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF6172CBA61C4CC5B551585237B7DE87"><enum>(15)</enum><text>On September 22, 2020, the People’s Republic of China announced a pledge to achieve net zero carbon emissions by 2060 in its updated Nationally Determined Contribution to the Paris Agreement, done at Paris December 12, 2015, but given the need to accelerate the reduction of global emissions along a 2050 timeline, that pledge is insufficient to avoid an increase of 2 degrees Celsius in the global average temperature. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E7D2290CB3B4A2F9B54B62DCA60FBC5"><enum>(16)</enum><text>India, in contrast, is demonstrating that climate action is a priority through concrete steps including a climate plan compatible with the goal of limiting global average temperature rise below 2 degrees Celsius.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40E3CDF776DB48238012FBE1D8FBFCBC"><enum>(17)</enum><text>India’s unconditional emissions target, as outlined in the Intended Nationally Determined Contribution of India to the Paris Agreement, aims to reduce emissions intensity of gross domestic product by 33 percent to 35 percent below 2005 levels by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EF20AAC30514639A2A8D60ACBA93092"><enum>(18)</enum><text>In its Intended Nationally Determined Contribution, India has also pledged to increase the share of its installed electricity capacity that comes from nonfossil fuel sources to 40 percent by 2030 and create an additional 2,500,000,000 to 3,000,000,000 tons of carbon sinks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H962F0A287C9C4C8A90F0DA412471CE20"><enum>(19)</enum><text>In 2019, Prime Minister Modi announced an ambitious domestic target of installing 450 gigawatts of renewable energy capacity by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC79CBA0BB3804DCAA742A2AF920697B2"><enum>(20)</enum><text>India is among the top 5 clean energy producers globally. Installed electricity capacity from renewables in India grew by 144 percent from 2014 to 2020, and between 2014 and 2019 there was approximately $42,000,000,000 in investment in the renewable energy sector in India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA303086A051341DC859CB97C6456CDBC"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Numerous global funds, private equity firms, and multilateral finance institutions are continuing to invest billions of dollars in the growing renewable energy sector in India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H517598D2445548878994E0D12B9A2D6E"><enum>(22)</enum><text>India leads the International Solar Alliance, a 75-country initiative to which the United States does not yet belong, to mobilize $1,000,000,000,000 in solar energy investment by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3C7074F5944D67BAB81D4C5F453DBA"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Increased ownership of appliances and cooling needs could lead to a doubling or even tripling of energy use in India by 2040. One billion air conditioning units are expected to be in use in India by 2050.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40053727BF63481988B35311BAE45C1F"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Under the Kigali Amendment to the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer, done at Montreal September 16, 1987, India has agreed to freeze its manufacturing and consumption of hydrofluorocarbons in 2028. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89121966C2F641C985A198D137BF23D6"><enum>(25)</enum><text>In 2005, the United States and India established a formal energy cooperation dialogue, the United States-India Energy Dialogue, which included engagement on clean, low carbon technologies. In 2009, the United States and India expanded the United States-India Energy Dialogue to advance clean and sustainable energy development. The expansion in 2009 included the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy initiative focusing on research into, deployment of, and access to clean energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1D3FABD64584715BBDE67496145562A"><enum>(26)</enum><text>The Partnership to Advance Clean Energy Research element of the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy initiative, commonly referred to as <quote>PACE–R</quote>, consists of research consortia under the Joint Clean Energy Research and Development Center launched in 2010 by the Department of Energy and the Government of India with support from the private sector. PACE–R has focused on solar power, advanced biofuels, energy efficiency in buildings, and smart grids and energy storage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H058725A4100E4A85AD1F4B89792ECA06"><enum>(27)</enum><text>The Partnership to Advance Clean Energy Deployment element of the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy initiative, commonly referred to as <quote>PACE–D</quote>, funds programs to improve energy efficiency, grid connectivity, clean energy finance, and more.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0687B0C853794DBB95BE4DA281564DB4"><enum>(28)</enum><text>The Partnership to Advance Clean Energy Access element of the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy initiative, commonly referred to as <quote>PEACE</quote>, has focused on finance and technology innovation, skills development, and ecosystem strengthening for clean energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2613C396CFE9438DAFA57B1F1D716891"><enum>(29)</enum><text>In 2015, the United States and India launched the U.S.-India Clean Energy Finance Task Force, which draws on the finance expertise of the governments and private sectors of both countries to tailor business and finance models to scale India’s clean energy sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF7C95E60C14B3DBB989CB234AB22EB"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Since 2015, the United States has supported the Partnership for Climate Resilience, which links United States Government climate scientists with their counterparts in India to produce climate data and information to inform local decisionmakers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC87738FFB45E4899BB0C3274E713F521"><enum>(31)</enum><text>In 2018, the United States Government established the Asia Enhancing Development and Growth through Energy initiative, commonly referred to as <quote>Asia EDGE</quote>, to support sustainable and secure energy markets throughout the Indo-Pacific. Asia EDGE integrates elements of the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy initiative along with new programs such as the South Asia Group for Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2E44C07E634D738162013F19289CAF"><enum>(32)</enum><text>In 2018, the Governments of India and the United States elevated the energy partnership to the U.S.-India Strategic Energy Partnership to advance energy security, expand energy innovation, and increase stakeholder engagement. That partnership included pillars of cooperation on power and energy efficiency, renewable energy, sustainable growth, and oil and gas. The Governments of India and the United States also continued clean energy research and development under the Partnership to Advance Clean Energy Research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2043CDC6883A4FCBA6979502E07DD79F"><enum>(33)</enum><text>In 2021, the United States Government, through the United States Agency for International Development, awarded approximately $9,200,000 to support the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, which the Government of India launched in September 2019 at the United Nations Climate Action Summit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E3D1B83A8B34326B4ADD05018F5131B"><enum>(34)</enum><text>In 2021, at the Leaders Summit on Climate, the United States and India launched the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership to mobilize finance toward and accelerate clean energy deployment, demonstrate and scale innovative clean technologies, and build capacity to measure, manage, and adapt to the risks of climate-related impacts. The Partnership has two main tracks, the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership (led by the Department of Energy) and the Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue (led by the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Climate), which build on and subsume previous, aforementioned processes.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H32F84165974B4A929DBFD791ADB9D50F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H09883A03845B453BB3A46F4B55AED225"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC14B7952A3094977AF727ADDB2A987AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H037F34EF6C6048A4A128CD2D97361988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H932CB754A3E243FFA156B8EA2BD3D97E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A202298607A4FDA8118FBF33B4873AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean energy technology</header><text>The term <term>clean energy technology</term> means a technology related to the production, use, transmission and distribution, storage, control, or conservation of energy that will contribute to the stabilization of the climate by reducing greenhouse gas emissions or sequestering or using carbon dioxide and—</text><subparagraph id="HBE1624725F5944C9A68E29B534769B15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduces the need for additional energy supplies by using existing energy supplies with greater efficiency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H189A1D22C4DC453D8AAB08170157E3F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increases and diversifies the sources of energy in a manner that will—</text><clause id="HDCF240CAAF5D477591B1805CD668C149"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce risk to human health, safety, and welfare and the environment; and </text></clause><clause id="H51864F9A850D4F5FA363AC087F2776A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strengthen energy security.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H933372C7BAC84EBBA994D57F418D9D61"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7FB6CA86B19E455682EB4FE54651FEB1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on climate and clean energy cooperation with India</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H6C8F97B14D964A93844F5FA9199CD4CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>robust cooperation on the development and deployment of clean energy technologies should be a priority in relations between the United States and India and the top priority in the countries’ energy diplomacy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8488D5A3DDB41F3B758792D5F95B3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the collaboration of the United States and India on the development and deployment of clean energy technologies has resulted in innovative new technologies that have helped significantly lower the carbon emissions of the power sector in India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92D039120004A15BD53F6C4494F604F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demand for energy in India will increase with the expansion of the economy and middle class of India, and it is in the interest of United States national security and global security for the United States to support India in growing the energy sector of India in environmentally and socially responsible ways that mitigate greenhouse gas emissions and improve the climate and energy security of India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41B9F795EEAC41048018E63164C30964"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States and India should continue collaborating on research and development of new clean energy technologies, as well as deployment of clean energy technologies, so people across India can access power generated from clean energy technologies and to help decarbonize India’s entire energy sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB945D904D17D40F4AE33FBBD36F0BEA4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States, through the Bureau of Energy Resources of the Department of State, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Department of Energy, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the International Trade Administration, and the United States Agency for International Development, should encourage private sector investment in and financing for the development and deployment of clean energy technologies in India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C3F512176AD4870A7479F360AB509A9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States should support the Power for All initiative created by the Government of India through technical and other forms of assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H435DEC613AA145B6A756DFB9C9DBB309"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the United States should support the ambitious renewable energy generation goals set by the Government of India through technical and other forms of assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0DB19A0FC7649BEB17AD2FE7493BFF6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Mission Innovation, in which India plays a critical leadership role, represents an unmatched opportunity to make clean energy technologies more affordable and accessible by increasing funding for clean energy innovation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79C0B97237524BDDBAFE2E6FB2264F3A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the United States should increase its participation in and contributions to Mission Innovation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF3E75D0FF6A4834A9627EFE09CF778D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the International Solar Alliance led by India will play a key role in mobilizing significant international investment in solar energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD1583C4903F44578C41C3101436410D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the United States should join and contribute to the International Solar Alliance led by India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9BCEF66A1F54382BABBF71CF36E07F7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>India has implemented several new policies to promote the production and use of electric vehicles in India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13350FA1E5654824BD0110387C987B34"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the United States should promote research, development, and private sector cooperation with India on the production of electric vehicles and the planning and execution of an expansive charging station network to support extensive use of electric vehicles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB092C5AD06664656BCD611AF5987C5F1"><enum>(14)</enum><text>increased demand for refrigeration and air conditioning in India, and the adoption of the Kigali Amendment to the Montreal Protocol, done at Montreal September 16, 1987, are driving innovation and investments in next-generation refrigeration equipment and refrigerants in India; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9706497BADF458CB3C7626797869C89"><enum>(15)</enum><text>enhanced United States-India bilateral cooperation and engagement on the development of technologies and chemicals that are compliant with the Kigali Amendment are in the interest of United States industry leaders in the refrigeration and chemical coolant industries.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCDA1D08D6A69489C979047546631341F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to increase engagement and cooperation with the Government of India, the Indian diaspora community in the United States, and the private sector and civil society in both the United States and India in a concerted effort—</text><paragraph id="HC1005030B2794B1983E54FF88581A9C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support the ambitious goals of India—</text><subparagraph id="HF3DB97BB0B4845B88152C3BBEBF018B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to expand renewable energy production and the optimal integration of renewable energy into a flexible, resilient electrical grid in India; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7471E6556E854272BE63493E59D98406"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide reliable and affordable access to electricity for all communities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0C54DA6B364C71A8CD86CC10C472CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to help improve the energy security of India and decrease the dependence of India on imported fossil fuels;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50CBDDF577814A33B115DC266A792154"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to foster innovation through academic and research partnerships and mutually beneficial arrangements relating to technology transfers and protection of intellectual property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70E541745819495592E2F130B2B47887"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to facilitate United States private sector investment in projects to expand power transmission and distribution capacity, energy storage, and territorial coverage in India to increase the number of people, households, and communities with access to power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07873D3B53204B3A91B11187B5CBB008"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance and advice as appropriate, and solely at the request and with the consent of the relevant national and local authorities and stakeholders, on—</text><subparagraph id="H2DABFD274D0049E8A4A06AB81C0BC193"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reforms of power production, delivery, and pricing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30B9E846E5C2455B9537E7F2036CA45E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing aggregate technical and commercial energy losses in India’s energy transmission and distribution systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B1712117A93453AAAF3DBA6AB0EFCCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>regulatory reforms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H717D6D8159D54D8193927FB2BEE747E5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>long-term, market-based power generation and distribution; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11489D4CC40E47B880573802B4A04908"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to support efforts to lower India’s greenhouse gas emissions and increase adaptive capacity by promoting United States private investment in—</text><subparagraph id="H845B8D2766A544888E3D70B2B38D7C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>renewable energy production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3708FC3D92A14C98BEBF95E0295EF7DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>electric vehicle technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87001278E2FE4FD7B118AA5A88718986"><enum>(C)</enum><text>energy efficiency in appliances, buildings, and the industrial sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14D7C90157614455A1FF42BF9965F957"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technologies to decarbonize the industrial and transport sectors in which emissions are hard to abate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5388224073842D88B99B499EB2D58A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>technologies and infrastructure modifications to improve the efficiency and resilience of existing electricity generation units; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06B8538E026A4DCB9F9F16022C030BDB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>electricity transmission and distribution projects to improve—</text><clause id="HB9E5061D628A4A4CBD98AD4227472758"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the affordability of electricity;</text></clause><clause id="HB64D4875818C410B8BCE94A5ADC1F6A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>grid reliability, efficiency, flexibility, digitalization, and resilience to climate impacts;</text></clause><clause id="H26902EBF283144D0B5C5E4C8C2972AEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of citizens and households with access to electricity;</text></clause><clause id="HE5D48C3961CD4108933076DE49BAD14B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>rural electrification; and</text></clause><clause id="HCF5395101C5647B29FB00C5DDCF1A2AF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>electric vehicle charging infrastructure; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H331B9650BDAA410DB48822D066497C81"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to strengthen India’s resilience capacities that ensure people, households, communities, institutions, and systems can assess, anticipate, reduce, adapt to, respond to, and recover from shocks and stresses associated with the effects of climate change.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBD370D95356345E3ADA2A11FF5F6FC59"><enum>6.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="HCCFB13099205483C87E5048D8ABCA197"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to advance cooperation between the United States and India on, and private sector engagement and investment in, the development and deployment of clean energy technologies, and improvement in the planning, reliability, flexibility, and resilience of India’s electrical grid to integrate increasing use of renewable energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD7F90EEF51C4F65888DB8C93A3F03CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve research collaborations that develop and deploy innovative clean energy technologies in India;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FBABF7D0A894D68BA21C060578E0958"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enhance citizen access to electricity across India; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H819F9BD4779B49028C15892F333BBAE4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to build capacity to measure, manage, and adapt to the risks of climate-related impacts.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7DC6C4AF1E244CBFA40DC70DF3EA0E86"><enum>7.</enum><header>Establishment of United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</header><subsection id="H34A0C2C07844407EB3C99E398521D05D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The purposes described in section 6 shall be advanced through the development and execution of bilateral initiatives under an initiative to be known as the <quote>United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8BCA37925A46410B966077F3B4B6A026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership shall serve as—</text><paragraph id="H281ADECE99ED42F6B4BF9CA45A361314"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the primary forum for cooperation between the United States and India on clean energy technologies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBFE2CD89A3742F58CC681D7B7CB7373"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the mechanism through which such cooperation is funded.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAB0E5C0FD4C3450DBD4C9195C39F8E92"><enum>8.</enum><header>Strategy for implementation of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</header><subsection id="H4649D93BB1E24BA295BDB46952201702"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive, integrated, multi-year strategy for implementing the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership. </text></subsection><subsection id="H924680F5B2EC4F998E29AE88488559C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Flexibility and responsiveness</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall maintain sufficient flexibility and responsiveness to technological innovation with respect to climate and clean energy in India.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B360E2303E643B09556ACCA59E82DAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HA64E7915795A43A4A44876B45ABA7D1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a general description, developed in collaboration with the Government of India and local and regional authorities in India, of the goals and ongoing efforts in India—</text><subparagraph id="H76E8DC3AD5B44C168E1B6ACF1662312F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to increase power production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09C26DBF66B54DC0806906C056B1A0C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to build and maintain climate resilient electrical transmission and distribution infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EEA883955554658BD4419CFA23A2044"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to expand electrical transmission and distribution infrastructure in order to provide equitable household and community access to electricity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C116702DA53419F91C038CF816206D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to implement regulatory reform, regional interoperability, and transparent and accountable governance and oversight;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8AFE052CBC44CB6B0D7D0E5834B7546"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to strengthen the reliability and regional interoperability of the electrical grid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H641AE9EABE49433CB3FC7E6330D6D044"><enum>(F)</enum><text>for electricity service providers—</text><clause id="H4BB27C2B2B5B402F8C6A678E21AB5029"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide affordable and reliable power;</text></clause><clause id="H2E12EE28939C495FB4982430A1260955"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to reduce technical and nontechnical losses;</text></clause><clause id="H1DA29BDD68414056A94148B430B45CB6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to collect fees for services; and</text></clause><clause id="HA76CC50EA5374464B3D961465ADEE5BA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to expand service to underserved communities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA4F88B5AF4E44F8AF696554AC568E1B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to advance energy efficiency in appliances, buildings, and the industrial sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5E1441AAAB4919ABE18DE1BCA06522"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to advance decarbonization across the energy sector of India, including in transport and heavy industry;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6318DACF46D4D38A851357B09903CA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of how the initiatives included in the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership will support achievement of the clean energy and expanded energy access goals of India, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC145AD00E8F34A4081D13EAAED03B426"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text><clause id="HFA702542F4DA4239AC79CE553AE813F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the flexibility and carrying capacity of India’s electrical grid to better integrate renewable energy generation; and</text></clause><clause id="HF9AA471BF74646F8AB6F5F3200DAAE50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the state of distributed renewable energy in India;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7193C49315044A3BB8B4FADA85DA77C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of market barriers to the deployment of clean energy technologies, including distributed renewable energy technologies both on- and off-grid in India;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEAE2B38718B44B899B48A0F64FF1C9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of the efficacy of efforts by the Department of State, the Office of the United States Trade Representative, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and the United States Agency for International Development to facilitate the financing of the deployment, importation, distribution, sale, leasing, or marketing of clean energy technologies in India; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC841B14565CD441B8CCB86EC7F56639F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how bolstering distributed renewable energy can enhance the overall effort to increase power access in India;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3A7C28A62964DDC803FD184AE84AB86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of programs or initiatives in existence as of the date of the submittal of the strategy that—</text><subparagraph id="HE5C6D5368DE647D5AF79E95EC5E21941"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the requirements for initiatives under sections 9 through 11; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF7712370183472DBEEFD36E664A1B74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can be integrated into the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8051514B8134A57B868FE60858DDC67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a list of programs in existence as of the date of the submittal of the strategy that will be integrated into the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4BCA32C0EDC4C119257245F650A18F1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommendations on the establishment of any new programs to meet the requirements for initiatives under sections 9 through 11; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A9C4B0EDD4045878322D2F9A93AEED5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a plan describing which parts of the United States Government shall serve as the lead for which components of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC9E55DF6508B4F6EB8A668DCBAA73436"><enum>9.</enum><header>Partnerships for cooperation on research and innovation for clean energy technologies</header><subsection id="H650C09DC8A2D407FBAD811C53DF5DCD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is—</text><paragraph id="H7C01E2FFDA3449389B363569D8C543B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote and accelerate the pace of innovation and deployment of clean energy technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE10D0E46709840A9804148A756AA7E99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to expand community and household access to power in India; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0618139246064E258C334F3EFB359841"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to facilitate demonstration projects of new, innovative clean energy technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H806604EE6A784889A8F9917C664E7DD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research and development partnerships</header><paragraph id="H0821EAE3248341E18069E90A6849B2A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, and with the cooperation of the Government of India, shall promote partnerships between United States clean energy centers of excellence designated under paragraph (4) and partner entities in India described in paragraph (5) on research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of clean energy technologies. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F7F5B5B95B1442383AFE0C523489668"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exchanges; sharing</header><text>The partnerships described in paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H2FFD9E9BD7F847ADAD5C17F6F16806E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exchanges between United States clean energy centers of excellence designated under paragraph (4) and partner entities in India described in paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08DEB382F6F14FDAA286A4105CEBBF47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lawful sharing of intellectual property between the United States and India, including between private sector entities in the two countries, with respect to—</text><clause id="H744854BF2E1C4C4A857A7375B4FB54F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clean energy technology, including carbon capture technologies;</text></clause><clause id="H9F4A4943CE42432BA7E537427C313AD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>air conditioning technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H7AC3B8231BE7406ABC319B6563010512"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>refrigeration systems technology.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65C40C5B4E7C4345BF623411593F8EF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>United States clean energy centers of excellence designated under paragraph (4), in collaboration with partner entities in India described in paragraph (5), shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph id="H46CA660AE375425F8C972A695230B5BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing different potential technological, development, policy, and technical solutions to address capacity constraints affecting the development and deployment of existing and emerging energy technology in India, consistent with the lawful sharing of intellectual property described in paragraph (2)(B); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD02393B8AAAA429693499DF3BAFDF45F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating engagements between energy authorities in India and private sector clean energy technology suppliers and project developers that could provide solutions to energy capacity challenges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EDE8971357D4C98A4E4D0A0357E7DAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensuring that local stakeholders and host communities in India where energy projects supported by partnerships under this section are being developed are adequately engaged and given due consideration in the development of such projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC988788F0754E72AD9FDC1C440FDC96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>arranging for the appropriate and lawful sharing of prototyping, technology transfer activities, and production facilities for clean energy technologies, including assistance to clean energy technology start-up ventures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H100D8ABFF299477A98A6724343AFE861"><enum>(E)</enum><text>promoting job training opportunities in the deployment and operation of clean energy technologies and energy transmission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H598938CACE1642DEB1A423128BB25B09"><enum>(F)</enum><text>performing such other duties as determined by the Secretary in coordination with the Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3FCC3180AA447FB8BBBB00469F9739A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States clean energy centers of excellence</header><subparagraph id="H73B7BF0C9A0C4C82A576A89A1C106325"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><clause id="H7517B851C3FF400ABF34C2C223C59C32"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall designate not more than 10 eligible entities to be United States clean energy centers of excellence.</text></clause><clause id="H87B45A0D1C1D48E8A959622AA8BB1B8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the total number of eligible entities designated under clause (i) may be National Laboratories. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF55A13530EF942038BE1EEAD4370AD37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>For purposes of this section, an <quote>eligible entity</quote> is—</text><clause id="HA40E7DC4EBDD43D5882C22E87763C48A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an institution of higher education; or </text></clause><clause id="H07B7CBD96B85472B8A7746239C8630E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a National Laboratory. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0055EE51B34378B16A93BE6A434C58"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applications by institutions of higher education</header><text>An institution of higher education seeking designation as a United States clean energy center of excellence under this paragraph shall submit an application to the Secretary containing, at a minimum, the following:</text><clause id="HDF41EF70692C4904AC56C5BF0A00D2A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of all entities within the institution that would comprise the United States clean energy center of excellence (in this subparagraph referred to as <quote>component entities</quote>).</text></clause><clause id="H8A49AD42BAA54E0AAA16A9BE0E0F9F94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any appropriate information on the qualifications of individuals in key management positions in the institution and the component entities.</text></clause><clause id="H6C6CC5048AF4452BBED49D6A333F499D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A full description of the governance structure and management processes of the institution and the component entities, including a conflict of interest policy.</text></clause><clause id="H4C75301ED47D46FC8412247174978576"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A description of the policies and procedures of the institution and the component entities for managing new intellectual property created by a partnership under this section.</text></clause><clause id="HE3F3D0A7F14342ADA6E1692373BA8CE8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of how the institution would carry out the functions described in paragraph (3).</text></clause><clause id="H69E33547C71A4C00867D88C436D79E40"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Recommendations on—</text><subclause id="HF6C630F41D234410AEB7C27569CB159E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the scope of work for the initial year of activities of the institution under the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H451184C37C4243338A19F216113814D4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>focuses for future programming.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA84FC90CC0A4D26BD2949FDC9C8D505"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Selection process</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall select eligible entities for designation as United States clean energy centers of excellence under this paragraph through an open and competitive process. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC214FDF193A4530BC910AE3FA2962C3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish criteria for selecting United States clean energy centers of excellence based on—</text><clause id="H7627630D4B48446B801A029096F3058B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an evaluation of—</text><subclause id="H39C540958D46410994F47786B5FCA7B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the strength of the governance structure of an eligible entity and the entities within the eligible entity that would comprise the United States clean energy center of excellence;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6F65543B10E24B669869430D860B7F47"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the expertise and experience of key research management and academic personnel of an eligible entity;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9572660DB757447DB095AE69CC1161DD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the demonstrated knowledge of an eligible entity with respect to—</text><item id="HAFEB7C413FA44366A335115898B525D4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>energy markets in India;</text></item><item id="H4550C3CB4036444FAE6F6D1E2080E17F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>regulatory frameworks and energy policies in India;</text></item><item id="HA37FC0AA45244857AA2DAD4DA39EFCA6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>power service providers in India;</text></item><item id="HC8FC17588EB54B5299C503A5742D9A12"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>applied energy technologies in India; and</text></item><item id="H757E0626102C4D71946D420FC4588396"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>energy challenges, including capacity constraints, in India; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1B0B789E4B72424EA343B905517D706B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the capability of an eligible entity to conduct regional energy market analyses and assessments of the practicality of applying various clean energy technologies to address various energy challenges in India;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF8B89E11BCA44B76A1C8535AD5D68A74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commitments of co-funding from non-Federal sources;</text></clause><clause id="HE97312B7FEF742E48744DDBBB91AD5F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability of an eligible entity to attract matching funds from both non-Federal and nongovernmental sources for follow-on investments in widespread application of successful projects; and</text></clause><clause id="H04249E8EB0BC405E839C5DE7598DE449"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the capability and experience of an eligible entity in managing technology transfer programs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0603417EDBF4CD2A37B4C2BF2CAD464"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Selection priority</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall select eligible entities for designation as United States clean energy centers of excellence under this paragraph in a manner that represents the geographic diversity of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06BA6975567148E693DD825C8AF5B773"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Partner institutions in India</header><subparagraph id="HF734943D2F6149869407B6B336D4A7D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and in collaboration with the appropriate ministries of the Government of India, shall support the establishment of partnerships between United States clean energy centers of excellence designated under paragraph (4) and partner entities in India.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5DA9C81C9FF433DAA99810E22901905"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility and selection</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage the Government of India to select partner entities described in subparagraph (A) for participation in partnerships under this section based on criteria similar to the criteria for eligibility and selection of United States clean energy centers of excellence described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB72A1B633CC24A949F01EF56E4554258"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pairing</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and in collaboration with the relevant ministries of the Government of India, shall pair selected United States clean energy centers of excellence designated under paragraph (4) and partner entities in India according to the strength and similarities of the respective applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8CBCD6937D642F2976A578E523C38A9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Private sector involvement</header><text>United States clean energy centers of excellence participating in partnerships under this section are encouraged to, in collaboration with their respective partner entities in India under paragraph (5)—</text><subparagraph id="H5F5376AE408E4E4A978643FB2BC38311"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collaborate with private sector energy and technology companies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69EEDC5D9E66438684DBDB4C2E7EA285"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify private sector entities that will contribute resources to the initiatives and projects developed through partnerships under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DEBD10E5FF9427D85685C748F80EAE6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="H8C0C2D0E99C74701B3DC989029EFA4F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A0988CA3A624A44A1595FEB7294A996"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF8AB74FF2F44A6BB2010CE6B0B5C412"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H87C1385A07DF483FB2726D71F9B474BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026 for the Joint Clean Energy Research and Development Center established by the Department of Energy and the Government of India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F8413C28E7245BD8C01A9D4947E3E2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1) may be used only for clean energy projects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AD1402185B946ED930F2E9F38394387"><enum>(e)</enum><header>United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</header><text>All initiatives established or continued under the authorities of this section shall be part of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF4D5FDFDEFE549F8A9467AA12F296547"><enum>10.</enum><header>Initiatives for technical assistance for grid improvement and energy efficiency in India</header><subsection id="H06FE8A6941224A81A0B5BFCD10E2BC77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, and with the cooperation of the Government of India and regional authorities within India, shall support initiatives, including new initiatives and initiatives in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act, as appropriate, to provide technical assistance and expertise on electrical grid and energy efficiency improvements in India for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HBC6E26BD53A74FEFAE26D568495ADE84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Expanding and improving the reliability, flexibility, and resilience of the electrical grid to reach all regions and populations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A28A346C4D8422A97A71A348C0E284C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing microgrids or distributed energy resources in areas in which connection to the larger electrical grid is challenging.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF39381EA00F447098100C57B1DB887A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increasing the optimal integration of renewable energy into the electrical grid.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB269CBE52F7041368371C3E2BE523C18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhancing the interconnectivity of electrical grids across States of India.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A1F4E0340749E1AA247173DC6206F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Boosting the energy storage capacity of the electrical grid.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H629E4F79FBB34FF98DCF225CCBE61932"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Developing standards for clean energy technologies, smart buildings, and data centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01357759F60E43068D74D466F3C9E06D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Increasing deployment of smart meters and other energy efficiency technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE41D0C7EE3F47BEAE1B88B4793CDBCF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Increasing the energy efficiency of buildings, appliances, and the industrial sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A66D6B550274E3E9FC1FA06AA5A5988"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Improving pollution controls and the efficiency of fossil fuel electric generating units.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7420BFB226F949488D0A8364AF8F369C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H447E17667C0543B881B4C427EABDAF9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</header><text>All initiatives established or continued under the authorities of this section shall be part of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBD7B143CE22F42D09BE704EAA002EF60"><enum>11.</enum><header>Initiatives for generation of new renewable energy in India</header><subsection id="HC47839B85AC34555B93656BD0A7EE944"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, and with the approval of the Government of India, shall support initiatives, including new initiatives and initiatives in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act, as appropriate, to develop new renewable energy generation capacity in India.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD11EA6A3528D41418E01C372D03C715A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of initiatives</header><text>In selecting initiatives to support under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, and in coordination with the Administrator, shall take into account the priorities of the Government of India, including such government’s target of installing 450 gigawatts of renewable energy capacity by 2030 and related goals established by the Intended Nationally Determined Contribution of India to the Paris Agreement, done at Paris December 12, 2015.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB533DF00C6A945D18EF439B15828F78B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA043785297704AD097569AADB6F141DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership</header><text>All initiatives established or continued under the authorities of this section shall be part of the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6B82E6D24101497789230E40A473A217"><enum>12.</enum><header>Report on promotion of State-State clean energy cooperation</header><subsection id="HC35D724725C249CD9716D91CC9B4C6F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator and the Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the prospects for cooperation between States of the United States and States of India on clean energy.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5A41B20A0134410FAC7848FD6AF425E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H63DE71EB541C4C7C9D577EF16318548E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of which areas have the most potential for cooperation between States of the United States and States of India on clean energy technologies, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H03C9C68DFAFC4079A5FF7978CD025805"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrating clean energy into State electrical grids;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47D8D71A4C545F8A9CAC91F86312B49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving the efficiency of State electrical grids;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F828A142E164193B20E5D396143B2D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increasing the resiliency of State electrical grids, especially against cyber attacks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE738CEAB73354714BF360E25D03C8374"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improving power transmission and distribution within States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501D5FCC76D546DC97A162DFCA8CAF2E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>enabling expanded use of electric vehicles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C7E3430E4334729A5F8CB39A5A11DA1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increasing energy efficiency of buildings and methods of transportation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1633590E119C48C1A238BD520E77FCB8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>demonstration projects of new clean energy technologies, including in industrial sectors that are hard to decarbonize;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A8D27E1734C44EBA071B597BC3F4D58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of potential opportunities for cooperation between States of the United States and States of India on the development and deployment of clean energy resources through—</text><subparagraph id="H59228BE1324142378A011F775A2B6D4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal Government programs in existence as of the date of the submittal of the report that provide financial support, technical assistance, or other support for subnational cooperation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4897E1F3DBCD4FA9BA38E02E8F0A9C38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal Government forums in existence as of such date to promote subnational communication; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25E4256E75BC4A4DB73B81C9AA58FCAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for steps the Federal Government, with the cooperation of the Government of India, can take to promote cooperation between States of the United States and States of India on clean energy, which shall include recommendations on—</text><subparagraph id="HC27258740E564E30971870C289F7A2B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which programs or forums in existence as of the date of the submittal of the report should be used to promote such cooperation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AB0DA1641BF4C7BB0A0A3BF427B84C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>new programs or forums that could be created to promote such cooperation, and whether the creation of those programs requires additional authorities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8554BB2EB2F4324BC7E13758AB68FB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what agencies or offices within the Federal Government should lead the implementation of each recommended program or forum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H438259988D074022B725A61FF10124DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>what additional funding would be needed to implement each recommended program or forum; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEE7260239E445678BCCE5304B4B0F3F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>what role the United States mission to India should play in promoting such cooperation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2B5CED1DFED247FABFDCF8A8E4DE3D78"><enum>13.</enum><header>United States-India climate change risk reduction and resilience cooperation</header><subsection id="H8CAC214144774493AEB19DC271CE8A71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, under the direction of the Secretary, shall work cooperatively with the Government of India on integrating scientifically supported climate change risk reduction and building resilience capacities in India. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA69729A5F6254BEB9453236DF4792A20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>Advancing the risk reduction and resilience capacities described in subsection (a) shall be a priority for United States diplomatic, security, and development programs within the United States mission to India.</text></subsection><subsection id="H236883D73A4A41DCBB807A355166BFD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Administrator, under the direction of the Secretary, and in coordination with other agencies with direct international development programs and investments, shall support efforts—</text><paragraph id="H76BB2AFAA1AC4382B52D92F97AA9F97D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to bolster resilience capacities to the effects of climate change in India by supporting efforts in India to help ensure that climate risk assessments and security planning in India adequately evaluate and account for risks and vulnerabilities associated with the effects of climate change using best-available climate change data, forecasts, tools, and information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CDEB8906B7743848F1EBA565E905791"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use shared knowledge, data, forecasts, tools, information, frameworks, and lessons learned in incorporating climate change resilience programming, planning, projects, investments, and related funding decisions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC169C8A1A9D54E8DA1D308B2BF128210"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to work with civil society and local leaders, as appropriate—</text><subparagraph id="HEF750FB7E54F41CFB7847C1F565C7AFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify risks associated with the effects of climate change in India; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD57E212FAC74AD3B369BA3AAA0DE5E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage and support efforts in India to enhance resilience to the effects of climate change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FA87ECF18CF45509DFA377FA6DD0AB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H538275D40A5E45BB84BD321D44AB5144"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agencies with direct international development programs and investments</header><text>The term <term>agencies with direct international development programs and investments</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HF9CCDA5BF1D946FD89BFDCA1F86FDA8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC8928020D1426BA78A2162DFB837A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE04599BAC4E044E1AA2D2286E3DDE04F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C58B4EF907A407CB9E5B73F3A0383B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413FA66999C94DBBA3823FFD2EA2BDA6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00A84E4D9A0148569E18F87EA8D1CA0C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE37116C116FA4A11AE9519C1ABCA57D2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Trade and Development Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF1D3635F6D400D86A3D1FA770C5B67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The term <term>resilience</term> means the ability of an individual, household, community, country, or region to withstand, adapt to, and quickly recover from shocks and stresses associated with the effects of climate change. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

