<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9CCBFFD664DB493DA992D80AB28E9190" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6367 IH: Guaranteeing Ukrainian Autonomy by Reinforcing its Defense (GUARD) Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6367</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220110">January 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote security partnership with Ukraine.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA640D340C3584D3BB1EA6FBE3CC92FD7" style="OLC"><section id="H754B8E5668B3490B89E38729D95CA2BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H7FDE328B72614535B6F38A17AD0BA371"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteeing Ukrainian Autonomy by Reinforcing its Defense (GUARD) Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H202B723904364C228562DB9341FD6A6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H754B8E5668B3490B89E38729D95CA2BB" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6B1E3221DC0044B280E0772D80E9A52D" level="title">Title I—A Deterrence Policy Regarding Ukraine</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB2EB52569E064AF9BAE93385CC3A82B2" level="section">Sec. 101. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD731DD96988043CF817C9659A64921DD" level="section">Sec. 102. Strategy on United States diplomatic support for Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA8EF91AD72714DA28BB52439ADCDFEDB" level="section">Sec. 103. United States ambassador to Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC61C4CEB7EF04C9F8D50B27B52E89F05" level="section">Sec. 104. Potential designation of the Government of Russia as a state sponsor of terrorism.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA7CAF769A3E54B76B5A31BA3608CFFF3" level="section">Sec. 105. Extension and modification of limitation on military cooperation between the United States and Russia.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7062461A82CD4C86ACC394F7A151F064" level="title">Title II—Bolstering Ukraine’s Deterrence Against Russian Aggression</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD266AF69E9774B85946D08CAB78A6497" level="section">Sec. 201. Appropriate congressional committees defined.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6B9879A8635C47D180CD4847F0991654" level="section">Sec. 202. Amendment to presidential drawdown authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA2F0A958CDD14081BD48FAA6DBDA2C94" level="section">Sec. 203. Foreign Military Financing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBF512C6F73C44F519633D279D703DBE6" level="section">Sec. 204. Expedited excess defense articles transfer program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H59451F9C6EB44A7BAF86AFD5ADC8453E" level="section">Sec. 205. Strategy on excess defense articles from allies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCC10781706F54FB2814533A16112A0F4" level="section">Sec. 206. Report on Ukrainian capabilities to counter air-based threats.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H06C8A1B72EBA4B0493312D1677344749" level="section">Sec. 207. International Military Education and Training cooperation with Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H68BEC7217373432CA106A7A2E01C5F43" level="section">Sec. 208. Strategy on IMET programming in Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H56DE0349B6844EE5AB6648FA58D8D61F" level="section">Sec. 209. Sense of Congress on loan program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCB5AA5D805244531BFF9C1217E0E99D4" level="section">Sec. 210. United States-Ukraine strategic security partnership.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD3DA97BA6EF6497680437E8F2008AE95" level="section">Sec. 211. Strategy to protect Ukraine’s defense industry from strategic competitors.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H78C73D464964468D80FB693A02501DF5" level="section">Sec. 212. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD98AD4DC518B41A29113F7F75EB36CCD" level="section">Sec. 213. Expanded broadcasting in countries of the former Soviet Union to combat Russian disinformation and information operations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF175582934B74364ADACBEFBBC8F7D9B" level="section">Sec. 214. Strategy on INCLE programming in Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8E1121D7AE2D4C7F912FAC851371951D" level="section">Sec. 215. Strategy for cooperation on intermediate-range missile launchers and systems to NATO allies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE51E66764A3F480DA1B3F062F53651E2" level="title">Title III—Securing Ukraine Against Russia’s Use of Energy As a Weapon</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC1AB744405094F0CBD89AA14DC0BF339" level="section">Sec. 301. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4AA66832A4C947F0B1C178FBBC380604" level="section">Sec. 302. Congressional review of waiver under Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2B4BDBADDD24440EB4DE01EBE7B9C022" level="section">Sec. 303. Application of congressional review under Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2B69A4FC6C5D432DA43DF6B8B0811EE4" level="section">Sec. 304. Consideration of information provided by Congress in imposing sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD0F7FEB2826046669AAE86E5F6FC3B31" level="section">Sec. 305. Inclusion of matter relating to Nord Stream 2 in report under Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HECAFB7FB18CF4C6E9EB6D446BE0D0DDF" level="section">Sec. 306. Ukraine security assistance initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6EBE0AA61B5B45EEBBE71D754C502D4B" level="section">Sec. 307. Appropriate congressional committees defined.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="H6B1E3221DC0044B280E0772D80E9A52D"><enum>I</enum><header>A Deterrence Policy Regarding Ukraine</header><section id="HB2EB52569E064AF9BAE93385CC3A82B2"><enum>101.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="H9364230B83D44761AD87D7D966E488EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD692518FE24D4AC78CB7AC695D23E4D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>declassify or downgrade United States intelligence, consistent with the need to protect sources and methods, on Russian malign activities in Ukraine, Belarus, and the Baltic and Black Sea nations, to the maximum extent possible, to enable and encourage dissemination to United States allies and partners and to the American public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B042AA3B8047ACA9ED11714392E595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide critical capabilities, including surface-to-air missiles, air defense systems, anti-ship missiles, anti-tank mines, and others, to Ukraine on an expedited basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0847E304F18A4905B27710FC011EFA60"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirm <quote>the freedom of States to choose their own security arrangements,</quote> as pledged in the 1990 Charter of Paris for a New Europe, to which Russia was a signatory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DA49FAA5D044078B8C9595499FE1731"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demand the Government of Russia reaffirms its commitment to agreements to which it is a signatory, including the 1975 Helsinki Final Act, the 1990 Charter of Paris, and the 1994 Budapest Memorandum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA30C73F01F64103BBC04C3240C1C95F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>remain fully committed to NATO’s Open Door Policy, which provides a path to membership for any European country that shares our values and meets the necessary responsibilities and obligations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E336080D517464FADE1527E7E4DCDEA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>continue to fully support NATO’s decision in the 2008 Bucharest Summit Declaration, reaffirmed ever since, including in the June 2021 Brussels Summit, that Ukraine and Georgia will become NATO members;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8354B6E1DDD34AA58A8BDFFFA9A99996"><enum>(8)</enum><text>commit to include all relevant European countries in discussions about European security and to prioritize existing mechanisms, such as the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe and the NATO-Russia Council, for those discussions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E044DBF0FB743FB8423B8A3160B8C1E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>reject the proposals publicized on December 17, 2021, by the Government of Russia as a legitimate basis of negotiations on European security issues;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H220A3DC238914D40AB51A2F0D4AC51CE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>repudiate Russia’s proposal for a <quote>deployment moratorium</quote> in the European theater for intermediate-range ground launched missile systems that were previously banned under the Intermediate Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty until Russia repeatedly violated the agreement causing its demise;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2CF05564C5D4C69BC2FBD396C12A506"><enum>(11)</enum><text>encourage near-term, in-person visits by United States and Ukraine leaders to each other’s countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A42D02E41E45339C32CA11FC55BA43"><enum>(12)</enum><text>support the rapid deployment of additional observers from the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe to monitor the Ukraine-Russian border and report aggressive acts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACF629A224F547F89B760C01C656E57B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>continue the current United States nuclear declaratory policy of <quote>calculated ambiguity</quote> and reject changes to United States nuclear declaratory policy of <quote>calculated ambiguity</quote> and reject changes to United States nuclear declaratory policy that would invite further Russian aggression and undermine NATO unity, and tempt nuclear proliferation, such as <quote>Sole Purpose,</quote><quote>Fundamental Purpose,</quote> or <quote>No First Use</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD731DD96988043CF817C9659A64921DD"><enum>102.</enum><header>Strategy on United States diplomatic support for Ukraine</header><subsection id="HD426636C5DFA424DA955842DC26E9403"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report with a strategy on how the United States will work to diplomatically support Ukraine during fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB9608BF6B66E4751A457EBE345DDAC05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H980CEAB72A6D4A57BDBF9C8C81F46416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how relevant departments and agencies of the United States Government will work together to collectively support efforts by the Government of Ukraine to deter Russian aggression in the form of military incursions, cyber attacks, the coercive use of energy resources, the disruption of lawful commerce and traffic to Ukrainian ports, use of passportization, efforts to corrupt the Ukrainian political and economic systems, and attempts to manipulate the public through disinformation campaigns.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C8169C732EA483C9066FF6334E9B7A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the United States current efforts and strategy to support Ukrainian diplomatic initiatives when they align with United States interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE31E53FB34EC4D0D851573B171D80103"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A strategy on how the United States will use its voice and vote at the United Nations, OSCE, Council of Europe, NATO, and other relevant international bodies to support Ukraine and its reform efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6C998E236914F13B994B48481BF8F4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A strategy on how the United States will assist Ukraine in bolstering its diplomatic, economic, energy, and maritime relationships with key Black Sea countries, including Bulgaria, Romania, Turkey, and Georgia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C575CB6C5FE483FA57083D254BAE7AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A strategy on how the United States will engage with Germany, France, Ukraine, and Russia to advance the Normandy Format and Minsk Agreements, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3D1D1CB315D74A7F829B79107097D3A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to set Russia’s adherence to an immediate and comprehensive cease-fire and the withdrawal of Russian forces, military equipment and mercenaries from the territory of Ukraine as prerequisites to further negotiations on other provisions of the Minsk Agreements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H653CEBDB972F47828756B63FADCCE32F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure Kyiv is not obliged to alter the status of the areas in the Donbas illegally occupied by Russian-backed separatists in a manner that would permanently undermine the Government of Ukraine’s full sovereignty over the region or foreclose its freedom to choose its own security arrangements and foreign policy trajectory.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85ADEABC93C4E0EB7BA037F5D6E49F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of Ukraine’s recent progress on anti-corruption reforms and a strategy on how the United States will work with allies to continue to engage Ukraine to ensure meaningful progress on democratic, economic, and anti-corruption reforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B131D8A1DE45B68A037CF2F58C0436"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the views of United States European allies and partners, including Ukraine and NATO members that joined the alliance in 1999 or after, of the proposals publicized on December 17, 2021, by the Government of Russia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8A351C3E51449E3ABF24E6EE029042B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2686D84B5E204B939B243381101B06B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H9FE52484A4E04D139EC50BDD425E25D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD4D5B8B0D347A68F41E99676AFA7CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA8EF91AD72714DA28BB52439ADCDFEDB"><enum>103.</enum><header>United States ambassador to Ukraine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HD83E5B5E85BC48D7B9510D9366DFFC69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>President Biden’s failure to appoint a United States ambassador to Ukraine has undermined the United States-Ukraine bilateral relationship and has played into Russia’s calculus regarding its military buildup in and around Ukraine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A43FCCF5774F5486FB34BEAF1F63EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Biden should move to expeditiously submit to the Senate for its advice-and-consent a nominee for the Ambassador to Ukraine that has experience addressing the Russian problem set and serving in war zones or conflict areas.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC61C4CEB7EF04C9F8D50B27B52E89F05"><enum>104.</enum><header>Potential designation of the Government of Russia as a state sponsor of terrorism</header><subsection id="H1B7485907D7D4E70AE73FD8595493C70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination that indicates whether the Government of Russia meets the criteria to be designated as a state sponsor of terrorism.</text></subsection><subsection id="H77713262511040CC8AECD050F902302F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>state sponsor of terrorism</quote> means a country, the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>), section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>), section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>), or any other provision of law, is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7AD54BEE1A143D5A2DC77159C419389"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The reporting requirement authorized under subsection (a) shall terminate 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F10B3361BB54A35AE11DD4B14DBD4F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HDC77171FD17745DE9A059ECF1864DB5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5737C71DFD1F4434945336F052832D8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA7CAF769A3E54B76B5A31BA3608CFFF3"><enum>105.</enum><header>Extension and modification of limitation on military cooperation between the United States and Russia</header><subsection id="H5EF9B623020148C2AF94C89B45ACACCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1232 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2488) is amended by striking <quote>or 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2021, or 2022</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B1B4F7E287349258EF4E5F4A140316B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>Subsection (c)(2) of such section is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HC4AA998EB03A4707B4F9435851B58C00" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF7BE4303E39C4487A33654CA23C5FF87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 15 days before the date on which the waiver takes effect, and every 90 days thereafter, submits to the appropriate congressional committees—</text><subparagraph id="H2B5EB42AFEA5494698428DE4D050A02A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a notification that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States and a description of the national security interest covered by the waiver during the applicable reporting period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ADE7C23D35946E3BCE3B312B8B48F97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any condition or prerequisite placed by Russia on military cooperation between the United States and Russia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15BCA3F992B34059A8BCA4B035F98058"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the results achieved by United States-Russia military cooperation during the applicable reporting period and an assessment of whether such results meet the national security objectives described under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09D9AC331FAC459A9E3B28CA5C2747A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the measures in place to mitigate counterintelligence or operational security concerns and an assessment of whether such measures have succeeded, submitted in classified form as necessary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36D9D18AA4384A208197FECD847CFBFF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a report, submitted in classified form as necessary, explaining why the Secretary of Defense cannot make the certification under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="H7062461A82CD4C86ACC394F7A151F064"><enum>II</enum><header>Bolstering Ukraine’s Deterrence Against Russian Aggression</header><section id="HD266AF69E9774B85946D08CAB78A6497"><enum>201.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H1AFAC444E0224795911F07200AB7722E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC120BBFAD9C3491DA41AAF00338760BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6B9879A8635C47D180CD4847F0991654"><enum>202.</enum><header>Amendment to presidential drawdown authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority under section 506(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2318">22 U.S.C. 2318(a)</external-xref>) may be exercised during fiscal year 2022 for Ukraine to the maximum extent available for that fiscal year, without diminishing the dollar limitation available under that section for such fiscal year.</text></section><section id="HA2F0A958CDD14081BD48FAA6DBDA2C94"><enum>203.</enum><header>Foreign Military Financing</header><subsection id="H2107B54337E04193AD1818A392586A7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State for fiscal year 2022 $450,000,000 for Foreign Military Financing (FMF) assistance to Ukraine to assist the country in meeting its defense needs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H29492390E42C45B2BB9D762078FA848D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text>Not later than 15 days before providing assistance or support pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a notification containing the following:</text><paragraph id="HFFF70AD24F584008A3F97B64BC81E88B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the assistance or support to be provided, including—</text><subparagraph id="H840FADBC7B1046B9A5EFE7310DAB405A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the objectives of such assistance or support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CC3F8196FFE4E15A5B3F34753D1C4F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the budget for such assistance or support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF416ED703DCC48D7836852739089716C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected or estimated timeline for delivery of such assistance or support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H987C5A3DF44942F7808D646CE6E53CB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86220AA9F3F24FF0880FBA25DE6C422C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated under this section, $200,000,000 shall be set aside to—</text><paragraph id="H2586B6AA6EA4423898561CCA3806B7A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize the development of Ukrainian air defense capabilities, to include weapons systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H412B1A52D8CC45D7A38835D1257BD85A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize the procurement of vessels for the Ukrainian Navy and other articles that bolster the capacity of the Ukrainian Navy to counter Russian maritime aggression and maintain the freedom of innocent passage throughout the Black Sea; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61F39962F63C4DBAB9BAE194F727EF65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure adequate planning for maintenance for any equipment provided.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF353E4BFE4354739B8C5FC3528DA34FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To provide lethal assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized to provide lethal assistance under this section, including anti-armor weapon systems, mortars, crew-served weapons and ammunition, grenade launchers and ammunition, anti-tank weapons systems, anti-ship weapons systems, anti-aircraft weapons systems, and small arms and ammunition.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBF512C6F73C44F519633D279D703DBE6"><enum>204.</enum><header>Expedited excess defense articles transfer program</header><subsection id="H9460E6405D044F748CCC9403B09F8599"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine shall be given the same priority as that given other countries and regions under section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5F1BF49637742F5AF11EBEA97E7076B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Notwithstanding section 516(f) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(f)</external-xref>), during fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine shall be subject to a 15-day notification requirement.</text></subsection></section><section id="H59451F9C6EB44A7BAF86AFD5ADC8453E"><enum>205.</enum><header>Strategy on excess defense articles from allies</header><subsection id="HB98AB7E406F346A5ACC878AF92899428"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a classified strategy on how the United States will encourage, reimburse, or otherwise incentivize third countries to donate excess defense equipment to Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE093DFE00DD2488C884781E9B93AF7CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HF8580746691B40F3A2145BAC3DF8EF1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A listing of all friendly and allied nations that have excess defense material that may be compatible with the needs and systems utilized by the Armed Forces of Ukraine, including air defense systems, small arms and ammunition, artillery and multiple-launch rocket systems, anti-ship systems, and anti-tank systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64C294207F9145C994380840E25BE5EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the diplomatic efforts undertaken by the United States Government to encourage, reimburse, or otherwise incentivize allied and partner nations to donate their excess defense articles to Ukraine on an expedited basis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCC10781706F54FB2814533A16112A0F4"><enum>206.</enum><header>Report on Ukrainian capabilities to counter air-based threats</header><subsection id="H88379640E9D744B9AC72AF0CAC29A37E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the capabilities of Ukraine to counter air-based threats.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFABF0DADBBD9436899E1545A4FD6F171"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HA37880F10A2A4D61B0EDDC383F072D4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the risk to the armed forces of Ukraine posed by aerial threats, including current threats from weaponized unmanned aerial vehicles, manned aircraft, and missile and rocket attacks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7276A0CB47E54127B12D55EE1F65DF5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the current defensive capabilities of Ukraine to counter the threats described in paragraph (1) and assessed gaps in capabilities to address such threats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BFAD740BC94464E94DC969AC6BFF1F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of current efforts to build the defensive capabilities of Ukraine, an assessment of potential options for additional United States security assistance to address shortfalls identified pursuant to paragraph (2), and any considerations with regard to absorption capacity, maintenance, and sustainment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H06C8A1B72EBA4B0493312D1677344749"><enum>207.</enum><header>International Military Education and Training cooperation with Ukraine</header><subsection id="H4A70D58424324219B4ECF759AAB74754"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026 for International Military Education and Training (IMET) assistance for Ukraine. The assistance shall be made available for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HCB131E4A7BE24BACB86C53F925DF7478"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training of future leaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB16EA4D0046245819F055E4DD1279955"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fostering a better understanding of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68FE15A49FDD48D4AC1EE7270805BC9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establishing a rapport between the United States Armed Forces, regional allies and partners, and Ukraine’s military to build partnerships for the future.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0E2A01499BC4B0BA89AA9E86ECCFB29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhancement of interoperability and capabilities for joint operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6711F6CA4F465880916CCCF2204E86"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Focusing on professional military education, civilian control of the military, and human rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD49276FE9C4E4603937D72A1A2F07C69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text>Not later than 15 days before providing assistance or support pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a notification containing the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H9B24506DC37F4FC8BFEC4AE99C4ACF29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the assistance or support to be provided, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE43889B304454999B99A1D9E9880CCC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the objectives of such assistance or support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24667516CDE44352A9BBADC51AC59688"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the budget for such assistance or support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72B4E8A89AAB410E8EA09DBCE4954A50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected or estimated timeline for delivery of such assistance or support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AA22D82FEF4472A967BCF39C7C630AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H68BEC7217373432CA106A7A2E01C5F43"><enum>208.</enum><header>Strategy on IMET programming in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H2DBDE12C1EC04857B4B9FC57BC8E8709"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Government of Ukraine should fully utilize the United States IMET program, encourage eligible officers and civilian leaders to participate in the training, and promote successful graduates to positions of prominence in the Ukrainian Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60495F6B8C684E2185B79FB3429F936D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for the implementation of the IMET program in Ukraine authorized under section 207.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE6488C7FF9A4E8AAAA504C64D32D166"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HF91AD1FB105141CCAC09D97ED3924481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A clear plan, developed in close consultation with the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense and the Armed Forces of Ukraine, for how the IMET program will be used by the United States Government and the Government of Ukraine to propel program graduates to positions of prominence in support of the Ukrainian military’s reform efforts in line with NATO standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72A8733F755F48359DD8CEDE2D4AF17E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the education and training requirements of the Ukrainian military and clear recommendations for how IMET graduates should be assigned by the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense upon completion of education or training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92A36A9344C46D4A44B256A5EF93BE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An accounting of the current combat requirements of the Ukrainian military and an assessment of the viability of alternative mobile training teams, distributed learning, and other flexible solutions to reach such students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6579775965094FE5B1658B7703380B78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of opportunities to influence the next generation of leaders through attendance at United States staff and war colleges, junior leader development programs, and technical schools.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A23182B8F1E4128BC52CAF1BFF7F29E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H56DE0349B6844EE5AB6648FA58D8D61F"><enum>209.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on loan program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H38E3B293E1624B86BA5272FDD1F85632"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as appropriate, the United States Government should provide direct loans to Ukraine for the procurement of defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services pursuant to the authority of section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>) to support the further development of Ukraine’s military forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H476C5D815D31477E8DDC61C9723E578A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such loans should be considered an additive security assistance tool, and not a substitute for Foreign Military Financing for grant assistance or Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative programming.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCB5AA5D805244531BFF9C1217E0E99D4"><enum>210.</enum><header>United States-Ukraine strategic security partnership</header><subsection id="H7687CB139E8E4BE6A07B1FECB431CB81" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H588726D0DE044D48BDCF9EE9E55A7B1F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expeditious consideration of certifications of letters of offer to sell defense articles, defense services, design and construction services, and major defense equipment to Ukraine under section 36(b) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)</external-xref>) is in the security and foreign policy interests of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82CDAE8604314FFD8BBD4F8113330DC6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of Ukraine as a member of the colloquially titled <quote>NATO Plus</quote> community of states, which presently includes Japan, Australia, the Republic of Korea, Israel, and New Zealand, with respect to consideration by Congress of Foreign Military Sales to Ukraine, as well as all other rights, privileges, and responsibilities afforded to such community of states, is in the security and foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09C4AFC7799544578618527A83F55465" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application and administration of provisions of law with respect to Ukraine</header><text>During the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, in furtherance of the United States support for Ukraine’s NATO aspirations, including through work towards a Membership Action Plan, or until Ukraine deposits its instrument of accession to the North Atlantic Treaty with the Department of State in Washington, DC, Ukraine shall be treated as if it were a country listed in the provisions of law described in subsection (c) for purposes of applying and administering such provisions of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H474AC1DFB4004CC3817657B315C2B3C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provisions of law described</header><text>The provisions of law described in this subsection are—</text><paragraph id="HAC9C9725935546558C22C6B923D456AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subsections (b)(2), (d)(2)(B), (d)(3)(A)(i), and (d)(5) of section 3 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2753">22 U.S.C. 2753</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F263DC0FCBF4852A6231D9373CF3BC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsections (e)(2)(A), (h)(1)(A), and (h)(2) of section 21 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2761">22 U.S.C. 2761</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE9CD913B1E1476194C1D6F9733091E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subsection (b)(1) and subsections (b)(2), (b)(6), (c)(2)(A), (c)(5), and (d)(2)(A) of section 36 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E26BCBB22474751B0BF0053C5E81DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>section 62(c)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2796a">22 U.S.C. 2796a(c)(1)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC94978964855492AB1BA90BE7A6215E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>section 63(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2796b">22 U.S.C. 2796b(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7870BAB1AB0A4E1CBB8B2C182436F15D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continued application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to continue to treat Ukraine as if it were a country listed in the provisions of law described in subsection (c) for purposes of applying and administering such provisions of law for one or more additional 3-year periods, or until Ukraine deposits its instrument of accession to the North Atlantic Treaty with the Department of State in Washington, DC, beginning after the end of the 5-year period described in subsection (b) if, with respect to each such additional 3-year period, the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H7137FE8219EC4F07A471F71AA3D326CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such continued application is in the national security interest of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA566DBEDD885482EBA33F8AE2BBD57F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determines that such continued application is carried out alongside United States support for Ukraine’s NATO aspirations, including through work towards a Membership Action Plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC844127902AD42C8BB42B57F1D296C84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submits such determination to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate not later than 15 days before the start of such an additional 3-year period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H294FB8CC695240B5816BFAA5666437AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date on which Ukraine deposits its instrument of accession to the North Atlantic Treaty with the Department of State in Washington, DC.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD3DA97BA6EF6497680437E8F2008AE95"><enum>211.</enum><header>Strategy to protect Ukraine’s defense industry from strategic competitors</header><subsection id="H36203F845284448B9F3AD97E016486E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should work with the Government of Ukraine to ensure strategic assets and companies in Ukraine’s aerospace and defense sector are not subject to foreign ownership, control, or undue influence by strategic competitors to the United States, such as the People’s Republic of China (PRC). These efforts will require support from across the Executive Branch and should leverage all available tools and authorities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF1BA27B66C2941169490DFCBCA100CCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><paragraph id="HA035F38E104B4D1EA17595EFF5F37384"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President, acting through the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State and in consultation with the heads of other relevant Departments and agencies as the President may determine, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a strategy to support Ukraine in protecting its aerospace and defense industry from predatory investments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48456763CEBF4F61A85F0B4F7166C76A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="HA3531A44D8094DAF85025C08807D160D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the efforts by strategic competitors, such as the PRC, to acquire strategic assets and companies in Ukraine’s aerospace and defense sector and the national security implications for Ukraine, the United States, and other NATO allies and partners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2104FFD36B3A4F6A8269F8BBAB652A58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the vulnerabilities that strategic competitors of the United States exploit to acquire strategic assets in the Ukrainian aerospace and defense sector, Ukraine’s progress in addressing them, and United States initiatives to support these efforts such as assistance in strengthening Ukraine’s investment screening and national security vetting laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51003E96DA004DCB93D956AD714C7720"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of Ukraine’s efforts to make reforms necessary to incentivize Western investment in Ukraine’s aerospace and defense sector and United States support for these efforts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H668F4C36A1CE42BBA831568940C5433A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A strategy to—</text><clause id="H125F42E28B274019AC14C4207C170F08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promote, as appropriate, United States direct investment in Ukraine’s aerospace and defense sector;</text></clause><clause id="H6C632B3922B64BC1BEBB9CED3C19854F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>better leverage tools like debt financing, equity investments, and political risk insurance to incentivize greater participation by United States firms;</text></clause><clause id="HEDFE3F8083504043BD3076B166FEBFD1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide an alternative to PRC investments; and</text></clause><clause id="H1ED571BD3C50401F9207B0E0340E7FC4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>engage like-minded allies and partners on these efforts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4585089B15D477BAF5AE5122180089F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in classified form.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H78C73D464964468D80FB693A02501DF5"><enum>212.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HD09FA95901814B8D83980A9D539A023B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2026 for the purposes described in subsection (b) with respect to Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE5A264D86B145B18D74E2282BC14D1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) may only be used—</text><paragraph id="HA518412AC8404AF4B6878DA3A1EFF678"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to strengthen Ukraine’s cyber security, cyber resilience and intellectual property enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C203BF91C54571B1F221AD465AD0EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide support and training in Ukraine for—</text><subparagraph id="HCCB94D2EC01F4571855B7D7DF1DE6650"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sectoral reforms related to banking and public finance management reform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H262EE63E4F2D4F46AD554C128DDB0FB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the privatization of state-owned enterprises;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33F1481506B74440AC44C268F7DEE13B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>regulatory independence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26A3FEE551604A7F8A7DA43F72D815C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subsidy reform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD2CF588AA79470BB274214685AD4119"><enum>(E)</enum><text>land reform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04F112D2A02C4DB781A1FDE9A0C8BC1D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>corporate governance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD871D0A8B2142EA84ABBF83349419A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>foreign investment screening;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79948ED1CFB643CD9E487C4F4AB9A04B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to combat corruption, improve the rule of law, and otherwise strengthen independent legal institutions, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H378AD0B3F713468F8994BE2E4CDB56AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expanding regional anti-corruption training and exchanges among Ukrainian Ministry officials, law enforcement officers, judges, and prosecutors to build peer support, share best practices, maintain reform momentum, and protect reforms from capture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257DB41F66804BCC96760939132249C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting regional training of United States Embassy personal responsible for supporting anti-corruption and the rule of law to improve their effectiveness in supporting the consolidation and expansion of reform;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A6166D80EB46948EC2C57BFDBF7CF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to respond to the humanitarian crises caused or aggravated by the invasion and occupation of Ukraine by Russia, including by supporting internally displaced persons and communities in conflict-affected areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAA831B604DF4A8A85BE8F92A9E65874"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to improve participatory legislative processes in Ukraine, including through—</text><subparagraph id="H4CBEB686DA994A6A825B32CC9DFA618B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engagement with members of the Verkhovna Rada;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97ACD98A9F90408C9BAC4E6899DD0062"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training on government oversight, legal education, political transparency and competition, and compliance with international obligations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E09721170F449F9F748A0AA6994F6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting the development of professional legislative staff to advise and assist member of the Verkhovna Rada and committees in the execution of their duties and build legal and policy expertise within the Verkhovna Rada; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F983DABDA14431A56B8F75666CDEE0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to further build the capacity of civil society, independent media, human rights, and other nongovernmental organizations in Ukraine, with an emphasis on—</text><subparagraph id="H44D47033F1F14017A29977C5E009C566"><enum>(A)</enum><text>building capacity outside of Kyiv; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6CD0928C9F4B3190D1A2B50615406B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regional civil society training and exchange programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD98AD4DC518B41A29113F7F75EB36CCD"><enum>213.</enum><header>Expanded broadcasting in countries of the former Soviet Union to combat Russian disinformation and information operations</header><subsection id="H6C2A5E3753C649B69A8FD61F07C795CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the U.S. Agency for Global Media $155,500,000 for fiscal year 2022 for purposes of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty expanded broadcasting in countries of the former Soviet Union to combat Russian disinformation and information operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB2831F8F0804784A3DA0DFF1AE090F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritization of broadcasting into ukraine, georgia, moldova, and belarus</header><text>Amount appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) shall prioritize broadcasting to Ukraine, Belarus, Georgia, and Moldova.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF175582934B74364ADACBEFBBC8F7D9B"><enum>214.</enum><header>Strategy on INCLE programming in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H0DD048FB326A49A986708886BAE32987"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Government of Ukraine should fully utilize the United States International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement (INCLE) program, to continue to support the Ministry of the Interior and the Security Service, and the Public Prosecution Service of Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1673384334554A36AFD703BA9CE4914D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for the implementation of the INCLE program in Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB6754D416BA4F7FA2CE586AD2BD3429"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H489E1DBB80BE47A6B3DF422825214AE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A plan for the INCLE program in Ukraine to enhance the capacity of the National Anti-Corruption Bureau of Ukraine, the Specialized Anti-Corruption Prosecutor’s Office and the High Anti-Corruption Court, as well as other institutions and ministries involved in conducting prosecutorial reform efforts, investigating allegations of corruption, prosecuting individuals engaged in corrupt practices, and transnational organized criminal activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H443CC321086C4EE7AA7F39579919D1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An accounting of fiscal year 2020 and fiscal year 2021 INCLE spending and an evaluation of the program implementation identifying Ukrainian partners, implementers, and unexpended assistance from these fiscal years and prior fiscal years that remain unexpended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H182114B1DA654CCDBD92B267C29457B0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, and may be accompanied by a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8E1121D7AE2D4C7F912FAC851371951D"><enum>215.</enum><header>Strategy for cooperation on intermediate-range missile launchers and systems to NATO allies</header><subsection id="H2FD5896B742C44F7AE44215BD3F57C8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD4272A20624940399ED3110B924A74CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All NATO allies agree that the SSC-8/9M729 missile system developed and deployed by the Government of Russia violated the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty (in this section referred to as the <quote>INF Treaty</quote>), while posing a significant risk to NATO security. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F5A4C9767D14002863D97F31669BEDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite NATO allies’ repeated calls on the Government of Russia to return to full and verifiable compliance with the INF Treaty, Russia continued to develop and deploy INF Treaty-violating systems, which led to the INF Treaty’s demise on August 2, 2019. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H083CA7F1E60D41C2B114324C2AF75834"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As of the INF Treaty’s demise, Russia had produced and deployed multiple battalions of INF Treaty-violating missiles, capable of reaching key European capitals and targets. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8034695F428440D8B64E3C5B3E23D870"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mutual deployment moratorium in the European theater with the Russian Federation is not in the interest of the United States. Even if a European-Theater intermediate-range ground-launched missile deployment moratorium were verifiable, any such moratorium would significantly advantage Russia and disadvantage NATO. This is due to the Russian Federation’s continual threats of aggression against sovereign European nations, the relative ease by which Russia could deploy such systems to the theater, and the logistical impediments with which the United States and NATO would have to contend should it be determined a commensurate response was warranted. </text></subsection><subsection id="HF92D317DEBEB49B8A3ADD09790A57F38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall jointly develop a strategy to cooperate with willing NATO member countries in the joint research, development, training and possible transfer of conventional intermediate-range ground-launched missiles, associated launchers and support equipment, and associated technology.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HE51E66764A3F480DA1B3F062F53651E2"><enum>III</enum><header>Securing Ukraine Against Russia’s Use of Energy As a Weapon</header><section id="HC1AB744405094F0CBD89AA14DC0BF339"><enum>301.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2</header><subsection id="H4FFF2AA1E72147A6B43BF15A29455FCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H47A3207F05EC4BFDB7D476E3815E5CDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to any corporate officer of an entity established for or responsible for the planning, construction, or operation of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline or a successor entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FF1950310E04BE7BECAD3101007FA9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose sanctions under subsection (c) with respect to any entity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4AC24F2D2744BAC8E1FE4075D1C165C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole of identified persons and corporate officers</header><paragraph id="HF4C9C8BE45D14A0AB98E2C1CA60400F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a)(1) is—</text><subparagraph id="H1B633665A37746E39170D93DD9B3F01F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE21982B4B1742E086C564DBC8489BD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1D1F09EC88A44E0982C2BA9B060B981"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H441FF955F0FD42D9B4E87406243308A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph id="HDDAC810D55BE47FC9BB483364870AEB3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subsection (a)(1) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H207E6955E8FC4CB79B5F8CBC2568683C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><clause id="H5CE8BE9AE40542C3BBD6D4C7FF45F26D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause id="H6097D0CA13B94EF499BE94E584070B70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC305B90684244EA3958F7D478111DB60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Blocking of property of identified persons</header><text>The President shall exercise all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of an entity described in subsection (a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2EFB1555150440E92763A8E05CEA8CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H0D9C1D449D214165BE94330986B1084D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to law enforcement activities, activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2091">50 U.S.C. 2091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H110F96DDB8FC4182A62C53E3E7D9DD6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to comply with united nations headquarters agreement</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien to the United States if the admission of the alien is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEB51A54256141DF9179CF97F1F669FC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conditions for removal of sanctions</header><paragraph id="H328D2C664D1946139B9DE7051C56D483"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the President may waive the application of sanctions under this section if the President—</text><subparagraph id="HE4A46A1D8CF548E18F82CB0B4BDDCAE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF299D018704D689D01C8897D2C1BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the waiver and the reason for the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE7F5AFA84F64E619A48E32CE4293AE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (b) and (c) of section 216 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9511">22 U.S.C. 9511</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to a waiver of the application of sanctions under this section to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a proposed action described in subsection (a) of section 216 of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC2B0477ADB4499685044CCA068A1E27"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="HF55A6805C1E34820AA4069931DA80539"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8D212CCD1384D6BAF273BF11989AC25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46C0A7BC34884889A91AE56720D22F1A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority to impose sanctions under this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4EE6A4DCF0984304967F514FB6C315D5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H97D664073B4F42B19A9FADD178FFC968"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <quote>admission</quote>, <quote>admitted</quote>, and <quote>alien</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7924EFF6E8BE4A10B78C3F24B41B4C49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress </quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H032FAE649148433797D94B42FEBB7B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB29FCB07E7149C096C03320E8AE18D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H021DEB4C43D2470E99BB05BFFE640F42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE9FD116DDF3B4944AE03C372E1F891C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H686782ED1872484681B94426EC5786AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2995B45D023243799444EB8D7DC42641"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person within the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4AA66832A4C947F0B1C178FBBC380604"><enum>302.</enum><header>Congressional review of waiver under Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7503(f) of the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 (title LXXV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9526">22 U.S.C. 9526</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3BB432D22669425A8A5FC6E59720A685" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H990953B9E3D14951A166719E715136C1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>National interest waiver</header><paragraph id="HF698FD93492841E1ADAF85CC55880AAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President—</text><subparagraph id="H2B8DDA4C6A56424282B5004177CFCAAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the waiver is in the national interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E43CC8AECCE4399A7D28DC584FF0274"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC3D77C48F52407685182015A30C80CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (b) and (c) of section 216 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9511">22 U.S.C. 9511</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to a waiver of the application of sanctions under this section to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a proposed action described in subsection (a) of section 216 of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2B4BDBADDD24440EB4DE01EBE7B9C022"><enum>303.</enum><header>Application of congressional review under Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 216(a)(2) of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9511">22 U.S.C. 9511(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H53478C3DC16A4B8A8476B57EED6E893F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="H1E5199B6D5854C3EAF0BB11FF41B0BE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>(other than sanctions described in clause (i)(IV) of that subparagraph)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C451817A2B943809ABE78484CEECFB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or otherwise remove</quote> after <quote>waive</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C17FFDFA11045AFB910D5BEDCA87917"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)—</text><subparagraph id="HBB2C40E11D914421A0FFE9724DC7ECA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A09EC251A8A4EA89BF8585DE1AA47C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61D336CCDAB14E16A8A2CC03547438A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC7A6C89CA3F7468DBFA631363453007F" style="OLC"><subclause id="HB085DA3B32354A2691C0928472BA4C3B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Executive Order No. 14024 (86 Fed. Reg. 20249; relating to Blocking Property With Respect To Specified Harmful Foreign Activities of the Government of the Russian Federation);</text></subclause><subclause id="H5C96EAD7F2C4456BB1F88B423E3A01C8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>section 7503 of the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 (title LXXV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9526">22 U.S.C. 9526</external-xref> note); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H0593712DF407415CB9FC614A6A40BDC9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 301 of the <short-title>Guaranteeing Ukrainian Autonomy by Reinforcing its Defense (GUARD) Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2B69A4FC6C5D432DA43DF6B8B0811EE4"><enum>304.</enum><header>Consideration of information provided by Congress in imposing sanctions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receiving a written request from the chairperson and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate with respect to whether a foreign person or entity has engaged in an activity described in section 1 of Executive Order No. 14024 (86 Fed. Reg. 20249; relating to Blocking Property With Respect To Specified Harmful Foreign Activities of the Government of the Russian Federation), the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H23D0CF85AF7C462D90298677536E7A64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine if that person has engaged in such an activity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE88AA4D57A49FEB618F258922C72BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the chairperson and ranking member of that committee with respect to that determination that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H7320D68E1D5E4D768028D0CF457CA940"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to the person; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ACA28DDDB304CFF8D5D49CF84B4D6D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions, a description of those sanctions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HD0F7FEB2826046669AAE86E5F6FC3B31"><enum>305.</enum><header>Inclusion of matter relating to Nord Stream 2 in report under Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each report submitted under section 216(a)(1) of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9511">22 U.S.C. 9511(a)(1)</external-xref>) relating to sanctions under section 301 of this Act or section 7503 of the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 (title LXXV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9526">22 U.S.C. 9526</external-xref> note) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H53988964816548B586929859AC88656A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the security risks posed by Nord Stream 2, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA745FC94D8B640D8B73F68B85BD9D256"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the presence along Nord Stream 2 or Nord Stream 1 infrastructure or pipeline corridors of undersea surveillance systems and sensors, fiber optic terminals, or other systems that are capable of conducting military or intelligence activities unrelated to civilian energy transmission, including those designed to enhance Russian anti-submarine warfare, surveillance, espionage, or sabotage capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D84EE04F6FA4D8BB4BB09D22B4CF5CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of Nord Stream-affiliated infrastructure, equipment, personnel, vessels, financing, or other assets—</text><clause id="H425F2ADB42194A5BB70981011C94F673"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to facilitate, carry out, or conceal Russian maritime surveillance, espionage, or sabotage activities;</text></clause><clause id="HDBF7CA62FF734398B06FF5E065AC5403"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to justify the presence of Russian naval vessels or military personnel or equipment in international waters or near North Atlantic Treaty Organization or partner countries;</text></clause><clause id="HFACB97D9BF3B44069AD547DE67453CB2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to disrupt freedom of navigation; or</text></clause><clause id="HA2303A067183423E8E52074896BB4D7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to pressure or intimidate countries in the Baltic Sea;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A04C7F2547148649D1DEFA584ED4CB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the involvement in the Nord Stream 2 pipeline or its affiliated entities of current or former Russian, Soviet, or Warsaw Pact intelligence and military personnel and any business dealings between Nord Stream 2 and entities affiliated with the intelligence or defense sector of Russia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H209FB3D6101E42DEB2DB78A67BA04824"><enum>(D)</enum><text>malign influence activities of the Government of Russia, including strategic corruption and efforts to influence European decisionmakers, supported or financed through the Nord Stream 2 pipeline;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A14B67BC614A91A7A53391FA51393B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of whether Russia maintains gas transit through Ukraine at levels consistent with the volumes set forth in the Ukraine-Russia gas transit agreement of December 2019 and continues to pay the transit fees specified in that agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF392E3F2A44E41B3A78D50952BE3B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the status of negotiations between Russia and Ukraine to secure an agreement to extend gas transit through Ukraine beyond the expiration of the agreement described in paragraph (2); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6C8322546384AFEB04380A242E33FDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the United States and Germany have agreed on a common definition for energy <quote>weaponization</quote> and the associated triggers for sanctions and other enforcement actions, pursuant to the Joint Statement of the United States and Germany on support for Ukraine, European energy security, and our climate goals, dated July 21, 2021; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2D4835EB3F4A70B8C1D749A36307B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of the consultations with United States allies and partners in Europe, including Ukraine, Poland, and the countries in Central and Eastern Europe most impacted by the Nord Stream 2 pipeline concerning the matters agreed to, as described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HECAFB7FB18CF4C6E9EB6D446BE0D0DDF"><enum>306.</enum><header>Ukraine security assistance initiative</header><subsection id="H6324770711BD407EAF75983BC7D428C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2022 for the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative for the purpose of providing lethal aid assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0A3FEFE8F344F0180BA4C93B9F8AE02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts in addition to other available amounts</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) are in addition to any other amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for such fiscal year for such purposes.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6EBE0AA61B5B45EEBBE71D754C502D4B"><enum>307.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HCF330ABAFBDA40F7864CF74FAEB5951B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67D99A8F41AB4ACD8DC86ABCAAE1A0B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

