<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A2B0C2135924439A87603F9BD15AB48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9246 IH: Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221028">October 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to disallow the deduction of certain expenses relating to ownership of single-family homes by specified large investors, to impose an excise tax on the sale of such homes by such investors, to establish the neighborhood homes tax credit, and to prohibit Federal mortgage assistance relating to certain large investors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4BEB89DE68F24E7EAF202A1168B67A37" style="OLC"><section id="H6598E7D4C58E4305B3DCFEAC1293B1E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H99648499033845F7B202721ADD64249D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disallowance of deduction of certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors</header><subsection id="H8528504E3E9E47C39731AD810E39FF8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IX of subchapter B of Chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEBD79DA673EB46F3B34719184B1A56F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HECD9A6C01A32462DB021140252EB5582"><enum>280I.</enum><header>Certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors</header><subsection id="HDD9613B091B4437BADEE8000C647A704"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a specified large investor, no deduction shall be allowed under this chapter for the following expenses relating to the ownership of a single-family home:</text><paragraph id="H27B6FEE6920B42C99F3F1BB4A7546A38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for the interest on a mortgage relating to such single-family home or to insure such single-family home.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AD000DD4BFE4F019A339B1081A6B10A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Depreciation of such single-family home.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C5F2EFD60BC44289F0595C56E468FD6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified large investor</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H0E5D6EC3E29E4076A7401CF1B7D98926"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified large investor</quote> means any person for any taxable year if the aggregate fair market value of all assets of such person (reduced by the aggregate debts of the taxpayer) exceeds $100,000,000 at any time during such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E3A31201BF04230BEF6A0F828D5A367"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of controlled groups</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H8AE0E2BC32794BD2B4F4A65D65666AC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All persons which are part of a controlled group (within the meaning of section 1563(a) applied by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears) shall be treated as 1 person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FE55FBCCD9B4B288218B2D9571617C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonincorporated persons under common control</header><text>Under regulations or other guidance provided by the Secretary, principles similar to the principles of subparagraph (A) shall apply to a group of persons under common control where 1 or more of such persons is not a corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD1919C8F10444CF9712FB561A199CF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government entities and certain tax-exempt entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term shall not include either of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE30E234CD27F403385F76CD540A2A7BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any governmental entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBEB7577A00F4D78810EB6D7A7D37E45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any organization which is described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E6308E6F5D7432EA5D1C6F5CAE27706" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Single-Family home</header><paragraph id="H368480CE3FE447248E3B867F1261B774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>single-family home</quote> means any real property located in the United States if such property includes at least 1 dwelling unit and not more than 4 dwelling units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E13563549C4C35A7377524FEED6A9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for federally-assisted buildings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><subparagraph id="H402F65E552FF4690BA56B0F340957601"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such term shall not include any federally-assisted building.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA71911057D3445E4B8CAE967885BDD7F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federally-assisted building</header><text>The term <quote>federally-assisted building</quote> means any building—</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98E87461F4B3499685F133675BB1C7F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which is substantially assisted, financed, or operated under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, section 221(d)(3), 221(d)(4), or 236 of the National Housing Act, section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949, or any other housing program administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development or by the Rural Housing Service of the Department of Agriculture,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3133CF7A3950427CAC28C38C5B6B3157"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to which a credit is allowed to the taxpayer under section 42, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42ADDC5C1CD24BF4893FC4ADF2A9BF85"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> for which financing is provided by a qualified bond (within the meaning of section 141).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D72D409B675479487B5763FFD12FB57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H5DF255698BE6401CBEA172507CD60336"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>In the case of a specified large investor who is an individual, subsection (a) shall not apply to any single-family home if such home is used as the principal residence of such investor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H115566D473A64BDFB640D792D1FC5D7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Original construction or substantial rehabilitation</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a single-family home originally constructed or substantially rehabilitated (as defined in section 47(c)) by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFE0B8124708244EEB81260186627AC91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 280H the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7FE9D3E173344A7CA7236DEA76E3D841" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HEBD79DA673EB46F3B34719184B1A56F3" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HECD9A6C01A32462DB021140252EB5582" level="section">Sec. 280I. Certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H95C857E3964244508BD3C6DC4E2A07E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred and depreciation that occurs after the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB84D94E2926B4B7CAF92CF1E3FE87DA0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Excise tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors</header><subsection id="H082C7B9227964690B572E4B435BB5C1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter C of chapter 36 of subtitle D of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H223DBEFBD4434CACA1C6F8AAD39956A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subchapter id="H259CE8B07BFB4B07AB5FFE1EC9C5D97F"><enum>C</enum><header>Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H259CE8B07BFB4B07AB5FFE1EC9C5D97F" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H51DB3FB21F4343FFA4A6E6DAA96E643E" level="section">Sec. 4471. Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H51DB3FB21F4343FFA4A6E6DAA96E643E"><enum>4471.</enum><header>Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors</header><subsection id="HBBF87C012679418189C4B8A5965A7DCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed a tax on the sale or transfer of a single-family home by a specified large investor in an amount equal to the sale price of the single-family home.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87A552BAAE7240AB8455880C1E588639"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified large investor; single family home</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the terms <quote>specified large investor</quote> and <quote>single-family home</quote> shall have the respective meanings given such terms in section 280I.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36DABDC2E6B84475AD1781AE058C7D49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (b)(2), (d)(1), and (d)(2) of 280I shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4F1DD1461DCE4876A3A76FD9538F14F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 36 of subtitle D of such Code is amended by adding after the item relating to subchapter B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBE5FF53AB93F4941A02F6F8786B120F0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Subchapter C. Tax on Transfers of Single-Family Homes by Specified Large Investors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H669D4032D10149E1AA5FB25EB14F3D37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales and transfers occurring after the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H83B83D6255FE4662A6C185CC2440BBD6" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Neighborhood homes credit</header><subsection id="H456F935A6255470BBF4C83CFF131889A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 42 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAE3FED351AA5479597C9D5E32FF70718"><section id="H605AF23874EB46F29447A49DB05F5E08"><enum>42A.</enum><header>Neighborhood homes credit</header><subsection id="H8DD688559C0446EB808A63FC8E4DABCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the neighborhood homes credit determined under this section for the taxable year is, with respect to each qualified residence sold by the taxpayer during such taxable year in an affordable sale, the lesser of—</text><paragraph id="H50E832ECA02B4A8F86B2F8ACABC76760"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subparagraph id="HC0449DB5630C49A393CE634C81CA503A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reasonable development costs paid or incurred by the taxpayer with respect to such qualified residence, over</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5645D09EE8FA47DCB8A5C8E166532345"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sale price of such qualified residence (reduced by any reasonable expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with such sale), or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H062DBB4CD5D14CFA8B4E788526B3FA46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>35 percent of the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="H431895B1ECDD4D50B7C6713681F4F044"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible development costs paid or incurred by the taxpayer with respect to such qualified residence, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99B938CC6AB4423CA435D04B1F243EF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>80 percent of the national median sale price for new homes (as determined pursuant to the most recent census data available as of the date on which the neighborhood homes credit agency makes an allocation for the qualified project).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40EF92AAD39C4A9A9C15F09A1B0668A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H63BC3DAFFBD941E585712F77DC30FBE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reasonable development costs</header><subparagraph id="H8D318054DA17479A972C5CCA457A4459"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>reasonable development costs</term> means amounts paid or incurred for the acquisition of buildings and land, construction, substantial rehabilitation, demolition of structures, or environmental remediation, to the extent that the neighborhood homes credit agency determines that such amounts meet the standards specified pursuant to subsection (f)(1)(C) (as of the date on which construction or substantial rehabilitation is substantially complete, as determined by such agency) and are necessary to ensure the financial feasibility of such qualified residence. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FB336EBD17842B7AD1A16D01BF43BDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations in making determination</header><text>In making the determination under subparagraph (A), the neighborhood homes credit agency shall consider—</text><clause id="HCEB8BE20BFEF4C54BFE45DCC4AE99B7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sources and uses of funds and the total financing, </text></clause><clause id="H9A3839FF0D4140FAA2A011EE01AB1B34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any proceeds or receipts generated or expected to be generated by reason of tax benefits, and </text></clause><clause id="H19461FB10749438C959267D9893D843A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the reasonableness of the developmental costs and fees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA01F6E1A7BE4BB28FBBFED613046483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible development costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible development costs</quote> means the amount which would be reasonable development costs if the amounts taken into account as paid or incurred for the acquisition of buildings and land did not exceed 75 percent of such costs determined without regard to any amount paid or incurred for the acquisition of buildings and land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC741201F5CB140DD9B6F3B3EB7F32856"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Substantial rehabilitation</header><text>The term <term>substantial rehabilitation</term> means amounts paid or incurred for rehabilitation of a qualified residence if such amounts exceed the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="H3F1D2CF054BE42BA93D5C123A1664294"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$20,000, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB3F7B052C7045DAA541D72C6C7F8696" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">20 percent of the amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer for the acquisition of buildings and land with respect to such qualified residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90BE5123BFD94C6CB7301A91438AE81D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Construction and rehabilitation only after allocation taken into account</header><subparagraph id="HEAFAB66E46334F4093A5E3A78AEEFECD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The terms <quote>reasonable development costs</quote> and <quote>eligible development costs</quote> shall not include any amount paid or incurred before the date on which an allocation is made to the taxpayer under subsection (e) with respect to the qualified project of which the qualified residence is part unless such amount is paid or incurred for the acquisition of buildings or land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F30D90647B74ADA93B6B96491ED74A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Land and building acquisition costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts paid or incurred for the acquisition of buildings or land shall be included under paragraph (A) only if paid or incurred not more than 3 years before the date on which the allocation referred to in subparagraph (A) is made. If the taxpayer acquired any building or land from an entity (or any related party to such entity) that holds an ownership interest in the taxpayer, then such entity must also have acquired such property within such 3-year period, and the acquisition cost included under subparagraph (A) with respect to the taxpayer shall not exceed the amount such entity paid or incurred to acquire such property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF1639F4AFC944B5B65C8A498FBB9652"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified residence</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H077217DC12954190BB6042755303BAF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified residence</term> means a residence that—</text><subparagraph id="HF58B86DBE331490F91CA6984E239226D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is real property affixed on a permanent foundation,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0972F2EA4402411F8BB0E086041BD71D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="H64A6CB74F0FA47138D53DDBF75F1709F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a house which is comprised of 4 or fewer residential units,</text></clause><clause id="H74C97CBDD62C44429BB9EE6A5001F2AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a condominium unit, or</text></clause><clause id="HD7E8470D6A6A45ABA525D4D243267967"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a house or an apartment owned by a cooperative housing corporation (as defined in section 216(b)),</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F48E51BA9914EE39069FB37F6D2AA85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is part of a qualified project with respect to the neighborhood homes credit agency has made an allocation under subsection (e), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB042B6046C24DF0A52D4F587845B80B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is located in a qualified census tract (determined as of the date of such allocation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE8C1E8D5F624239BEABB3732CA3B37C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified census tract</header><subparagraph id="HEDBF8AF70E6D49C89DFCE920F5D6DCF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified census tract</term> means a census tract—</text><clause id="HDEAE4F726402408C96706E6C496C8B70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which—</text><subclause id="H2364F9EA3C8449AF881D40641BDD5326"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a median family income which does not exceed 80 percent of the median family income for the applicable area,</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F82DD50A3354BA0B4BD0BF72902300C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a poverty rate that is not less than 130 percent of the poverty rate of the applicable area, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8C8B0C75AAC04888A7C9D5047082DC03"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a median value for owner-occupied homes that does not exceed the median value for owner-occupied homes in the applicable area,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H50EB350EAA9D469890E2734CB709FC66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which—</text><subclause id="H530B9012AE714805840151137A5BCAF0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is located in a city which has a population of not less than 50,000 and such city has a poverty rate that is not less than 150 percent of the poverty rate of the applicable area, </text></subclause><subclause id="H9C03B8B1434E49B4B51C1082DA60A55E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a median family income which does not exceed the median family income for the applicable area, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H091A14BBBE274D4AAFD1E9DB7BD672F0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a median value for owner-occupied homes that does not exceed 80 percent of the median value for owner-occupied homes in the applicable area,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H376612FBC56C4633BE041BD4813EE6F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which—</text><subclause id="HB7A1E0D088184E99AB8168601AA3918D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is located in a nonmetropolitan county,</text></subclause><subclause id="H35420390C9D14970BCFFE4DD6B884CBD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a median family income which does not exceed the median family income for the applicable area, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC42F333C24A64795829B2EA6932FF7FB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has been designated by a neighborhood homes credit agency under this clause, or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD82031C8B5D84D199427D4F5BF5C5AB0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is not otherwise a qualified census tract and is located in a disaster area (as defined in section 7508A(d)(3)), but only with respect to credits allocated in any period during which the President of the United States has determined that such area warrants individual or individual and public assistance by the Federal Government under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3B29385A997400185EE1AAD0A873709" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable area</header><text>The term <term>applicable area</term> means—</text><clause id="H8F9566FB500F4B368D89F7F78D646F11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a metropolitan census tract, the metropolitan area in which such census tract is located, and</text></clause><clause id="H1866C16B40C84F9C8D020890F43B2B54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a census tract other than a census tract described in clause (i), the State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1491B08A12054F189D991C0FD8AE650B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Affordable sale</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H4F7ADCFAEE11421FB51C9F0052B5F39C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>affordable sale</term> means a sale to a qualified homeowner of a qualified residence that the neighborhood homes credit agency certifies as meeting the standards promulgated under subsection (f)(1)(D) for a price that does not exceed—</text><subparagraph id="HEB88D1A929734311ADF77A2E11B56189" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any qualified residence not described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D), the amount equal to the product of 4 multiplied by the median family income for the applicable area (as determined pursuant to the most recent census data available as of the date of the contract for such sale),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H435176158E1B45F093C61F7319F8FE18" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a house comprised of 2 residential units, 125 percent of the amount described in subparagraph (A),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8624597230FD454A97AF85E6E089A8EB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a house comprised of 3 residential units, 150 percent of the amount described in subparagraph (A), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70826135E1A84B0BB38C6131C15D6FD3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a house comprised of 4 residential units, 175 percent of the amount described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4649FAADED834B14AEFF12629EB58C85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified homeowner</header><text>The term <term>qualified homeowner</term> means, with respect to a qualified residence, an individual—</text><subparagraph id="HD5515430D3D147B293690B906DDBB2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who owns and uses such qualified residence as the principal residence of such individual, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B9BA42A007747EEBAF6F70261A648ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose family income (determined as of the date that a binding contract for the affordable sale of such residence is entered into) is 140 percent or less of the median family income for the applicable area in which the qualified residence is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03F6F721E599474BB0D58469BB70472F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Credit ceiling and allocations</header><paragraph id="H812DCA3FE3144B8CA343918C5180736A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credit limited based on allocations to qualified projects</header><subparagraph id="HD4C5B0C86A71403299FD8984C41065D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year with respect to one or more qualified residences which are part of the same qualified project shall not exceed the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H17D1075541CA48FF9FB2F61541814356"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount allocated by the neighborhood homes credit agency under this paragraph to such taxpayer with respect to such qualified project, over</text></clause><clause id="H236E45758E294F5D86FF5FBEF72DF8A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of credit allowed under subsection (a) to such taxpayer with respect to qualified residences which are a part of such qualified project for all prior taxable years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83247519257244A3A12510E9FF410343"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for completion</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) with respect to any qualified residence unless the affordable sale of such residence is during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the allocation to the qualified project of which such residence is a part (or, in the case of a qualified residence to which subsection (i) applies, the rehabilitation of such residence is completed during such 5-year period).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3464858A73C64341B5FB6A7DCD473F69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on allocations to qualified projects</header><subparagraph id="H27EEB34F296D4327AE69181AB1304024"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Allocations limited by State neighborhood homes credit ceiling</header><text>The aggregate amount allocated to taxpayers with respect to qualified projects by the neighborhood homes credit agency of any State for any calendar year shall not exceed the State neighborhood homes credit amount of such State for such calendar year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FF254EC47894922B2508030CD65ED1A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Set-aside for certain projects involving qualified nonprofit organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of section 42(h)(5) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65CCB83E81E948BCB6CABBF707A42C4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of State neighborhood homes credit ceiling</header><subparagraph id="H043EB1B8367943CB983DEF958AEA0846"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State neighborhood homes credit amount for a State for a calendar year is an amount equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="HD9DE96E2C5264935A1E45E812EBE4B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the greater of—</text><subclause id="HD0A23D14FBAD47ECAAA22319853641AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the product of $3 ($6 in the case of calendar year 2025), multiplied by the State population (determined in accordance with section 146(j)), or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A852D5D52A0432D9A7E132C896F570B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$4,000,000 ($8,000,000 in the case of calendar year 2025), and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H98099AB1C58048D6A2FB20E140CCAA0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any amount previously allocated to any taxpayer with respect to any qualified project by the neighborhood homes credit agency of such State which can no longer be allocated to any qualified residence because the 5-year period described in paragraph (1)(B) expires during calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0E66B61B194EEC9AE2EB274F42A9B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of additional amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount determined under subparagraph (A)(i) shall be zero with respect to any calendar year beginning after December 31, 2025. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB48E0D857EC4755B5845E73E9F9DBA3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>3-year carryforward of unused limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State neighborhood homes credit amount for a State for a calendar year shall be increased by the excess (if any) of the State neighborhood homes credit amount for such State for the preceding calendar year over the aggregate amount allocated by the neighborhood homes credit agency of such State during such preceding calendar year. Any amount carried forward under the preceding sentence shall not be carried past the third calendar year after the calendar year in which such credit amount originally arose, determined on a first-in, first-out basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB3AADE2497254A00B0A21413A5EC3589"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Responsibilities of neighborhood homes credit agencies</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H478F62063C31402CBF031B1B20CB6364"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (e), the State neighborhood homes credit dollar amount shall be zero for a calendar year unless the neighborhood homes credit agency of the State—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C3BB3B7B6A14BA498A5723012A33717"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allocates such amount pursuant to a qualified allocation plan of the neighborhood homes credit agency,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D33FA7F2C6C4EF0A0ED89D052D7131B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allocates not more than 20 percent of amounts allocated in the previous year (or for allocations made in 2022, not more than 20 percent of the neighborhood homes credit ceiling for such year) to projects with respect to qualified residences which—</text><clause id="HA21C35533B1C43919533E7E7DE613CCD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are located in census tracts described in subsection (c)(2)(A)(iii), (c)(2)(A)(iv), (i)(5), or</text></clause><clause id="H862D7CFEB5C24205BECAEB41987FE0F7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are not located in a qualified census tract but meet the requirements of (i)(8),</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1AEEAEEDE221467EB4084B8725021876"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promulgates standards with respect to reasonable qualified development costs and fees,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAECE9984BDCA4683953D4CE34634DB16"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promulgates standards with respect to construction quality,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32DBEA7E388841F2BE7F924724689158"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any neighborhood homes credit agency which makes an allocation to a qualified project which includes any qualified residence to which subsection (i) applies, promulgates standards with respect to protecting the owners of such residences, including the capacity of such owners to pay rehabilitation costs not covered by the credit provided by this section and providing for the disclosure to such owners of their rights and responsibilities with respect to the rehabilitation of such residences, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0215B1354DB84A72A712F27538A14714"><enum>(F)</enum><text>submits to the Secretary (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) an annual report specifying—</text><clause commented="no" id="HC03DAEA30B4A4AEC8DBDD041F709811E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of the neighborhood homes credits allocated to each qualified project for the previous year,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H2E3D2CC269B348E1801A725497D74639"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to each qualified residence completed in the preceding calendar year—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HEC1C4E3C4FD3433CA7129E960042A68F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the census tract in which such qualified residence is located,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H22BE0AE570F84B1CACA202FA057854FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to the qualified project that includes such qualified residence, the year in which such project received an allocation under this section,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC1BAFB45DC644AC2970AC6874A182CE9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether such qualified residence was new, substantially rehabilitated and sold to a qualified homeowner, or substantially rehabilitated pursuant to subsection (i),</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCE41EF741675463FAFEB060B30A5D178"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the eligible development costs of such qualified residence,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H63065C4528D34DEC8A1018BB48CFFA01"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the amount of the neighborhood homes credit with respect to such qualified residence,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H437CF8B6EFEE4B34983025BF98B1D2D1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the sales price of such qualified residence, if applicable, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H75422508994A4E369C7A462F5849000C"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the family income of the qualified homeowner (expressed as a percentage of the applicable area median family income for the location of the qualified residence), and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE11FFF1ED232441C9F7C0AEB2C3F908C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF2A445E94F514DF6B04FFBE79AA75A9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified allocation plan</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified allocation plan</term> means any plan which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5034BCB61A0B45CF914EC2F14210E465"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sets forth the selection criteria to be used to prioritize qualified projects for allocations of State neighborhood homes credit dollar amounts, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="HB07E442D8C994D5CA477C08FC512F51A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the need for new or substantially rehabilitated owner-occupied homes in the area addressed by the project,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA66448C122E8408DA519F7A2DD05B6F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the expected contribution of the project to neighborhood stability and revitalization, including the impact on neighborhood residents,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H59263B331D5E488982B865BA8D38D636"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability and prior performance of the project sponsor, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC55A7B3EAF30490A951BBA5B4AFC4DB8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the likelihood the project will result in long-term homeownership,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2006E9FE3A4A49FB85C94D96C76FF329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been made available for public comment, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA674004602304FD7B9732152AB9F1144"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides a procedure that the neighborhood homes credit agency (or any agent or contractor of such agency) shall follow for purposes of—</text><clause commented="no" id="H566099F738F244AA8D5062F3DAC778E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying noncompliance with any provisions of this section, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6B5474EA22754E698EACD8BDD4C50537"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notifying the Internal Revenue Service of any such noncompliance of which the agency becomes aware.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0392AB84DA1640059435C90B2019CEA5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Repayment</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H10EDCC2A1EAE4FA3812E65BF13C1CA21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H827F4276EF7544319F5AB13A634200E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Sold during 5-year period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a qualified residence is sold during the 5-year period beginning immediately after the affordable sale of such qualified residence referred to in subsection (a), the seller (with respect to the sale during such 5-year period) shall transfer an amount equal to the repayment amount to the relevant neighborhood homes credit agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3F030D2470C14A8FA861B1490A0C2C5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of repayments</header><text>A neighborhood homes credit agency shall use any amount received pursuant to subparagraph (A) only for purposes of qualified projects. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD062E689C5FB490FB40685514EA2F3D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repayment amount</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the repayment amount is an amount equal to 50 percent of the gain from the sale to which the repayment relates, reduced by 20 percent for each year of the 5-year period referred to in paragraph (1)(A) which ends before the date of such sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85616938FBF34DF8A206308E18342497"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lien for repayment amount</header><text>A neighborhood homes credit agency receiving an allocation under this section shall place a lien on each qualified residence that is built or rehabilitated as part of a qualified project for an amount such agency deems necessary to ensure potential repayment pursuant to paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA61E7929949A483088BFE7727CFED431"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Denial of deductions if converted to rental housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, during the 5-year period described in paragraph (1), an individual who owns a qualified residence fails to use such qualified residence as such individual’s principal residence for any period of time, no deduction shall be allowed for expenses paid or incurred by such individual with respect to renting, during such period of time, such qualified residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H80DDE4E47392490DA2B29C89AC302051"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The neighborhood homes credit agency may waive the repayment required under paragraph (1)(A) in the case of homeowner experiencing a hardship.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H462063843F5146029D70F6945344FB53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Other definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H1DBD03B004CD44429E911E2FE1B51D03" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Neighborhood homes credit agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>neighborhood homes credit agency</term> means the agency designated by the governor of a State as the neighborhood homes credit agency of the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBA6C2A3630D456EBE528B84314A93AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified project</term> means a project that a neighborhood homes credit agency certifies will build or substantially rehabilitate one or more qualified residences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEC7410A0E8540CB84D0F58D60BABA38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determinations of family income</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 143(f)(2) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BE1F65B534048C193F0FB568B7DEFA6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Possessions treated as states</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes the District of Columbia and the possessions of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD363E637AAC94DE79304EA1E2B2F1D6F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rules related to condominiums and cooperative housing corporations</header><subparagraph id="H5D661D36972541038485C35EC8696F04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination of development costs</header><text>In the case of a qualified residence described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subsection (c)(1)(A), the reasonable development costs and eligible development costs of such qualified residence shall be an amount equal to such costs, respectively, of the entire condominium or cooperative housing property in which such qualified residence is located, multiplied by a fraction—</text><clause id="H5DB3821E4A0B492EA6418C017F501B1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the numerator of which is the total floor space of such qualified residence, and</text></clause><clause id="H02904FE9BA9E4CE58D87D10C2DCF109E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is the total floor space of all residences within such property.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D622A5BD57542FB98DEE1C11BDABB63"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tenant-stockholders of cooperative housing corporations treated as owners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a cooperative housing corporation (as such term is defined in section 216(b)), a tenant-stockholder shall be treated as owning the house or apartment which such person is entitled to occupy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0BD8F68E37D49B58B865A4A80B143C4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Related party sales not treated as affordable sales</header><subparagraph id="H121FE11DDD04400699A6DCAA35BF2CC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A sale between related persons shall not be treated as an affordable sale.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5264C543A8434DA28925C376DA51F323"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a person (in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>related person</quote>) is related to any person if the related person bears a relationship to such person specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or the related person and such person are engaged in trades or businesses under common control (within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52). For purposes of the preceding sentence, in applying section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), <quote>10 percent</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>50 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CCBF3AF1CB14EA8983DA88C715F3C18"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="H4FB08EC098D54110A01684C8CCF5C5D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a calendar year after 2022, the dollar amounts in subsections (b)(3)(A), (e)(3)(A)(i)(I), (e)(3)(A)(i)(II), and (i)(2)(C) shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H87B7C6DDBC4B4B339806D846B4F7D9F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="H5FB7D43793D44B7CAF86DC8A192B46FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting <quote>calendar year 2021</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F3E548EB4CA482D84A25664E99A99B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><clause id="H6D59220EA6754CD3A9A4A633F8085637"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of the dollar amounts in subsection (b)(3)(A) and (i)(2)(C), any increase under paragraph (1) which is not a multiple of $1,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.</text></clause><clause id="H6E1C9CD38F234D5AB7C58CD31CDED885"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of the dollar amount in subsection (e)(3)(A)(i)(I), any increase under paragraph (1) which is not a multiple of $0.01 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $0.01.</text></clause><clause id="H6E89972255C345D3AAE91A27DC623298"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In the case of the dollar amount in subsection (e)(3)(A)(i)(II), any increase under paragraph (1) which is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFDBC82D6D764DE3B91E78D35E3FD176"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HBA160FFBA8E242ED89C34C90EED63C24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall annually issue a report, to be made available to the public, which contains the information submitted pursuant to subsection (f)(1)(F).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A337977AEC7428C917698CD1E8D5452"><enum>(B)</enum><header>De-identification</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any information made public pursuant to paragraph (1) excludes any information that would allow for the identification of qualified homeowners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FDEAC416244489F95F72D2857C970ED"><enum>(9)</enum><header>List of qualified census tracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, for each year, make publicly available a list of qualified census tracts under—</text><subparagraph id="HE9F98B6B41934731ABB78EC23336A73E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a combined basis, clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (c)(2)(A),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H777790C2D55B48AFA9AADD309C812BAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clause (iii) of such subsection, and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49D9B09D57D9449EACEEEB91E925C606"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsection (i)(5)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10A68E9053D04AFBB76B758FE63D75C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application of credit with respect to owner-Occupied rehabilitations</header><paragraph id="HF560879FF75743ADA0D5EFCCBD6FF849"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified rehabilitation by the taxpayer of any qualified residence which is owned (as of the date that the written binding contract referred to in paragraph (3) is entered into) by a specified homeowner, the rules of paragraphs (2) through (7) shall apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF3E49A3DE104A7BA5EEA8C67DCAC32A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative credit determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any qualified residence described in paragraph (1), the neighborhood homes credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to such residence shall (in lieu of any credit otherwise determined under subsection (a) with respect to such residence) be allowed in the taxable year during which the qualified rehabilitation is completed (as determined by the neighborhood homes credit agency) and shall be equal to the least of—</text><subparagraph id="HEDE76A992D1E465CAFC985C373E19C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H2965069B85AF4F49AD115873F0B9D4F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer for the qualified rehabilitation of the qualified residence to the extent that such amounts are certified by the neighborhood homes credit agency (at the time of the completion of such rehabilitation) as meeting the standards specified pursuant to subsection (f)(1)(C), over</text></clause><clause id="HB8FD44BDDE634C8880E27E80854ABF00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any amounts paid to such taxpayer for such rehabilitation, </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A73317C189478A8BAEE200B0745009"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of the amounts described in subparagraph (A)(i), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47BDB722266140D48984C01B9B727657"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$50,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13321B6E296E46E7995A2BD3CF819655"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified rehabilitation</header><subparagraph id="HF664BE96979F48D2AFE671D637F1617E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified rehabilitation</quote> means a rehabilitation or reconstruction performed pursuant to a written binding contract between the taxpayer and the qualified homeowner if the amount paid or incurred by the taxpayer in the performance of such rehabilitation or reconstruction exceeds the dollar amount in effect under subsection (b)(3)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CCD2EF06E844612B84E6A171A26D7C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application of limitation to expenses paid or incurred after allocation</header><text>A rule similar to the rule of section (b)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4F1026122AA4AF59BCB40BE969DFEF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified homeowner</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified homeowner</term> means, with respect to a qualified residence, an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H4E4388E864404941AC946F9781E1357B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who owns and uses such qualified residence as the principal residence of such individual as of the date that the written binding contract referred to in paragraph (3) is entered into, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF926BF730A948869112900ECB2925C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose family income (determined as of such date) does not exceed the median family income for the applicable area (with respect to the census tract in which the qualified residence is located).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE607E58605C548EF8FED16199B98BB27"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional census tracts in which owner-occupied residences may be located</header><text>In the case of any qualified residence described in paragraph (1), the term <quote>qualified census tract</quote> includes any census tract which—</text><subparagraph id="H0CBC483E2A894B028C7A5521CA01B370"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements of subsection (c)(2)(A)(i) without regard to subclause (III) thereof, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB5898168D8C4E909C0BC79312101630"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designated by the neighborhood homes credit agency for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C536EAFCE742F7925C519773983229"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Modification of repayment requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any qualified residence described in paragraph (1), subsection (g) shall be applied by beginning the 5-year period otherwise described therein on the date on which the qualified owner acquired the residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB5AEEBD02343EF8199C7641104D370"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Related parties</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the taxpayer is the owner of the qualified residence described in paragraph (1) or is related (within the meaning of subsection (h)(6)(B)) to such owner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8B577B468E24CD985ACB1537206F157"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pyrrhotite remediation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of subsection (c)(1)(C) shall not apply to a qualified rehabilitation under this subsection of a qualified residence that is documented by an engineer’s report and core testing to have a foundation that is adversely impacted by pyrrhotite or other iron sulfide minerals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCA869100E8C49B88EC2E37E65F5D511"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations that prevent avoidance of the rules, and abuse of the purposes, of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H604068043D2E460E938700DAD72A4B10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38(b) is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (39), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (40) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H16DA5CF96F00485F892FC0A685D1ED5D"><paragraph id="H00023D9C94654D14AEFF6D601CC0C759"><enum>(41)</enum><text>the neighborhood homes credit determined under section 42A(a),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC8F59F89AB07424FB24DD5423187011E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit allowed against alternative minimum tax</header><text>Section 38(c)(4)(B), as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is amended by redesginating clauses (iv) through (xiii) as clauses (v) through (xiv), respectively, and by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0692B6099FDC404B89ACEB0BEF04696D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H0E2C712983D5437BA2ED6F3DB97BC3ED"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit determined under section 42A,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFF2715C3BF0640779673C386BF67FFE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HD67F75EAC93D4AABB2DC2934A52A8088"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsections (i)(3)(C), (i)(6)(B)(i), and (k)(1) of section 469 are each amended by inserting <quote>or 42A</quote> after <quote>section 42</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC36ED64FFAC647248BE4CB341DA6E339"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 42 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H60DE76BE248C4DC5AFE8F049805A457D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HAE3FED351AA5479597C9D5E32FF70718" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H605AF23874EB46F29447A49DB05F5E08" level="section">Sec. 42A. Neighborhood homes credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A8428E5B90E468C97B85FD2BDE3DBA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H767429460A4F4F30A04FB3F3A42A486C" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibitions on federal mortgage assistance</header><subsection id="HF7DE8372C2BA4164B88A35E0657FFE3E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part 2 of subtitle A of title XIII of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4541">12 U.S.C. 4541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H89C8CA9BC9FA4E67A230A0EB82B2FC85" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2488D80A6EF34CB0B88EF613B826239B" commented="no"><enum>1329.</enum><header>Prohibition relating to specified large investors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall, by regulation, prohibit the enterprises from newly purchasing any mortgage on a single family housing or any portion thereof (or any interest in such a mortgage), and from newly lending on the security of or securitizing any such mortgage under which the mortgagee is a specified large investor (as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/280I">section 280I</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H90B6B982F8FE4243965556AC9DFC44F6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ginnie Mae</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(c) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1717">12 U.S.C. 1717(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H36FF5339C45F48B0A620EE83675B6E39" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC00A2B909F484723BDCD7A99ECB3FE39" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Association may not newly guarantee the payment of principal of or interest on any trust certificate or other security based or backed by a trust or pool that contains, or purchase or acquire, any mortgage under which the mortgagee is a specified large investor (as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/280I">section 280I</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

