<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72091FBDEC1A46489707E00219705C2C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7031 IH: Change of Ownership and Conversion Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7031</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the application and review process for changes of control, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE7F93BD01C494E0FB30460B4B363523B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17654B2A5F3D4558A3B504076B7DD666" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Change of Ownership and Conversion Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H27DC53F3D9C64AABBC884FD1BECC8A9B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC507E8355A1A431CB2A91803FE9BD9B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education in the United States frequently merge with, consolidate, and acquire other institutions that result in a change in ownership.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF780B23FF5FE4821B125E09B111CFCE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These transactions are generally good for students, as they promote innovation, drive competition, and prevent stagnation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B4757F295D843A7B02B695E73FE8DF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Changing demographics and evolving higher education enrollment patterns may lead to more mergers and acquisitions in the future.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H826F5516A91648AAB604B0FA875ABABC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Proprietary institutions that voluntarily convert to nonprofit status or are acquired by nonprofit and public entities can have a positive impact on students and society.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5426FFF8CE34AB6851EDD432FD8998E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Education has an interest in safeguarding Federal student aid funds and therefore should conduct thorough and comprehensive reviews of all changes in ownership involving institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE024931AC2E48D7AE2379467CCB3894"><enum>(6)</enum><text>These reviews are necessary to ensure that the acquiring entity has the financial and administrative capacity to manage the target institutions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EDC4CECA55343D4A26C67D5A24A15FA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Education should conduct these reviews in a thorough and comprehensive manner but should do so as quickly as possible to promote the execution of these transactions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA543A694E7246D29F058EFD718C1FD5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As of May 2021, the Department of Education had <quote>very few staff</quote> assigned to evaluate pretransaction, change of control, and conversion applications on a full-time basis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H539EE9DABCC64566A432B1FAA37BE2F0"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consequently, these transactions are processed by the Department of Education at an extraordinary slow rate of speed, with some institutions waiting up to 5 years before receiving a final determination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA536D721D3B7402F9937012708271750"><enum>(10)</enum><text>One of the primary challenges in processing these applications quickly is the lack of funding to hire enough qualified staff.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88EDF5D0E2004A0A93F05857FADDFE02"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Currently, general taxpayers are bearing the cost of reviewing these transactions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD00B9694115B471498A2F72CBB9C7421"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the interest of institutions and the United States to charge a fee for applications involving changes in ownership at institutions of higher education that are submitted to the Department of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5EF0FF4ED5E4F6AA44AD9BD8FC1B928"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consideration for the fee, the Department of Education will be required to guarantee an expedited review process for all applicants, absent compelling circumstances where good cause exists for delay.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7ECD1FFFE83441A6BE2A2523FC275436"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government Accountability Office has identified weaknesses in the Department of Education’s post-transaction monitoring process, which will likewise require additional staff to be hired to conduct monitoring.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC6E0196504A4241AAFA31BDAEDFED3D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Institutions that have converted from proprietary status to nonprofit status and have an ongoing financial relationship with the former owners of the institution are at highest risk of entering into financial arrangements that result in improper private inurement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB06BDC36D8B43D6B4F94383385C770E"><enum>(16)</enum><text>These institutions should be closely monitored for a period after these transactions occur and should be required to pay a fee to support the hiring of staff to conduct this monitoring.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B15EB686D804DE4B6FD90B07DFA6028"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Government Accountability Office has likewise found weaknesses in the Internal Revenue Service review process for conversion requests and the post-transaction monitoring process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA2A1874F25D481EA138CCE09603934E"><enum>(18)</enum><text>In order to support a more thorough review of these applications and to conduct monitoring, the Department of Education will remit part of the fee paid by institutions to the Internal Revenue Service for these purposes.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB0FA98FD98DF4623B101FF3639E67909"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modifying the approval process for changes of control</header> 
<subsection id="H79E12EF35A8D46C79EB49F20581A7A53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 498(i) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c">20 U.S.C. 1099c(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC9828C873EA042CD9A26042499FFBB9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and Proposed Changes of Ownership</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Ownership</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H560BC7B8B0164E2CA8910552FCAC21AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2C965F355B144A684877588F860CFCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) An eligible institution</quote>, and inserting the following: <quote>(1)(A) An eligible institution</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE55B725DEA964C5B85A4BB3FE5A2CD20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the requirements of section 102 (other than the requirements in subsections (b)(5) and (c)(3))</quote> and inserting <quote>the applicable requirements of section 102 or 103(13)</quote> </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD50C685C07144A3A0434F2E53EF4BCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H721F67856AEE4D6FAD5B4272CC23629F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HCB57A7C437724F3BB9E8D394AC239F8F"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause id="H8515F8ED54CC4364AD85BF6600BAF353" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to a change in ownership resulting in a change of control, an institution may seek a pretransaction determination about whether the institution will meet the applicable requirements of section 102 or 103(13) and this section after such proposed change in ownership by submitting to the Secretary a materially complete pretransaction review application. </text></clause> <clause id="H9AF9F47BB40A407EB0678E2B7F3491AE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing applications submitted under clause (i), the Secretary shall only provide a comprehensive review of each such application, and may not provide an abbreviated or partial review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H03E6D657491845B88647B05248F2C0FC" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If an institution submits a materially complete pretransaction review application at least 90 days prior to the transaction and the Secretary approves the application, the subsequent change in ownership application shall also be approved and the institution shall be certified as meeting the requirements for such transaction, provided that the institution—</text> <subclause id="H02477BE172D947A38E04F12E61F5D360"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complies with the applicable terms of this section; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9D96D8163269481EB1F2780AFB3FFA3A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the transaction resulting in a change of control does not differ materially in its terms from the transaction proposed in the pretransaction review application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF53DA60E0E7243419E16F5C2CF4A7F44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC949911D37BF4B1FBBE4F39BCD2D5055"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E7EB99E1EFE4E38A15F2C5216557466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H879CFEC05677481B9D5D7B884C335B60"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding the following at the end:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA3A58C784C3443EB93B6DD993A3087BB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H5F8C5373B50648B9B8D167AE6711532D" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a proprietary institution of higher education, a conversion to a public or other nonprofit institution of higher education. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A3F348098744C96B2089DD6FCE13A5A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDC39204F4E2A4AA9AB32D3712AE72CDD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H404E37F784844896A02123FB7B97614B" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph id="H45640297495B4DBD8E5A028D94A580A0" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), when any institution submits an application for a change in ownership resulting in a change in control under this section or submits a pretransaction review application under paragraph (1)(B) (other than in the case of a conversion transaction), the institution shall be required to pay to the Secretary an administrative fee that shall—</text> 
<clause id="HB20207F6DA9A4F8AB8CE24440D495104" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be in an amount equal to 0.15 percent of the total institutional revenue derived from this title by such institution for the most fiscal year for which data is available; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAB1BF7DFD38745B1AE5C2D9B61381948" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be used exclusively for expenses related to the processing of such application, and be available to the Secretary without further appropriation, exclusively for expenses related to the processing of such approval or application.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FB319359CD04D7CB38B08AE8A05D921" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a proprietary institution submitting an application for conversion, or a pretransaction review application for conversion, the institution shall be required to pay to the Secretary an administrative fee that shall—</text> <clause id="H209A8F3AD3794AA29600465FB80D5F69"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be in an amount equal to 0.30 percent of the total institutional revenue derived from this title by such institution for the most fiscal year for which data is available; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H21F42452C2FA4E44A7FF79FDDEFA1285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be used exclusively for expenses related to the processing of such application, and of which—</text> <subclause id="HC0D4D69EB8D44F0780221429D1972D1D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>50 percent shall be available to the Secretary without further appropriation, exclusively for expenses related to the processing of such application; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7A3022D2BEA74562B835CD3003A9AE71"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent shall be remitted by the Secretary to the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue, and shall be available, without further appropriation, to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue exclusively for purposes of determining whether the institution seeking such conversion or pretransaction review is an institution exempt from tax and is otherwise in compliance with applicable requirements of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4B52D9A54954E0286196AB022AE517B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution that pays a fee under subparagraph (A) or (B) for a pretransaction application with respect to a proposed transaction shall not be required to pay another fee under such subparagraph for a change in ownership application with respect to such transaction.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H939E3307BA634E65912671B18528D671" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In no case may any fee remitted under subparagraph (A) or (B) exceed $120,000 for any transaction (or pretransaction) application, nor may the Secretary require an institution that has paid a fee under subparagraph (B) to pay an additional fee under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H273987E3FF9F4B7F8B3DC3AE372D3285" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum> <subparagraph id="H3A3CB10F2D4F44F0AE85895D98A39F13" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall approve or deny a materially complete application (including pretransaction reviews and conversion applications) submitted under this section as soon as practicable and not later than the 90-day period beginning on the date of receipt of such an application, except that in a case in which the Secretary determines, on a nondelegable basis, that good cause exists to not make the determination during such 90-day period, the Secretary shall notify the institution in writing detailing the reasons for a good cause extension.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59B9EBCDF20F47539C724C0028E6748D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Secretary fails to approve or deny a materially complete application during the period described in subparagraph (A) and does not find good cause for extension, the materially complete application shall be deemed approved.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0854C79C97B44FBFB467C0C06571B08C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In no case may the Secretary grant a good cause extension under this section to an institution for more than one month at a time, or for a total of more than more than 12 months.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08F541FB62C04C6C9F7E87A092461E29" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To ensure timely submission of all relevant documentation, the Secretary may deny an application if an institution does not make a good faith effort to submit to the Secretary, in a timely manner—</text> <clause id="HA7D9F9B0761943EDB5CCD8806AC58739" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all relevant documentation; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H90CC327412FE484D901C579AB69348DF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a materially complete application.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8BE1D950D894E1A9CDDFD378DA11435" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum> <clause id="HEBFA606FD07549039AF48EEBF1236F83" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Upon approving or denying an application under this paragraph, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the reasoning for such approval or denial, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H28AF7BF4CEDB426E89A2E9C0AB3F1B2B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a copy of the approval or denial letter sent to the institution; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H091A525D8D184ED384F8D4E8C6AF438E" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any analysis regarding how the Secretary determined under paragraph 7(A)(iii) that a director of the institution was an interested or disinterested party to the transaction.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H100CEBF7F22B4CE9B08AE2174950B78D" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall not publish under clause (i) any information that is otherwise exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (relating to the Freedom of Information Act), including trade secrets and commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H899EB502279E43A58D18D9A83F1E14B8" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum> <subparagraph id="HFB19172A90FF4C5480BAE70A216D1ABB" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of a proprietary institution that subsequent to the transaction would be owned and operated by an entity (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>buyer</quote>) seeking to be recognized as a public or other nonprofit institution, the buyer shall meet the definition of a nonprofit institution under section 103(13) if—</text> 
<clause id="H163E574E011140A78C7D8AA36BD39E4A" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the buyer pays no more than fair market value for any assets of the proprietary institution;</text></clause> <clause id="HB41F0061054145A8B00C17B0B511D7EE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the buyer pays no more than fair market value for any service or lease contracts, including such service and lease contracts provided by the entity selling the proprietary institution; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37B8CFF814D346839CBF917D270D077C" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent self-dealing in the case where one or more individuals with a substantial ownership or controlling interests in the proprietary institution will also have substantial or controlling interests in the institution seeking to be recognized as a public or other nonprofit institution (meaning that one or more individuals are on both sides of the transaction), the change of control transaction, and any substantial asset acquisition, service, or lease agreements with the proprietary institution shall be approved by a disinterested committee of directors of the entity that seeks to be recognized as a public or other nonprofit institution.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF160463B15BD4204B9701BE1952BAF68" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the purposes of this paragraph, parties to the transaction are entitled to a rebuttable presumption that the assets, lease contracts, and service contracts that are part of the transaction are purchased at fair market value if—</text> 
<clause id="HBCFADD09AE6C47F78750CC6206EC476B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the acquiring entity pays no more than fair market value for such assets, lease contracts, or service contracts; and</text></clause> <clause id="H03647BD328E5408C99F9635669ABB06C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the value of the assets, lease contracts, or service contracts are evaluated by at least one independent third-party entity hired by parties on both sides of the transaction.</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6B9EB90F7794798B72775C00E21C363" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H2516EFA4852048D19975986A69481003" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution that has been approved for conversion by the Secretary shall be subject to a monitoring period<italic></italic> for a 5-year period beginning on the day after the date of such approval. In conducting the monitoring of the institution under this paragraph, the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H58E450E990734CDE990418952E583DDB" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall only conduct monitoring to ensure that the institution is in compliance with the requirements of section 103(13) and paragraph (7) of this subsection; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD2C63D7B7FE34BEEB9C33EF6C2F15B23" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may require the institution to submit regular reports or conduct audits of such institution relating to such compliance.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5296AEDE1674338A439D6A0D6BC6742" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each institution that is subject to the monitoring period under this paragraph shall remit an annual fee to the Secretary—</text> 
<clause id="H8F3690E3AECD4509AF18F05F1AC0B49C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in an amount equal to 0.15 percent of the total revenue derived from this title by such institution for the most recent fiscal year for which data is available; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBBD7E5C64BC84C31AD76AB22126876C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that shall be exclusively for expenses related to monitoring of the institution for the period described in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subclause id="H35B512490B3A4A8D8099336226356002"><enum>(I)</enum><text>of which 50 percent shall be used by the Secretary, without further appropriation, exclusively for expenses related to monitoring of the institution during such period; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC4F70D61ECE4B3B807703396C51D06B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of which 50 percent shall be remitted by the Secretary to the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, to be available to such Commissioner, without further appropriation, exclusively for monitoring compliance with the Internal Revenue Code of such institution during such period.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H158EBE46558C49BD820A04366145B715" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An institution may not be subject to an annual fee under subparagraph (B) for monitoring related to a conversion that exceeds $60,000.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H033C478B691841A89BF6F403E6C18D44" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that an institution should be subject to the monitoring under this paragraph beyond the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide the reasons justifying an extension in writing to the institution (and in the Federal Register) at least 30 days before the expiration of such period. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF2A635382FA4D23B98E3B48389CEA83" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any institution that is subject to monitoring under this paragraph may seek a waiver to be exempt from such monitoring (including the annual fee under subparagraph (B)) on an annual basis for any year during the monitoring period and the Secretary shall grant such waiver if there is no ongoing contractual or financial relationship between the institution and the former entity or individuals that previously owned the institution. The Secretary may grant a waiver for more than 1 year in the case where the entity that formerly owned the proprietary institution has closed or no longer exists and the Secretary determines the institution is not at risk of violating the requirements of section 103(13) or paragraph (7) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC28B7EEFB2F642478DD6F64621B00D94" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Any institution that submits an application for conversion shall not promote or market itself, in any manner, as a public or other nonprofit institution of higher education unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6C464197E08D47A5A0A463B678C3CFA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary has provided final approval of the conversion of the institution to a public or other nonprofit institution of higher education under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3FCA0F84CFB424BBE777FD213C89B16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary pursuant to section 496 has approved such public or nonprofit status of the institution;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H452BDA262C9E422CAA2C2A2F3511A749"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State has given final approval to the institution as a public or nonprofit institution of higher education, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAB98C80F6014266B4E37100F2243E83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of an institution seeking nonprofit status, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue has approved the institution as tax exempt pursuant to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBC54563B19C45D49D6B4DD56279ECDD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Change of Ownership and Conversion Improvement Act</short-title>, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary shall publish (and update as necessary) in the Federal Register—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C2B4B8A2E9045AD8AA04B132E364669"><enum>(A)</enum><text>descriptions of the documents and materials the Secretary expects or requires institutions of higher education to submit (including any standardized forms) as part of any pretransaction application or change in ownership application under this section, including a description of what the Secretary considers to be a materially complete application; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1D326B9342E4668A56A2D797E2CA36C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after at least a 30-day notice and comment period, responses to any public comments received with respect to such descriptions or updates to such descriptions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9C1F11ABCFC465796CE34A4BD432FB3" indent="up1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In a case in which the Secretary requests a document under this section as part of a pretransaction or change in ownership application that is not described in the Federal Register under paragraph (10), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90A66F1F20314590943137E51168C55B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substantiate, in writing to the institution, the reasons why the Secretary is requesting such documents; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H436BC071E7DC4C259EFB9113F346F2BA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish such reasons in the Federal Register, including whether the Secretary may request other institutions that submit applications under this section to produce similar documentation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE88AC634BB24EB3A3869ACC3493CA4E" indent="up1"><enum>(12)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H19A45727FA5B4D82BC6355072957299A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Change of Ownership and Conversion Improvement Act</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to authorizing committees, and post such report on a publicly available website regarding implementation of the amendments made to this section by such Act, including the following information:</text> <clause id="HA1518192B2EC49489129E6287A6BE1F1" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The mean and median length of time taken by the Secretary to review applications under this section during the preceding 12-month period.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD81BE6E1C9804203A7C0DD3E39305D8C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of applications approved or denied during the preceding 12-month period.</text></clause> <clause id="H0F19F428AFB74077B3BD6A3DBC24E1DD" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For any application not processed during the 90-day period beginning on the date of receipt of the application for which the Secretary found good cause under paragraph (6)(A) to extend the deadline in which the application shall be processed, a copy of the letter sent to the institution explaining why the Secretary believed good cause existed for such extension.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC8A6CFB54338431592D276506A29FD7B" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For any application not processed during such 90-day period, which was deemed to be automatically approved by the requirements of this section under paragraph (6)(B), the name of each institution involved and an explanation for why the application was not processed in a timely manner.</text></clause> <clause id="HDACEF35825F9489E9183E0E624E86F58" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any legislative suggestions the Secretary may have to improve the application or monitoring process under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H954FC8989B214FC7A125BF8916C0FD5A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Secretary fails to submit a report under this paragraph by not later than 90 days after the deadline for such submission under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may not, for the 12-month period following such failure, spend the fees remitted by institutions under this section or remit such fees to the Commissioner unless Congress provides for such use by further appropriation.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF73F33D8EBF44FBB414F402445BDDB0" indent="up1"><enum>(13)</enum><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term <term>conversion</term> means any transaction under which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2CF5005ECAF1426E9743B6889960E96B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a proprietary institution is reorganized and seeks recognition as a public or other nonprofit institution; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB086FDE2C17144EFADEA3C79F38B76F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the control of a proprietary institution is transferred as a result of a sale, donation, or other method to an entity that seeks certification under this section as a public or other nonprofit institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DC260D88256419981173C07542B7741"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall be apply with respect to applications submitted for change of control or conversion submitted on or after January 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9106893CB5114E5C919E21A9027C1695"><enum>4.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, a report on the implementation of the amendments made by this Act, including recommendations to improve—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A9B4E25B4E74B04B6043B8BE8F72B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application process under section 498(i) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c">20 U.S.C. 1099c(i)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, for institutions of higher education seeking a change in ownership resulting in a change in control; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA0D054AEF2D4B8FB9110FBD40D63A5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the monitoring process under such section for institutions of higher education that have recently converted from being recognized as a proprietary institution to a public or other nonprofit institution.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 

