<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HC68FCFEBB6694D9497777EFDFF4460DD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 6722 ENR: To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in French Camp, California, as the “Richard A. Pittman VA Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6722</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in French Camp, California, as the <quote>Richard A. Pittman VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H41C536C37D354E2CA1119CE9BAC141C4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8420A26DC7914D72B1006C0FF12A55C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H32C6C14B3AAA49EA9EC22255B6E5D777"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Richard A. Pittman was born on May 26, 1945, in French Camp, California.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76CC17073D5D4EF8AE695B450B640CF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Richard A. Pittman enlisted in the Marine Corps in 1965 and was later promoted to Lance Corporal.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H959E8C0A3CC64392BB65911290791D76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 24, 1966, Lance Corporal Pittman’s unit, First Platoon, Company I, Third Battalion, Fifth Marines, was moving along a trail near the Demilitarized Zone in the Republic of Vietnam when the Marines ahead of them came under attack.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5521AF8337184CF3B737AD980D44EE64"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon hearing the attack, Lance Corporal Pittman took a machine gun and several belts of ammunition and rushed to aid his comrades. As he advanced, Lance Corporal Pittman encountered intense small-arms fire at point-blank range. He was able to return fire and silence the enemy combatants. Continuing towards the attacked Marines, Lance Corporal Pittman came under heavy fire from two automatic weapons, which he was able to destroy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB6680421AA04007A0E503ED016A1C18"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When Lance Corporal Pittman learned there were additional wounded Marines further along the trail, he endured enemy mortar and gunfire to get to them. As he reached them, he faced an attack by 30 to 40 enemy fighters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6ADAED5ADD74FE781F6A73A8684FC67"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lance Corporal Pittman used a combination of machine-gun fire, an enemy submachine gun, a pistol from a fallen comrade, and a grenade to cause enemy forces to withdraw. Due to his courageous actions, many of his wounded comrades were saved.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA485FD57DC584E34B23848473D1A1294"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition of his bravery that day, Richard A. Pittman, who was then a Sergeant, was awarded the Medal of Honor by President Lyndon B. Johnson on May 14, 1968.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEE4284AB11D4029AD4A5A0EE5126831"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Richard A. Pittman retired in 1988 as a Master Sergeant, after having served in the Marine Corps for more than two decades.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD85ED36E79364A3EB348061921E189B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Name of Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic, French Camp, California</header> <subsection id="H2E2C45CC76A14FDB9480CBF3291CC959"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in French Camp, California, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Richard A. Pittman VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0711CCE9CA104BBF89CB7927276D70EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Richard A. Pittman VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

