<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83C7B400DD8849728D8A65D16ADD438A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6530 IH: Safeguarding Elderly Needs for Infrastructure and Occupational Resources Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220128">January 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to sustain senior congregate care operations in the wake of ongoing COVID–19 financial burdens, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DE1E5993B7944D3AF26FD5FE94ECA48" style="OLC"><section id="HCCA7E0F25D5D4365B41381BED3077041" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Elderly Needs for Infrastructure and Occupational Resources Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SENIOR Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H03FEAEECF91744779E14E7671E628BD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H2076E8D7D7A241B19CFC9DD345A95E9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Long-term care facilities and senior congregate care homes provide direct and personalized care, where social distancing is not possible, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F197AC63EAA4F3DA9EDE9790546D785"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisted living, memory care, independent living, and other senior congregate care settings are the homes of America’s seniors and critical options on the long-term care continuum; these senior residences provide safety and security for our Nation’s most vulnerable population.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H004B2796B55348EF8BC8C9B8D423F919"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Sixty percent of a senior’s health is based on social determinants of health which include the need for adequate nutrition, housing, and social activities; thus supporting caregivers and home- and community-based care models that prioritize the social determinants of senior health should be a priority of the Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A25A8BBBA7B49F1958EAEC413AA4F0F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Investing in senior care and the caregiving workforce prevents hospitalization and skilled nursing expenses, preserving Medicare and Medicaid budgets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1083CC7BE5EC4846A415CAB0354334C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since March of 2020, senior care facilities have lost over 380,000 caregivers and are experiencing a workforce crisis as America’s population rapidly ages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE86B3BF315F47A9A6C5FB2BCA861E8D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>By 2030, the entire Baby Boomer Generation will be 65 years of age or older.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9BE97303F184B57B779ED2E376B3968"><enum>(7)</enum><text>By 2060, nearly 95 million Americans will be 65 years of age or older and the portion of the population over 85 years of age will have tripled to nearly 20 million persons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D974E8A3509451F81768E9204B0D3C5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Fifty-two percent of individuals require long-term care by age 65. Individuals over 65 years of age are 70 percent more likely to need long-term care, with half of those seniors requiring an even higher level of care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E725BDB6F21481B95F2C377DCC714BC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The average duration of long-term care is nearly 4 years, and 14 percent of individuals need long-term care for 5 or more years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF91F16362BBE46E18FCC4EC9214E752F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Twenty-seven percent of seniors over 65 years of age will spend at least $100,000 on long-term care, and 15 percent will have costs for long-term care surpassing $250,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAC28C2AD98B4D7584585D51444C9EF6"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The average cost for long-term care for a 65-year old today is $138,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43FF6619725E49D28F844B121AF27BBD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Long-term care infrastructure must address the availability of cost-effective care and housing options to meet the growing needs of the Nation’s aging population.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F8850002084480C884DC57FD0885C0B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On average, assisted living costs $4,300 per month, which equals $5.91 per hour of available care (based on 24/7 care). Nursing homes cost $8,821 per month (or $13.13 per hour based on 24/7 care). In-home care costs $4,576 per month (or $26 per hour based on 44 hours per week care).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92E2D699A461492388FBECB35A4E63DD"><enum>(14)</enum><text>An individual 85 years of age or older is 630 percent more likely to die of COVID–19.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE24B32D75A4EB29E6EC0065C188CD2"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Sixty-three percent of residents of long-term care facilities need assistance with bathing; 48 percent need assistance with dressing; and 40 percent need assistance with toileting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC58D6274B23D475992DEF408EE4B54AA"><enum>(16)</enum><text>More than 42 percent of residents of long-term care facilities suffer from Alzheimer’s disease or some other form of dementia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD10F5433C3CC4F5EB7DF8371B1404356"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The people of the United States are a compassionate people who are committed to protecting the most vulnerable in our society, and we should not jeopardize the financial underpinnings of the long-term care communities our Nation’s senior citizens depend on day-in and day-out.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB63BBFCAE5BF477EAC8FAC5E4E38B7D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Senior caregiver relief assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part K of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280c">42 U.S.C. 280c et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subpart: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04D764252DDA470CBEA6505D5D88B9AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subpart id="H45F4A96DCB9942BBA6A38F0943FF93FD"><enum>IV</enum><header>Senior caregiver relief assistance</header><section id="HBBCA2FB555664677B67FF4D1B73CBEE3"><enum>399A–1.</enum><header>Senior caregiver relief assistance</header><subsection id="HF33FF254AB60430B84084C27F7511121"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide assistance under this section to eligible entities to stabilize and preserve senior congregate care operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H74074C529A264FB08A5793CB4C1E1CA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><paragraph id="H2794D8B27A504FE5A00F1A33A174817A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide assistance under this section only to an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="HADF3C4EE7E4F495BAC0234F61E59B55B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an assisted living facility; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71C297345D084486A22B3CA8038834F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates, by providing such documentation as the Secretary shall require, financial need by having—</text><clause id="H3CB66C8D3DB24E7AAA62E446A1E49015"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incurred uncompensated losses because of the public health emergency declared under section 319 with respect to COVID–19; and</text></clause><clause id="H88472CD1FCEB4657B52FCAA15DC5FB3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistently maintained ongoing operations during the period from March 13, 2020, to December 31, 2020; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97315A880B5146DF9F876AF8D415025E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes a good-faith certification to the Secretary—</text><clause id="H4F8826B13C0145D1819D6A7733F730D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the uncertainty of existing economic conditions makes the application for assistance under this section necessary to support ongoing operations of the entity; and</text></clause><clause id="HD48BE9D121CB4E7DBE0E6689C876A439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that all amounts of such assistance will be used to promote the health and well-being of the facility’s population of seniors, to retain workers, to maintain the facility, and for other eligible uses under the relevant provisions of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDED869F1C048457BA7D93AF4774BF57B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis of determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual determination of qualification of an entity as an eligible entity for purposes of this section shall be based on review of the entity’s existing versus recent historic financials, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3E9005CE653C4245A662802B5754A884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>profit-loss statements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C56E219ED6C4AB2893CE249C5357DA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>account receivables;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2D67C3B25AF45A7A23CEFBFFA9195BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal tax filings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0045A96F79E468E959748C1BCBD6347"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other materials that the Secretary deems relevant to meet the purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68A34C4D1ABD482B9ABECE2B132EB006"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H95AD0397D95348138656058229B93E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for eligible entities to submit applications for assistance under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H428D93A7C83641EF8CFEE6719CF7A990"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require such applications—</text><subparagraph id="HE2FA2296063747E09D22FE4BDE6D4A1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to set forth the proposed uses of such assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C2CEF67B2394DEEB14FCE9136E3EB33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to contain such other assurances and information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DC9541EC8E5499282679DF50225D3D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Formula grants for health care-Related expenses and lost revenue attributable to COVID–19</header><paragraph id="H906E0A828F6A41BD9794689A44D7597B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent and in the amount of appropriations made in advance to carry out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFF7477787FFA4F7AACF6DB018FA97DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make grants to eligible entities for health care-related expenses attributable to COVID–19 or to supplant lost revenue attributable to COVID–19; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB947E991120A4396AED9F82C2C15782F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distribute such amounts among eligible entities in an equitable and timely manner, but not later than December 31, 2022, based on the order in which approvable applications from such entities are received by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00697E92B3A245B0A27A7A023D5953B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to use not more than 5 percent of the amounts received through the grant for administrative expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52E0C7AC16AD4743BAA5AFAAA537E8A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of assistance distributed to an eligible entity pursuant to this subsection shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HF4723B5F3E434FFEA67396CDDBE3C052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based on the number of beds in the facility to be assisted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6C531A13C2E44CF9128B52E947A48E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proportional to the uncompensated losses of the eligible entity referred to in subsection (b)(1)(B)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3029CBC31F540BA8957C60E51EB0534"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preventing the Secretary from making assistance available to eligible entities at any time before the date specified in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B5F28DB10CC4890A655EB973F321B6D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Senior caregiver relief grants</header><paragraph id="H2333632F51BE4A4481CC04E821DEB391"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent and in the amount of appropriations made in advance to carry out this section, the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities for use (subject to paragraph (2)) only for the following purposes:</text><subparagraph id="H44251A8CCC0C40EE84F19DD59B73AFA0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Enhanced broadband connectivity and telehealth support</header><text>To ensure regular and reliable communications connections between seniors residing in the assisted living facility of the entity and their physicians and medical support personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F00836CA1E4BC7BB8DAD6BD052C3EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Caregiver sustainability</header><text>For costs of operating and maintaining the assisted living facility of the entity, including—</text><clause id="H465337A76E6C478CAA5A468DDF3FC74E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for payments of principal or interest on any mortgage obligation in connection with the facility, but not including any prepayment of principal on such a mortgage obligation;</text></clause><clause id="HF26504257A6F4617BCD7162C9DBC45FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for payments of rent for a facility, including rent under a lease agreement, but not including any prepayment of rent;</text></clause><clause id="H17546695E27D4A649CC9FE446B60451A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for costs of activities to prevent, prepare for, and mitigate the presence of COVID–19 on facility premises, including costs of purchasing and installing equipment and supplies to disinfect the premises, support emergency management operations, and provide for associated staff-related expenses;</text></clause><clause id="HD872B21C1CCB41C5A48C232982E726AF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for maintenance expenses for the facility for the purposes of COVID–19 mitigation and infection control, including construction to accommodate social distancing and other preventive measures, such as plexiglass barriers;</text></clause><clause id="HF6CF4D51A72248C9B56D767544A466C4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for costs of supplies for the facility, including protective equipment and cleaning materials; and</text></clause><clause id="HD0BB476D6D9343418414FCADD12FD6F4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>for any other expenses that the Secretary determines to be essential to maintaining the facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA94F8C140A0A46D7B73F3A0398211AEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other activities</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the Secretary from approving applications providing for use of funds for other costs, purposes, and activities not specifically identified in paragraph (1) that the Secretary deems appropriate and consistent with the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA3AD1C8F0A1482A9034AD4EF85FA8A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recipient of a grant under subsection (d) or (e) shall submit reports and maintain documentation by such deadlines, in such form, and containing such content as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure compliance with the conditions of the grant. </text></subsection><subsection id="HD1E8FAFD4FA5448A9D22E5ABDA7202E8" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Tax treatment</header><paragraph id="H0383ACD156CE4ADB91CEC3BAE2472D10" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, amounts received by an eligible entity from the Secretary under a grant under subsection (d) or (e) shall not be included in the gross income of such eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB70195B543264773933353B621190480" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of exclusion</header><text>An eligible entity shall not have a tax deduction denied, a tax attribute reduced, or any basis increased by reason of the exclusion from gross income pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98E2AB0B6A914E92BAB7B8F8B9D731CA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>GAO report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Congress a report assessing the efficacy of assistance made available under this section and the activities supported with such assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="H44AB6A1E0D7B418485C3D89BBBE6E704"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8B8C4851CDB5466AB27321AE1999A693" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>assisted living facility</term> means a licensed, registered, certified, listed, or State-regulated residence, managed residential community, building, or part of a building that provides, or contracts to provide, housing with supportive services on a continuing basis to individuals who—</text><subparagraph id="HF6FE4E90B645429CA3472267C80ED038" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are elderly or have a mental health, developmental, or physical disability; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E80637FEE35479AA0985ADA864292B1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are unrelated by blood or marriage to the owner or operator of the residence, community, building, or part of a building if the owner or operator is an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C9157625124CA6A9A8F0F9E89D5482"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity that is eligible under subsection (b) to be provided assistance under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08AF393796174E7A86B1B099CEBABF9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health care-related expenses attributable to COVID–19</term> means health care-related expenses to prevent, prepare for, and respond to COVID–19, including the building or construction of a temporary structure, the leasing of a property, the purchase of medical supplies and equipment (including personal protective equipment and testing supplies), providing for an expanded workforce (including by training staff, maintaining staff, and hiring additional staff), the operation of an emergency operation center, retrofitting a facility, providing for surge capacity, and other expenses determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA951162C4B7640AFA5D14819ABC923C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>lost revenue attributable to COVID–19</term> means the cost of services that were received, building modifications made, and tangible property ordered for mitigation and prevention of COVID–19, including the difference between such provider’s budgeted and actual revenue if such budget was established and approved before March 27, 2020, for the purposes of preventing, preparing for, and responding to COVID–19.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4034990E6F7D4833B12E3E2649D42395"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7E3329722C4E4F59B236BCC4471432F7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Senior caregiving workforce development sustainment grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part K of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280c">42 U.S.C. 280c et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 399A–1, as added by section 3 of this Act, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3603184E96F6490D9071914CA1B6C392" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H637BC81A266449558A94C54E2EB522F6"><enum>399A–2.</enum><header>Senior caregiving workforce development sustainment grants</header><subsection id="HA30AD092FF38492BB732F1943DFD4A46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to establish or expand a senior caregiver workforce training and recruitment program on the campus of the respective eligible entity. </text></subsection><subsection id="H9A2D83097F3148CE9ADFDB51D066FEB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount; duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for—</text><paragraph id="H64EC90A44A724C50A1992715207629E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an amount of not more than $1,000,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F47DB3F18524D13A56972F557FDEAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a term of not more than 4 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22AEF20B49CD4889BCF373F427827C16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts provided to an eligible entity through a grant under this section shall be used to cover the costs of—</text><paragraph id="HDB1738C0BB634165BE94236708D1A133"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing or expanding a senior caregiver workforce training and recruitment program described in subsection (a), including costs associated with recruitment, training, and retention of senior caregivers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23ABF1FEAEEA446EB785EC1F0FC4189D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>technical assistance provided by the eligible entity in connection with such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49C039A76E75483C833C0103D66CF7C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H23D2B5CEA1954814928F3762C610C173"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recipient of a grant under this section shall submit reports and maintain documentation by such deadlines, in such form, and containing such content as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure compliance with the conditions of the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A8BE630A69044B28BB6BFFC6130CF89" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tax treatment</header><paragraph id="H697EB1A39B7F4CA7A79C24A4875B1623" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, amounts received by an eligible entity from the Secretary under a grant under this section shall not be included in the gross income of such eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29975E9098164413A208F7F04BCA2EBD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of exclusion</header><text>An eligible entity shall not have a tax deduction denied, a tax attribute reduced, or any basis increased by reason of the exclusion from gross income pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5825009524B74B84953AA1519FB24D6E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="H1EB1024647264D7192562F71153F384C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H773A8CE3487D48A69259B6AACFBEB949"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an assisted living facility as defined in section 399A–1; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2301924BCD54300BC20C139B8AAA99D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any skilled nursing facility as defined in section 1819(a) of the Social Security Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3317491C3E544EFA6710E3E5B7E1002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>senior caregiver</term> means an individual who furnishes direct personal care, assistance with activities of daily living, or any other related service for older adults located on a campus of an eligible entity. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBD13AABD2EB44EE9DDE5505252EE8EE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,250,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HFF5E34A687CC4DF38A66D5B31EAC6A46"><enum>5.</enum><header>National Health Care Workforce Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Health Care Workforce Commission established under section 5101 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294q">42 U.S.C. 294q</external-xref>) shall—</text><paragraph id="H52CB6772CE5C4D5781686B188E604EF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, pursuant to subsection (d)(4) of such section 5101, designate as a <quote>high priority area</quote> the current and projected workforce needs of assisted living and other senior care settings that attend to the care of the senior population; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE0DD9F99EEA4045856C9D9C80775A67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after finalizing such designation, submit a report pursuant to subsection (d)(2)(D) of such section 5101 to the Congress and the Administration containing a review of, and recommendations on, such high priority area.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

