<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FD0BCD4405644B4B64A4EC4F9729D46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6548 IH: Justice in Power Plant Permitting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6548</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish new Federal renewable energy use requirements, support the equitable transition to clean energy power generation, and require cumulative impact assessments for fossil fuel-fired power plant permitting, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H4936F35BFFFD4633B58CEF90B6FDCA75" style="OLC">
<section id="H403458B6914147509CF30DD28ADB3DA1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice in Power Plant Permitting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H777C3DE875CF4AD5858882DE3C08A300"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HFDF0C810F83C438AB060B07F2C086D51" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community intervenor</header><text>The term <term>community intervenor</term> means an effective, qualified, and compensated representative, or group of representatives, that participates in public service commission and permitting authority proceedings on behalf of ratepayers in, and residents of, impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF17D716C9264DE7801F1EE2DE0DA518" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>propose independent analyses of, including alternatives to, fossil fuel-fired power plants and other polluting projects seeking approvals, permits, or renewals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB5E8A89718744389025CC731123944B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>decrease electricity costs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97E9AA4E016C43CDB6560794EFCB7A28" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce environmental burdens;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFE5A629BF9E1431887538C6FEF00F1E4" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve public health; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5D6F9DA885346D3A688DBEE8061EE0E" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>otherwise advocate to benefit such communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34BD82BF13564FCDA04CA0B42C5F3CC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical facility</header><text>The term <term>critical facility</term> means any facility critical to public health infrastructure, including health care, water and wastewater systems, and emergency services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49F1B6991BAE44B08731D72678FEBD27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cumulative impacts</header><text>The term <term>cumulative impacts</term> means any exposure to a public health, environmental, or climate risk, or other effect occurring in a specific geographical area, including from an emission, discharge, or release—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1EFD70540DF24250BA68F586522DDE13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including—</text> <clause id="H655DC467BFF34BE2B32AEFFD193072FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental pollution released—</text>
<subclause id="HC6B5FF9FFAD140F0A9DEE2A7483D0DD4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>routinely, accidentally, or otherwise; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCBC386B9B4E240138EB6652BFD5C5491"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from any source, whether single or multiple; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HF293077018B24DC88BACCDB6FDE55D47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as assessed based on the combined past, present, and reasonably foreseeable emissions and discharges affecting the geographical area; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11B926CBC7EC45B7A69B61532137E059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluated taking into account sensitive populations and other factors that may heighten vulnerability to environmental pollution and associated health risks, including socioeconomic characteristics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0DDFCAC41F3B4E19B9FDBEF068A5CB11"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, linguistic isolation, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies to ensure that each person enjoys—</text> <subparagraph id="H5028DA35DE404FB9B1FBE9F2269873C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B049DCB5FF6470DBEF89198A24A354A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equal access to any Federal agency action on environmental justice issues in order to have a healthy environment in which to live, learn, work, and recreate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DF47F9AD6D3461EB041C3914EE83D91"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and Indigenous communities, that bears burdens of negative public health effects, environmental pollution, and the impacts of climate change, and possesses certain socioeconomic criteria, which may be identified based on geographic, public health, environmental hazard, and socioeconomic criteria, including, but not limited to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4566E012C6D44EA0AAA2105B07035063"><enum>(A)</enum><text>areas burdened by cumulative environmental pollution and other hazards that can lead to negative public health effects;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD99567850424D42B36BD8DA1B5A2B5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas with concentrations of people—</text>
<clause id="HB9AA395A1821495889DB562DB5DB92AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">experiencing high unemployment rates, high rent burdens, low homeownership rates, or low levels of educational attainment; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD5DC1527A101405F8AB2D1D541EE25C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who have historically experienced discrimination on the basis of race, ethnicity, ancestry, or place of origin; or</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51B5AE1AB27C404CAF7A52DBEC4E6A48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>vulnerability to the impacts of climate change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H677F5D479B4647C39AE824DD7DD819DB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fossil fuel-fired power plant</header><text>The term <term>fossil fuel-fired power plant</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H60E7BA257EB0440AB4919ADE6E78293A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a powerplant or electric generating unit that combusts fossil fuel or a fossil fuel byproduct or derivative for the production of electricity in part or in full; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H654CFB9B9E2B4945AB43ABF4FE426BC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any boiler or generator that combusts fossil fuel and is—</text>
<clause id="HBF350936EEF743CC8EDB84698BC2D910"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a census tract or adjacent to a census tract with one or more power plants or electric generating units that combust fossil fuel; or</text></clause> <clause id="H7233935E05A64A49A665A45E79C70AEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a census tract or adjacent to census tracts with stationary and mobile sources of air pollution that have combined annual emissions of more than—</text>
<subclause id="H73C9655492534BA6862758A5AF1290EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>10 tons per year of any single hazardous air pollutant;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6DC1B6BD55BD40BA9D91C239978221BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>25 tons per year for any combination of hazardous air pollutants;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HCB3321F5901140BDBD39B8FCC0F09D2F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>100 tons per year of any single air pollutant; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H892DD33BA5D240BF9A7EC7DE24E90722"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the lower major source threshold in non-attainment areas for the air pollutant in non-attainment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC2A455121656482398A11ECCF493D56A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Impacted</header><text>The term <term>impacted</term> means the condition of being affected by one or more fossil fuel-fired power plants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D9C988A2E9148C7A04981CDABECA8CC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Permitting authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>permitting authority</term> has the meaning given such term in section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C75F91BB9174700B31472C32CE5DF3E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Susceptible subpopulation</header><text>The term <term>susceptible subpopulation</term> means a group of individuals within the general population who, due to either greater susceptibility or greater exposure, may be at greater risk than the general population of adverse health effects from exposure to air pollution, such as infants, children, pregnant women, workers, or the elderly.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2F8BC5CCD854F0191C81C3F7E8F647F" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tribal and indigenous community</header><text>The term <term>Tribal and Indigenous community</term> means a population of people who are members of—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC76A25BE2D634EA5823318B3535D1E86" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a federally recognized Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4CE84C6831440FCAF3F5629988E5082" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State-recognized Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A253364CC13433F9E7797147E26F7C2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A57A55A329B4C3CB226507A2645A93D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other community of Indigenous people located in a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H4E3D14098C0449489E7E3582BC80AD82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal requirement</header>
<subsection id="HF59E32B1E0BC432C84D90364058DF3F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Section 203 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15852">42 U.S.C. 15852</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H575D3C4B451D4F828FBD8C21FBC6D102"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>the following amounts shall be</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: </text>
<quoted-block id="HF0B4BB2011774FBEB989EBC1D9147561" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>not less than—</text> <paragraph id="HE6B1DC9F1EB7489691A3CBBA73AB6420"><enum>(1)</enum><text>3 percent shall be renewable energy in fiscal years 2007 through 2009;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EB2BDD73A204961A557A98ABAE62CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>5 percent shall be renewable energy in fiscal years 2010 through 2012;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA9549B0063A443DAF9D8B1D6A8C44F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>7.5 percent shall be renewable energy in fiscal years 2013 through 2019; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC0F0AF522D32463788C46CA07C24628C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>100 percent shall be air pollution-free renewable energy, including battery storage charged renewably, in fiscal year 2030 and each fiscal year thereafter, with steady and incremental progress toward this goal required in fiscal years 2020 through 2029.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61F7E4AB786347BC8FE1F18152B2CFCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H9A568C905BBB4F2893BFC335BEA0C81B" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H471D6BD2E26B4B27B4089D85A80E73DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In meeting the requirement of subsection (a), the President, acting through the Secretary, shall prioritize the transition to consumption of air pollution-free renewable energy, including renewable energy and battery storage charged by renewably generated electricity, by any facility within the vicinity of a major source (as that term is defined in section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>)), or units of such major source, run primarily to meet peak electricity demand.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H14FA9BD3258B466D867B96F93C5D4642" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public utility contracts</header><text>Section 501(b)(1)(B) of title 40, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H3EC558F9F6D047D7ADB811D76F172CC2" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H9EDDBC1E1328482587E0637978823E98" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public utility contracts</header>
<clause id="H5934662123FE41B98E88EF417C4EFB37" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), a contract for public utility services may be made for a period of not more than 10 years.</text></clause> <clause id="H0BE58A6EC12D43CAB0A542787C9C8542" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewable energy contracts</header><text>A contract may be made for a period of not more than 40 years for—</text>
<subclause id="HCD0916D20B184506AAEF55D205FE1137" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the acquisition of air pollution-free renewable energy or battery storage powered by such energy; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA43084ACFF424348BEF60400F587B0E2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the provision and operation of air pollution-free renewable energy production facilities and the purchase of air-pollution free renewable energy from such facilities.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="HE272C90B3C144D76818FB7210F312738"><enum>4.</enum><header>Just energy transition fund</header>
<subsection id="H54F48425FCEF4EF3B64F92E936C605C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023, $10,000,000,000 for a Just Energy Transition Fund, to be administered by the Administrator in consultation with the Secretary and the Advisory Council, to remain available until expended, to award funds to States, territories, and Tribal governments for projects described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC50558E8155B42F9A6C5212598A2D974"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State, territory, Tribal government, local government, community-based organization, nongovernmental organization, or private sector organization may submit an application, in such form and manner as the Administrator may require, for—</text>
<paragraph id="H8CC94E1AF519418BB8B74D0716A14A62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a project that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4BBA3E4EA67848B4AA0F7601BED11FCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addresses energy needs resulting from the denial of renewal, or anticipated denial of renewal, of a permit for a fossil fuel-fired power plant pursuant to section 165(f) or section 502(j) of the Clean Air Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H74B4862FFA4743609A50CD566DC51ABA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apportions sufficient project funds, as determined by the Advisory Council, to income support, health insurance, pension fund protection, job training, and job placement for workers displaced or expected to be displaced due to the denial of renewal, or anticipated denial of renewal, of a permit for a major source or a fossil fuel-fired power plant pursuant to section 165(f) or section 502(j) of the Clean Air Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7737564A685C427CBE9FBB79BC2BE9B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is supported by residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities, as discerned through active and inclusive solicitation and documentation of feedback and input from such residents through a process established by the Advisory Council;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4B75972E68504D73B0E27F80C2640C92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not rely on fuels or technologies that create environmental harm, including greenhouse gas emissions and air pollution, or contribute to health burdens on environmental justice communities and impacted communities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H490C3827B8084FE2A44307ED04751246"><enum>(E)</enum><text>results in a quantifiable improvement to the health and well-being of residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities as measured by the Advisory Council; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48A3BFACF2DE4BE7877F5D6821896C32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a program supported by residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities, as discerned through active and inclusive solicitation and documentation of feedback and input from such residents through a process established by the Advisory Council, that results in a quantifiable improvement to the health and well-being of residents of environmental justice communities and other impacted communities, as measured by the Advisory Committee, including one that—</text> <subparagraph id="H18443B86D49B44EA804AF84E4E33AA90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>apportions funds to individuals who face burdensome energy costs, including from supply charges, delivery charges, capacity payments, and other costs that may or may not be itemized in utility bills, or to individuals who are expected to face burdensome costs due to the denial of renewal, or anticipated denial of renewal, of a permit for a fossil fuel-fired power plant pursuant to section 165(f) or section 502(j) of the Clean Air Act, to reduce the cost of—</text>
<clause id="HF33681DDACF14B4583F20DFAFFECE4EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>utility bills for ratepayers; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB71DF38FAC894D50917AA546F86F1F74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost of rent for tenants in instances in which utilities are included in the tenant’s rent; or</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF825333070B34ACDB74F0590D4C23ACF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supports intervenor compensation opportunities to lower energy costs and reduce pollution faced by residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC38A2D7DBA544368AF032E49A8E192C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary and the Advisory Committee, shall establish a process of applying for funds allocated under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC4050BEA37F64949B2B3FC522371DD73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subgrants and contracts</header><text>A recipient of funds under this section may award such funds to community groups and other entities as subgrants or contracts in furtherance of a project described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4B9EAF65F44B43A083C68B1481119A8B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Just energy transition fund advisory council</header> <paragraph id="HA857B49912B846A493C564FFFD4C629F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall establish an advisory council, to be known as the <quote>Just Energy Transition Fund Advisory Council</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H114649E8F0FB4353B1C45FC386B9B85C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be composed of 26 members who have knowledge of, or experience relating to, the creation of, and transition of workers to, good-paying jobs to combat climate change and pollution, as well as the effect of environmental conditions on environmental justice communities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0A521E1470A43E48EB42290DD913727"><enum>(A)</enum><text>representatives of—</text>
<clause id="H7BED19E249B7494795D05A2CD75D5AEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>community-based organizations that carry out initiatives relating to environmental justice and the just transition to a clean energy economy, including grassroots organizations led by people of color;</text></clause> <clause id="H10B56D93EC4B46A0B1AD8AE4C3F02132"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>labor unions;</text></clause>
<clause id="HCCF0252F01164F64B9223B230C9EBFF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>State governments, Tribal governments, and local governments;</text></clause> <clause id="H6E2498712D8345B48F89F2EC0CDA42DB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Indian Tribes and other Indigenous groups;</text></clause>
<clause id="HD395A5C0E8674AF7AB08D710B5936392"><enum>(v)</enum><text>nongovernmental and environmental organizations; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDDAB9F22853346E4972F26655DD066FE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>private sector organizations (including representatives of industries and businesses); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B34736FD13946209E131DAE90EA832C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experts in the field of—</text> <clause id="HEFD06530B77A4C90806FA61D0E2D3A3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>socioeconomic analysis;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9DBE1C44601B47FB9B02A84F22E12E13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>health and environmental effects;</text></clause> <clause id="H7C7DD4050F4348F09878EC73387E93F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>exposure evaluation;</text></clause>
<clause id="H37CF6FAE7C834F9E937F458A27057DAB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>environmental law and civil rights law; </text></clause> <clause id="H6CB3D3204C9545D39A2BCEFC011C21B3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>environmental health science research; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H4D4524F8D7504A79831AC1D00CD76EF9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>energy systems.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA050D0C6A22E43F1B0CFAFD323FB81E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subcommittees; workgroups</header> <subparagraph id="HED6914C11E294A73A95E6E1FFFF93026"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Advisory Council may establish any subcommittee or workgroup to assist the Advisory Council in carrying out any duty of the Advisory Council described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCFA789975C9F4D48ABC2363D880D715D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the request of the Advisory Council, each subcommittee or workgroup established by the Advisory Council under subparagraph (A) shall submit to the Advisory Council a report that contains—</text> <clause id="H5C7310CCC773415FA78814DF7F32C22C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of each recommendation of the subcommittee or workgroup; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H80A8E53F302B426D81E8771653D958EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any advice requested by the Advisory Council with respect to any duty of the Advisory Council.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03FF80C38EB84A49846F5C56D1629893"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council shall provide independent advice and recommendations to the Administrator and the Secretary with respect to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H18712422F1BD41339D39E916963FD9B1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>awarding grants through the Just Energy Transition Fund to maximize progress toward a transition to a clean energy economy while maximizing benefits for environmental justice communities, including by prioritizing applications that will direct funds to support entities that have urgently and expeditiously pursued priorities that are aligned with the projects and programs described in subsection (b)(1) and (2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H563A35C9AB564E319A776A03316CC92F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measuring and evaluating the success of grants and subgrants awarded through the Just Energy Transition Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0C709C292444CFFB5606FB9486F529A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
<subparagraph id="HDF288A4027AD4171B4CCF2B499EED462"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Frequency</header>
<clause id="HCA39A51FC65E46D2B5A502141935DF4F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the Advisory Council shall meet biannually.</text></clause> <clause id="HE369674AD6CB451284AED0EBF642CCD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority of administrator</header><text>The Administrator may require the Advisory Council to conduct additional meetings if the Administrator determines that the conduct of any additional meetings is necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0497C8EEED284084B301E1F8AB3C268D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public participation</header>
<clause id="H718F6DBCAEC14E1A8A966CAAFC43EC94"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), each meeting of the Advisory Council shall be open to the public to provide the public an opportunity—</text> <subclause id="HE29D7EAF1DC74A47AA38573606295677"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to submit comments to the Advisory Council; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H568A5E5FD15C48CAB732FC13DC4385CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to appear before the Advisory Council.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H77229D9385F1415B808745CD2B7AC086"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority of administrator</header><text>The Administrator may close any meeting, or portion of any meeting, of the Advisory Council to the public.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD6490FBDCB54769BD33595CD7AFCF0B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>FACA</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H468A2D3355154A26BBF1205C9A420E79"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The Administrator may provide to any member of the Advisory Council travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H314DC590E35B43F08E20E871BF8ECC1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H757DC6939F8543F9AD6B515DB8CF7204"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCFD89D851BF4962B90CC1A1938998E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the Just Energy Transition Fund Advisory Council established under subsection (e) of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H394474333FD242928B6D07486FF145D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B6D05DEA33A47CC81F46B9AC0516522"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F8EE5467CEB4A3F9DB1F00E7B9D9736"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Territory</header><text>The term <term>territory</term> means the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35036B490E5D41B5B28FA05485599EA0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H01535183E8EE4276889E0E49A2476803"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consideration of cumulative impacts in power plant permitting</header> <subsection id="HC3E0716E5EB74748B7D40F87A43DB693"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permits generally</header> <paragraph id="H45428F71E43C4E3A94C72BA10F89FD4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Section 502(b) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661a">42 U.S.C. 7661a(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding after paragraph (10) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H19D71E1CD8E34FB4A5382A156C843DBE" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HC59C8026474C450D8E6A63E10972CBA8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A requirement for performing cumulative impacts analysis in accordance with subsection (j), if applicable.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H931E0ADF283A421CA29175DC4DC2E21E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cumulative impacts analysis</header><text>Section 502 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661a">42 U.S.C. 7661a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H1948C55759C04E5A8D1393A1642A7EEF" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H261FF69A5C5B42D19E7A58945206CE00"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Cumulative impacts analysis</header>
<paragraph id="H60BA23BBC3604460A456D2E57122D91A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
<subparagraph id="H969385B7E22F4AE5B506A7F273E4FDEF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Permit requirement</header><text>Whenever an applicant seeks a permit or renewal of a permit for a fossil fuel-fired power plant, the permitting authority shall require such applicant to utilize a neutral third-party assessor to perform, in consultation with a community intervenor, an analysis of—</text> <clause id="HD8D4DC346BF24522B495AAF94718B6D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cumulative impacts of pollution, including the combined past, present, and reasonably anticipated future emissions, from all stationary or mobile sources, affecting the area within five miles of the fossil fuel-fired power plant proposed to be permitted; </text></clause>
<clause id="H7911EF8EFD234B71BF91BEAC5519C918"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each census block group or Tribal census block group (as those terms are defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census) located in, or adjacent to, such area, the cumulative impacts of pollution, including the combined past, present, and reasonably anticipated future emissions, from all stationary or mobile sources; and</text></clause> <clause id="H00DCC8AE9B5B4E76A1C0F5F06FD7E8DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>alternative projects sourced with air pollution-free renewable energy.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6BBEE39C196549A49D5AA1E321756D10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>One year after this section takes effect and at least every five years thereafter, the permitting authority must ensure that a fossil fuel-fired power plant undergoes a cumulative impacts analysis as described by this subsection if the fossil fuel-fired power plant is—</text> <clause id="HF4BBE8DB80F743758ABA54EF2973D346"><enum>(i)</enum><text>located, or proposed to be located, within one mile of a major source; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H50EABFDFEE924F7D9B19764BB2E9ACC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not subject to permitting requirements pursuant to this title.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E5AE1F8353147E693077598B3453381"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>A cumulative impacts analysis under subparagraph (A) shall include consideration of—</text>
<clause id="H353F89130AE7449E82468B203DFC488B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>community demographics and locations of community exposure points, including schools, day care centers, nursing homes, hospitals, health clinics, places of religious worship, parks, playgrounds, and community centers;</text></clause> <clause id="H15B648E249C045EE99D34AE12A3C39AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>air quality and any potential effects on that air quality of emissions of air pollutants from the fossil fuel-fired power plant proposed to be permitted, including in combination with existing sources of pollutants;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFC9666A2FC6744758D8869CDE1BA8128"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the potential effects on soil quality and water quality of emissions of lead and other air pollutants that could contaminate soil or water from the fossil fuel-fired power plant proposed to be permitted, including in combination with existing sources of pollutants;</text></clause> <clause id="H7E096BFBD57E4BDEB43F1DB448A37945"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>public health and any potential effects on public health from the emissions of pollutants from the fossil fuel-fired power plant proposed to be permitted, including in combination with existing sources of pollutants;</text></clause>
<clause id="HAFFB7FD1F3BE4CFEBB123E2534F878B9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the potential adverse impacts on health and well-being of residents of impacted environmental justice communities and populations with heightened vulnerability to pollution and associated health risks, which may be due to socioeconomic characteristics including housing insecurity, barriers to receive quality healthcare or afford health insurance, energy cost burdens that limit use of heat and air conditioning, long-term impacts of siting polluting sources in environmental justice communities, and public disinvestment and redlining; </text></clause> <clause id="H55901019AEF443F1880AF8E15CF8A8E7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the potential effects of any proposed action on environmental justice communities, including if the action causes or exacerbates a disproportionate or inequitable burden on the environmental justice community; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H237CF767B9F446078BF470EDD5FCEDA2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>shall be based on an analysis of data that accurately describes the potential cumulative impacts of the proposed action, and may include a supplemental qualitative analysis.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H347B401B03ED4E7D9FD0934AD60AC90C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public engagement and procedural justice process</header><text>The cumulative impacts analysis under subparagraph (A) shall include a public engagement and procedural justice process, to include—</text>
<clause id="H056DA7C8617C4D1795460BE82D7EA474"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the active and inclusive solicitation and receipt of, and to the greatest extent practicable, action to address, input and feedback from residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities, to be documented and provided to the permitting authority in the final cumulative impacts analysis;</text></clause> <clause id="H2C9669AE58A7490084E70666C3BF26DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>documentation and investigation of claims brought by residents of impacted environmental justice communities and impacted communities, including the applicant’s proposed or agreed-upon mitigations, whether and how each claim was addressed, and documentation of the satisfaction or dissatisfaction of such residents with the investigation of claims and corresponding responses, if any;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF79BC365CF9F459FA15A685669C46B52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>advanced notification to residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities through various means including but not limited to written notification, local news advertisements, and canvassers;</text></clause> <clause id="H531C4B867C2047B4B4A1DADBC59E2F2F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>multiple opportunities for residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities to participate;</text></clause>
<clause id="H32AB99F7B2F44713B37EC31918C77C81"><enum>(v)</enum><text>multiple media and formats for participation, including in-person and remote options, which shall include large and small group settings, mail-in feedback opportunities, and other such avenues to ensure that health, socioeconomics, lack of technological resources, and settings that are unwelcoming or unfamiliar to residents of impacted environmental justice communities are not barriers to participation;</text></clause> <clause id="H6024099E66084AC991321850FA50C683"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>transmission of a preliminary cumulative impacts analysis at least 30 days in advance of any public comment period or public comment event to—</text>
<subclause id="H45A1464537F04CE699570DB1003B6871"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the permitting authority for online publication;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H90E0EE2D504B4BC588E0E76546EB31F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>community groups and community representatives of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HCCAF4F95C5E54E0FADD6BFDF96EC98C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to a reasonable extent, the residents of impacted environmental justice communities and other impacted communities; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8D1F8B39412C478D8537BA57DDFC953A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in instances in which a resident participating in the process outlined in this paragraph stands to benefit, financially or otherwise, from the permit under consideration, disclosure of such benefit in the final cumulative impacts analysis.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H98BF1DF6A9B548C8915CCE0A0CFA2865"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), a permitting authority shall not grant a permit or renewal or allow operation of a fossil fuel-fired power plant unless the cumulative impacts analysis under paragraph (1) indicates a reasonable certainty that such permit, renewal, or operation will result in no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, including environmental justice communities, of a census block group or Tribal census block group described in paragraph (1)(A), and the public engagement and procedural justice process described in paragraph (1)(C) is fulfilled.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D95A3B1623A4C00A5B647F0BEFD4ED7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical facilities exemption</header><text>A fossil fuel-fired power plant that is a boiler serving a critical facility may only be denied a permit or be otherwise prohibited from operation if the cumulative impact analysis under paragraph (1) indicates a certainty that the permit or renewal will result in harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, including environmental justice communities, of a census block group or Tribal census block group described in paragraph (1)(A), and the alternative is deemed to be of reasonable cost.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA8F1DD50B6B04778969503DFCF8156CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preconstruction permits</header><text>Section 165 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7475">42 U.S.C. 7475</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAA6B79FB0DE44CB5B4582D246830EAC7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA524D9559F8644EEBB8BE2D6E8E85997"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cumulative impacts</header> <paragraph id="H0F34B8874A5544BA9A23866D96AF2A62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H39B17E7ED5C149D3AD2BA351494B18F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Whenever an applicant seeks a permit under this section or renewal of such a permit for a fossil fuel-fired power plant within one mile of a fossil fuel-fired power plant or a major source (as defined in section 112), the permitting authority shall require such applicant to perform an analysis of the cumulative impacts for each census block group or Tribal census block group (as those terms are defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census) located in, or immediately adjacent to, the area in which the fossil fuel-fired power plant to be permitted is, or is proposed to be, located.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6352DC5E605F443B9BF95CE039DB9556"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability of certain provisions</header><text>The provisions of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 502(j)(1) shall apply to any cumulative impacts analysis performed under this subsection to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply to a cumulative impacts analysis performed under such section 502(j)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29DD8E08C9F5417BAD1F17E29D96A34D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A permitting authority shall not grant a permit or renewal described in paragraph (1)(A) unless the cumulative impacts analysis under paragraph (1) indicates a reasonable certainty that the permit or renewal will result in no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, including environmental justice communities, of a census block group or Tribal census block group described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H90D277EC361147D79DA02EABD5A33E5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transitional provision</header><text>Section 165(f) and section 502(j) of the Clean Air Act (as added by this section) shall apply with respect to a fossil fuel-fired power plant for which, on or before the date of enactment of this Act, a permit has been issued pursuant to section 165 or title V of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7475">42 U.S.C. 7475</external-xref>, 7661 et seq.), but for which construction has not commenced as of such date.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

