<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H88FADAA416DD4D3AA6026B9711D3CF03" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8686 IH: Wounded Warrior Research Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8686</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to award grants to fund research on orthotics and prosthetics.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDE05444FEC0842BB9F3B197FE27985F9" style="OLC"><section id="H1C49A405923D4DD58A1AE9CBAABDA19D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wounded Warrior Research Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4ACC990481D947A1A5476906FD599648"><enum>2.</enum><header>Orthotic and prosthetic research</header><subsection id="HE0514962FD8A4B199D562ABE7152E423"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the grants described in this section is to advance orthotic and prosthetic clinical care for members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and civilians who have undergone amputation, traumatic brain injury, and other serious physical injury as a result of combat or military experience.</text></subsection><subsection id="H81B14BA4CEA14D9BA43ECA19D07C5F88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for research on patient outcomes</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall award grants to persons to carry out research on the following:</text><paragraph id="H42CCF1E7A1AB496B9C7545080C967967"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The actions that can be taken to prevent amputation of limbs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5421B75A8C94E78899CE358AE6E1DC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The point in the course of patient treatment during which orthotic and prosthetic intervention is most effective.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA32B58E936D54510B6B175DDE6F36872"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The orthotic interventions that are most effective in treating the physical effects of traumatic brain injury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H148D71576EB644DF806E15DC583B0CC0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The patients that benefit most from particular orthotic and prosthetic technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDCC97C2EF834083AD722949B90647B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The orthotic and prosthetic services that best facilitate the return to active duty of members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0596E348A296410E81A19D82DB712027"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The effect of the aging process on the use of prosthetics, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE5F84495216E43BD86C763BA47FF5855"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increased skin breakdown;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BB5225345644C008D2E744B2C0F42A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>loss of balance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3150FC15A3B4CBE8C4FD2B3E7F43AD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>falls; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDA89BAC4B1844ED9FBC5B1BE20E8A20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other issues that arise during the aging process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H189596BF2F0F4B0188EE7931B26B71A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants on materials research</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to persons to carry out research on the following:</text><paragraph id="HB2792C6BB24A4D218060749653C28259"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The improvement of existing materials used in orthotics and prosthetics for the purpose of improving quality of life and health outcomes for individuals with limb loss.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE459ECE945894ED9A423056F3066C801"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The development of new materials used in orthotics and prosthetics for the purpose of improving quality of life and health outcomes for individuals with limb loss.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2171FE7BB93D4889BCCB1CE771473DE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants on technology research</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to persons to carry out research on the following:</text><paragraph id="H08F384A5233041F0BC21F4DA97085987"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The improvement of existing orthotic and prosthetic technology and devices for the purpose of improving quality of life and health outcomes for individuals with limb loss.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2E49C02796B41329A69B0375195AC10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The development of new orthotic and prosthetic technology and devices for the purpose of improving quality of life and health outcomes for individuals with limb loss.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6BD2832BCF94AE0B7F317BB9AF781FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Request for proposals</header><text>A person seeking the award of a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application therefore in the form and accompanied by such information as the Secretary shall require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6521BE2F61FB4098821AF9BC91048C8F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Award requirements</header><paragraph id="HF21505B8B0B84D4CAC8DD6BEDD0F31C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Peer-reviewed proposals</header><text>Grants under this section may be awarded only for research that is peer-reviewed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A74D3911DEB4457848F0A47346943E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competitive procedures</header><text>Grants under this section shall be awarded through competitive procedures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0EB669227B7246A7AE40F9840B39F79E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grant use</header><text>A person awarded a grant under subsection (b), (c), or (d) shall use the grant amount to carry out the research described in the applicable subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6EE9389251F34D06AD32DFA784B1550E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, veterans, community-based clinicians, and expert researchers in the field of orthotics and prosthetics, submit to Congress a report setting forth the following:</text><paragraph id="HEF95B9E607E24C9A87FA5B81B63EFE67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An agenda for orthotic and prosthetic research that identifies and prioritizes the most significant unanswered orthotic and prosthetic research questions pertinent to the provision of evidence-based clinical care to members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and civilians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90EC5A14A3E24B1CA1A2121D8D00DA11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each report after the initial report under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H3A886D70C3E147D28BC9411716AB85F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of how the grants awarded under subsection (b) are addressing the most significant orthotic and prosthetic needs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34A27024C9BF4F02A4D61E5461D74156"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the progress made towards resolving orthotic and prosthetic challenges facing members of the Armed Forces and veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE384AA9EEA9449CB31E246E7DF1A8CF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Veteran defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9DDB168996E4EA78A1734272DC39DE7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023 for the Department of Defense for the Defense Health Program, $30,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

