<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07ACD890C6084F4E94C22D0821AD6987" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8877 IH: Biologics Competition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to evaluate the extent to which the substitution of interchangeable biological products may be impeded by differences between the system for determining a biological product to be interchangeable and the system for assigning therapeutic equivalence ratings to drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H126760B381564994A80B2DBF2FACDC76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB4682D3E8F6E401D9B58A76E64374AD3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biologics Competition Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3632A19118664995A3550774FBBA7F4D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on certain impediments to the substitution of interchangeable biological products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8636EB8B844415EA02EA579644B4D26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete a study to evaluate the extent to which the substitution of interchangeable biological products licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) may be impeded by differences between the system for determining a biological product to be interchangeable under section 351(k)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)(4)</external-xref>) and the system for assigning therapeutic equivalence ratings to drugs approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E5F63490E9943D3AE7C5C474DFB4157"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the Congress on the results of the study under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE2C7DA6298A4401850F442543EAE951"><enum>(3)</enum><text>update the list published under section 351(k)(9)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)(9)(A)</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Purple Book</quote>) to implement such changes as the Secretary deems necessary to harmonize the approach for communicating the substitutability of interchangeable biological products with the approach for communicating therapeutic equivalence ratings assigned to drugs, with the goals of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC3F76E76344D4068B51954172185974D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>minimizing impediments to the substitution of interchangeable biological products; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE136A671DAD24D09B909BA657516E58B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintaining the distinct pathways by which biological products are licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) and drugs are approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

