<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H240EA76BDB104A2A819F987482FE0863" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8576 IH: Travel Nursing Agency Transparency Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study on the effects of travel nurse agencies on the health industry during the COVID–19 pandemic.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H75052517EAFC418B8B6B9B28C776961F" style="OLC"><section id="HC8AB4AB6ADAF47E7BE7CDDE43B923C6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Travel Nursing Agency Transparency Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2B598049EFD1401DBD08EDD939821893"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on travel nurse agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="HCC373E426F954F7D972878E9BAAE1076"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the effects of travel nurse agencies on the health care industry during the COVID–19 pandemic, which shall include consideration of—</text><subparagraph id="HE132F293B202488184BAD4402E5D4613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the business practices and payment practices of such agencies, including any potential price gouging and taking of excessive profits; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CEE05AA950547AC92F36A04FB7AADC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the difference between how much such agencies charged health care institutions and how much they paid their contracted nurses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9599A0F019964457A2F005731FE62EDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which such agencies could provide more transparency regarding the payments received from health care institutions, and the payments made by the agencies to the nurses who are contracted by such agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B46CB7931B44DC3AB6633AE16157F6A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the specific ways in which rural areas of the United States were affected by the rise of travel nursing across the country, and subsequent workforce shortage disparities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H044E229426464593A0861D91E1DE027F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how States that imposed caps to travel nurse pay were affected by the market reaction to such caps; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE571D1C6C3B044F0AA0FF30F16544767"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how Federal funds, including the Provider Relief Fund and any assistance granted to a health care institution under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/121">42 U.S.C. 121 et seq.</external-xref>), were used by health care institutions to pay such agencies throughout the workforce shortages exacerbated by the COVID–19 pandemic; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7626E437640B44E2963677D48A3304E6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the extent to which travel nurse agency practices contribute to workforce shortages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE0E8B3C2574570AB51217AD6E60B8B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the extent to which travel nurse agencies have been acquired by private equity firms and the impact of such acquisitions on the profits of the agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8653BD36C544E2F8A69824522C3D769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report to Congress on such study.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

