<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E3CD0D7CD5B4356AEEF3EEE3069BB52" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6396 IH: Climate Risk and Emergency Support In Livable Inclusive and Equitable Neighborhoods and Communities Everywhere Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6396</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220113">January 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act with respect to hazard mitigation plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0ADD8C22E7CA418EB61A08D3AA224E35" style="OLC"><section id="HB58E5B9F845C44C09CDEA2183718C455" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Risk and Emergency Support In Livable Inclusive and Equitable Neighborhoods and Communities Everywhere Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Climate RESILIENCE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFD96AE3352524CF0AC23F53D589E5E54"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H9BB18EE3E09E4BCD8274992A97EC7F06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the 2018 National Climate Assessment, climate change due to global warming has caused, and is expected to continue to cause, substantial interference with and growing losses to human health and safety, infrastructure, property, industry, recreation, natural resources, agricultural systems, and quality of life in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB7E09920B1B4A08B8AAA6718600BFB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, climate change is already increasing the frequency and severity of extreme weather and other climate-related disasters, including drought, wildfire, and storms that include precipitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E5B3675C85E4669BDF6D39500BCF578"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in 2020, there were a record 22 weather and climate disasters costing $1,000,000,000 or more across the country, shattering the prior annual record of 16. These events totaled $95,000,000,000 in damages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA514119E0F943CDA69D4EC008B0F5D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since 2015, the United States has experienced more than 81 individual disasters, amounting to $630,200,000,000 in economic losses, and close to 4,000 deaths.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA30F7FBCC124B248C67B30F7975927D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Researchers have found that Black, Latino, and low-income families are more likely to live in high-risk areas like flood zones, less likely to have money to harden infrastructure and homes in advance of disasters, and less likely to receive assistance during recovery periods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50564A668AE448E4AF04F725E80838EB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to Dr. Beverly Wright and Dr. Robert Bullard, <quote>environmental and public health threats from natural and human-made disasters are not randomly distributed, affecting some communities more than others</quote>, and therefore our response to disasters necessitates the adoption of policies and processes rooted in principles of racial equity, self-determination, and democracy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB2AA20D3C074045807C2669F9E1DC98"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Research from the University of Colorado shows that the top 10 percent of disaster hotspots account for about 30 percent of the contiguous United States but are home to nearly 60 percent of buildings in the country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77EEDB21427E4FB5A0A07B9DDFDBD441"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to testimony in November 2017 from former Federal Emergency Management Agency Administrator Brock Long, <quote>I cannot overstate the importance of focusing on investing in mitigation before a disaster strikes. Building more resilient communities is the best way to reduce risks to people, property, and taxpayer dollars.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BDC13C84B2B473AA27BDC2D762C90C0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Government Accountability Office found that the Federal Emergency Management Agency spends 88 percent of its budget on postdisaster mitigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2995D18A6EA40F188C1229699F39395"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2020 grant application cycle, the Federal Emergency Management Agency received nearly $4,000,000,000 in applications for their grant programs. However, in fiscal year 2020, the Federal Emergency Management Agency only made $700,000,000 available for predisaster mitigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37E8A0CA3F9A49DCABBA9550563B9CD8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Public-sector investment in mitigation since 1995 by the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Housing and Urban Development Agency cost the country $27,000,000,000 but is projected to save $160,000,000,000, totaling $6 saved per $1 invested.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3E063512FB64DE78EFD6882AC1EB15D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States has an opportunity to use disaster mitigation to minimize risk, improve resiliency, and address social problems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3BDCD6A774CF4BE68F39B5C1F14531F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA173A19D3A5241C6B5B87823A8CDCE60"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2) by inserting <quote>extreme temperature event, including heat wave or freeze,</quote> after <quote>snowstorm</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43B76FFF045C48DE844CD7A763E1E9AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2215B99C40D84228A3CF484E6C876CDE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H32B7973CA8C44622B0071D4705C81C80"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, the term <quote>resilience</quote> means the ability to prepare for and adapt to changing conditions and withstand and recover rapidly from disruptions, including the ability—</text><subparagraph id="id688AD8AABEA445399FAC0E49DAEAFDAA"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0AC375A8B1D4C3E9ECDB998F3D91F0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to resist hazards or withstand impacts from a weather event or major disaster; or</text></clause><clause id="id59E044F46C49469F900EE736F361C473" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to reduce the magnitude or duration of impacts of a disruptive weather event or major disaster on a project; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33E0BAAB1DC5474196F1CB8B86125B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0AC375A8B1D4C3E9ECDB993F3D91F0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assess and understand current risk to extreme weather and major disasters, as well as the potential for changing risk over time;</text></clause><clause id="H1219938BD06145108E6FD05E3EC79C04" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the community’s capacity to lessen its risk by planning for and adapting to changing conditions; and</text></clause><clause id="H65AAA1AD9C0740D0819B2233A2541743" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to achieve equitable outcomes through risk management and protect the safety and well-being of an entire community, including its most vulnerable populations. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H18C8CEE867EE4156962E3B18ACC0BF92"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal and state preparedness and mitigation assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H58370FE7F138425594A18902B8BAA450" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7E30AFC8DB514679964D34EEF49CF300"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this section may also use grant funds for other purposes, including—</text><paragraph id="H8FE5FACED3B44B5D8A45269042A96FD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to weatherize and retrofit building structures, including the installation of heat pumps, air conditioners, and air filtration or ventilation systems in a way that is cost effective and reduces the risk of damage from further disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92C3BDA904EF4784A350E619951F82E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce the impacts of extreme temperatures, including by improving building insulation in a way that is cost effective and reduces the risk of damage from further disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0DC0E9FB2714DDC8ECA2CB6C3A374B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase or enhance natural climate resilient infrastructure, including urban tree canopy, green space, functioning floodplains, creeks, streams, and wetlands, or other mitigation activities that conserve or restore natural features that can serve to abate or lessen the impacts of future disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6145FEF581B43E3B0B14E0209F61CB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve air quality and mitigate against wildfire smoke or other air quality contaminants related to a major disaster or emergency; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A351F96BBB456B9D9D94693C70F3D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide financial and technical support to State, local, and Indian Tribal health providers or organizations to carry out community-led climate adaptations and interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C318CA79B6D4346BE37080738048F38"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide disaster preparedness or community emergency response team training to community-based organizations and residents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C758D72D8DE4A29AA51CADEF5EC2DA5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop emergency plans for disadvantaged communities, including homeless residents, disabled residents, children, the elderly, non-native English speakers, residents lacking access to reliable transportation, and otherwise disadvantaged communities, as well as pets and service animals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C74942CD3AF43048DEEE3F68EB84DC4"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop community climate resilient infrastructure, including extreme weather or temperature shelters, emergency transportation or mobility options, and resilient community energy infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H525EE8FA91714DB5A301CB47E9A2CAB8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advise, plan, and implement for community resilience and adaptation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFABF07592C654A179DAE11D949484FC5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and implement participatory processes that allow for public engagement in determining and addressing local risks and vulnerabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D32A2DF0FDA4374A8BAA0B06BD5B74D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to adopt and comply with the standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4012F0721C6546D9B248B29942D8EF77"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the fire resistance of structures, including homes, businesses, public buildings, and critical facilities, as well as non-structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCECAF5DF551E4F4899691168892DCE27"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the seismic resilience of structures, including homes, businesses, public buildings, critical facilities, critical systems such as sewage and water, as well as non-structures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B784B499D2D44EA9B90D72DA399A49F"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for other specific resilience activities determined appropriate by the Administrator. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A84A08105094390936A61AF1362C46A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Administrator shall coordinate with other relevant agencies, such as the Department of Energy, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the Environmental Protection Agency, as necessary, to improve collaboration for activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9C913B0E20384BA886825960433E6787"><enum>5.</enum><header>Predisaster mitigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB8EBF717FFC54A4EAC5FA1D89858388E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0A6AE3A2B6A9453CAD85102DEA4C5AC8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H25F880243C70491399EC57A58B7A922C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H106D802066A04058A0CC7B00C3BED6E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Underserved community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>underserved community</quote> means a community of 30,000 or fewer individuals that is identified by the State as a rural community, and is not a remote area within the corporate boundaries of a larger city that—</text><subparagraph id="HF7B70A96DBD84FEFA0E4E6B5CA4EED8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is economically disadvantaged, by having an average per capita annual income of residents not exceeding 80 percent of national, per capita income, based on best available data; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DAD86937DE247388933806B2191EDD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the local unemployment rate exceeds by 1 percentage point or more, the most recently reported, average yearly national unemployment rate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H484756DE379C4ECD8813B0F9641BAE3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other factors identified in the State Plan in which the community is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EECDE4F98AD462BBFF6E4B14DF63B76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disadvantaged community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>disadvantaged community</quote> means a community, or a specific neighborhood within a community, that is—</text><subparagraph id="H7DF0DAFCDCA0461FB3240431E6ED1F9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in a census tract with a Centers for Disease Control Social Vulnerability Index score of not less than 0.7501;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888267D9B00945D1A557C2FFCF1BF59B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comprised of residents having an average per capita annual income not exceeding 80 percent of national per capita income; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H284C5D43DE61404EB202B79756AA7ED9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise determined by the Administrator based factors such as percentage of homeless population, demographic information such as race, age, and disability, language composition, and transportation access or type.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H203B1F940CC145F7B05298AC1FC6CEDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <quote>private nonprofit organization</quote> means any non-governmental agency or entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H085AA73537174D4DA1C9781650DA93EB"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2d123cbf580f4b488dc7a80dd1995d7e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">currently has an effective ruling letter from the Internal Revenue Service granting tax exemption under section 501(c), (d), or (e) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></clause><clause id="idFCE3BB3CFB8F472C9B34D360373F0BC1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has satisfactory evidence from the State that the organization or entity is a non-profit organized or doing business under State law; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68D1BFE6A65647848B09A00B804EEBC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets any other criteria established by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H22B97ACE2B5A4706BAC4942A398F5EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b) by inserting after <quote>assistance to States and local governments</quote> the following: <quote>, or to a private nonprofit organization, through a State, in the form of grants under this section for carrying out mitigation activities and</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC91844B29544DFEBB59BA61B21152CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="HADF5F490155D47CCADA049FD9655CF29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A) by striking <quote>principally</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCA55C4520E464301A300852334E04E77" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>principally—</text><clause id="H89C1CBDB04714410AC329164CE0002A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement predisaster hazard mitigation measures that will be cost-effective and equitable long-term and provide enhanced protection to the community, including vulnerable residents, and are described in proposals approved by the President under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H14FEAA48859A4886AE33853D6C0DAEA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify and provide financial and non-financial technical assistance, including non-financial and direct technical assistance to underserved or disadvantaged communities under this section; </text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A844202584D4E329DE9069D2108BDD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)—</text><clause id="HBFE77CD09740470AB3C28D0659A654F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>may be used</quote> the following: <quote>for purposes, including</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HB03756948C2F4302BF740B3B159A58AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (ii);</text></clause><clause id="H85C45ABB48464339B0A248D33090A4E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end of clause (iii); and</text></clause><clause id="H002225C414054516BDC57439F8092859"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H74F13F9529614ECD9B9BA06B0A911394" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HECF5EB17C73240F5B77FEF05ED98D1AB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to weatherize and retrofit building structures, including the installation of heat pumps, air conditioners, and air filtration or ventilation systems in a way that is cost effective and reduces the risk of damage from further disasters;</text></clause><clause id="HF9FBEE787CE248D2AE66743AEEC8F6BE"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce the impacts of extreme temperatures including by improving building insulation in a way that is cost effective and reduces the risk of damage from further disasters;</text></clause><clause id="HF8DF787F447D45878D843A4D9C724DAB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase or enhance natural climate resilient infrastructure, including urban tree canopy, increased green space, green roofing, functioning floodplains, creeks, streams, and wetlands, or other mitigation activities that conserve or restore natural features that can serve to abate or lessen the impacts of future disasters;</text></clause><clause id="H10661324AECB4B20876DBC1DBBCE899C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve air quality and mitigate against wildfire smoke or other air quality contaminants related to a major disaster or emergency; </text></clause><clause id="H9E466034759C4EA3B16D33BF61D5215F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to provide financial and technical support to State, local, and Indian Tribal health providers or organizations to carry out community-led climate adaptations and interventions;</text></clause><clause id="HC36B5FECE5BD44229452D3D703AFB829"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and implement participatory processes that allow for public engagement in determining and addressing local risks and vulnerabilities;</text></clause><clause id="H5B1036F0D8D548EB8DA5C85E30446826"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop emergency plans with input from disadvantaged communities, including consideration for homeless residents, disabled residents, children, the elderly, non-native English speakers, residents lacking access to reliable transportation, and otherwise disadvantaged communities, as well as pets or service animals;</text></clause><clause id="H7924A82D817F447B9CF9AD0968FB560D"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop community climate resilient infrastructure, including extreme weather or temperature shelters, emergency transportation or mobility options, and resilient community energy infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="H524B3040830B47E4B3E58CA404255925"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>to adopt and comply with standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></clause><clause id="H147033F99B404042A4E08C0E77C971BB"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the fire resistance of structures, including homes, businesses, public buildings, and critical facilities, as well as non-structures;</text></clause><clause id="H2C87DE2283254B5BADF4EFDB6047A344"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the seismic resilience of structures, including homes, businesses, public buildings, critical facilities, critical systems such as sewage and water, as well as non-structures; and</text></clause><clause id="H8849B68F08E94B61838B5E03A0C97E91"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>for other specific resilience activities determined appropriate by the Administrator. </text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1C36535344647759CC92F3CBFD65E1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H58A214E2569E40398324E4AC75995FDC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE800BB788F4F447CA09DF5D0159A1685"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specific technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide financial and non-financial technical assistance, including non-financial direct technical assistance for grant applications, to underserved communities and disadvantaged communities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H376A8D3BB13C4E38A87229490B2333B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h) by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD5E396EA432C4236ADFA4FDD29B9BA0C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA01F9449172E4DEDBB8F37A1E368C450"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Underserved communities and disadvantaged communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the President shall contribute 100 percent of the total cost of a mitigation activity carried out in a underserved community or disadvantaged community.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F06ADCCE0FB45D3A9ACF178EBF539EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H3FA0F760C6F6491AA3B2792D506A50B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>6 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>15 percent</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H424D5844BD314E66ADF9CE50094D9616"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>From such total amount made available from the Disaster Relief Fund, with respect to each major disaster, the President may set aside 2 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of the grants to be made pursuant to sections 403, 406, 407, 408, 410, 416, and 428 for the major disaster for community planning and capacity building assistance.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H569CACD3EAC048A398EA66D8CF25E693"><enum>6.</enum><header> Hazard mitigation plans</header><subsection id="HD5013EF71B1D48D3AEB46E7737AA59E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1CBA59960A1D47E6AA49F38302D68924"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2) before the semicolon insert the following: <quote>, including not conflicting with local plans, but integrating State, local, and tribal planning</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E79709292044A25B76E26B9C55F4067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H639D1167DCC64F4F9F4BF10AED6A9B8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A8BBEE358824A4580AAB6209584E011"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H12914C87155B4D97957E09CE50A1628B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB4311AA436754D289197A62B5D167671"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specifics in mitigation plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conjunction with subsection (a), not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, each State, Indian Tribe, and territory shall clarify and include in its mitigation plan—</text><subparagraph id="H0B7E141AD41E4230B3F104BBBE8B9A96"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the extent to which resilience is or will be incorporated into other mitigation planning processes, including capital improvement budgets and transportation planning processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42BBF08E4F3B4403803CDDB369632B85"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">goals and objectives related to increasing resilience over a 5-year period, including benchmarks for future work and an assessment of past progress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB25EECD7D33244EB9AA752BF4273BF98"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the building codes in existence at the time the plan is submitted and standards that are in use by the State for all manner of planning or development purposes and how the State has or will comply with the standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4BD2FAB2AAB43A79E6AA5065876A6C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of nature-based solutions, including urban tree canopy, increased green space, green roofing, functioning floodplains, creeks, streams, and wetlands, or other mitigation activities that conserve or restore natural features that can serve to abate or lessen the impacts of future major disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99751899F190460088B409B253CB828D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>integration of each local mitigation plan with the State, Indian Tribe, or territory plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC88793BB10A424E843171742D8E2E2B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disparate impacts on disadvantaged communities and how the State intends to address such disparities. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H426B0F954E8C42A19B0F197B7D8645F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), as redesignated, by inserting <quote>specific</quote> before <quote>mitigation</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCA67AFE087C4CB1BD34EA65629659B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0761B6FA29E34C1F81F3F2A27EB9B666" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H20C887F3D3C644EF92A09C9B35749E31"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue specific guidance on resilience goals and provide technical assistance for States, Indian Tribes, and territories to meet such goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC24267E09E74F18AFAB3EB71A9F6F27"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than every 5 years, the Administrator shall report the progress of meeting the goals under this section to the Committees on Homeland Security, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86C3C9B3125148769F2A222CF67EC534"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adequate staffing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall ensure that ample staff are available to develop the guidance and technical assistance under section 322(e)(4) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, including hazard mitigation planning staff and personnel with expertise in community planning, land use development, and consensus based codes and hazard-resistant designs at each regional office that specifically focus on providing financial and non-financial direct technical assistance to States, Indian Tribes, and territories.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9F5505094167478594585335DFC95BA1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Minimum standards for public and private structures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 323(a)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165a">42 U.S.C. 5165a(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6A4802C0C9FD4B7F84DCEA000A351EEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HD05DB3927DDD4EFDA723D39B630271C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>applicable</quote> the second time it appears and inserting <quote>the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4ACB13FE3D04732B1F0D653843134BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding before the period the following: <quote>, including hazard-resistant designs</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69B69EBB92044EC58070C96347FBF1B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text> by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H29AEFAA96F834D22ABE1874D851CEA7C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H5D290FFFCB0F4203967C1A47F4280F70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide guidance to implement the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H70C0EF746024491EB0ADF5A48D56F3A3"><enum>8.</enum><header>General federal assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(5) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170a">42 U.S.C. 5170a(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>building code</quote> and inserting <quote>the latest editions of relevant consensus-based building codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs,</quote>. </text></section><section id="H81880FDA16E2483680E9E59778FCFE00"><enum>9.</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(f) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5179c">42 U.S.C. 5179c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB1403C8A7B574A5D871E7423117888D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13) by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2370CE48DBD94553973248AADF767395"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14) by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8758124E3C0F488BB221A3C15743DB1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA9055AE84D384AB699C524FD46F55718" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0B3F3FBCF4EF4345B56EA279E9FA3D05"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, to comply with the standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H496E07BFE62847989BC383AEC8336A59"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist in the abatement of lead, mold, mildew, radon, asthma, and allergen triggers or other pollutants and hazardous materials directly caused by a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7849EAE4A4416096C7DBEDCDE70E07"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve air quality and mitigate against wildfire smoke or other air quality contaminants related to a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD294DC587F0247E6B8907515488F2399"><enum>(18)</enum><text>to the extent practicable to improve the fire resistance of structures, including homes and public buildings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74ECB62A346D463FBB77BCBDA9665F42"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the seismic resilience of structures, including homes, public buildings, non-profit facilities, and infrastructure, including roads, bridges, and critical systems such as sewage and water;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA45A7461E8114D9A9324100A9416B341" commented="no"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, for the replacement of mobile homes, travel trailers, and manufactured homes that serve as affected individuals’ primary residences that were damaged or destroyed by a major disaster or emergency, including by partnering with State and local housing agencies and non-profits to reduce the time or cost required to implement housing solutions after a major disaster or emergency as well as comply with the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D2F356C34045409E2E630014B8E8EE"><enum>(21)</enum><text>for other resilience activities as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H52168455DD0E40E891AB9BF5D1C392C1"><enum>10.</enum><header>Repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 406(c)(1)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFC54923518E84443ABED27BB396EADFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(D) by striking <quote>adopted building codes</quote> and inserting <quote>the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and any future higher standards for resistance to hazards of increasing severity</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H071E5E80DC0C4DC0B507FA7F12669741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>clause (ii) by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H424B1B4DF53A46EAB899CA78D77ABC61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (iii) by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D3A4DD320F949ACA7CB59190BBB51B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4D5D26F4F1474BEE9B914D0C65E11851" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HB4A8E4D2433A4C33BD9B87EB1969D1F6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to comply with the standards set forth in subsection 406(e)(1)(A) and any future higher standards for resistance to hazards of increasing severity;</text></clause><clause id="H30DEAF9C906048ABA3D71A40CF6C5176"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist in the abatement of lead, mold, mildew, radon, asthma, and allergen triggers or other pollutants and hazardous materials directly caused by a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator;</text></clause><clause id="HB19400048D9C4C35BBE1262DDA28D3C7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve air quality and mitigate against wildfire smoke or other air quality contaminants related to a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator;</text></clause><clause id="H7EDABD9EABB449A1B490A0881E42D3A8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the fire resistance of damaged facilities, including public facilities and private non-profit facilities;</text></clause><clause id="HD1C58F24EFBA41E7A8B1F6A0F7265424"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the seismic resistance of damaged facilities, including public facilities and private non-profit facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H11689989F7C840F080CCF9A10E111C92"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>for other resilience activities as determined by the Administrator.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HCDDE805175B743E585DAB973AC277FBE"><enum>11.</enum><header>Federal Assistance to individuals and households</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE2945B6D30624F0BB7F532D06B1B7C78" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HB0941B178A49446F9E4D61B959E7AA8C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Additional uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of assistance provided under this paragraph, may use such assistance—</text><paragraph id="H8C6951F3D76A45B7882C7A8892920A41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve compliance with the standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2276433FFFE4AAABD9860BE814651DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist in the abatement of lead, mold, mildew, radon, asthma, and allergen triggers, or other pollutants and hazardous directly caused by a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC2EC681859400FB4CB7EA844247F52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve air quality and mitigate against wildfire smoke or other air quality contaminants related to a major disaster or emergency, or as directed by the Administrator;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97B8C4D51F7242259392A107044929C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to improve the fire resistance of structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69E0B0E6BAA64902BA670411B3464472"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the seismic resilience of structures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB487635C10AA4590965D01D0B228DBB7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>for other resilience activities as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H837D150ADDD3430A872B0859D9A0C3C6"><enum>12.</enum><header>Report to congress and update of cost-effectiveness determination</header><subsection id="HCEDC90D9DF504505937CA98130457AEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit a report to the Committees on Homeland Security, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives regarding the challenges posed by the Agency’s requirements for determining the cost-effectiveness of mitigation activities and specifically how such requirements may disproportionately burden underserved or disadvantaged communities, or specific vulnerable populations within communities. </text></subsection><subsection id="H44E705BC24DB4C0EA5FE9FDF478D4B4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update of cost-Effectiveness determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act or as soon as practicable, the Administrator, to the extent practicable, shall update the requirements for determining cost-effectiveness, including selection of appropriate interest rates, based on the findings made under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

