<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5611A916B59C4483B8190EBDD05110B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8480 IH: Turn Off Federal Funding of Threatening Entities that Thwart American Prosperity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8480</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to certain entities subject to sanctions imposed by the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9CD1CFFDA80343A98FE23D8510A55C12" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD4793C16B31B47288D79E58B35D37DF2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Turn Off Federal Funding of Threatening Entities that Thwart American Prosperity Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Turn OFF THE TAP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA007A8C75DB34BC99806D4B17BE67719"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on providing Federal funds to certain entities subject to sanctions imposed by the United States</header> <subsection id="H8E15A0D0395B480CB775CFE6D12201C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal contracts</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not enter into, renew, or extend a contract with a covered entity.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8A7B17AB73424879ACAAA8762769B9E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of Federal funds</header><text>No amounts provided by the Federal Government to any entity may be used by that entity to purchase goods or services from, invest in, enter into contract with, or otherwise provide funding to a covered entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBED59935A4AE45B7A526B22B875C4BC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HA7BB56D4FD6A4E28890D531927E90A54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0BE2D93B76764298937092A42602AC32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An entity on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury (commonly referred to as the <quote>SDN list</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2976BB8E4D74424E84997929882683AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An entity on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List—</text> <clause id="HE4DDDA78E8774424B4D29FBE29380E19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>established pursuant to Executive Order 13959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance Communist Chinese military companies), as amended before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HE78CABD087DC47AB8F0DC0641C2224A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC5574FDF77443439A3D55FC325A82BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A Chinese military company on the list required by section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note). </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FD6C75DA0AA4323A696FFC7C0E8F0D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An entity on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FC7BC9BEAC14F1E83253A3C95BFB6D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An entity that produces equipment or services on the list of communications equipment and services that pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons maintained by the Federal Communications Commission under section 2 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A129AC12F1546978950FEFB8C5DE207"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any entity that is owned or controlled by, or under common ownership or control with, an entity described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F20AC9DEC4842D7957178F6D75485D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

