<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8EE7CD11085D450A8B5213A4C0EEF505" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>107 HR 6663 IH: Fleet Reserve Association 100th Anniversary Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6663</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint commemorative coins in recognition of the 100th anniversary of the Fleet Reserve Association.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD473B952337474BA43E29BB9E2ABFCE" style="OLC"><section id="H93AF49D5493C4EE0B3B38B127E285C10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fleet Reserve Association 100th Anniversary Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H47853E53EA23457F9C4865A346CA55D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5E4E07A2C61E4336B6000386ADE9FC1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On November 11, 1924, the Fleet Reserve Association (FRA) was founded by Navy Chief Yeoman George L. Carlin and chartered in 1924 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. FRA was born out of the need for an organization to protect the pay and benefits of enlisted Sea Service members and their families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD84EE0C3FC7E42939AD231458CF2E02A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Fleet Reserve Association (FRA) is a congressionally chartered, non-profit organization that represents the interests of the Sea Service community. Although the association was originally named for the Navy’s Fleet Reserve program, membership in FRA is open to all current and former sailors, marines, and Coast Guard personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7E1C1BBB0F4696BA40AF9E375A5450"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1930, FRA-proposed legislation was enacted that authorizes a death gratuity benefit of six months basic pay to the estates of recalled Fleet Reservists who subsequently die on active duty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H075D4DEC73C049F0B9407D350F2222DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 1932, FRA was successful in exempting enlisted personnel from Great Depression-era pay cuts that deferred pay for Federal employees by 8 to 20 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H580E59B9E507496582F8F5B843380D99"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 1934, FRA regained two-thirds of the 15 percent pay cut authorized in the Economy Act of 1933. The remaining 5 percent was restored in 1935.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DC17A4F829948FEAB475E13BFF95DCD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1935, FRA was successful in obtaining eligibility for Navy retirees and Fleet Reservists to receive emergency care in veterans’ hospitals in areas where military facilities were not available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC664B1ED12D0486B8A7AA837FAA201B1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1937, FRA helped advance legislation that authorized commissary privileges for military widows.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29BE491FA3194AC0BD8210F0371A09F2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 1946, FRA was successful in establishing equity in disability compensation for disabled peacetime veterans with their wartime counterparts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED4D0EFC31EE4A868CBEE3B1337A80C6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 1950, FRA first proposed legislation to provide a survivor benefit program as part of the military retirement system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB69B7D9C9764FD680A97429BB03A07E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 1972, FRA played a major role in the enactment of the Widow’s Equity bill, the precursor of today’s Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP) and FRA sponsored the Navy’s first Sailors of the Year competition, a tradition that continues today.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8369D54411454125A714B4CBFE5E4519"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1985, FRA became a founding member of The Military Coalition when laws threatened to significantly cut military retired pay. The FRA is one of 12 military and veterans organizations that banded together to reverse the potential loss of 22.5 percent in cost-of-living adjustments (COLA) over a seven-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H327C6F9804AA436C92831FA14DC7AEBD"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1986, FRA played a key role in restoring full cost-of-living adjustments (COLA) for military retirees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A9443B2B8F4C74A5BCCBBA0A2FC95D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In 1996, FRA became federally chartered as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/201">Public Law 104–201</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE9797BD6D949249E5234E9A185F472"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2002, the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/314">Public Law 107–314</external-xref>) authorized combat-related special compensation (CRSC) for disabled uniformed services retirees wounded in combat, which FRA acknowledged as a significant first step toward full concurrent receipt of military retired pay and Department of Veterans Affairs disability compensation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D67D47E824946F9B3A37127CB171277"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In 2009, the FRA Education Foundation was launched in conjunction with FRA’s 85th anniversary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD190FA08E7CE4ED5BC9A19DC8D74A1FA"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2013, FRA successfully defeated efforts to reduce future cost-of-living adjustments (COLA) for military retirees by blocking implementation of the chained consumer price index (CPI) in lieu of the current consumer price index (CPI).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75702D3E50D940A2B38B56080EB04CDF"><enum>(17)</enum><text>November 11, 2024, will mark the 100th anniversary of the Fleet Reserve Association.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD980058042074210BA8AC76BB6A8AAF7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header><subsection id="H739F4E7C05CE480EB21B233464F4B9EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text>In recognition and celebration of the 100th anniversary of the Fleet Reserve Association, the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue the following coins:</text><paragraph id="H55E290E4E1E44FAFB781A034AF8DEB93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>$5 gold coins</header><text>Not more than 50,000 $5 coins, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="HEB89023DE14B49049E815AFEB14E4E28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 8.359 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA546847D72B84CE18F44DCA137C2A1EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 0.850 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3310004B335E456F97A71418388BB1DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent gold.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DBABC3A75F54A6183F7B9DC5CFE4931"><enum>(2)</enum><header>$1 silver coins</header><text>Not more than 400,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8B35BCC019E243BA809B66841C4C86E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AD5828D2BAE4F9FAFECA66780D59FA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC00CDAC7EE948FAA0F97BC64A20B93A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent silver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBED7FC51DB04F8DA3B2BD886744E954"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Half-dollar clad coins</header><text>Not more than 750,000 half-dollar coins which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9827783FC93F408AAE6F53A012913696"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 11.34 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE270C4A45A3649CD96D7876195A616EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.205 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68394F96BCC84D7D8D5163949E7FC40E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be minted to the specifications for half-dollar coins contained in section 5112(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H007C2CE47B8E45A79F95E8DC5E5DE2F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3AD3C6CEE70242478586669659D8ADA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC9FAFEEBCE0044E9B6FB4D03F4CFD976"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of coins</header><subsection id="H4BE213210C414578A517837C01A1FD92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The design for the coins minted under this Act shall be emblematic of the Fleet Reserve Association.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBBB2E1D2B2E2463E83CBE063FA07F77A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designations and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act there shall be—</text><paragraph id="H361DA52267DF4E60A23054C75BF729EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a designation of the denomination of the coin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E99BF761A564853B9DDA6BC7CCD0149"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2024</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24260F0C50E9430DAF2E5F7A7E5DF319"><enum>(3)</enum><text>FRA’s motto: <quote>Loyalty, Protection, and Service</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H074B601B3ADD44FDA673A2A5EC913C91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4AE8F64E95746FCAACADE425F373CBC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The design for the coins minted under this Act shall be—</text><paragraph id="HD518A7ECA792410AA59B78C793F2B3F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selected by the Secretary after consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="H3A635E361694419AA1DB296005CF7D42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commission of Fine Arts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85BB9C8DE46F428681E8F84893B86CE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Board of Directors of the Fleet Reserve Association, as defined in the constitution and bylaws of the Fleet Reserve Association; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D36A33826F84FF4AFD5E26E28BA2A54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Commemorative Coin Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2399C5D56CCE46A3A479BE9B714E2BFB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header><subsection id="H431674E83742452FAA288290A4945318"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9995E1DF37A9412DA3DC9D58B961BEE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins minted under this Act only during the 1-year period beginning on January 1, 2024.</text></subsection></section><section id="H86209A4D51564F5DA1962BB131F29343"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header><subsection id="H4D1BF1EC057E4845ADDAD5303C3EBF48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price based upon the sum of—</text><paragraph id="HF95C69E7AEE94AE0A3DF534266102E70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC5B74B9131D41A38A77704ED2EED9D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCE009A92518434D82F56CA679159194"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1108E56556344A5A88B6C4D4FBD04EC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1125A1682045478DB42DA607DA1E89B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header><paragraph id="H186680BA7F064A79A442265A2599A7EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of such coins.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H238B352042F1482CB8931DC6AA12D260"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H69CCC7B13D184ED4AF83F3E28B58D61E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header><subsection id="HBA73F4677F9E49A1B08031EB3C580EED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins minted under this Act shall include a surcharge as follows:</text><paragraph id="H52FD40AB6C9044AE8C1F2E20563EB980"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A surcharge of $35 per coin for the $5 coin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB860A699577841078F70B844CED4BA89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A surcharge of $10 per coin for the $1 coin described under section 3(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AABD1FD89B742FF925A0E2B61BAA2B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A surcharge of $5 per coin for the half-dollar coin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD57635561A4144F980825A25B60A4AC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be promptly paid by the Secretary to the Fleet Reserve Association for costs related to—</text><paragraph id="HE2302AE3283448099BD08AF71C041635"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting the importance of and caring for those who have served in uniform, ensuring they receive proper health care and disability benefits earned through military service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC2375E9D7A414585BA1860D100FF4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promoting the importance of, and caring for, those who are still serving in the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC54FFA7660D43548F3E8B7490570FEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promoting the importance of maintaining the patriotic values, morals, culture, and citizenship of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EE00C9B53E944478B72E2F6A3D7CBFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promoting the importance of maintaining strong families, assistance for at-risk children, and activities that promote their healthy and wholesome development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A8A4D54FF5648318BDD6AC78AE971A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act). The Secretary of the Treasury may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H06987575B60A4CA585F749A38B41E1B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The recipient described under subsection (b) shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HAA3E4DAC6BC243D08402F47957C5DCB4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H4AA72A8566D34B96B339E0ACF0E7064A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the United States Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE53095162AB341AEB2477A4C895F628F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funds, including applicable surcharges, are disbursed to the recipient designated in section 7 until the total cost of designing and issuing all of the coins authorized by this Act (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping) is recovered by the United States Treasury, consistent with sections 5112(m) and 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

