<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HA9C83E4374D6441BA8F69450F89099E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1437 RH: Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 224</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1437</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–304]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210226">February 26, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 26, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 to direct the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to provide comprehensive and regularly updated Federal precipitation information, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H5309ABF3AF104B0BB8382C68C246DC70"><section id="HD94F6441D4F340EAB067F36D31D4FA2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRECIP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H78DA2A6263D247EBBD1254DD761C042B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of <enum-in-header>2017</enum-in-header></header><subsection id="H837150520EE54CD897E5B0D80ABE7336"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8521">15 U.S.C. 8521</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7A29C60F3FC44E3DBEAAB522E29AB6A5" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><title id="H01799784C5D04A3A856DDFF734DB3CEF"><enum>VI</enum><header>Improving Federal Precipitation Information</header><section id="H3CD8B749A76C4A998D55F8AE29AE00B2"><enum>601.</enum><header>Study on Precipitation Estimation</header><subsection id="H58757BB00B264C418928C7E29C399FA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the PRECIP Act, the Administrator, in consultation with other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall seek to enter an agreement with the National Academies—</text><paragraph id="HC03F89840CB94C818C6DE01FA871A52C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct a study on the state of practice and research needs for precipitation estimation, including probable maximum precipitation estimation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0996B230EFE4AEF89C2DDEFF698B647"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit, not later than 24 months after the date on which such agreement is finalized, to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and make publicly available on a website, a report on the results of the study under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48986542A65D415FAA804A89CED6B8E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="HCB2525EA5970479DBAD71CF0B0FD2513"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An examination of the current state of practice for precipitation estimation at scales appropriate for decisionmaker needs, and rationale for further evolution of this field.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9248FD0DE0D4BD0B524CC3E734C10F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of best practices for precipitation estimation that are based on the best-available science, include assumptions of non-stationarity, and can be utilized by the user community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H302EA0D5210A4B80BAE463B071DFD618"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A framework for—</text><subparagraph id="H17994D8460AD42DAA22C1014A252DEA0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of a National Guidance Document for estimating extreme precipitation in future conditions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFB2B08324F74536949E706862270A07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluation of the strengths and challenges of the full spectrum of approaches, including for probable maximum precipitation studies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE2EC9940C2348A39013101E39C2DA65"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of existing research needs in the field of precipitation estimation in order to modernize current methodologies and incorporate assumptions of non-stationarity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8729A5F934734422B928FBD823C3A1ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of in-situ, airborne, and space-based observation requirements, that could enhance precipitation estimation and development of models, including an examination of the use of geographic information systems and geospatial technology for integration, analysis, and visualization of precipitation data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84145BA856714BA18F8AD70CD6A7251B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A recommended plan for a Federal research and development program, including specifications for costs, timeframes, and responsible agencies for addressing identified research needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AB2811586674F42A009F171B08589EB"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the respective roles in precipitation estimation of various Federal agencies, academia, State, tribal, territorial, and local governments, and other public and private stakeholders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0A11F88C4A44254B37C36069018EB54"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for data management to promote long-term needs such as enabling retrospective analyses and data discoverability, interoperability, and reuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD976B9A821724AC588ACAFBA9C62547D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Recommendations for how data and services from the entire enterprise can be best leveraged by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16BA495F225477DA0410E4E388E5C01"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of non-Federal precipitation data, its accessibility by the Federal Government, and ways for National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to improve or expand such datasets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF33D4D702F490DBDF420B31141D523"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other topics as the Administrator or National Academies consider appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B38A5BEA475452DA730A609B0416346"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized $1,500,000 to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this study.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6A7FD1F0520049EDB206654B3E303C04"><enum>602.</enum><header>Improving Precipitation Frequency Estimates</header><subsection id="H936F5635F8FC4B1591783894B74EF35E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H8F5C97EB117E451FB3AA75C47628B804"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this title and not less frequently than every 5 years thereafter, update precipitation frequency estimates for the United States, such that each update includes at least one precipitation frequency atlas that incorporates assumptions of non-stationarity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD3FC174CCE46DEB8B7534375A84321"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop products targeted at users of this data in support of the mission of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11ED1E0360404DF8B599F5ADC1F82B24"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make publicly available, in a searchable, interoperable format, all precipitation frequency estimate studies developed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that the Administrator has the legal right to redistribute and that are deemed to be at an appropriate stage of development on an internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87CA938992C94C3F9D1709577FE2DC1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure all precipitation frequency estimate data, products, and supporting documentation and metadata are preserved, curated, and served by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20D9F73BBBC4425E9CF855ECDDD85E0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this section $3,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA5B2311CA5344F9BBDDBB7757B3AE323"><enum>603.</enum><header>Improving Probable Maximum Precipitation Estimates</header><subsection id="HA1BDD61001D94133A0EFF8C4E0EA448B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the National Academies makes public the report under section 601, the Administrator, in consideration of the report recommendations, shall consult with relevant partners, including users of the data, on the development of a plan to—</text><paragraph id="HBD9917952D8647DB9E56741228BC0FEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 6 years after the completion of the National Academies report under section 601 and not less than every 10 years thereafter, update probable maximum precipitation estimates for the United States, such that each update includes estimates that incorporate assumptions of non-stationarity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD89C75783F0A419EB173CF49D92E600C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate with partners to conduct research in the field of extreme precipitation estimation, in accordance with the research needs identified by the National Academies report under section 601;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8E65EDA1E44E4FB7C10856265E99EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make publicly available, in a searchable, interoperable format, all probable maximum precipitation studies developed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that the Administrator has the legal right to redistribute and deemed to be at an appropriate state of development on an internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96BBF36ADE404AD492A62C9A64659B48"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure all probable maximum precipitation estimate data, products, and supporting documentation and metadata developed by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration are preserved, curated, and served by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H424D7422F3D94C429F422D7DB21D9204"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Guidance Document for the Development of Probable Maximum Precipitation Estimates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in collaboration with Federal agencies, State, territorial, tribal and local governments, academia and other partners the Administrator deems appropriate, shall develop a National Guidance Document that—</text><paragraph id="H44056FD650C74D5CA0C397F86BEC32AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides best practices that can be followed by Federal and State regulatory agencies, private meteorological consultants, and other users that perform probable maximum precipitation studies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F516723EF22434997418CB4CB23B453"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considers the recommendations provided in the National Academies study in section 601;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0264A8F19CE549699BD9A9F3EF601EB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitates review of probable maximum precipitation studies by regulatory agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE22A3F9BD97D44CA8891793735F2BD55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides confidence in regional and site-specific probable maximum precipitation estimates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E718C189B84629870CE7E438BB20FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes such other topics as the Administrator deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4ADC78FE689247FEA0FBC17424F97E57" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the National Academies makes public the report under section 601, the Administrator shall make publicly available the National Guidance Document under subsection (b) on an internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D2F1E8AEBEE469BACB2F43ADA96FE9F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Administrator shall update the National Guidance Document not less than once every 10 years after the publication of the National Guidance Document under subsection (c) and publish such updates in accordance with such subsection. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA4380E99E3A14AFB8A0CD28F2E0AF408"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this section:</text><paragraph id="HBD3B0C314B2043ECA31C28D9F89ACF06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$13,000,000 for fiscal year 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H450CE2B17D80497797DF747ED3BDC31D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$14,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H763128AE5D184EB0A2D8A806C3EDF4D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$14,000,000 for fiscal year 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC21F3FF9E20406283F495756B48AABE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8987CBB645B4DFEB4C2C283B6F4AD51"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF34AF2B63B5F4BB29DB0AE7318716108"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H20F9846537BA4C64954FF99D70C2D4C8" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>604.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> In this title:</text><paragraph id="HFC30137682CD426C8F7F1633C527724D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H474B0E9BFB214178A61321FA47B81138"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Academies</header><text>The term <term>National Academies</term> means the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB40654CD8FF04561822959190EFF2D3B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Precipitation frequency atlas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>precipitation frequency atlas</quote> means a geographical atlas, such as the NOAA Atlas 14, that contains precipitation frequency estimates for the United States with associated lower and upper bounds of a determined confidence interval and supplementary information on temporal distribution of heavy precipitation, analysis of seasonality, and trends in annual maximum series data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A3B9692F654297A5939AEB262F9780" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Precipitation frequency estimate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>precipitation frequency estimate</term> means the magnitude associated with specific average recurrence interval or annual exceedance probability for a given duration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC923C20A769B4FE0A4761405C38E8EB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States</term> means, collectively, each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBDF5B0EC8A9F4F67AD10954E8E174746"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1(b) of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref> note) is amended in the table of contents by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H88F91578B68F41458E88049D1E4C8EBD" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><toc-entry level="title">TITLE VI—IMPROVING FEDERAL PRECIPITATION INFORMATION </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3CD8B749A76C4A998D55F8AE29AE00B2" level="section">Sec. 601. Study on precipitation estimation. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6A7FD1F0520049EDB206654B3E303C04" level="section">Sec. 602. Improving precipitation frequency estimates. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA5B2311CA5344F9BBDDBB7757B3AE323" level="section">Sec. 603. Improving probable maximum precipitation estimates. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 604. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

