<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A0549858C8F41F883081A2EA9E0C3C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8966 IH: Simplify Timelines and Assure Regulatory Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8966</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220922">September 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify regulatory certainty, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA09B4B62D5C849F3B81745216F62E90C" style="OLC"><section id="H56A3B8CB58AB4471B79867B66CBFD608" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Simplify Timelines and Assure Regulatory Transparency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>START Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB31DFD3793894612B4AD8DF01182EE30" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of NEPA regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The revisions to the Code of Federal Regulations made pursuant to the final rule of the Council on Environmental Quality titled <quote>Update to the Regulations Implementing the Procedural Provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act</quote> and published on July 16, 2020 (85 Fed. Reg. 43304), shall have the same force and effect of law as if enacted by an Act of Congress.</text></section><section id="H07F97F0B10554B1FB420413D526456BE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Providing regulatory certainty under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</header><subsection id="H2444076D28FD47FAB97EFEF1D879F27D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waters of the United States</header><text>The definitions of the term <term>waters of the United States</term> and the other terms defined in section 328.3 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on January 1, 2021), are enacted into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C0600F3D725487DB826DBAB579716C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Codification of section 401 certification rule</header><text>The final rule of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Clean Water Act Section 401 Certification Rule</quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 42210 (July 13, 2020)) is enacted into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7085F1EB8E9A44D5B40F9EFE7BFA49A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Codification of Nationwide Permits</header><text>The Nationwide Permits issued, reissued, or modified, as applicable, in the following final rules of the Corps of Engineers are enacted into law:</text><paragraph id="H334E282968B8426CB2526FF1B8F15B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The final rule of the Corps of Engineers entitled <quote>Reissuance and Modification of Nationwide Permits</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 2744 (January 13, 2021)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA929BA0D1DE844D4AF6208050B34D1E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The final rule of the Corps of Engineers entitled <quote>Reissuance and Modification of Nationwide Permits</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 73522 (December 27, 2021)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H007D2025BE3E4CE482139DE6DBE9BE58"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National pollutant discharge elimination system</header><text>Section 402(b)(1)(B) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>five years</quote> and inserting <quote>10 years</quote>. </text></subsection></section><section id="H3C20B63E6BF348F184915AFEC6928919"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of social cost of greenhouse gas estimates raising gasoline prices</header><subsection id="HDC88ADDFDD0C469DB9A1CE42BF021C64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In promulgating regulations, issuing guidance, or taking any agency action (as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) relating to the social cost of greenhouse gases, no Federal agency shall adopt or otherwise use any estimates for the social cost of greenhouse gases that may raise gasoline prices, as determined through a review by the Energy Information Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE861566D8BF4051B3F98098755FB9BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The estimates referred to in subsection (a) include the interim estimates in the document of the Interagency Working Group on the Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote> and dated February 2021.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9C2FEFA2F6804E2E8AC66DD2F67712DE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expediting permitting and review processes</header><subsection id="H1C2F4B606ADC47F4B538682FD2814162"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H59B82F1A7EC34142930E6F636ACB9007"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The term <term>authorization</term> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, or other administrative decision issued by a Federal department or agency that is required or authorized under Federal law in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of an energy project, including any authorization described in section 41001(3) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m">42 U.S.C. 4370m(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C16E78AB0C4D93986D3972247496A2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy project</header><text>The term <term>energy project</term> means any project involving the exploration, development, production, transportation, combustion, transmission, or distribution of an energy resource or electricity for which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H449679106AF3462D827794F9F55F7832"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an authorization is required under a Federal law other than the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H02FBF0DA031E4738876FB327528169F3"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC265BD7BE428470CA167CEC5489B73CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the head of the lead agency has determined that an environmental impact statement is required; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H97B75EC12CC4466B9663691B32C51EBB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the head of the lead agency has determined that an environmental assessment is required, and the project sponsor requests that the project be treated as an energy project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD01D228BD840C0A10765403DA1036F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental impact statement</header><text>The term <term>environmental impact statement</term> means the detailed statement of environmental impacts required to be prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7630284B34374907AAC53082CADCBA4A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental review and authorization process</header><text>The term <term>environmental review and authorization process</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H345F4E5F99E543198C3E93721DEE0A72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the process for preparing for an energy project an environmental impact statement, environmental assessment, categorical exclusion, or other document prepared under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H662B6BFFCF2A4547B9063BCF145CFDCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion of any authorization decision required for an energy project under any Federal law other than the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC8288833F9746A791A27118481A179D" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text>The term <term>lead agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2BC98C90852C45AA959F92D84FFB7F9A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD57A957AB9AD45C980BA1BF54702619A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB37566F2CC894B2394413D6CB5AB2FF1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA8617B2E39064B5B95B07AE011142CBE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6165E6583218429E9AEABC1A731752D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Nuclear Regulatory Commission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1DEF163F54764EBB8E350E7EB1C8BE25"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other appropriate Federal agency, as applicable, that may be responsible for navigating the energy project through the environmental review and authorization process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FADF331A4EC46678E40173D0480EDF6" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Project sponsor</header><text>The term <term>project sponsor</term> means an agency or other entity, including any private or public-private entity, that seeks approval from a lead agency for an energy project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80DCF2F72843480E9179091C486BC8BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timely authorizations for energy projects</header><paragraph id="H47D682B46CE44A71A9E28A30B40BFEC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H031D7FBB659F4CF0A723C9AA01987358"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), all authorization decisions necessary for the construction of an energy project shall be completed by not later than 90 days after the date of the issuance of a record of decision for the energy project by the lead agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6427E55D070E494E8A45F0E53DAC4512"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detail</header><text>The final environmental impact statement for an energy project shall include an adequate level of detail to inform decisions necessary for the role of any Federal agency involved in the environmental review and authorization process for the energy project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H680839DEAA564D49855D1175525129FA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension of deadline</header><text>The head of a lead agency may extend the deadline under subparagraph (A) if—</text><clause id="HA1FB56D3EE754B689A228D0F5D4DA5E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal law prohibits the lead agency or another agency from issuing an approval or permit within the period described in that subparagraph;</text></clause><clause id="HE86097A4E9C74972971FDEA66A39C342"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the project sponsor requests that the permit or approval follow a different timeline; or</text></clause><clause id="HF7E92884EEDF49EE9F641E02BA328BBA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an extension would facilitate completion of the environmental review and authorization process of the energy project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CBB04DED3464CAD83C24294F63FB26A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy project schedule</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable and consistent with applicable Federal law, for an energy project, the lead agency shall develop, in concurrence with the project sponsor, a schedule for the energy project that is consistent with a time period of not more than 2 years for the completion of the environmental review and authorization process for an energy project, as measured from, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="HD25E66C5E5E349FB8F0C21F58AF7493C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date of publication of a notice of intent to prepare an environmental impact statement to the record of decision; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78CD7F39D7B245EE88E9BE6D34D68B54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the head of the lead agency determines that an environmental assessment is required to a finding of no significant impact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D0EE22509E4451BE542F2CE192EF10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Length of environmental impact statement</header><subparagraph id="H92E57F25AE6D453194DDAF20E2948505"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), to the maximum extent practicable, the text of the items described in paragraphs (4) through (6) of section 1502.10(a) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), of an environmental impact statement for an energy project shall be 200 pages or fewer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13566E33EED74866BD8A820CDE96425F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The text referred to in subparagraph (A) of an environmental impact statement for an energy project may exceed 200 pages if the lead agency establishes a new page limit for the environmental impact statement for that energy project. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3D3D28DF0774E51B1B92659110D97C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline for filing energy-Related causes of action</header><paragraph id="HBC2122EED06D45B6A50F11CF56C01F83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H62EBB5857D1B469BA99C3E2DCC670A76"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agency action</header><text>The term <term>agency action</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDD3C8B7792847BDB4366E382A27E093"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Energy-related cause of action</header><text>The term <term>energy-related cause of action</term> means a cause of action that—</text><clause id="H39507F336FB94A66A8BB9DA686D4B87C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is filed on or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HD71EB5436AF248E9A29D0EFFD782AFA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seeks judicial review of a final agency action to issue a permit, license, or other form of agency permission for an energy project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0B978560D7F479385CFD29AADC6BD1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for filing</header><subparagraph id="H9D5500167D8747C198795CFD64E69ED4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, an energy-related cause of action shall be filed by—</text><clause id="H086347C478184BC980A1C7FF5B96460B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of publication of the applicable final agency action; or</text></clause><clause id="HD6612EC0CF6341769E380A0FE33C3D87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if another Federal law provides for an earlier deadline than the deadline described in clause (i), the earlier deadline.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1314D5F59730494C8FBBEEE48C414A60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An energy-related cause of action that is not filed within the applicable time period described in subparagraph (A) shall be barred. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A3C2B8C62614092B6B1B5F63B4C3446"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of categorical exclusions for energy projects</header><text>In carrying out requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) for an energy project, a Federal agency may use categorical exclusions designated under that Act in the implementing regulations of any other agency, subject to the conditions that—</text><paragraph id="HCC4AF8AA08E74CBABFD15BB2F5A3B8DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agency makes a determination, in consultation with the lead agency, that the categorical exclusion applies to the energy project;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86730943C2F946549B66170BBB489F59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the energy project satisfies the conditions for a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H457B8E11DA424278BD9B9D2BC9C4FE5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of the categorical exclusion does not otherwise conflict with the implementing regulations of the agency, except any list of the agency that designates categorical exclusions. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB5B0112AFBD94897B5EE320AD7C406AE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Fracturing authority within States</header><subsection id="HD1FD8602B0FD41B18174F1DD0E471B22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of Federal land</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HE993861AB02C4F0C942F28F7249680D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public lands (as defined in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9703146CA494454DA954ADA20DF9E7E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>National Forest System land;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC6CEB2FAF724F7FB3487708845637F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Reclamation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H516DC5E53E0548CD97A6F3BEE67DF5BD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>land under the jurisdiction of the Corps of Engineers. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DE37553448D4D2A83306F700D16705F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State authority</header><paragraph id="HDC1A92C598DA4F51B10FD9834EEDA8E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State shall have the sole authority to promulgate or enforce any regulation, guidance, or permit requirement regarding the treatment of a well by the application of fluids under pressure to which propping agents may be added for the expressly designed purpose of initiating or propagating fractures in a target geologic formation in order to enhance production of oil, natural gas, or geothermal production activities on or under any land within the boundaries of the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H166EDFE8DB1E4DD6A327643192C74FD2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The treatment of a well by the application of fluids under pressure to which propping agents may be added for the expressly designed purpose of initiating or propagating fractures in a target geologic formation in order to enhance production of oil, natural gas, or geothermal production activities on Federal land shall be subject to the law of the State in which the land is located. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H831C4543AFB94D5497F6537EDA271897"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal land freedom</header><subsection id="HFED047C67044498295C608295A35B09D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H95352F5A176247A7BA3D222FE1C66D61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Available federal land</header><text>The term <term>available Federal land</term> means any Federal land that, as of May 31, 2013—</text><subparagraph id="HF864528384EE497291509597BC8A7CBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located within the boundaries of a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E696EF7E0AB4684B8E8514F2D36A869"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not held by the United States in trust for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33B701D1C7DB49239D92F7D9FD888C64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not a unit of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E717F5328064674865F0D7D343989CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7308B8E722FB4F83BD90D95404849A30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is not a congressionally designated wilderness area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H47DB5D263BBD47C1B7C2B7DD16421336"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B9B2D76A5204BBC9092E67DD9E91F80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE6FD6697264422AB273FB103D23FCA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB875696683D94DFFBA3102D71F35470C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State leasing, permitting, and regulatory program</header><text>The term <term>State leasing, permitting, and regulatory program</term> means a program established pursuant to State law that regulates the exploration and development of oil, natural gas, and other forms of energy on land located in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACEB9F657B4C4CC887D34784FE2C07A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State control of energy development and production on all available federal land</header><paragraph id="HE025870545664FDBA81496B34BD461A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State leasing, permitting, and regulatory programs</header><text>Any State that has established a State leasing, permitting, and regulatory program may—</text><subparagraph id="H9650C2525A574A87955218ABB19335A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, and Energy a declaration that a State leasing, permitting, and regulatory program has been established or amended; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H761C8C62D6204E77BF126023A482AA12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to transfer responsibility for leasing, permitting, and regulating oil, natural gas, and other forms of energy development from the Federal Government to the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6525590ADF945F0835C00E79E581B70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State action authorized</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on submission of a declaration under paragraph (1)(A), the State submitting the declaration may lease, permit, and regulate the exploration and development of oil, natural gas, and other forms of energy on Federal land located in the State in lieu of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA09CCA228404C3694E38C4A2076A9E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of State action</header><text>Any action by a State to lease, permit, or regulate the exploration and development of oil, natural gas, and other forms of energy pursuant to paragraph (2) shall not be subject to, or considered a Federal action, Federal permit, or Federal license under—</text><subparagraph id="H62D6104DF13E465A9B2C2F9C95D6C684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the ‘‘Administrative Procedure Act’’);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DCF6C2501EE437E83194D9603A3198A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEED01A7766BD4035B82B9383C8418B95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0948AD8AECFC4903B1827FA267CDF65C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BC124BECD2644ED8025A3D5A2808B11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on Federal revenues</header><paragraph id="H7121B56BA9E147FFB9EEBB08DB7BC50B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any lease or permit issued by a State pursuant to subsection (b) shall include provisions for the collection of royalties or other revenues in an amount equal to the amount of royalties or revenues that would have been collected if the lease or permit had been issued by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A5BDCEC0EF2422D80B71D5E6FF41124"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disposition of revenues</header><text>Any revenues collected by a State from leasing or permitting on Federal land pursuant to subsection (b) shall be deposited in the same Federal account in which the revenues would have been deposited if the lease or permit had been issued by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53FD76ED67D84D71AEE6C37E6F24EEBA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect on State processing fees</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits a State from collecting and retaining a fee from an applicant to cover the administrative costs of processing an application for a lease or permit.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H13A0DB65DFF049ECAC982904427EBE0B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Faster project consultation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(b)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HADB4F3A2897A477DA8CD2842CDAD5796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>90-day</quote> and inserting <quote>60-day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HD211C343F71942CD81F9E14D3DC74F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H654CB04C2AD04BAEA72A38881EEBE4EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4BA8C78C07F249DC954D28328CB826AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>90 days</quote> and inserting <quote>60 days</quote>; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3BE04B644CEF4396904E2B4B0D937B54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>90th day</quote> and inserting <quote>60th day</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H18413C1EA22D4F92949F88577C90DA74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>150th day</quote> and inserting <quote>100th day</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4BAB0A81F3A2442FA42269486C1F756E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>150 or more</quote> and inserting <quote>100 or more</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H19482F3F9C634FA0A891433C7B358CAF"><enum>9.</enum><header>New source review permitting</header><subsection id="H9A45D0AD0A084307923B1547F7E908BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of definition of a modification for emission rate increases, pollution control, efficiency, safety, and reliability projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA25B99F4849145AFAA0F2E326697A98F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(A)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote> before <quote>The term</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35F27D52A8BC4B9EA3925FB0ED79438B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a change increases the amount of any air pollutant emitted by such source only if the maximum hourly emission rate of an air pollutant that is achievable by such source after the change is higher than the maximum hourly emission rate of such air pollutant that was achievable by such source during any hour in the 10-year period immediately preceding the change</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51BA77C75504C708AF01DEB2C054C63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD24B12A0D4F4E378E8487B5D254A9A7" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HBFF2B78748014F98842A63E048F6C4EF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the term <quote>modification</quote> does not include a change at a stationary source that is designed—</text><clause id="HE439FA99A5534B16B2581EC869B325A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to reduce the amount of any air pollutant emitted by the source per unit of production; or</text></clause><clause id="H178AABD5344C48E086F59A7D6F708AB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to restore, maintain, or improve the reliability of operations at, or the safety of, the source,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">except, with respect to either clause (i) or (ii), when the change would be a modification as defined in subparagraph (A) and the Administrator determines that the increase in the maximum achievable hourly emission rate of a pollutant from such change would cause an adverse effect on human health or the environment.</continuation-text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF34F387ABFC946C995D75065EB97B8F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of definition of construction for prevention of significant deterioration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (C) of section 169(2) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7479">42 U.S.C. 7479(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7865F9F76F2D4531A2FADA24CDB85F04" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H1ECF837FCEB645AABC4781748EB0D673"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>construction</term>, when used in connection with a major emitting facility, includes a modification (as defined in section 111(a)) at such facility, except that for purposes of this subparagraph a modification does not include a change at a major emitting facility that does not result in a significant emissions increase, or a significant net emissions increase, in annual actual emissions at such facility.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H77393DADF736487D86329F343969673D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of definition of modifications and modified for nonattainment areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of section 171 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7501">42 U.S.C. 7501</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C22D0CD45C44CD19D8CEB917C2F3C2B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0F9B9D9EBF45436BAF47750904B366DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>modifications</term> and <term>modified</term> mean a modification as defined in section 111(a)(4), except that such terms do not include a change at a major emitting facility that does not result in a significant emissions increase, or a significant net emissions increase, in annual actual emissions at such facility.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8CEA61010B234AB481D69E2311CA47B9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to treat any change as a modification for purposes of any provision of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>) if such change would not have been so treated as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H6CFA2CFE2D7F4357B37A70EADD1576D9"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prohibition on retroactive permit vetoes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H02FCCAF83CC145E5B3F6013B7B850460" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="HABE2868590E44E7C9702B63192034BF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority of EPA Administrator</header><paragraph id="HDFAA0DBD61B14403980D696172B9975A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Possible prohibition of specification</header><text>Until such time as the Secretary has issued a permit under this section, the Administrator may prohibit the specification (including the withdrawal of specification) of any defined area as a disposal site, and the Administrator may deny or restrict the use of any defined area for specification (including the withdrawal of specification) as a disposal site, whenever the Administrator determines, after notice and opportunity for public hearings, that the discharge of such materials into such area will have an unacceptable adverse effect on municipal water supplies, shellfish beds and fishery areas (including spawning and breeding areas), wildlife, or recreational areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD990AF04EEAF4677A0B2F339C6BBFDDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>Before making a determination under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8712CF58992401B91A77EDBAEFDE380" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Written findings required</header><text>The Administrator shall set forth in writing and make public the findings and reasons of the Administrator for making any determination under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H06010F18696A45C1B6C778C2E506D31C"><enum>11.</enum><header>Policy review under the Clean Air Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 309 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7609">42 U.S.C. 7609</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71792E78B6874E59B9E013F36D30717E"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H46B478FC904A49C48C01F213F662EE15"><enum>309.</enum><header>Policy review</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HBF7A96F915CC4F4BB3E6633265BA86AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Environmental impact of proposed legislation</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H2B5ABC7AC98C489088205B2300EAE063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall review, and comment in writing, on the environmental impact of any matter relating to the duties and responsibilities granted to the authority of the Administrator pursuant to this Act or any other law contained in any legislation proposed by a Federal department.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H5390C59577EB4789A732122A9B98B2D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publish</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A written comment referred to in paragraph (1) shall be made public at the conclusion of any review conducted under that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H63C314FB2A424F8A8D1EEB362251FE41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unsatisfactory legislation</header><text>In the event the Administrator determines that any legislation reviewed under subsection (a)(1) is unsatisfactory from the standpoint of public health, welfare, or environmental quality, the Administrator shall publish the determination of the Administrator and the matter shall be referred to the Council on Environmental Quality.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

