<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C3ACE9A2A1F4C5ABD870B8B92A474FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8525 IH: Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31C3408673844D76B615C2F3B53F162E" style="OLC"><section id="HD8FCCF533EB14A7DA3160F5797963188" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H47F8FA2BE204486582A7F957C0E3331B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 508 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/318">6 U.S.C. 318</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB309A4C9B39C4EEE8DE34557045D4D5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAAC2845608E476BAB017846187727CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H796FCBC4A907424AAF5482D818A09A70" style="OLC"><subsection id="H87FB8E43548A4645AD6E3C70F82C3E7B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee</header><paragraph id="H6FC1C0E41319436EB4579740F17306DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</short-title>, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish, as a subcommittee of the National Advisory Council, the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ED886B5FC4342AA809AC371F12DF3F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee shall be appointed by the Administrator, in consultation with members of the National Advisory Council and the White House Environmental Justice Advisory Council (or any relevant successor organization focused on environmental justice), and shall be composed of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7AD9B6D417024BC1B847008A84CC1B18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Individuals that have the requisite technical knowledge and expertise to address disaster equity and justice issues, including—</text><clause id="HBCF04601789947449F86038ADF60C94A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>emergency management and emergency response providers, including those with direct experience serving underrepresented and underserved communities; and</text></clause><clause id="H5D3B161799B44D9A8626145907221F0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal government officials, particularly officials from communities that are underrepresented and underserved, communities of color, and communities that have been disadvantaged by inequitable Federal disaster assistance in the past.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD064CEF865FD4F158131987E2FFCF3DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals who have the requisite technical or experiential knowledge and expertise to serve on the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee, including—</text><clause id="H6CF790DE075443E1B1FD799FD486103F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 1 academic expert who has studied equity implications of disaster response and recovery efforts; and</text></clause><clause id="H48CBB1E9FB2E4ED9BA278C70C7C51E38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 1 representative from each of the following:</text><subclause id="HD514326EEE4442B4A62987B9B636501F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A civil rights organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE1E58CC49CB1452793477B7D5EBCFDF6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A fair or affordable housing organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="HBAAB0F5E48EA44D9A1C36855E02424BF"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Tribal and Indigenous community rights organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="H624C700521BB455AA9D34197CACDFEA5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>An environmental justice organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC5A9F41D04E5419088808F310D719060"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A community-based and faith-based organization that aids in disaster recovery and response.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7ABE71BD60AD45D9AE7E48D23C978CA6"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>An equity, justice, bias, and non-discrimination training provider.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD0CE91FDA52402BBC8DB0A0D7BB58B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Representatives of other stakeholders and interested and affected parties as the Chair considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45745F263EA2421C9DC17FE26B99F015"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair of the subcommittee shall be the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EDE6EF8AB78465EBA21C8120B6689C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The initial meeting of the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee shall take place not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FFE75CFCA0949F0831DF2C1EC5B589B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation with nonmembers</header><text>The Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee shall consult with other relevant agencies and groups which are not represented on the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee to consider new and developing practices and methods that may be beneficial to ensure the equitable and just delivery of programs and aid through the preparedness, response, and recovery cycles to communities and individuals across the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AD914DC7644C788F8D2FE74F7FE95B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee shall develop recommendations, as appropriate, for improving equitable and just policy and program delivery before, during, and after disasters, including recommendations relating to the following topics: </text><subparagraph id="H91FB682B5F7D447DBD29B1D7C09FF65D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The accessibility, utilization, and receipt of Agency grants and assistance by underserved, under-resourced, and underrepresented populations and communities including—</text><clause id="HA918FE15B4544507B5770BE59DF32E38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subpopulations and communities of color;</text></clause><clause id="H19E61A8EFDB14396B9027A898158D909"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rural and remote communities;</text></clause><clause id="H279B404E73B5493092B7514FD3F15213"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>small communities;</text></clause><clause id="H498FC2C4E3E64FF5B8B20FCDCEC21489"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>low-capacity communities;</text></clause><clause id="HF721955F58F34891A5F13F68E7D3A704"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Tribal and Indigenous communities; and</text></clause><clause id="HF514FEF839784A9799532BA08595E79A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>environmental justice communities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C175AF549049F18091622E72EB0E20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Strategies and policy recommendations to address the inequitable delivery of disaster assistance, grant programs, technical assistance, and training.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B5FCE1DED01466B8B4A7BD3EBCEE88C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Effective strategies to prioritize and direct additional preparedness and mitigation funding to improve planning, preparedness, mitigation, and recovery outcomes as well as overall resilience in culturally, economically, and socially vulnerable communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEDD6587E3C047E08B8B085ACA478723"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The capability and capacity of the workforce of the Agency to deliver equitable and culturally competent assistance to underrepresented communities and the most effective training solutions to increase cultural and equity competencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABDF247700144C449C008E163FA5CC5D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The capacity and effectiveness of consultation from Tribal and Indigenous communities to the Agency and liaison roles in communicating and addressing needs of all Tribal and Indigenous communities and solutions to address existing deficiencies, including regionally specific recommendations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE626DF15D0843D8A6A25BF07B169656"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any gaps in current State emergency management resources and program delivery resulting in inequitable access to Agency resources across different States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98AB38A79F134BC58E6F2C3D28BCF5F1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Opportunities and strategies to ensure a portion of Federal contracting and subcontracting agreements are awarded equitably to minority-owned businesses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5368C17D171042FCAB80C34C144D77E3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Identification of opportunities to update and further integrate the National Risk Index into equity considerations across the Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E5DC617CCD245208BA443518EEE61BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Strategies to address any disparate impacts climate change will have on culturally, socially, economically vulnerable communities, with particular consideration given to hazard mitigation, preparedness, and planning resource delivery.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E30473B5FFA43BA977D55FF02F0B511"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementation of the Justice40 initiative across relevant Agency programs, as well as recommendations on the data utilized in the identification of eligible recipients of resources from such initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7587971CAD5E4593A8A376EFB51DDBA5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="H363BF7EA7981407EA911A718CB57369B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</short-title>, the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee shall submit a report to the National Advisory Council that—</text><clause id="H52D39714012642C899868B1E5AB7A61F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes the recommendations developed under paragraph (6);</text></clause><clause id="H8F1BCD10743C466CBF5D4098CD70DCF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specifies the time frames for implementing any such recommendations that do not require congressional action; and</text></clause><clause id="H54818462C5AC4FE88E9704DD80124959"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identifies any such recommendations that do require congressional action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3CDA4255B2E4E138618DE3ECD6C5CD9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving the report under subparagraph (A), the National Advisory Council shall begin a review of such report. The National Advisory Council may ask for additional clarification, changes, or other information from the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee to assist in the approval of such report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H787001C4F6614E87BA6D00D591D76DEB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon approval of the report of the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee under subparagraph (B), the National Advisory Council shall submit such report to—</text><clause id="HE51814B8252143D9933A7C0CF276CB97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator;</text></clause><clause id="H9D9D22F1599849B69759811FE34B4361"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the heads of other Federal agencies with a role in disaster response and recovery, including the Department of Housing and Urban Development, Environmental Protection Agency, Department of Transportation, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, Small Business Administration, Economic Development Administration, United States Coast Guard, National Guard, and Department of Homeland Security;</text></clause><clause id="H875E2D5779B9448E85FDFD2A9F3F7E66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="H2E0CD6DD41F04C67B21B2AE48A692018"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA64D9E97E3A94A6E988021914158C4FD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Interim updates and oversight</header><text>After the submission of the report by the National Advisory Council under paragraph (7), the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDCB38FD12FA5421A8B2D406C3B3F6C90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide annual updates to the congressional committees referred to in clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (7)(C) regarding the status of the implementation of the recommendations contained in such report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H858BB9B79AAE435EB09D5968C4B2C975"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate the implementation of such recommendations, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3584978CC0B94719A0C004D0AE47A038"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HF3F281DF60ED45C9A5016DB997C595F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC969664D8E26464EAE03C38254B9E89D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tribal and Indigenous community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Tribal and Indigenous community</quote> means a population of people who are members of—</text><clause id="HABB28B28E05947B9B0239B819D71238D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a federally recognized Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="HF60F717F4BD94E1992A2F79B0FF74327"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State-recognized Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="HC0EE5DFFE8A24D658087736E5C46A6D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization; or</text></clause><clause id="HE247EFCCF81D41E3AE56910C01923722"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other community of Indigenous people located in a State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5354386EAD6349BC8432F0A08F4FC4E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <quote>Tribal government</quote> means the governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

