<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDF1E6341674496C9D85226EBE3F183D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8852 IH: End Veteran Hunger Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8852</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on food insecurity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0CD4013531754D34B2F5835CC89B9B92" style="OLC"><section id="H971D9FDEA0B84D64847B5D0562394C35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Veteran Hunger Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HAA2A0532CCE84FBBA58B104E14390C7D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program on food insecurity</header><subsection id="HF91FFE9ABFED411F9C81F71BF8533FC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Director of the National Nutrition and Food Services Office, shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H1155511B05CE43F3BFCF400E61515150"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of supporting partnerships that address food insecurity among veterans and family members of veterans, including veterans who receive services through Vet Centers or other facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs as determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H509047E7463A4AA290B65757D3ECCB87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of supporting partnerships that address food insecurity among veterans who have recently transitioned from serving as members of the Armed Forces to civilian life, and the family members of such members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H634E1E0112584696A683B1B0509B1DBB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution and duration of grants</header><paragraph id="H1727360F43CA4D9D94E374C75C700CEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award at least five grants under subsection (a)(1) to eligible entities that principally serve Native Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6E54AE5CC664C1C9329DD2584F13EC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award at least one grant under subsection (a)(2) in five different geographic areas that the Secretary determines have a high rate of individuals described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54963F59EF1C48468B0A36F98FEBB554"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant awarded to an eligible entity under this section shall be for a period of two years, but the Secretary may renew the grant for additional periods, subject to subsection (h).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C66DF64F61A4CE5A7FEF0602140FA35" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H80B94707B05545A3AE49E7AB85706172"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall be used to carry out either or both of the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="HC7E6C410C26F4370A372B5493C98BA90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing access to, and enrollment in, Federal assistance programs, including the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>), the low-income home energy assistance program established under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8621">42 U.S.C. 8621 et seq.</external-xref>), and any other assistance program that the Secretary determines advisable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61C6F5A67627441CA948EB9247EBE3D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Increasing participation in nutrition counseling programs and providing educational materials and counseling to veterans, and family members of veterans, to address food insecurity and healthy diets among those individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC08348F63BAB487CA5C90B3D8953CCD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional use</header><text>In addition to being used to carry out either or both of the activities specified in paragraph (1), any grant awarded under this section may be used to provide direct food assistance to covered individuals, or otherwise to provide assistance to covered individuals in accessing food.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AE41A41874F4226B81FF64D0E0DFA4D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF69AA0DAB2FC416FB132A77EFFEA8618" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection of recipients</header><text>The Secretary shall select eligible entities that submit applications under subsection (d) for the award of grants using a competitive process that takes into account the following: </text><paragraph id="HABA27AE4CED044F0AE2917FAC5BB8C05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capacity of the applicant entity to serve covered individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H178AFA2062644FFC81F6B260B64E4166"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The demonstrated need of the population the applicant entity would serve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC72E395D583417BB1D41CAC74DFBF29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The demonstrated need of the applicant entity for assistance from the grants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75E4234A89094E149455EDF6364DF941"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capacity of the applicant entity to serve covered individuals from underserved or disadvantaged populations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F44643E5AF44D69BE7C39AFFD67E371"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such other criteria as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H322C7964E32940329C6450D74AAE741C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Multiple grants</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to an eligible entity under both paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1C8393DCEB84E318A376D772E117642"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information</header><paragraph id="H8FD3315489F544AC9F67BCB61B4B06B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection</header><text>The Secretary shall collect such information from eligible entities that receive a grant under this section as the Secretary determines appropriate to monitor and evaluate the use of grants, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2240690527394B7CA0BA4D01769C3F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data regarding the results or outcomes of the services provided to covered individuals under the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA40B8B1B3A544669DA9046E6A71530F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data regarding how activities or programs carried out under the grant contribute to specific goals, including eligibility screening, application assistance, and food insecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H468CB81198F0450A8EC6FF98E7A55E06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form and manner</header><text>Information under paragraph (1) shall be furnished in such form and manner as the Secretary may specify.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF06E0E07B3E4DF7A38DBBDB9B72F945" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duration of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under this section for a five-year period.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3E83D0ADA2274111B692B358027F309D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports required</header><paragraph id="H19A44B30B4BC48D6B89A58F00BEFA77E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="H65CCD139322E4E2FAEF9F0290FD8E285"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than three years after the date on which the pilot program under this section commences, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an initial report on veteran food insecurity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4920054FFAA4CCCBC67F3CB405E8612"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the two years after the date on which the pilot program under this section concludes, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a final report on veteran food insecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1BD8F53E24B4B56853F3681A63DE702"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under paragraph (1) shall include the findings of a study on the effectiveness of the grants made under such pilot program (including an analysis of the data specified in subsection (g)(1)), disaggregated by grants awarded under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), respectively. With respect to grants awarded under such paragraph (2), such study shall—</text><subparagraph id="HAE9974FEE75744409311B55CE4CA0E9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measure the need for food assistance by individuals described in such paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB74828C9B6949CD987CFCC673C6FC7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a description of how improving access to food during the period in which an individual transitions from service in the armed forces to civilian life affects the outcomes of the individual and the family of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E44EB130215409F8BCB44CA93A7302E" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection><subsection id="H064CBFF07B684E76A226493E8A217E4F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H384C954A58934EEFB7997F0AE6B680E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered individual</term> means any veteran or family member described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65FC865D1EDA4448BD067788284586B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HAC05CB723ACB42F4A3851F67D7C31265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D05DBB702B74C99AC347E5657F9F242"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a veterans service organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EB2DA68C744B0985EBA025DC3E5CCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or local government agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA05920D58FB436CB2B23E1F2B490A06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or tribal organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03A10F426ACE4C8DA03508BDD27F5C33"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a community-based organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1930F5A938941CDB72441D264A3AE64"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BF4EDF61D9645D7B5109B3DF5F2911D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <quote>tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B27B493DDE40C0884EA413568B449D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0617790A337C4222B5D2555EB108DF13"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>Native American</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3765 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25E0898982DD4505B2FB1446A46740CB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, territories, and possessions of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECFF7768FCF84E6E9CC697CC535B6005"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veterans service organization</quote> means any organization recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

