<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4ADE0E4114D4A9B91F6CBB3CC16A409" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8380 IH: Prairie Band Potawatomi Nation Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation Settlement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8380</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220714">July 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the settlement of claims relating to the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation in Illinois, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD12CE479EB434AF491C411DB63357189" style="OLC"><section id="H2BD42E9F149B48168CC20DFCC6A27E83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prairie Band Potawatomi Nation Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation Settlement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE126C5D997B44981ABB5BA5F3F65C608"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header><subsection id="H1E77D0D2760444C48281C1AE9560AF88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H37032314A1EE41BEA9D7BC9592B79899"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pursuant to the Treaty of July 29, 1829, made and concluded at Prairie du Chien (7 Stat. 320) (commonly known as the <quote>Second Treaty of Prairie du Chien</quote>), the Potawatomi and other affected Indian Tribes ceded certain land in northern Illinois, except for 2 parcels totaling 1,280 acres for Potawatomi Chief Shab-eh-nay and his Band at their village near Paw Paw Grove, Illinois;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FC85C687129418FAF96914E86C4FACA"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8930A5537871462F96FED9CAC217E740"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pursuant to the Treaty of September 26, 1833, made at Chicago (7 Stat. 431) (commonly known as the <quote>Treaty of Chicago</quote>), the Potawatomi and other Indians ceded approximately 5,000,000 acres of land, including the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation; but</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H753EB6E340804EA68ACFD8301C3D25F7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Senate rejected the provision that ceded that reservation, with the effect of affirming the Indian-held title and boundaries of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1854EFC7F67C4BA69B492260EEAD69A4"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H04DB4A14EF2C49B7AF8F99F464A5BCC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in 1849, while Chief Shab-eh-nay was visiting his relatives in Kansas, the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the United States sold the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation at public auction to non-Indians who erroneously believed that they had acquired good title to the land on which the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation is located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B5844AA79084CD1B59B509E60D248EC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation is illegally occupied as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA4DD226A3D8482A8880B4C10DA3CA48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Associate Solicitor of the Department of the Interior issued an opinion on July 24, 2000, that concluded that—</text><subparagraph id="H96DADC816FC341B38E1E11BDD023B508"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation continues to exist</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C9B1358F66441A381D06571C99F0EB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is no evidence that Chief Shab-eh-nay abandoned the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEFA42364A69466F8AFFA498B6A68DAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>even if it were true that Shab-eh-nay’s Band had abandoned the land, the Band’s treaty recognized title to that land could not be extinguished without Congressional action</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1365486F6B624D55BACB26A0B47044EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Solicitor of the Department of the Interior issued an opinion on January 18, 2001, that—</text><subparagraph id="H56386AE523AE434183576FA68B0EC573"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confirmed the findings of the Associate Solicitor of the Department of the Interior under paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CF78D944F2649C48B1B1D85D30997B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stated that—</text><clause id="H060A57AC8A03420DAC06F8FF0EEF058B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Shab-eh-nay Band held recognized title to the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></clause><clause id="H5127E7BAF2424FEC8E099973994EF72F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Congress never authorized the conveyance of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></clause><clause id="H7B70A2D9193B48C49373F4C571D4785A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Tribe is the lawful successor in interest to Chief Shab-eh-nay and his Band; and</text></clause><clause id="HA4F3A7C6811C4ED0910B87AC5802C422"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior believes that the United States continues to bear a trust responsibility to the Tribe for the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3996CF04C7FA47498114805B6C80AA22"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress has never acted by treaty or statute to extinguish the recognized Indian title to the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED5444DA4808461DB0BB817707AE5505"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Tribe is the successor in interest to Chief Shab-eh-nay and his Band and the rightful owner and occupant of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H328EF1C05B6E4581BDC687BF6B9E5D73"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Federal Government, through the actions of the General Land Office, has deprived the Tribe of the right of exclusive use and occupancy of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation without legal authorization or just compensation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDB35DB437244E56ABB540D70372A3DA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>certain non-Indian individuals, entities, and local governments occupying land within the boundaries of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation as of the date of enactment of this Act, including the State and the County—</text><subparagraph id="H81A7CA031A914F16AEDF306191E744B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acquired ownership interests to the land in good faith; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A9B3F972DFB4F8FBB86892B14F4AE26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should be able to possess clear title to the land; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA47CE8A8481E4C31ABE2FFDD4C4AAC88"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the United States has a moral and legal responsibility—</text><subparagraph id="HB116F1C1D53245179F52CD26777C1BF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to help secure a fair and equitable settlement of past inequities to the Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61674F9FB9414DC7920ED8D1CEE46D26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure protection of the ownership interests of non-Indian occupants of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H455ABFC071A7488C932818D03504F64E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="HA0046A4E1EC34A8A931D6A20E4B4B965"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to acknowledge the unlawful sale by the Federal Government of the valuable right held by the Tribe to the exclusive use and occupancy of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03397B5F0CD64796985C5A8EF4CB5339"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to reaffirm Federal recognition of the ownership by the Tribe of, and jurisdiction over, land that the Tribe owns within the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC48875937AC4B0EB176ADB71E59BC90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to promote the economic self-sufficiency of the Tribe and the members of the Tribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F0A186AB994534888526E97CF7A268"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to extinguish the Indian title to, and confirm the ownership by the State, the County, and certain individuals and entities of, certain land within the boundaries of the Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41A886533DA84BD3A1E267DE1296D27A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide stability and security to the State and residents of the State, the local governments and the areas over which the local governments exercise jurisdiction, and businesses regarding the ownership and use by the Tribe of the Reaffirmed Reservation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3452F2B6D4A4FD884398EC1B4C1C242"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to extinguish potential claims by the Tribe against the United States, the State, the local governments, and private individuals and entities that could be a direct consequence of not reaching a settlement with the Tribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C63E17066FB47489E1CDBA90C4B07A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to require the Secretary to preserve and protect, but not manage, the Reaffirmed Reservation in furtherance of trust responsibility of the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71893AED904C46D188FABC7FD4EFABBB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to authorize the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H32641AA348CA4334AE531CEDE9B7E708"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to execute the waiver and release of claims and compensate the Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAAF9CED9AFD4822AF121BAD376B153F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to take any other action necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H460221BB617F4F9E803DD157594F79BA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H30ABC049FF494468B130B1F228F53188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Dekalb County in the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H599237FA346348938194BA043AE6871E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <term>local government</term> means any unit of local government exercising authority over land located within the Reservation as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0441643F0EAA42EA97F8B0BFD9EFD5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reaffirmed Reservation</header><text>The term <term>Reaffirmed Reservation</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6675B762FF0541B9852A38DE08623DCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the land recognized as being under the ownership of the Tribe under section 4(a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9AB4768130F48ADAD7CAFE854DB42ED" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any land located within the Replacement Area that is acquired by the Tribe in restricted fee status after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16352218F4CF481889E605DF033FA33B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Replacement Area</header><text>The term <term>Replacement Area</term> means the aboriginal territory of the Tribe, located near Shabbona, Illinois, which is contained within the area bounded—</text><subparagraph id="H5B0C76928F2D44DDB33A9A6874E0DACD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the north by Interstate 88;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB34E881D43A14B4680611ACA3F01D86F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the west by Interstate 39;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4B83F6646E941B6B036139429E9AAB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on the south by State Route 30 and Preserve Road; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCB1332DA4449ECA17201B81E0292D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>on the east by South 4th Street and State Route 23.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10052D6CB9DD41CBAC2238535B333A9C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>The term <term>Reservation</term> means the 1,280 acres of land in the State located in sec. 23, the W<fraction>1/2</fraction> of sec. 25, and the E<fraction>1/2</fraction> of sec. 26 in T. 38 N., R. 3 E., Third Principal Meridian.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E789D9D196E40258A63B28CCD6E25AD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restricted fee status</header><text>The term <term>restricted fee status</term>, with respect to land, means that the land—</text><subparagraph id="H62087E664E3E453E9B5D3D98AA2DFC22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="HF3441B9B9AC740919A38C9ADB186F0E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owned in fee by the Tribe by aboriginal title or conveyance;</text></clause><clause id="HF6050D17DCB4445B9EE9EFE825EC6175"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>held by the Tribe subject to a restriction against alienation and taxation, and therefore may not be sold by the Tribe without the consent of Congress; and</text></clause><clause id="H80391594BD744730BA4807186260D817"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>expressly subject to the jurisdiction of the Tribe; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H410A982C0A6E40D4A5F96EBE314F847B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not subject to—</text><clause id="H7128CB217443482B8F06B105079393D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>taxation by any State or local government other than the Tribe; or</text></clause><clause id="HBA65D9B4C8EA443C99430E30C5E4D000"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any provision of law governing land use that provides for the review or approval by the Secretary, directly or through agreement with another party, before the Tribe may use the land for any purpose.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41E54F05B203408EA6E980838B8493D0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11F8463ED7AE47F79363522112972EC1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Illinois.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD04148B6029245008F9E47072DCD615B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Prairie Band Potawatomi Nation, a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H15F0F7DE26914C89AD92E18795ED77DA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reaffirmation of Shab-eh-nay Band Reservation</header><subsection id="H7E00DC3A2C8D454D89E89479755DC029"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reaffirmation of title</header><text>Title to the 130 acres of the Reservation owned in fee by the Tribe as of the date of enactment of this Act is recognized as being under the ownership of the Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H12FDDD8825FD40F9A9B14E4FA6E89E0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restricted fee status</header><text>The Reaffirmed Reservation—</text><paragraph id="H3FB80B59449746AA8636B294B731D9B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be considered to be owned by the Tribe in restricted fee status;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F6A0BA0C974FFA9815AFC65D3FEBA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is expressly subject to the jurisdiction of the Tribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H793C8DAA6E724010A30EEEC0DACFBE11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall not be subject to—</text><subparagraph id="H5829FE4E85F04BECB49EFCA108B7B53D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>taxation by any State or local government other than the Tribe; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5488C26195943C69CE8F65E3AD93159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any provision of law governing land use that provides for the review or approval by the Secretary, directly or through agreement with another party, before the Tribe may use the land for any purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC3EF36DA320349BA96C2BBA7394B84FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extinguishment of Indian title; confirmation of land ownership</header><subsection id="H11350A51A5C14900A89565ED7B5D28AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extinguishment of Indian title</header><text>Title held by the Tribe to the Reservation (other than the Reaffirmed Reservation) as of the date of enactment of this Act is extinguished.</text></subsection><subsection id="H319408ECE0B942DB866718449C0DD129"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Confirmation of land ownership</header><text>Each title to land and right-of-way within the Reservation held by the State, the local governments, or any individual or entity as of November 5, 1849, is recognized and confirmed.</text></subsection></section><section id="H471169ADD42342A8BFDF77A66E3BAF48"><enum>6.</enum><header>Waiver and release of claims</header><subsection id="HCB9BFB95366E423888260865FCFC708F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Claims against United States, State, local governments, and other parties</header><text>The Tribe and the Secretary shall execute appropriate documents providing for the relinquishment by the Tribe of all claims against—</text><paragraph id="HC371B9DB74A54D18B1DFB5BF8FD66DD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States for a breach of trust responsibility associated with any sale of any portion of the Reservation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE340520CB274384BDB86C04751452B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State, the local governments, and any individuals or entities occupying the Reservation for any trespass and related damages in connection with the occupation and use of the Reservation during the period beginning on November 5, 1849, and ending on the effective date described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E984E8EF9C14C89A25E88DCA6AA5DB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The relinquishment of claims under subsection (a) shall take effect on the later of—</text><paragraph id="H71571B55156F46F2A74C339CF1E60CB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the Tribe receives payment of all of the settlement funds under section 7; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE389F32039DB45B1B48EDC0D0930FDC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a notice that the documents described in subsection (a) have been executed by the Secretary and the Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA73B008C841A48E9B0DDE36F88296569"><enum>7.</enum><header>Settlement funds</header><subsection id="H6D6DB01116D9452D8935A04FE1EB0CFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial payment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall pay to the Tribe $10,000,000 in partial settlement of the claims of the Tribe, to be managed, invested, and used by the Tribe to promote economic development and land acquisition, as determined by the Tribe in accordance with the constitution and laws of the Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H716BBE75FB19407ABAEC0050F96736B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent payments</header><paragraph id="H49DAC06A547A4468AFCC53F86E8CD7ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><subparagraph id="H48AE2C7109AE4144AA2B41653D77DDB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Tribe, shall calculate an assessment of the total damages to the Tribe associated with the liability of the United States for the illegal sale of the Reservation, including the current land value of all land located within the Reservation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H605B80A4E0754D3EA30BCA592014B001"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report describing the assessment calculated under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E53B69F53B1494694EB1667799C08E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final settlement agreement</header><text>The Secretary and the Tribe shall negotiate and execute a final settlement agreement in lieu of litigation to resolve the claims of the Tribe, in a form and manner acceptable to the Attorney General, which shall include terms for the payment of the remaining settlement funds to the Tribe, as calculated under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4AB475AACF480881A6FAD17C55F7F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall pay to the Tribe <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the remaining settlement funds, as described in the final settlement agreement executed under paragraph (2), on each of—</text><subparagraph id="H674BF809D91A482AA324262459DDD2F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H469A3DD8E7CB4F319F7B72FD88380F0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 6 years after that date of enactment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C211902CEF4465597257B7CB46A0BCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date that is 9 years after that date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0F45DAAE4F3E4567BC2CF5487CF4B31C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Land acquisition; Tribal authority to enter into agreements; no use of condemnation or eminent domain</header><subsection id="HF62FAA544ABA480A869AF01C546A0484"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header><paragraph id="H5E74ED949D614E4791F8E75C7C8651C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), after the date of enactment of this Act, the Tribe may acquire from a willing seller in restricted fee status not more than a total of 1,151 acres of land within the Reservation or the Replacement Area using the settlement funds received by the Tribe under section 7 or other funds of the Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0657A3D35A43B9BA626092C2DF4512"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><subparagraph id="H9F3DCCF505134D4BA825C8778E87DE15"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before acquiring land under paragraph (1), the Tribe shall give notice to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42AE67B708524C829E71F471B9C0F35D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>On the date that is 60 days after receipt of the notice under subparagraph (A), the land shall automatically—</text><clause id="H61EE31261E0D490CBC72B5E19D2A07EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>convert to ownership by the Tribe in restricted fee status; and</text></clause><clause id="H505AF0D9CF7242A9857BF88546DEB9EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be considered to be part of the Reaffirmed Reservation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67121265310643F9B782F321F415A932"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recognition of Tribal government authority To enter into agreements with State and local governments</header><text>The Tribe shall have the authority to enter into agreements with the State and any local government regarding the Reaffirmed Reservation and activities occurring on the Reaffirmed Reservation, including agreements relating to jurisdiction, land use, and services.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF0AA3C88817547AB87AFE87C04723938"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No use of condemnation or eminent domain</header><text>Land or interests in land—</text><paragraph id="HDF7CE2D390CB4C259124A425985DC653"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not be acquired by condemnation or eminent domain under this Act; but</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AF6E97FB2EB40489C8AFD7090AFB52E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be acquired by purchase by payment of fair market value.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H180BE4042CA84549A7A6E454C88EBB24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cultural and historic preservation of reservation</header><text>Land owned by the State and the local governments located within the boundaries of the Reservation shall be managed to protect any human or cultural remains, consistent with applicable Federal and State law and subject to consultation with the Tribe.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1ECAF812FFB24FBBA1B04B40197FC7BC"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $10,000,000.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

