<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H02D4E5038EA94607898AC3FA78C01620" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8658 IH: Emergency Price Stabilization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8658</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Sub-Task Force on Emergency Price Stabilization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H62F2966E9DB743649462AC06B10E9787" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H72DF56E5A1B045449C62CED888E01DA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Price Stabilization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H8C0E82F9A88D40C98D7999B9D0A419C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1C7ACDA54B5B4121BF36157195497965"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in response to global economic disruptions, including those related to the COVID–19 pandemic, and in anticipation of future disruptions caused by climate change and other factors, the Federal Government requires additional tools to protect residents of the United States from price shocks and profiteering; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04AA48F2C2D7498AAFAAACB554A1BAB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as one such tool, the Federal Government should build the capacity to establish limits on the growth of certain prices, and to otherwise strategically regulate such prices, in order to stabilize the cost of essential goods and services.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7DF48FFD0C7C455B9ACCCADDDC25F109"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HC51F835CEFB244D5904C920D4791BA1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Advisory Board</term> means the Advisory Board established pursuant to section 4(f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5A874ABD1B44A91B2E36DB34A45224C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCB691C089684AC4982533C722D61014"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sub-Task Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Sub-Task Force</term> means the Sub-Task Force on Emergency Price Stabilization established pursuant to section 4(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC21526CA824949E8B02D516B143AF7C9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strategically important price</header><text>The term <term>strategically important price</term> means a price associated with any good or service that is ubiquitous as a productive input, investment asset, or benchmark used to determine other prices.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H2D4E5CE78B004CB9A82B373241282DC2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sub-Task Force on Emergency Price Stabilization</header> <subsection id="HDFD34EE0346A4669B6336B15DA04E0F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish a sub-task force to be known as the <quote>Sub-Task Force on Emergency Price Stabilization</quote> under the White House Supply Chains Disruption Task Force.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7DF16D0CE244D3A961C4E98FCEA9773"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Sub-Task Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sub-Task Force (in consultation with the Advisory Board, the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission, the Director of the National Economic Council, the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Chair of the Federal Reserve System, the National Climate Advisor, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and as needed, with other agencies whose jurisdiction is relevant to the prices described in paragraph (1)), using each methodology, tool, and process described in subsection (d)(1)(A), shall do the following:</text> <paragraph id="HABA639E558BE430A97B9D18C6B5654D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitor the price of certain goods and services, including in the following categories:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CFB7F1A7F3649DFBDA68784CE7EF75F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Food.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33E73908ABC2484781C557C5377B6D83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Energy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80540FFEB82649BF9EC6DB8FCF6D271B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Housing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97EC387CAF5F4F3BA9750C0DBEC813B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Health care.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H138EF75A82FE4C2F9892BFC57E48AC76"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Transportation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8479458BEF2B4ABBBA2983A1246C6CB5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any price from the list of strategically important prices described in paragraph (2) as the Sub-Task Force determines appropriate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BB450FA5F574D66A109112B3EC12942"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a list of strategically important prices that are of critical importance to the health, safety, economic security, or well-being of residents of the United States and update such list (based on changing economic conditions) not later than once every 6 months.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H657747F6C6ED46B4B23223F86F2EFE41" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analyze how the prices described in paragraph (1) are impacted by disruptions to supply chains, including those related to the COVID–19 pandemic and similar threats to public health, climate-driven disasters and extreme weather events, and geopolitical conflict, and by other disruptive, distortive, speculative, or unusual conditions and practices that may be related to the increases described in paragraph (5).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4DECD06179D4BF9B0AE2D05D75E8863"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Investigate, including in relation to the disruptions described in paragraph (3), the costs, profits, price-setting and investment decisions, and other relevant indicators and practices of economically significant entities, especially large corporations, that exercise disproportionate pricing power over the prices described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FFD5B6A743C4061966FA811073244D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determine when any such economically significant entity has acted to raise or maintain a price described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE9AE95691D784045B5310F4A53FD2AFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to exceed corresponding increases in per-unit input and labor costs, or despite such costs that are falling; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF40CAC218D8C4AFE95C4D9FAD485282B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to an extent that is not economically necessary, including when such cost increases could reasonably be absorbed in whole or in part by the economically significant entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81057E1FE68547CA98C571FC6D313A91" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inform the President and Congress, in a prompt manner that is made available to the public on an appropriate website, if the increases described in paragraph (5) are widespread or burdensome such that action by the Federal Government is warranted to protect residents of the United States and the economy of the United States, including when such increases are related to inflation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE9E64E8EE764BDA9CDAA87B9EB6E9C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Make actionable recommendations, including quantitatively specific recommendations as appropriate, to the President on how to address the increases described in paragraph (5), including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF55ECABAAEBB4D8C8560099AB1BCF8E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Targeted price controls and regulations to—</text> <clause id="H1C03C7F3D4CA447A8295B57DD00AAFA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish limits on the growth of the prices of goods and services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2AEFA397A3EA467CA9B8A9C776F472E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce volatility and promote stability of such prices.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF13E122C7F5443F8E965BE66B9889B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other concurrent or subsequent action as the Sub-Task Force determines appropriate to ensure successful and equitable implementation of such targeted price controls and regulations, including action to do the following:</text> 
<clause id="HD736D6B8979843F38C5B2EFD237A3616"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Make adjustments to any enacted recommendation based on changing economic conditions.</text></clause> <clause id="H9C84B2F119F042F29186D484D14DEF11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guarantee sufficient production and supply of impacted goods and services, including through the use of measures to reduce sectoral demand. </text></clause> 
<clause id="HD5CB78B1707B41EFAAE661D7CD28B5C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Promote the expansion of relevant productive capacity and, as appropriate, of stockpiles and reserves.</text></clause> <clause id="H99AB0E821BAB44E1BDCA33612617307B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure and verify that such targeted price controls and regulations do not lead to an increase in (and wherever possible reduce) greenhouse gas emissions or any other negative impacts on public health, the environment, and local communities.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9049012CE0574A6A883A28E897A9DC96"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish conditions and requirements on firms that may benefit financially from the application of price controls and regulations to the supply chains of such firms, or that benefit from other forms of support under this Act, including requirements to pass on lower costs to consumers, contribute to sufficient production and supply of goods and services, and reduce greenhouse gas emissions and other negative impacts on public health, the environment, and local communities.</text></clause> <clause id="HF0AD485017D1431FA358BA5C1FBFDC22"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Establish price floors as appropriate, including through purchasing, procurement, and price supports by the Federal Government. </text></clause> 
<clause id="HE351A9D57AEE41A0A31FBE163202026E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Intervene directly in commodity markets to counter speculation, including by pursuing collaboration with the Federal Reserve and pursuing international coordination to stabilize such markets.</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C8900BEDD4C49868120C3B2835FAB87"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Design the recommendations in paragraph (7) by taking into account any other tool the Federal Government is authorized to use to directly prevent or counteract price-gouging, windfall profits, or other harmful practices under the purview of the Sub-Task Force, such that the recommendations of the Sub-Task Force will complement, work in tandem with, or address gaps in those tools, including by providing faster-acting mechanisms where necessary to achieve the goals of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7D92E0E30664994A28E9A42935B4376"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report to the Advisory Board on the actionable recommendations described in paragraph (7) that the Advisory Board advises the Sub-Task Force on pursuant to subsection (f)(3)(B). The Sub-Task Force shall make every effort to make recommendations that are approved by the majority of the Advisory Board.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C91C0E856BA4AE9BB0E039EA63DD74A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Powers of Sub-Task Force</header> <paragraph id="HA164D3507194497699EC229D14FF6858"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sub-Task Force, to the extent necessary to carry out the duties described in subsection (b)(4) or any other duty described in subsection (b), may conduct investigations, make reports, issue subpoenas, require the production, making, or keeping of relevant documents and records, take depositions, hold hearings, and conduct (directly, by contract, or otherwise) research activities. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA39F0476CDD4D9B98A6B4E22C957334"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Examination of records and properties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sub-Task Force, and any employee or agent the Sub-Task Force so designates, are authorized, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the person in charge, to enter, inspect, and examine, at a reasonable time and in a reasonable manner, records and properties to the extent such records and properties are relevant to carrying out the duties described in subsection (b). </text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44BE08E85BFF46B490AC1FC817491E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H012129128AF84953B0E4ADF4B6C9AB41" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the President establishes the Sub-Task Force pursuant to subsection (a), the Sub-Task Force shall submit to the President and Congress and make available to the public on an appropriate website an initial report that includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6EF7B6C952724EF98653003290EB1A7D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of each methodology, tool, and process formulated in consultation with the Advisory Board for the Sub-Task Force to use to carry out the duties described in subsection (b), in a manner consistent with the following goals: </text> <clause id="HA8039386EE3F4835A6F03F2D54422D45" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stabilizing the prices of goods and services that are of critical importance to the health, safety, economic security, and well-being of residents of the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H333CAD1716B64EEEBAD1F0AD887D89CB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preventing reductions in real wages and creating conditions to enable growth in such wages. </text></clause> <clause id="HC20E986EC80A443F9AB64734AD8C97C0" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Protecting the economy of the United States in light of the disruptions and threats described in subsection (b)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE15E80A6147E48AE8EF7FD92C1F52A63" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to seek and incorporate input on each such methodology, tool, and process from additional experts on the economy, public health, food systems, housing, and climate change, as well as from labor organizations, small businesses, community organizations, and the public, including through at least 1 process of notice and public comment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D3FA7BA7DCF454F81B83EA9879BDA3A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for how the Sub-Task Force will coordinate and collaborate with the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, the Census Bureau, and other relevant statistical agencies and programs of the Federal Government to conduct the monitoring, analysis, and investigation described in subsection (b), including the creation of new digital resources to collate and organize data as needed. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF681405CBB0D40E5871447DCAF696D14" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A preliminary analysis, which shall be updated as necessary in one or more subsequent reports, of how prices and profits described in subsection (b)(1) have already increased during the COVID–19 pandemic in the manner described in subsection (b)(5), relative to appropriate baseline periods as determined by the Sub-Task Force.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5E59AC91DC5403E95BDB8E45E771059" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A detailed analysis of the contribution of the housing sector, including the rental and homeownership markets, to the acceleration of inflation beginning in 2021, that considers the decision-making and practices of housing providers, financial institutions, and private equity firms.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34F262AD759D446694627A5B4C86766A" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the authority, other than the authority described in section 5, the President may use to implement and carry out the targeted price controls and regulations or other concurrent or subsequent action described in subsection (b)(7)(B), including under the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1145D762C56A4613B45A6A842D9D5743" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of how to enforce any such price control or regulation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A91FA568CE94E458BB3DEFB1BA4D320" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the steps Congress could take to facilitate the duties of the Sub-Task Force and the President under this Act, including further amendment of the Defense Production Act of 1950.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0883142602E44511BB237F2BF224ED9A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the Sub-Task Force intends to seek further input from Congress and the public in carrying out the duties of the Sub-Task Force under this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H531054AB8FBA4E21AC328DA76BAEDAD8" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for maximizing democratic participation in the activities of the Sub-Task Force, including by working with State, local, and Tribal governments to create websites and digital resources that allow residents of the United States to submit relevant information and feedback to the Sub-Task Force, which may include the establishment of volunteer committees or networks, in coordination with such governments and community organizations, to similarly assist in the monitoring, analysis, investigation, and regulation of prices under this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA265DDA985564D71ACCFDBBEE251DE18" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Sub-Task Force submits to the President and Congress the initial report described in paragraph (1), and at least annually thereafter, the Sub-Task Force shall submit to the President and Congress and make available to the public on an appropriate website a report that evaluates the efficacy of the activities carried out under this Act, including any update to the plans and analyses contained in the initial report.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H250F564285C547F2966959F0650FE9C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Staff</header> 
<paragraph id="H2E32CD68DE6E4934BC58DB8F14821F93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hiring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The White House Supply Chains Disruption Task Force shall hire staff to serve the Sub-Task Force as the White House Supply Chains Disruption Task Force determines appropriate. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A110FC2EEA74E1E84CAF5391B243CE0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A staff member so hired may be a detailee, on a non-reimbursable basis, from any agency to the Sub-Task Force, including from the Federal Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H04840264DFB14776890AC77FAA06AB9A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advisory Board</header> 
<paragraph id="H3373590AF38140BEAA6922923EFE3210"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish an advisory board to the Sub-Task Force.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4DB3AAA7BBB4151AE77AFDA7AB69157"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Board shall consist of an odd number of members appointed by the President and shall be composed as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H056D2004239248139E0B6042D4904E27"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representation of academic economists, historians, sociologists, or others with relevant expertise who have produced scholarship or public policy work regarding how price or profit controls have been, or can be, administered effectively. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D731C545AB345ED8D695F251BC7B806"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Representation of academic or public policy experts who specialize in subject matter areas relevant to the matters described in this Act, including public health, food systems, housing, and climate change.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93D4B055700E4C4BA1AF93ECEE02B2D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Equal representation of labor organizations, small business associations, and consumer or tenant advocacy organizations.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H31161EC8B34B46FA9348A16B6D95A615"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Board shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0FDA7BECB8D146A0B49A639B792CBF54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with and assist the Sub-Task Force in formulating the methodologies, tools, and processes described in subsection (d)(1)(A) for the Sub-Task Force to carry out the duties described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79FECD35E7B6419CB530D224CB318D4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Sub-Task Force on the actionable recommendations described in subsection (b)(7) by—</text> 
<clause id="H6D2D5D748861485ABEC8ED724D303240"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reviewing each such recommendation;</text></clause> <clause id="HDA9E25CBA08845878D762BA4F8C597C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>voting on whether to approve each such recommendation; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3C992AAB05E346EBB7FEE91AE073972D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case that a majority of the Advisory Board does not approve a recommendation, writing a dissenting statement of explanation for the Sub-Task Force to include in submitting such recommendation to the President.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E9E75E221824FA2A6A28B0B638EBE68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Communications</header><text>The Advisory Board, or one or more members thereof, may publish reports or any other communication at any time at their discretion, if such reports and communications are clearly distinguished from the reports of the Sub-Task Force, and the particular authors and co-signatories are clearly indicated.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34944B6C64494EF5A26D5006CA66FD7B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional advisory boards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sub-Task Force may establish advisory boards, other than the Advisory Board, as the Sub-Task Force determines appropriate to focus on specific industries, sectors, or geographical regions, and to consult with the Sub-Task Force on the actionable recommendations described in subsection (b)(7). Any such advisory board shall include equal representation of labor organizations and businesses (including small businesses) from any relevant industry or sector, broad representation of stakeholders and communities from any relevant geographical region, and representation from relevant subject matter experts and consumer or tenant advocacy organizations.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HCDB2E680B6B34DEF9D6607D20EDDACF4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sub-Task Force shall terminate not later than December 31, 2028.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4F7294AA85FF48A6941A8D4D5407B9BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Presidential authority</header> 
<subsection id="H913287243EF64E07AAE7BB2AF1DD4394"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Orders and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may enact or adjust price controls and regulations as the President determines appropriate to stabilize prices of goods and services, in accordance with the actionable recommendations of the Sub-Task Force described in section 4(b)(7) and the goals described in section 4(d)(1)(A).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60AFC010876440EA84BE448BC24C7C02" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Communications to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President enacts or adjusts a price control or regulation under subsection (a), the President shall submit to Congress an explanation that is made available to the public on an appropriate website that states how such price control or regulation is consistent with the requirements of this Act, including the goals described in section 4(d)(1)(A).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8B8A6AC24F7442B90D30708434579EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Divergence from recommendations of Sub-Task-Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President enacts or adjusts a price control or regulation under subsection (a), such price control or regulation may reasonably diverge from the relevant actionable recommendations of the Sub-Task Force described in section 4(b)(7), if—</text> <paragraph id="H33C702064DE84D90930677BD62DFAB7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President states and supports the reasons for such divergence in the communication described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6980D68128D8401CBE535F9D201C2D8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such price control or regulation is still qualitatively consistent with the criteria described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 4(b)(7).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H06984EF4B2DA4B4DB96280DDF2EDC3AD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Delegation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President may delegate the performance of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HABDC3210900F497BAE49760D77E0ACF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any authority of the President under this Act to the head of any agency as the President determines appropriate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29672335C8C2470782EA13E6FBE15114"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any function of the Sub-Task Force under this Act to any other agency or office, or any new entity or office the President may establish, as the President determines appropriate.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H2C99E639AAB44903BA1C87556DC7FDD9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Wages and salaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority to make recommendations and issue and enforce orders and regulations under this Act does not include the authority to make recommendations or enact price controls or regulations to in any way reduce, freeze, or establish limits on the growth of the wages and salaries of workers.</text></section> <section id="H1CD6A9FE87374C6EBE34FCFB68258905"><enum>8.</enum><header>Expiration of Presidential authority</header> <subsection id="HEEA76E1271D14A849E394AF9FED2D89F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority conferred by this Act on the President to issue and enforce orders and regulations under this Act expires on December 31, 2024.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB2ED54A550F4B179BEC794DA9AD7D3B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed to affect any other authority the President may use to implement and carry out targeted price controls and regulations, including such authority identified pursuant to section 4(d)(1)(D).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDE49DC499E524BE6888CA6E7643FCD0B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report of the National Economic Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Economic Council, in consultation with the head of any agency or private entity as the National Economic Council determines to be necessary, shall submit to the President and Congress and make available to the public on an appropriate website a report that analyzes how the Federal Government can expand its capacity to stabilize and manage prices over time, including an analysis of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1ADB2CFB02044243A261BC65AD1F5595"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the Federal Government, State governments, and other public regulatory bodies already regulate certain prices, directly or indirectly, and how such regulations could inform and facilitate further stabilization and management of prices by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B65CE336CAF494ABD6709027BA22D36"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the Federal Government has stabilized and managed prices directly in the past.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3711925D039E47B2BCAE50B38A3B3207"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conditions related to facilitating the stabilization and management of prices by the Federal Government, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B4CBCD2BC004EC18B12E629099E3A81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administrative needs, including Federal data and research needs and improvements in corporate transparency, data collection, and record keeping, to carry out effective, comprehensive monitoring of the prices of goods and services, corporate profits, price-setting and investment decisions, supply chains, and other relevant indicators and practices; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DAF6E48BB2C4588B5474A7B0C3F778C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximization of democratic participation by the agency or entity carrying out such price management; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF06CE2657F0F4C1C93F9E369557644F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods of enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD528895AA7B14EE8A5F50E3D5D03B211"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other policies and investments the Federal Government should prioritize, in conjunction with price management, to ease inflationary pressures and enhance the health, safety, economic security, and well-being of residents of the United States, including investments in sustainable agriculture and food systems, renewable energy and efficiency, domestic manufacturing, just and resilient global supply chains, public and affordable housing, public transportation, universal health and child care, other public care infrastructure, and other free or affordable public goods and services.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

