<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDED6223A7A5F46F8BE75F8874E99FEC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6681 IH: 100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial Commemorative Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint commemorative coins in recognition of the 100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F71967BBCAE4DBEB27C716A0BBEBC10" style="OLC"><section id="H6DD8D22E7D1E453382BCCEC9A9D9E666" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial Commemorative Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD6264AB73B304ABAA83AB3E3AFAA12B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H68E48BBD897B4C27AE5DCAE592ACB047"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The year 2022 marks the 100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial on the National Mall, dedicated on May 30, 1922.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5F30CCAE5E44FB9A389CB88AA0E9DC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The iconic Lincoln Memorial is a U.S. national memorial built in the style of a neoclassical temple in honor of the 16th President of the United States. Designed by Henry Bacon and sited on the western end of the National Mall across from the Washington Monument, the memorial contains a grand seated sculpture of Abraham Lincoln and includes inscriptions of passages from the Gettysburg Address and Lincoln’s second inaugural address.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB0C661B3BB240B3A024CDF32C86E93D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The most visited monument on the National Mall, the Lincoln Memorial provides visitors with a grand view of the Mall and meaningful and inspiring way to experience President Lincoln and his legacy. It has been the site of many important historical events, including Martin Luther King Jr.’s <quote>I Have a Dream</quote> speech, delivered on August 28, 1963, during the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6045FAA789054AF39C319CBC098C60ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress has invested significant funding to repair and restore the Lincoln Memorial over the years. The purpose of this Act is to build a long-term maintenance fund for future repairs and maintenance to augment the National Park Service budget and further protect and build upon Congress’s initial investment in the memorial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF5488C03CB4281BED8520691427635"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since 2007, the Trust for the National Mall has been the leading nonprofit nonpartisan philanthropic partner of the National Mall and Memorial Parks division of the National Park Service dedicated to bringing private and public resources and public awareness to support the preservation, restoration, and enrichment of the National Mall. The Trust will provide management of the maintenance fund in collaboration with the National Park Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79ED0E05A3634356B79EF0B19AAD0EA4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Trust for the National Mall wants to honor the contributions of Abraham Lincoln to our great Nation. The Trust will promote and encourage support for this commemorative coin as a way to increase public awareness and appreciation for Lincoln’s legacy and to inspire Americans to share in this important effort to preserve the memorial for generations to come.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H85E65F8CFCBD44AB896A11F8D476D149"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header><subsection id="H8B58BC093B5F4D48B6ADFCDD8930E683"><enum>(a)</enum><header>$1 Silver Coins</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue not more than 500,000 $1 coins in commemoration of the 100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial, each of which shall—</text><paragraph id="H62090462700F4928BE965FDB0FD61955"><enum>(1)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69260AEA6010433BA38C602593A2568F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A0CBF06F574AD3B7137AC84550811C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contain at least 90 percent silver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA5F9F347EBC41348263A76E870782BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF66E17C26B84EC8A0A35BE2A3CD114D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H173B9171651641C3A39D22F80A82F177"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of coins</header><subsection id="H51F51D8C84594FF0BFD8F002853A6EC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><paragraph id="H72F3DE5C24FF48B09DCC48EA3BCE5716"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The design of the coins minted under this Act shall be emblematic of the 100th anniversary of the Lincoln Memorial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6334190B45054CC89B37FFA526FC29C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act, there shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HD1FDC964406541FDB9232BD09DF2F447"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a designation of the value of the coin;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC2F8C9C421349A59C142A85FAA08A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2023</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE87E8E590744D76930DEE1BBAE0A64B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C1294FC045847ED839CCB746C5A7745"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The design for the coins minted under this Act shall be—</text><paragraph id="H4FE909FB447548BF9DE111047F94DB93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the Trust of the National Mall; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5B2120C794743609F87D856357142D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H875310CC586246A4A2F4ABAEC67DBC7F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header><subsection id="H87681E2641714AA7A9E8671B4050E864"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H56E36B3959E24953B90C92ECE230F1F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins under this Act only during the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4D1F4C5C8BCE472BB28E9A570414A468"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header><subsection id="H4CD03FE5D3004EA4A9412DECD2819C67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price equal to the sum of—</text><paragraph id="H9949E25B28DE4FC7A5A78132E5AFE29F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D304EDBF00A4806B8EDB4E3F6063F26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE79441DFE64899BA574FC5308A1F8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC439615603648AF8ED4B763EFA32456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header><paragraph id="H2BEA87FDA4D943539E1F16C3AEED9AAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of such coins.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC15DB90D4A5542DEAB68051954398944"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H16D40FED076A42238F9CC2DE583BAD76"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header><subsection id="HC1473F54F8324DF4B68039F40AA037F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins issued under this Act shall include a surcharge of $10 per coin.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1FB5510EA82D43B2A90EEB002292D165"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be paid to the Trust of the National Mall and for the purpose of restoring and preserving the Lincoln Memorial.</text></subsection><subsection id="H545192AD2845432489F02F20C0CF21F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Lincoln Memorial shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A1D774F09424DC4BE188E196FB175F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual 2 commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code. The Secretary of the Treasury may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

