<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC3FD44E4B1F4E55B7181F47FF016A47" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 HR 7633 IH: Hualapai Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To approve the settlement of water rights claims of the Hualapai Tribe and certain allottees in the State of Arizona, to authorize construction of a water project relating to those water rights claims, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H886BDB187FCE4E2EA3DE4DF5F0ACF0CF" style="OLC"><section id="HA2DA6EF40DFB4070BF10E5E20FC8AB9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hualapai Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF4C319BA7FC54E4CB930ACA17ECF7CAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="HD67D2DDAB8F74B65AD144F5A5EA30708"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to resolve, fully and finally, all claims to rights to water in the State, including the Verde River, the Bill Williams River, and the Colorado River, of—</text><subparagraph id="HA89F0D26F8784B5BAC83C827ED79F341"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribe, on behalf of the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762AC57D12124251877CF160F4A810FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States, acting as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, and the allottees;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC53E5226B64AA881A5CDDE4E74733D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize, ratify, and confirm the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, to the extent that agreement is consistent with this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C62C8FB43BD464BBDBC96A0A0A35742"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to authorize and direct the Secretary to execute and perform the duties and obligations of the Secretary under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ED79511AEBD4D229FB0D03C2CCA606B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to authorize the appropriation of funds necessary to carry out the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H93EF0FDF6AC94B6085269EF4085BC7C3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC18D42EEB6054DDE96A0E8E9F0AF77F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>1947 judgment</header><text>The term <term>1947 Judgment</term> means the Judgment and the Stipulation and Agreement, including exhibits to the Judgment and the Stipulation and Agreement, entered on March 13, 1947, in United States v. Santa Fe Pac. R.R. Co., No. E–190 (D. Ariz.) and attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.1.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53AC065976354F8980DEDD949A324F92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>AFY</header><text>The term <term>AFY</term> means acre-feet per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78927FEEF79C4658B577F4EEBADA3653"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allotment</header><text>The term <term>allotment</term> means any of the 4 off-reservation parcels that are—</text><subparagraph id="H95E8421E590944309A95E69013A167BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>held in trust by the United States for individual Indians in the Big Sandy River basin in Mohave County, Arizona, under the patents numbered 1039995, 1039996, 1039997, and 1019494; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEBAB061A9B942C68AA5E9C6065E1709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identified as Parcels 1A, 1B, 1C, and 2 on the map attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.6.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4953E0D2C89A4B0DB8DE492614D84DEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Allottee</header><text>The term <term>allottee</term> means any Indian owner of an allotment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9D33627115F46EAAF8EAC15C96D76DA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Available cap supply</header><text>The term <term>available CAP supply</term> means, for any year—</text><subparagraph id="H1B6E47211F074C2494907B79AA830ED8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all fourth priority water available for delivery through the Central Arizona Project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC06D4DBEFF2249E4A5E876B5D217918E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>water available from Central Arizona Project dams and reservoirs other than the Modified Roosevelt Dam; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E1D70641D04C7CA5C12DB3308F9548"><enum>(C)</enum><text>return flows captured by the Secretary for Central Arizona Project use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA54C26EB540D441981D2FA0D1CB09195"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Bill williams act</header><text>The term <term>Bill Williams Act</term> means the Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/223">Public Law 113–223</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 2096).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61B9EE900536411FB61707CAEE7BE04B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Bill williams agreements</header><text>The term <term>Bill Williams agreements</term> means the Amended and Restated Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement and the Amended and Restated Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement, including all exhibits to each agreement, copies of which (excluding exhibits) are attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.11.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7F202F84F37445BAD2DBDD0C0D83B4E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Bill williams river phase 2 enforceability date</header><text>The term <term>Bill Williams River Phase 2 Enforceability Date</term> means the date described in section 14(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H883162D674CE4BC6A79CC4BCE427FF98"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Bill williams river phase 2 water rights settlement agreement</header><text>The term <term>Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement</term> means the agreement of that name that is attached to, and incorporated in, the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 4.3.3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1735F2AA4C24EEFAE816C719B115A90"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Cap contract</header><text>The term <term>CAP contract</term> means a long-term contract (as defined in the CAP repayment stipulation) with the United States for delivery of CAP water through the CAP system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99ACE9B379ED4EAFBF6CCFAC23B448F7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Cap contractor</header><subparagraph id="H05F4DF7619C54ADCA3887D7E5D531A0C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>CAP contractor</term> means a person that has entered into a CAP contract.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68094C9E37EA4ADF99B2202C15FD29BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>CAP contractor</term> includes the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H869C1EF9AF9845E18E80622936AB1F06"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Cap fixed om&amp;r charge</header><text>The term <term>CAP fixed OM&amp;R charge</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Fixed OM&amp;R Charge</term> in the CAP repayment stipulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18363234F47458DBAF4580BB7FE9238"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Cap m&amp;i priority water</header><text>The term <term>CAP M&amp;I priority water</term> means water within the available CAP supply having a municipal and industrial delivery priority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1799EE97391496CB6A7F81F12F7A17F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Cap nia priority water</header><text>The term <term>CAP NIA priority water</term> means water within the available CAP supply having a non-Indian agricultural delivery priority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5994E6704724275BDFA9041A49C8BA3"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Cap operating agency</header><text>The term <term>CAP operating agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H165C35CD9ED04184AFCCD678500918EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 1 or more entities authorized to assume responsibility for the care, operation, maintenance, and replacement of the CAP system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC759959824734567893031EC23285D0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act, the Central Arizona Water Conservation District.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE37CAD08C9A1487092D5C83FB685DE30"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Cap pumping energy charge</header><text>The term <term>CAP pumping energy charge</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Pumping Energy Charge</term> in the CAP repayment stipulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD788F1628EB4D5485D8889FC1237542"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Cap repayment contract</header><text>The term <term>CAP repayment contract</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H120AA81C4F6D4F339D611F5B392B53B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contract dated December 1, 1988 (Contract No. 14–06–W–245, Amendment No. 1), between the United States and the Central Arizona Water Conservation District for the Delivery of Water and Repayment of Costs of the Central Arizona Project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FFDCA80B89B45438ED70A1EED43936D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any amendment to, or revision of, that contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D9DB95E09CC4E16953C0E7EBA294ECB"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Cap repayment stipulation</header><text>The term <term>CAP repayment stipulation</term> means the Stipulated Judgment and the Stipulation for Judgment, including any exhibits to those documents, entered on November 21, 2007, in the United States District Court for the District of Arizona in the consolidated civil action Central Arizona Water Conservation District v. United States, numbered CIV 95–625–TUC–WDB (EHC) and CIV 95–1720–PHX–EHC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75605D4BCEC84D3B81884A1CADF8F021"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Cap subcontract</header><text>The term <term>CAP subcontract</term> means a long-term subcontract (as defined in the CAP repayment stipulation) with the United States and the Central Arizona Water Conservation District for the delivery of CAP water through the CAP system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA67B37063B6641BFBBDBE5BC46510141"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Cap subcontractor</header><text>The term <term>CAP subcontractor</term> means a person that has entered into a CAP subcontract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD10C7579EEBF4FAC97F3A60498695C39"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Cap system</header><text>The term <term>CAP system</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H894867570D5B4F3EAD548FB78C640E45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Mark Wilmer Pumping Plant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF246430BFF04931B747A81D1177E73D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Hayden-Rhodes Aqueduct;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A4ED7001A24C308C62CEE380C196F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Fannin-McFarland Aqueduct;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36C40A7A9E074BA98452483C49617B4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Tucson Aqueduct;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339A5431C6B5418BABDE9770B7927CDB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any pumping plant or appurtenant work of a feature described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AEA0CE7DE3C4E73863D5C98F05B8B01"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any extension of, addition to, or replacement for a feature described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE458CA13604D2AB8FF75A68B87A2E3"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Cap water</header><text>The term <term>CAP water</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Project Water</term> in the CAP repayment stipulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC5A1007593E4E10B84A3D01843E777F"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Central arizona project</header><text>The term <term>Central Arizona Project</term> means the reclamation project authorized and constructed by the United States in accordance with title III of the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1521">43 U.S.C. 1521 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA2B52505C9041529306B16AC2A11425"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Central arizona water conservation district</header><text>The term <term>Central Arizona Water Conservation District</term> means the political subdivision of the State that is the contractor under the CAP repayment contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC082FA84E72248C289E43A8D2A687A69"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Colorado river compact</header><text>The term <term>Colorado River Compact</term> means the Colorado River Compact of 1922, as ratified and reprinted in article 2 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/45/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 45, Arizona Revised Statutes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H210FCB61BD1D4FF5855898D7F7D9B561"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Colorado river water entitlement</header><text>The term <term>Colorado River water entitlement</term> means the right or authorization to use Colorado River water in the State through a mainstem contract with the Secretary pursuant to section 5 of the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/617d">43 U.S.C. 617d</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A00A8907B7471C953A31558639EEEA"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Diversion</header><text>The term <term>diversion</term> means an act to divert.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1576F6C132C42FBB3E1DDA2F22438A0"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Divert</header><text>The term <term>divert</term> means to receive, withdraw, develop, produce, or capture water using—</text><subparagraph id="H5D6CE59D49D14DA2BC128F877CE88C60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a ditch, canal, flume, bypass, pipeline, pit, collection or infiltration gallery, conduit, well, pump, turnout, dam, or any other mechanical device; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFEF5B971E4241EFB3B02516D142894B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other act of man.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD66B7B29984BA784A1576541E167F7"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Domestic purpose</header><subparagraph id="HE06B217EB1E4452B9C95867E642B8B4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>domestic purpose</term> means any use relating to the supply, service, or activity of a household or private residence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE82D9152F244098C2916B36BF9F18A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>domestic purpose</term> includes the application of water to not more than 2 acres of land to produce a plant or parts of a plant for—</text><clause id="H94EF33E984F041869DE92DECBC8B8595"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sale or human consumption; or </text></clause><clause id="HE79FFF651C714CCA9E529ECDEAD57C0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use as feed for livestock, range livestock, or poultry.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B48E14683F4D10AE0DA315D7A45417"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Effluent</header><text>The term <term>effluent</term> means water that—</text><subparagraph id="H1D6C9EA9E01F4C95B3D366A527287B72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been used in the State for domestic, municipal, or industrial purposes, other than solely for hydropower generation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2497B65418A34178B815571B2D9A3C34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is available for reuse for any purpose, regardless or whether the water has been treated to improve the quality of the water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7E42FBC489448FCA9135AAD071A798F"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Enforceability date</header><text>The term <term>Enforceability Date</term> means the date described in section 14(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21544CF021674917928A4B1BE97DBEF1"><enum>(32)</enum><header>Exchange</header><text>The term <term>exchange</term> means a trade between 1 or more persons of any water for any other water, if each person has a right or claim to use the water the person provides in the trade, regardless of whether the water is traded in equal quantities or other consideration is included in the trade.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC360F17144CE41968DAD53ED5A5302D0"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Fourth priority water</header><text>The term <term>fourth priority water</term> means Colorado River water that is available for delivery in the State for the satisfaction of entitlements—</text><subparagraph id="H7339007190974D9DB9A78D155E723EE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with contracts, Secretarial reservations, perfected rights, and other arrangements between the United States and water users in the State entered into or established after September 30, 1968, for use on Federal, State, or privately owned land in the State, in a total quantity of not greater than 164,652 AFY of diversions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF23D4BA937D342C9BC301F992AD27C56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after first providing for the delivery of Colorado River water for the CAP system, including for use on Indian land, under section 304(e) of the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1524">43 U.S.C. 1524(e)</external-xref>), in accordance with the CAP repayment contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF0E541C09D45E2B91C24CB5B610B3D"><enum>(34)</enum><header>Freeport</header><subparagraph id="HEA5AA23C8F0B476998F6CD0DB6F0D643"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Freeport</term> means the Delaware corporation named <quote>Freeport Minerals Corporation</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC857F47EFCA43EA8487FEAD97DD4D08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Freeport</term> includes all subsidiaries, affiliates, successors, and assigns of Freeport Minerals Corporation, including Byner Cattle Company, a Nevada corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46BFB8C2EA0E40B08EB53B8698B4A70B"><enum>(35)</enum><header>Gila river adjudication</header><text>The term <term>Gila River adjudication</term> means the action pending in the Superior Court of the State, in and for the County of Maricopa, In Re the General Adjudication of All Rights To Use Water In The Gila River System and Source, W–1 (Salt), W–2 (Verde), W–3 (Upper Gila), W–4 (San Pedro) (Consolidated).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96008D08B5F47C9A10EE59CFDC7C67A"><enum>(36)</enum><header>Gila river adjudication court</header><text>The term <term>Gila River adjudication court</term> means the Superior Court of the State, in and for the County of Maricopa, exercising jurisdiction over the Gila River adjudication.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB5ABC60F1F648C5872BF675C3BF826D"><enum>(37)</enum><header>Gila river adjudication decree</header><text>The term <term>Gila River adjudication decree</term> means the judgment or decree entered by the Gila River adjudication court in substantially the same form as the form of judgment attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.43.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC1BFE0F3E114FA79C6EE75FEB1BD10F"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Groundwater</header><text>The term <term>groundwater</term> means all water beneath the surface of the Earth within the State that is not—</text><subparagraph id="H027D2DD248BC456E8021A45C14E4FF34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>surface water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60F2570F68274CD8800763BAC382C040"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effluent; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4FBB303EE02465BA3E04FEF7BE553A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Colorado River water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34A81FD22F7E47E6935E01C337BC7D1D"><enum>(39)</enum><header>Hualapai fee land</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai fee land</term> means land, other than Hualapai trust land, that—</text><subparagraph id="HC827A2B74B904A9386983C96142F7D60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located in the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CF74B3845DA4D7E9B0A7DDB712AA05A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is located outside the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation or Hualapai trust land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F2DD3646C374B448621291BD001645A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as of the Enforceability Date, is owned by the Hualapai Tribe, including by a tribally owned corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A18BCDC5834FA9B70559B1E3A7BC98"><enum>(40)</enum><header>Hualapai land</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD5209B47FBCD4A1C9F4119AAC522D36E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Hualapai Reservation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5E0057F19894FBC82EE1DAEFA4CBB3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hualapai trust land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E0DE5B1CCCB4B539A9ECE56EAFA7D49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Hualapai fee land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B850636DA3A400AB4E98401B95B4EB8"><enum>(41)</enum><header>Hualapai reservation</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Reservation</term> means the land within the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, including—</text><subparagraph id="H784F7A769EA2497EA4D51E8FA0874FA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all land withdrawn by the Executive order dated January 4, 1883, as modified by the May 28, 1942, order of the Secretary pursuant to the Act of February 20, 1925 (43 Stat. 954, chapter 273);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D94A4A5EA06435BAB45F2FC67572A85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the land identified by the Executive orders dated December 22, 1898, May 14, 1900, and June 2, 1911; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H068F164658B14E77A908AC485C09AD4D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the land added to the Hualapai Reservation by sections 11 and 12.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H074969F6ECFC45109B6935F444435136"><enum>(42)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Tribe</term> means the Hualapai Tribe, a federally recognized Indian Tribe of Hualapai Indians organized under section 16 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5123">25 U.S.C. 5123</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA867B4108642F29A4DB10D5F6343A1"><enum>(43)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe cap water</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Tribe CAP water</term> means the 4,000 AFY of the CAP NIA priority water that—</text><subparagraph id="HA068CAC043464BAE89B642FA7B1156AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was previously allocated to non-Indian agricultural entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H223B75D65E124FDF8A5674FD4E96C22F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was retained by the Secretary for reallocation to Indian Tribes in the State pursuant to section 104(a)(1)(A)(iii) of the Central Arizona Project Settlement Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/451">Public Law 108–451</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 3487); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BE8051582944DB09FFEC3C8FA345FC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is reallocated to the Hualapai Tribe pursuant to section 13.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC9C8EAE09942649F47336EA159E491"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe water delivery contract</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract</term> means the contract entered into in accordance with the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and section 13(c) for the delivery of Hualapai Tribe CAP water. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A3BC4851D94DE9A98C9E09D26C1936"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe water rights settlement agreement</header><subparagraph id="HCE4FB039FB0A4BDB913C90FC627D4360"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement</term> means the agreement, including exhibits, entitled <quote>Hualapai Tribe Water Rights Settlement Agreement</quote> and dated February 11, 2019.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65B886869DF94D3BACCF63B7A9E34B95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement</term> includes—</text><clause id="H7173B926DDDC40D3A2274D3A08CFE344"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any amendments necessary to make the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement consistent with this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H803E1CA637314F249D8E03AE994ECD28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other amendments approved by the parties to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8924AE476DC4342986BF6EFF7B9AD8F"><enum>(46)</enum><header>Hualapai trust land</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai trust land</term> means land, other than Hualapai fee land, that is—</text><subparagraph id="HC9F4FEB48D544844AE3D9434442BB239"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located—</text><clause id="H0EEA9A61098A4E72924D05DB7B754668"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the State; and</text></clause><clause id="HF55D22ABBDF44C81A9FFFAB82EEFA99D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>outside the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A3891FF85664BD1B77CD4157D902B5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the Enforceability Date, held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H242C3109479D4646B03C33A4667353A3"><enum>(47)</enum><header>Hualapai water project</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Water Project</term> means the project constructed in accordance with section 6(a)(7)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H646D07B392FE4FE9984202B941D376D9"><enum>(48)</enum><header>Hualapai water trust fund account</header><text>The term <term>Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account</term> means the account established under section 6(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB5D32B7E42940C4ACE89999823CAF7F"><enum>(49)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42CA4A3F5F9045B5A5140D99394A1F12"><enum>(50)</enum><header>Injury to water rights</header><subparagraph id="H6679A17F8ADB44BA9EF572F531ED7E00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>injury to water rights</term> means any interference with, diminution of, or deprivation of, a water right under Federal, State, or other law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04E1D755CB964CD0B86E2509E125FFDD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>injury to water rights</term> does not include any injury to water quality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4031EB87210F41B2B825E0B68EED91DA"><enum>(51)</enum><header>Lower basin</header><text>The term <term>lower basin</term> has the meaning given the term in article II(g) of the Colorado River Compact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30AAFA80D68A4C56A0DE48DE57DD937B"><enum>(52)</enum><header>Lower colorado river basin development fund</header><text>The term <term>Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund</term> means the fund established by section 403(a) of the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1543">43 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC873A497BE0E46D8849C9FA0AD2EA773"><enum>(53)</enum><header>Member</header><text>The term <term>member</term> means any person duly enrolled as a member of the Hualapai Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1D320F97C6E473BB025DD98582F082B"><enum>(54)</enum><header>OM&amp;R</header><text>The term <term>OM&amp;R</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H11DEC368E9DE4FA6A670010F9E13D743"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any recurring or ongoing activity relating to the day-to-day operation of a project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52A2D7D8D511463CA045889DD8FCD7C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any activity relating to scheduled or unscheduled maintenance of a project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1467A982EC2C4E2FB82519640117FF4D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any activity relating to replacing a feature of a project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B76340AF9C04CDB924080E873A08122"><enum>(55)</enum><header>Parcel 1</header><text>The term <term>Parcel 1</term> means the parcel of land that is—</text><subparagraph id="H53A1E9894140439D820E35108BF535CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>depicted as 3 contiguous allotments identified as 1A, 1B, and 1C on the map attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC767E77507C49B0ACE215BFABE8F222"><enum>(B)</enum><text>held in trust for certain allottees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H455351FF739F460AB40DE56CF37BC4EF"><enum>(56)</enum><header>Parcel 2</header><text>The term <term>Parcel 2</term> means the parcel of land that is—</text><subparagraph id="H265273E2D556468EB4D95464A6DCC9E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>depicted as <quote>Parcel 2</quote> on the map attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6932A700433B426E993D0D24525579A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>held in trust for certain allottees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6974DF9A86AF43E98BA8BFB52E8B4FCC"><enum>(57)</enum><header>Parcel 3</header><text>The term <term>Parcel 3</term> means the parcel of land that is—</text><subparagraph id="H0CB284E0B77E4DC3A4EC06E2BB261AD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>depicted as <quote>Parcel 3</quote> on the map attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.6;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B946FFC76F843EC9EC7C8070AC59D2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>held in trust for the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2815336FA2043FC889E27CDADCEF814"><enum>(C)</enum><text>part of the Hualapai Reservation pursuant to Executive Order 1368, dated June 2, 1911.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD78585039E4F44B7C3181A30C64B3A"><enum>(58)</enum><header>Party</header><text>The term <term>party</term> means a person that is a signatory to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4CAD772547D43229E184227C311C510"><enum>(59)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6BACF698B94F6785FD7BBB307035D6"><enum>(60)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35CC3CB261604B40A56402B66060C2D4"><enum>(61)</enum><header>Stock watering</header><text>The term <term>stock watering</term> means the watering of livestock, range livestock, or poultry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3C16632B15343A9AFD15FDC6CA4F331"><enum>(62)</enum><header>Surface water</header><text>The term <term>surface water</term> means all water in the State that is appropriable under State law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H156EBF97051E433296788AACBB127623"><enum>(63)</enum><header>Truxton basin</header><text>The term <term>Truxton Basin</term> means the groundwater aquifer described in the report issued by the United States Geological Survey entitled <quote>Groundwater Availability in the Truxton Basin, Northwestern Arizona</quote>, Scientific Investigations Report No. 2020–5017–A.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A00900F5134425B66E7C2BFF5C668D"><enum>(64)</enum><header>Water</header><text>The term <term>water</term>, when used without a modifying adjective, means—</text><subparagraph id="H6DB660D1363C49699D281D3F3A348280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>groundwater;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E6121CEDD5D4CF692F3C6633E710A98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>surface water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C9864EF7E0448C7A220CCF8AA2FD39F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>effluent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51DF16B88A99429AACC74E6EA8E1A965"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Colorado River water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A65D4EAB6AC4E7C99C68825E07A9E8B"><enum>(65)</enum><header>Water right</header><text>The term <term>water right</term> means any right in or to groundwater, surface water, effluent, or Colorado River water under Federal, State, or other law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4297A0E6EED34FB39875C01CDB55155E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ratification and execution of hualapai tribe water rights settlement agreement</header><subsection id="HF0AC3CD0A6AE4AFEA62F89F443CF15A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ratification</header><paragraph id="HC48E03388D62496CBBD384070F6EC10A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as modified by this Act and to the extent the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement does not conflict with this Act, the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement is authorized, ratified, and confirmed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C53FD42315C4CADAEC69BEEF23DABFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>If an amendment to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or to any exhibit attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement requiring the signature of the Secretary, is executed in accordance with this Act to make the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement consistent with this Act, the amendment is authorized, ratified, and confirmed, to the extent the amendment is consistent with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H167D987F3EA94B079D73F9B185D02D53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Execution</header><paragraph id="H6AF0E78FD14742218D489653B5D58D20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement does not conflict with this Act, the Secretary shall execute the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, including all exhibits to, or parts of, the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement requiring the signature of the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB0CE0359AB4CEC93A91D73A08E5AB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>Nothing in this Act prohibits the Secretary from approving any modification to an appendix or exhibit to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement that is consistent with this Act, to the extent the modification does not otherwise require congressional approval under section 2116 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/177">25 U.S.C. 177</external-xref>) or any other applicable provision of Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00937F4896A84EA084CA1E8FE2F13E71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Environmental compliance</header><paragraph id="HF21885BF474644E58D0143180F2CACB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In implementing the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement (including all exhibits to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement requiring the signature of the Secretary) and this Act, the Secretary shall comply with all applicable provisions of—</text><subparagraph id="HCBB98902ADD54E4D9C3BC453AAC10362"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CAE1D77C5114939BFC3910359E61495"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), including the implementing regulations of that Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC51FD8084B0541B8ACE00A3A7CC124A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all other applicable Federal environmental laws and regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC72AFAD11F1B4F0EB7881B72656CC460"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><subparagraph id="H8BD6A5CF71B04C94933411C6AE72609B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In implementing the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, the Hualapai Tribe shall prepare any necessary environmental documents, consistent with all applicable provisions of—</text><clause id="H53A540EECC2C42A0B3AA8A19535F5C9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H4137942634F04B81AA1F66AEA43F9E6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), including the implementing regulations of that Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H39E70CB89749435CA2823F01DDE7C851"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>all other applicable Federal environmental laws and regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A70BA693BD7457FA74B4D678BE2C55E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H62B6E792F77E4A4FA8313127CD471327"><enum>(i)</enum><text>independently evaluate the documentation submitted under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H2B8A3DD04CF54381BB70A6ED97340FD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be responsible for the accuracy, scope, and contents of that documentation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3C80F4DBC104111B025B9798BB20AF4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of execution</header><text>The execution of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement by the Secretary under this section shall not constitute a major action for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC71BB94B632B4F9390D2FE0B1E38A362"><enum>5.</enum><header>Water rights</header><subsection id="HADC8E29EF6244CE4A65A74B2F64AB253"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Water rights To be held in trust</header><paragraph id="H9D200D4EB854426FA8E0DACEFC448452"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe</header><text>The United States shall hold the following water rights in trust for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe:</text><subparagraph id="HE653F3B2ED3243A0817AE069D7CF21DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The water rights for the Hualapai Reservation described in subparagraph 4.2 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B5F9415B08A415EBABD17C2AD1C8514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The water rights for Hualapai trust land described in subparagraph 4.4 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H878528B3290A46DCA2FD2EB96EDD2060"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The water rights described in section 12(e)(2) for any land taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe—</text><clause id="H570EC7EF9C9D4C24A0813754C09CAEFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after the Enforceability Date; and</text></clause><clause id="H25222CCBAD13405986EFFA7389DE2102"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in accordance with section 12(e)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1361E08239A24471A97FD0C5C3CECB9E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>All Hualapai Tribe CAP water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC44A53890B844FCF9EA60E0A4F907BB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allottees</header><text>The United States shall hold in trust for the benefit of the allottees all water rights for the allotments described in subparagraph 4.3.2 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEFB785AA6754550B19D2D40BD9BAE31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forfeiture and abandonment</header><text>The following water rights shall not be subject to loss through non-use, forfeiture, abandonment, or other operation of law:</text><paragraph id="H8E974B0058CB4A7DB6D6BB4D0ED1C27B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The water rights for the Hualapai Reservation described in subparagraph 4.2 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E8DB48A4E641BFADB920343F02B2D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The water rights for Hualapai trust land described in subparagraph 4.4 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9C19E4D60B462D8C0862F4BED52B8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by the Hualapai Tribe wholly or substantially with amounts in the Economic Development Fund described in section 8.1 of the Amended and Restated Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H347499CA685C4801B55EBDB62AA19F9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Alienation</header><text>Any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by the Hualapai Tribe wholly or substantially with amounts in the Economic Development Fund described in section 8.1 of the Amended and Restated Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement shall be restricted against permanent alienation by the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98A577B966D8472386D995805F1E5486"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe cap water</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe shall have the right to divert, use, and store the Hualapai Tribe CAP water in accordance with section 13.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C571E1AAE8D429784FDD886852890FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Colorado river water entitlements</header><paragraph id="H1C45BFC4B64E4D4C96FA4F57241E34FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe shall have the right to use any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by or donated to the Hualapai Tribe at the location to which the entitlement is appurtenant on the date on which the entitlement is purchased or donated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0205CDF647F4A9A89971670A4200AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Storage</header><subparagraph id="H8BD0D59477F1436B91B23EBCA118481C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (5), the Hualapai Tribe may store Colorado River water available under any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by or donated to the Hualapai Tribe at underground storage facilities or groundwater savings facilities located within the State and in accordance with State law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12C1973B88143D6B0E41C420ED8DDF7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assignments</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may assign any long-term storage credits accrued as a result of storage under subparagraph (A) in accordance with State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB850B6D09BDE426282137A6A658ED294"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfers</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may transfer the entitlement for use or storage under paragraph (1) or (2), respectively, to another location within the State, including the Hualapai Reservation, in accordance with the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and all applicable Federal and State laws governing the transfer of Colorado River water entitlements within the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD29DE25C85FF4621911520B79F3D7A50"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Leases</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may lease any Colorado River water entitlement for use or storage under paragraph (1) or (2), respectively, to a water user within the State, in accordance with the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and all applicable Federal and State laws governing the transfer of Colorado River water entitlements within the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FCA9AA937F6400A8B2B7EA907F59072"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transports</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe, or any person who leases a Colorado River water entitlement from the Hualapai Tribe under paragraph (4), may transport Colorado River water available under the Colorado River water entitlement through the Central Arizona Project in accordance with all laws of the United States and the agreements between the United States and the Central Arizona Water Conservation District governing the use of the Central Arizona Project to transport water other than CAP water.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EE263941CED4C74B7B5D8BFEC02298B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use off-Reservation</header><text>No water rights to groundwater under the Hualapai Reservation or Hualapai trust land, or to surface water on the Hualapai Reservation or Hualapai trust land, may be sold, leased, transferred, or used outside the boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation or Hualapai trust land, other than under an exchange.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8AFFE23DAAC94B4F9711ACB031263D52"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Groundwater transportation</header><paragraph id="HD464013BFCC34AF08F1724C7F7FFC9A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fee land</header><text>Groundwater may be transported in accordance with State law away from Hualapai fee land and away from land acquired in fee by the Hualapai Tribe, including by a tribally owned corporation, after the Enforceability Date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD78C280AE7BB4EB5A831A147E8B181E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land added to hualapai reservation</header><text>Groundwater may be transported in accordance with State law away from land added to the Hualapai Reservation by sections 11 and 12 to other land within the Hualapai Reservation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H947E71C42AE14BD097DA3D8250D9298E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Hualapai water trust fund account; construction of hualapai water project; funding</header><subsection id="H45A3887B86B24F049AEB33AF5ECFF6EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hualapai water trust fund account</header><paragraph id="H9E80BE3E851E4218AFAFAAE360866A78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a trust fund account, to be known as the <term>Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account</term>, to be managed, invested, and distributed by the Secretary and to remain available until expended, withdrawn, or reverted to the general fund of the Treasury, consisting of the amounts deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account under paragraph (2), together with any interest earned on those amounts, for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CBB12C4789248119B9EC111C48E7C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>The Secretary shall deposit in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account the amounts made available pursuant to section 7(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F011CA6D1E14DF484AF9A32B0703A1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management and interest</header><subparagraph id="HB63118466BC24C11AD38FEB2A4D61C56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Management</header><text>On receipt and deposit of funds into the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account, the Secretary shall manage, invest, and distribute all amounts in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account in a manner that is consistent with the investment authority of the Secretary under—</text><clause id="HEE527E38EC2B479BA30526B72DD0A402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the first section of the Act of June 24, 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/162a">25 U.S.C. 162a</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H7A5BB915C600455AACD79E507CDFD706"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the American Indian Trust Fund Management Reform Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4001">25 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H76B891CEFE24452290658AC3ECD97987"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EFE3175D71847948ED0F764522D635E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investment earnings</header><text>In addition to the deposits made to the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account under paragraph (2), any investment earnings, including interest, credited to amounts held in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account are authorized to be used in accordance with paragraph (7).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35205EF347374317AA5214D0D758F4AF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability of amounts</header><subparagraph id="HD8774D300416476FBB7C18FB43C17434"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts appropriated to, and deposited in, the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account, including any investment earnings, shall be made available to the Hualapai Tribe by the Secretary beginning on the Enforceability Date, subject to the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93197FB937EC4EE3AB334CE126288026"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), amounts deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account shall be available to the Hualapai Tribe on the date on which the amounts are deposited for environmental compliance, as provided in section 8.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H729DEE6E97D04541A258CA901A1C00E4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><subparagraph id="H722A31FE9AE74109A7BEA1C695E66E64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Withdrawals under the american indian trust fund management reform act of 1994</header><clause id="HE025C907A0E642E693209FA83C6575B6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may withdraw any portion of the amounts in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account on approval by the Secretary of a Tribal management plan submitted by the Tribe in accordance with the American Indian Trust Fund Management Reform Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4001">25 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H9A703519C6B7493D84EAC6BFFED49D3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In addition to the requirements under the American Indian Trust Fund Management Reform Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4001">25 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Tribal management plan under this subparagraph shall require that the Hualapai Tribe spend all amounts withdrawn from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account and any investment earnings accrued through the investments under the Tribal management plan in accordance with this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H933081B2BA534592B0556F855223DDFE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary may carry out such judicial and administrative actions as the Secretary determines to be necessary to enforce the Tribal management plan under this subparagraph to ensure that amounts withdrawn by the Hualapai Tribe from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account under clause (i) are used in accordance with this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D73EC7A3C93486AB3E6DDE03F2F7B91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Withdrawals under expenditure plan</header><clause id="HB34B1FBD62DB4D9ABEB740F4B752A3BF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may submit to the Secretary a request to withdraw funds from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account pursuant to an approved expenditure plan.</text></clause><clause id="H2673F6AB80E34D93A046FC265BE203A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>To be eligible to withdraw amounts under an expenditure plan under this subparagraph, the Hualapai Tribe shall submit to the Secretary an expenditure plan for any portion of the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account that the Hualapai Tribe elects to withdraw pursuant to this subparagraph, subject to the condition that the amounts shall be used for the purposes described in this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H3DD03E3E6B2343E297E7549513CC6599"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>An expenditure plan under this subparagraph shall include a description of the manner and purpose for which the amounts proposed to be withdrawn from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account will be used by the Hualapai Tribe, in accordance with paragraph (7).</text></clause><clause id="H98D48157BBD84DE7B177EDC5772F99BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The Secretary shall approve an expenditure plan submitted under clause (ii) if the Secretary determines that the plan—</text><subclause id="H7DAD460DB512469C93F437E835441553"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is reasonable; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5E455DF4C0F34602A98E33007A980A5B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is consistent with, and will be used for, the purposes of this Act.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5FC95A2B740E4FDB9B1E6657732E33CC"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary may carry out such judicial and administrative actions as the Secretary determines to be necessary to enforce an expenditure plan to ensure that amounts disbursed under this subparagraph are used in accordance with this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3516D64E17047A780FFF729922EA91F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect of title</header><text>Nothing in this section gives the Hualapai Tribe the right to judicial review of a determination of the Secretary relating to whether to approve a Tribal management plan under paragraph (5)(A) or an expenditure plan under paragraph (5)(B) except under subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFA587F22DF74FBCB0B2325DBA549525"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>Amounts from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account shall be used by the Hualapai Tribe—</text><subparagraph id="H3F4A43F22BC84895BD6A2200A9E3217B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to plan, design, construct, and conduct related activities, including compliance with Federal environmental laws under section 8, the Hualapai Water Project, which shall be designed to divert, treat, and convey up to 3,414 AFY of water from the Colorado River in the lower basin in the State, including locations on or directly adjacent to the Hualapai Reservation, for municipal, commercial, and industrial uses on the Hualapai Reservation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB3F7A39705649268CE4828CF5288C28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to perform OM&amp;R on the Hualapai Water Project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H926F4DEFCA224AA0AFDCDBDA9EC7F869"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to construct facilities to transport electrical power to pump water for the Hualapai Water Project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA00C2FC42220446188F18929F9FC760D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to construct, repair, and replace such infrastructure as may be necessary for groundwater wells on the Hualapai Reservation and to construct infrastructure for delivery and use of such groundwater on the Hualapai Reservation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8B71EFB667E4AA681BD60600FC43776"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to acquire land, interests in land, and water rights outside the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation that are located in the Truxton Basin;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5489104E2BD34953A136CB090747DAD4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to reimburse the Hualapai Tribe for any—</text><clause id="HF508684EC08346C2A733ECACEC5D18BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>planning, design, and engineering costs associated with the Hualapai Water Project that the Hualapai Tribe incurs using Tribal funds during the period—</text><subclause id="H9C21A7F0BDEE44869A971F07CB9D31E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H33E8D7A42A914C8DB2331453E73A2943"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the Enforceability Date; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H142B3C4C20674FAD8473960571C2C161"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>construction costs associated with the Hualapai Water Project that the Hualapai Tribe incurs using Tribal funds during the period—</text><subclause id="HCB657B3D741D4DBFA9DA87DB870B712E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on the date on which the Secretary issues a record of decision; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H358C66E44A1D4AB0A0C41046721EEF8C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the Enforceability Date; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18A457822A7E4AEAB90C2758EC37840E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to make contributions to the Economic Development Fund described in section 8.1 of the Amended and Restated Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement for the purpose of purchasing additional Colorado River water entitlements and appurtenant land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A5DC7BAA79E42D4AAAA2A5F0E8912EC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of the Treasury shall not be liable for the expenditure or investment of any amounts withdrawn from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account by the Hualapai Tribe under paragraph (5).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H838AD6CE77CE4E3380D0B58D9CEA5379"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Title to infrastructure</header><text>Title to, control over, and operation of any project constructed using funds from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account shall remain in the Hualapai Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2951D3DF0E143948F5B782374250784"><enum>(10)</enum><header>OM&amp;R</header><text>All OM&amp;R costs of any project constructed using funds from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account shall be the responsibility of the Hualapai Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C6B19467F5426EBD60C83D0E12640E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>No per capita distributions</header><text>No portion of the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account shall be distributed on a per capita basis to any member of the Hualapai Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF4190D692D4F1F8501AEAC4D7765DC"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Expenditure reports</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe shall annually submit to the Secretary an expenditure report describing accomplishments and amounts spent from use of withdrawals under a Tribal management plan or an expenditure plan under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA5A2752FF064D70B22434077E1EEF34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hualapai Water Settlement Implementation Fund Account</header><paragraph id="H487A5974AF5540FEB16C01ACE1205214"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a nontrust, interest-bearing account, to be known as the <term>Hualapai Water Settlement Implementation Fund Account</term> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Implementation Fund Account</quote>) to be managed and distributed by the Secretary, for use by the Secretary for carrying out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EE6A032CC38440DB5843FD5E0EC5D28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>The Secretary shall deposit in the Implementation Fund Account the amounts made available pursuant to section 7(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD524848EAF343009BAD7183C79D3AC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Implementation Fund Account shall be used by the Secretary to carry out section 15(c), including for groundwater monitoring in the Truxton Basin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F288FC843F419980793A923D9C28A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interest</header><text>In addition to the deposits under paragraph (2), any investment earnings, including interest, credited to amounts unexpended in the Implementation Fund Account are authorized to be appropriated to be used in accordance with paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE7315445F6C41298840316E282834BD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header><subsection id="H2FCD05E6146C4321B6715347B5738408"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><paragraph id="H9434470C9F2746C59A7ED5D9705865A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hualapai water trust fund account</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for deposit in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account $180,000,000, to be available until expended, withdrawn, or reverted to the general fund of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F6EDAB18E04A52846ABE847556EF6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hualapai water settlement implementation fund account</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for deposit in the Hualapai Water Settlement Implementation Fund account established by section 6(b)(1) $5,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H075BBAB7B9BA40A7A624ABA89AA6EB01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fluctuation in costs</header><paragraph id="HAC4EC4D6FACA4886B2F056AE87D37AE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a)(1) shall be increased or decreased, as appropriate, by such amounts as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuations in costs occurring after the date of enactment of this Act, as indicated by the Bureau of Reclamation Construction Cost Index—Composite Trend. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAED3AF232D43B68BB03B2C9C0A165E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction costs adjustment</header><text>The amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a)(1) shall be adjusted to address construction cost changes necessary to account for unforeseen market volatility that may not otherwise be captured by engineering cost indices as determined by the Secretary, including repricing applicable to the types of construction and current industry standards involved.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2761E1C4EC064286838B4B657721564C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repetition</header><text>The adjustment process under this subsection shall be repeated for each subsequent amount appropriated until the amount authorized, as adjusted, has been appropriated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7253F4763A84DC6A7296A794221D56E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period of indexing</header><text>The period of indexing adjustment for any increment of funding shall end on the date on which the funds are deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1094439EF10A422AA7FFCEDA5FDD9426"><enum>8.</enum><header>Environmental compliance</header><subsection id="HE194229C80764349A645A46E74C51F9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of deposit of funds in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account, the Hualapai Tribe may commence any environmental, cultural, and historical compliance activities necessary to implement the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, including activities necessary to comply with all applicable provisions of—</text><paragraph id="H015E960A578F44988A0D6C803142775C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0500B0D9DE7140F3A684C26FF24B5334"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), including the implementing regulations of that Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE7C72F434B24BE4835004D4E8D81ADE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all other applicable Federal environmental or historical and cultural protection laws and regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1656E5F126814099AF4AC9A70B7491EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on outcome</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects or directs the outcome of any analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other applicable Federal environmental or historical and cultural protection law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC11AEF1E80004849B77981985FA23398"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance costs</header><text>Any costs associated with the performance of the compliance activities under subsection (a) shall be paid from funds deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account, subject to the condition that any costs associated with the performance of Federal approval or other review of such compliance work or costs associated with inherently Federal functions shall remain the responsibility of the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA39B736E1B13450F9E4FEFB3919CC4D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Record of decision</header><text>Construction of the Hualapai Water Project shall not commence until the Secretary issues a record of decision after completion of an environmental impact statement for the Hualapai Water Project.</text></subsection><subsection id="H133CF0819BDA4843AB7BD67AF872D86F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction costs</header><text>Any costs of construction incurred by the Hualapai Tribe during the period beginning on the date on which the Secretary issues a record of decision and ending on the Enforceability Date shall be paid by the Hualapai Tribe and not from funds deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account, subject to the condition that, pursuant to section 6(a)(7)(F), the Hualapai Tribe may be reimbursed after the Enforceability Date from the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account for any such costs of construction incurred by the Hualapai Tribe prior to the Enforceability Date.</text></subsection></section><section id="H015560F65BBB4C3EB2A83667ED7931DB"><enum>9.</enum><header>Waivers, releases, and retentions of claims</header><subsection id="HB45C4AAD45CE4D7788ADB4638D202B88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waivers and releases of claims by the hualapai tribe</header><paragraph id="HC851D9C0181744BEB38E7F78187F24D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claims against the state and others</header><subparagraph id="HBD044965FE2A49CB90526A69871B7321"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Hualapai Tribe, on behalf of the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees) and the United States, acting as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees), as part of the performance of the respective obligations of the Hualapai Tribe and the United States under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, are authorized to execute a waiver and release of any claims against the State (or any agency or political subdivision of the State) and any other individual, entity, corporation, or municipal corporation under Federal, State, or other law for all—</text><clause id="H706567EEC17947ECB24CA5CE2DA39472"><enum>(i)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, for Hualapai land, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever;</text></clause><clause id="HE44D6D4F91A741D0818B97B4627A2863"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the Hualapai Tribe, the predecessors of the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, or predecessors of the members of the Hualapai Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="HD687623EA249460E885E331162379704"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>past and present claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, for Hualapai land, arising from time immemorial through the Enforceability Date;</text></clause><clause id="H1AD398FD660649CE80CCFEC7168C4A45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the Hualapai Tribe, the predecessors of the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, or predecessors of the members of the Hualapai Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H866F4BD320DD41B1A26F1937F561FFBD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising after the Enforceability Date, for Hualapai land, resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of surface water, Colorado River water, or effluent in a manner not in violation of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or State law;</text></clause><clause id="H17F8443ABFAB45B58E3F6069D35EF45E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims arising out of, or relating in any manner to, the negotiation, execution, or adoption of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or this Act;</text></clause><clause id="HE4CA1056439C4EDBBCA517DFB201BE15"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>claims for water rights of the Hualapai Tribe or the United States, acting as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and members of the Hualapai Tribe, with respect to Parcel 3, in excess of 300 AFY;</text></clause><clause id="H180A2FC2F2F5412194D67C9760F64E01"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of groundwater from—</text><subclause id="HA1DBCA1D64A34B4691192ED35E1C32A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed outside of the Truxton Basin on or before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="H459311736D704884A7522C33AA12000F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed outside of the Truxton Basin, and not more than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, after the date of enactment of this Act if—</text><item id="H533EC8DA96144463957D7D52A5A13CDF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; </text></item><item id="HDA0A505A8A3B4F609965275C5014D842"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></item><item id="HD77F9D7E22C64692A75C7A971A188FFD"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H6459030657254344B14B8EC2B4AB20F4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any well constructed outside the Truxton Basin, and not less than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to the condition that the authorizations and restrictions regarding the location, size, and operation of wells in the Bill Williams River watershed set forth in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act, and the waivers of claims in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act, shall continue to apply to the parties to the Bill Williams agreements, notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF33913050BD2442382F97A1CA23ACCE2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date, for Hualapai land, resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of groundwater in the Truxton Basin from—</text><subclause id="HC187946FA21A4EBDBAF713224FF9431E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed within the Truxton Basin for domestic purposes or stock watering—</text><item id="H8AB729245FCE4E8AA539F626935676DC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on or before the date on which the Secretary provides written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2); or </text></item><item id="HBC647729FAD24661B70D902EE8082514"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after the date on which the Secretary provides written notice to the State pursuant to that section if—</text><subitem id="H15CFA2345C2B41DABD0DF36FE07D2286"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the date on which the notice was provided;</text></subitem><subitem id="H6D7BFCDE459D433C97343026DC2DD541"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></subitem><subitem id="HC2C0C14DC7844471B3ED22B9DD62F82F"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HCDFE4D9DD4B04C68B72326071274DE84"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed within the Truxton Basin for purposes other than domestic purposes or stock watering—</text><item id="H013D302D781C4F219D9113DB3E0E2AE1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on or before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></item><item id="H92F8FD92D93F44968B5E9031A03EC13F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary has not provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2); or</text></item><item id="HBB8442CDCF204FEC9747E8213BC0A826"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary has provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2) and if—</text><subitem id="HCB8DA6F6DF8D4868BE72B5317A044777"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the on which date the notice was provided; </text></subitem><subitem id="H8B536BECCABC45509572DEDBD86567A2"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></subitem><subitem id="HB5EEE5E5A01249B8B34FE7F6100807B4"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1B98595E884B96AC6FA4054AD7D27E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The waiver and release of claims described in subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the Enforceability Date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H982EA4D82BB947E0A6EAA4E6EB4E22F2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reservation of rights and retention of claims</header><text>Notwithstanding the waiver and release of claims described in subparagraph (A), the Hualapai Tribe, acting on behalf of the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe, and the United States, acting as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees), shall retain any right—</text><clause id="HAB5AC1B3F67F49F7ADCFA9F091D86E60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph 12.7 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or this Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="HE043585D1E8D43ECB435B094A635F6C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></clause><clause id="H5BDF6B1EB7DA4361B2C22A6B6DEEB527"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to assert claims for water rights based on State law for land owned or acquired by the Hualapai Tribe in fee, under subparagraph 4.8 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></clause><clause id="HAB89836B20514D4084D38149E775E39E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to object to any claims for water rights or injury to water rights by or for any Indian Tribe or the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="HE7AF32D4081A42CC96B76AA33BE49CA9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to assert past, present, or future claims for injury to water rights against any Indian Tribe or the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H150A453997A84C6F830F30918B39D798"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under the Bill Williams agreements or the Bill Williams Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="HB67924C9D4724BD4AD1DE6FA42191F3A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>subject to paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (5) of section 5(e), to assert the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by or donated to the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F6BA961DDD84A6184ECB4BA9117C2C3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to assert claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land resulting from any off-reservation diversion or use of groundwater, without regard to quantity, from—</text><subclause id="H3C50CFFD86074C9096E07BF1CCF08EBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed after the date of enactment of this Act outside of the Truxton Basin and not more than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, except a replacement well described in subparagraph (A)(viii)(II), subject to the authorizations and restrictions regarding the location, size, and operation of wells in the Bill Williams River watershed, and the waivers of claims, set forth in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="H25F722284B2946D18E8AAEEAA17C70BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed within the Truxton Basin for domestic purposes or stock watering after the date on which the Secretary has provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2), except for a replacement well described in subparagraph (A)(ix)(I)(bb); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0379F80FA03F4FB5BF0DBEB146502A56"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any well constructed within the Truxton Basin for purposes other than domestic purposes or stock watering after the date of enactment of this Act, if the Secretary has provided notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2), except for a replacement well as described in subparagraph (A)(ix)(II)(cc).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D95BEF6CE8540E99C9C178EE52E4865"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claims against united states</header><subparagraph id="H663BB145BF5B4DAB847E911970FB16F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Hualapai Tribe, acting on behalf of the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees) as part of the performance of the obligations of the Hualapai Tribe under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, is authorized to execute a waiver and release of all claims against the United States, including agencies, officials, and employees of the United States, under Federal, State, or other law for all—</text><clause id="HD8E00939BAEC4245A1616DD2235B2456"><enum>(i)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, for Hualapai land, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever;</text></clause><clause id="H4C2D295987C14C3C82B54726D8BF24D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the Hualapai Tribe, the predecessors of the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, or predecessors of the members of the Hualapai Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H0276CF2AAB1B4584ACAF229E484F62F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>past and present claims relating in any manner to damages, losses, or injury to water rights (including injury to rights to Colorado River water), land, or other resources due to loss of water or water rights (including damages, losses, or injuries to hunting, fishing, gathering, or cultural rights due to loss of water or water rights, claims relating to interference with, diversion, or taking of water, or claims relating to the failure to protect, acquire, or develop water, water rights, or water infrastructure) within the State that first accrued at any time prior to the Enforceability Date;</text></clause><clause id="H259A76BCDD0141E4BE49362CC11A07FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>past and present claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, for Hualapai land, arising from time immemorial through the Enforceability Date;</text></clause><clause id="H96BD44DB0AB74B1A800B9C2A7B278868"><enum>(v)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the Hualapai Tribe, the predecessors of the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, or predecessors of the members of the Hualapai Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H0F0789000BD9494DBDEAC8D6A70BE384"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land, resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of surface water, Colorado River water, or effluent in a manner not in violation of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or State law;</text></clause><clause id="H83926F1705324D1BA67FAA2B8022103F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims arising out of, or relating in any manner to, the negotiation, execution, or adoption of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or this Act;</text></clause><clause id="H8F711A17002B426693BDD16A3C1601A6"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land resulting from the off-Reservation diversion or use of groundwater from—</text><subclause id="H6BD6CEEE273147C3AE71A3D3D97F6A60"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land outside of the Truxton Basin on or before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9A4706F02AF2400CA989ECDC4D07D489"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land outside of the Truxton Basin, and not more than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, after the date of enactment of this Act if—</text><item id="H972E4309CF6943EE91C55D9E12747D01"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the date of enactment of this Act;</text></item><item id="HEE760B74BBEA47EC98D8CD1DBCA5EBBC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></item><item id="HBC94934EEB764D29BB0D7999C8A5E303"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H4FADD1B51DA54C1F91C9B35D93A5D89B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land outside of the Truxton Basin, and not less than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to the condition that the authorizations and restrictions regarding the location, size, and operation of wells in the Bill Williams River watershed set forth in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act, and the waivers of claims in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act, shall continue to apply to the parties to the Bill Williams agreements, notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEF02CAC1F1B747BC94BFC3DA98F07D12"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of groundwater in the Truxton Basin from—</text><subclause id="H838FFE3B282445008501D3A8EFD06277"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land within the Truxton Basin for domestic purposes or stock watering—</text><item id="HBB4D1C1B292A485BB668F2B2B146C53B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on or before the date on which the Secretary provides written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2); or </text></item><item id="HCBD4AF8663B24B15A6498CCDAAC098BF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after the date on which the Secretary provides written notice to the State pursuant to that section if—</text><subitem id="HE2C9C5F0D0B74D79A732321FA2F60EF9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the date on which the notice was provided;</text></subitem><subitem id="H4FDCA9A5D7CC4F41AD69D9C479DCB515"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></subitem><subitem id="H9DE6C66A3AF345308BDC97FE603B2797"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H9B003595B7B4464499E159D7D69A4343"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land within the Truxton Basin for purposes other than domestic purposes or stock watering—</text><item id="H00865F437F2548869FBDFACBA1947B2D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on or before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></item><item id="H236B130959F144DEBF902374744F7E20"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary has not provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2); or</text></item><item id="HBE50150E7EC744EB91C0F4A44E282B82"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary has provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2) and if—</text><subitem id="HB757662198DC4464970DFA40F39B6B96"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the well was constructed to replace a well in existence on the date on which the notice was provided; </text></subitem><subitem id="H6F09293B66D143EA9441D6941BE1C79F"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the replacement well was constructed within 660 feet of the well being replaced; and </text></subitem><subitem id="HA7F8A51C10474AFC9FCDF9FE9F60ACE3"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the pumping capacity and case diameter of the replacement well do not exceed the pumping capacity and case diameter of the well being replaced.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31E2DBC9FA1744AF94C09687C332AD3F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The waiver and release of claims described in subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the Enforceability Date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE44B500BCC04FA9A661E8C766EF1990"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention of claims</header><text>Notwithstanding the waiver and release of claims described in subparagraph (A), the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees) shall retain any right—</text><clause id="HA49154CA7A29497D97A947FEF59475B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph 12.7 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or this Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="H01F85A09FD7F437FB76055730B45D8EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></clause><clause id="HBAD27C39F5904AC19DDF189596838C4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to assert claims for water rights based on State law for land owned or acquired by the Hualapai Tribe in fee under subparagraph 4.8 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></clause><clause id="HE8B0371685484B12B9196DB8A6C83255"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to object to any claims for water rights or injury to water rights by or for any Indian Tribe or the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H8B8511B7B663426BB47586FDA8A5F3E1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to assert past, present, or future claims for injury to water rights against any Indian Tribe or the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe;</text></clause><clause id="H9BC20E228CCE45E39DABBB8E2709E358"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under the Bill Williams agreements or the Bill Williams Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="H1746812561684C7CA7F35B98066D567B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>subject to paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (5) of section 5(e), to assert the rights of the Hualapai Tribe under any Colorado River water entitlement purchased by or donated to the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></clause><clause id="H9D62A4C1BE89497B83C670E116A89642"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to assert any claims for injury to water rights arising after the Enforceability Date for Hualapai land resulting from any off-reservation diversion or use of groundwater, without regard to quantity, from—</text><subclause id="H59AEC13F18AC4E5DBD6E36A8CA3D1BE4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any well constructed after the date of enactment of this Act on public domain land outside of the Truxton Basin and not more than 2 miles from the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation, except for a replacement well described in subparagraph (A)(viii)(II), subject to the authorizations and restrictions regarding the location, size, and operation of wells in the Bill Williams River watershed, and the waivers of claims, set forth in the Bill Williams agreements and the Bill Williams Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7665B5C5D55B485FA3211D50548F9E74"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land within the Truxton Basin for domestic purposes or stock watering after the date on which the Secretary has provided written notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2), except for a replacement well described in subparagraph (A)(ix)(I)(bb); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H54355980BE2846C18CB67C09627413C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any well constructed on public domain land within the Truxton Basin for purposes other than domestic purposes or stock watering after the date of enactment of this Act, if the Secretary has provided notice to the State pursuant to section 15(c)(2), except for a replacement well as described in subparagraph (A)(ix)(II)(cc).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AAC11D1513B4E5D803466AF84221A01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waivers and releases of claims by united states, acting as trustee for allottees</header><paragraph id="HA31EBB993B9F45D7BE4A9FE8874BFF51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the United States, acting as trustee for the allottees of the Hualapai Tribe, as part of the performance of the obligations of the United States under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, is authorized to execute a waiver and release of any claims against the State (or any agency or political subdivision of the State), the Hualapai Tribe, and any other individual, entity, corporation, or municipal corporation under Federal, State, or other law, for all—</text><subparagraph id="HDE0E51CFDC2645FDB36D065F683AF8DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, for the allotments, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A42F7106914115B96673F088E933C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for water rights, including rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the allottees or predecessors of the allottees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7D40E019124DB18B96689548582D32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>past and present claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, for the allotments, arising from time immemorial through the Enforceability Date;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H608598DF08DD49D8AEC48437AB3C607B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims for injury to water rights, if any, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising from time immemorial and, thereafter, forever, that are based on the aboriginal occupancy of land by the allottees or predecessors of the allottees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89D7940583E84931A5A6C4B32A2CBCAF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising after the Enforceability Date, for the allotments, resulting from the off-reservation diversion or use of water in a manner not in violation of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or State law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE46906F8D142958B704DCEFD9AD410"><enum>(F)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims arising out of, or relating in any manner to, the negotiation, execution, or adoption of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H457716ED9E17499EAD1EBE37653D20E9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>claims for any water rights of the allottees or the United States acting as trustee for the allottees with respect to—</text><clause id="H1A488985A56147D986BCAB9F8C5147B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Parcel 1, in excess of 82 AFY; or</text></clause><clause id="HD09E27F3C3AC48B9B9CA88C89978FA2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Parcel 2, in excess of 312 AFY.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C491AE2668461B838D65B60525B7E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The waiver and release of claims under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the Enforceability Date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B9A1CB97F4A4B0081BBF868C67F4FC3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retention of claims</header><text>Notwithstanding the waiver and release of claims described in paragraph (1), the United States, acting as trustee for the allottees of the Hualapai Tribe, shall retain any right—</text><subparagraph id="H9D33F2E27CE7452688EA870F7B8A7B52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph 12.7 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the allottees, if any, under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or this Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2626C926B26F4CAE8B392DC415B89129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the allottees under any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B035B8B044C434DBF0C5FB979B9A39D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to object to any claims for water rights or injury to water rights by or for—</text><clause id="H83413B2F7D7C4DC691679098083CC5CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe; or</text></clause><clause id="H4FFFA7686691416B88A2D648DB68313D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D6C3FFE67684F6C97B38CED6F454F94"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to assert past, present, or future claims for injury to water rights against—</text><clause id="H00B55275B01E4D659E6D02ECF5531A8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe; or</text></clause><clause id="H3E33475F401F46F3A20DA5866C1BE5B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States, acting on behalf of any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04F5BC8F0E644810BF6BF613D75F7EBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to assert claims for injuries to, and seek enforcement of, the rights of the allottees under the Bill Williams agreements or the Bill Williams Act in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50290A89EC4C430EB72C2C63A22BF1BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver and release of claims by united states against hualapai tribe</header><paragraph id="H4954DC77A4E64F439EAB982B3604F0DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the United States, in all capacities (except as trustee for an Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe), as part of the performance of the obligations of the United States under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and this Act, is authorized to execute a waiver and release of all claims against the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, or any agency, official, or employee of the Hualapai Tribe, under Federal, State or any other law for all—</text><subparagraph id="H99E11A50080840B8B41DA15D30D5D7A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>past and present claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, resulting from the diversion or use of water on Hualapai land arising from time immemorial through the Enforceability Date;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H029344DB77574AEFBEFD81887159A220"><enum>(B)</enum><text>claims for injury to water rights, including injury to rights to Colorado River water, arising after the Enforceability Date, resulting from the diversion or use of water on Hualapai land in a manner that is not in violation of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or State law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E2B957CF5C44CA89871E006FCE5C69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>past, present, and future claims arising out of, or related in any manner to, the negotiation, execution, or adoption of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, any judgment or decree approving or incorporating the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37927D6C9BD24923B1F5E3420082BFDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The waiver and release of claims under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the Enforceability Date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90D51DE7A1B74209A65D78B12E12AB71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retention of claims</header><text>Notwithstanding the waiver and release of claims described in paragraph (1), the United States shall retain any right to assert any claim not expressly waived in accordance with that paragraph, including any right to assert a claim for injury to, and seek enforcement of, any right of the United States under the Bill Williams agreements or the Bill Williams Act, in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H545A17938FEE457EA07C5FCFF02D9273"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bill williams river phase 2 water rights settlement agreement waiver, release, and retention of claims</header><paragraph id="HB5C584AE0AD1420CA507589056EC9025"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claims against freeport</header><subparagraph id="HA932A5211E9F4E7690F68F01A86A4E9F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the United States, acting solely on behalf of the Department of the Interior (including the Bureau of Land Management and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service), as part of the performance of the obligations of the United States under the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, is authorized to execute a waiver and release of all claims of the United States against Freeport under Federal, State, or any other law for—</text><clause id="HA81C380D67D1431E942B9B3BBAA9944E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any past or present claim for injury to water rights resulting from—</text><subclause id="H4B98BD456E944109B6C9EE94FE1C39E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the diversion or use of water by Freeport pursuant to the water rights described in Exhibit 4.1(ii) to the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H79AE6F1074434F8AAA9F74C344EF6B51"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other diversion or use of water for mining purposes authorized by the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8A65230E3B974A2D81875E5283C8E4C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any claim for injury to water rights arising after the Bill Williams River Phase 2 Enforceability Date resulting from—</text><subclause id="H1507067317A342228585BA4FDC859F43"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the diversion or use of water by Freeport pursuant to the water rights described in Exhibit 4.1(ii) to the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement in a manner not in violation of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA6BA530C15864D6C95D94158C7DC5923"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the diversion of up to 2,500 AFY of water by Freeport from Sycamore Creek as permitted by section 4.3(iv) of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2A488A790BCF4A92B981F4D38BE12177"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other diversion or use of water by Freeport authorized by the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, subject to the condition that such a diversion and use of water is conducted in a manner not in violation of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C4F07586AB04EAEB9A6E4D23FDA6A72"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any past, present, or future claim arising out of, or relating in any manner to, the negotiation or execution of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, or this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H018FC716ED5C4AB682F4B8452545B633"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The waiver and release of claims under subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the Bill Williams River Phase 2 Enforceability Date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F76F52B43B3439C96CC8087991CC38D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention of claims</header><text>The United States shall retain all rights not expressly waived in the waiver and release of claims under subparagraph (A), including, subject to section 6.4 of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, the right to assert a claim for injury to, and seek enforcement of, the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement or this Act, in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction (but not a Tribal court).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED4F99D7FA54A6ABCE0919C624BD351"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No precedential effect</header><subparagraph id="H2D11E7A33EDA492D927FC3815F88FE46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Pending and future proceedings</header><text>The Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement shall have no precedential effect in any other administrative or judicial proceeding, including—</text><clause id="HF247467075954C0091970C3557C7C2EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any pending or future general stream adjudication, or any other litigation involving Freeport or the United States, including any proceeding to establish or quantify a Federal reserved water right;</text></clause><clause id="H138AB46694094DD6B1FC925C3A34C70D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any pending or future administrative or judicial proceeding relating to an application—</text><subclause id="H4C952343693C4E2296946F1DA96C5C5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to appropriate water (for instream flow or other purposes);</text></subclause><subclause id="H776C2F4EA1DB4DE786233B7746457CB0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to sever and transfer a water right;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0B8E0AE3EC8140F496E2C225E6B83594"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to change a point of diversion; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H315E2914B3234F88956E8DA34DA94A57"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to change a place of use for any water right; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1694F497427647BFA0B70478DA3BE20C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any proceeding regarding water rights or a claim relating to any Federal land.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8EB4949FBEF411BBFDD2B0233AEA9E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No methodology or standard</header><text>Nothing in the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement establishes any standard or methodology to be used for the quantification of any claim to water rights (whether based on Federal or State law) in any judicial or administrative proceeding, other than a proceeding to enforce the terms of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H39A1240BCA1D4DACBE6D65D99150AEDE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Satisfaction of water rights and other benefits</header><subsection id="H0FF6A7E649A94200864D46F59B286D8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe and members</header><paragraph id="H18567FE2F3DF44FEA47D7184086EA982"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The benefits realized by the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees) under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, this Act, the Bill Williams agreements, and the Bill Williams Act shall be in full satisfaction of all claims of the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, and the United States, acting in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe, for water rights and injury to water rights under Federal, State, or other law with respect to Hualapai land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31DB36342CF462391CF0C9C637822C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Satisfaction</header><text>Any entitlement to water of the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees) or the United States, acting in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees), for Hualapai land shall be satisfied out of the water resources and other benefits granted, confirmed, quantified, or recognized by the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, this Act, the Bill Williams agreements, and the Bill Williams Act to or for the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees), and the United States, acting in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe and the members of the Hualapai Tribe (but not members in the capacity of the members as allottees).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF58565A18DF43DF8FB678AE81F96BF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allottee water claims</header><paragraph id="HB8540D942F0E406D9135EF2764D48D83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The benefits realized by the allottees of the Hualapai Tribe under the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, this Act, the Bill Williams agreements, and the Bill Williams Act shall be in complete replacement of and substitution for, and full satisfaction of, all claims with respect to allotments of the allottees and the United States, acting in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the allottees, for water rights and injury to water rights under Federal, State, or other law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H526A49B45BB845A489944EAB995EAED3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Satisfaction</header><text>Any entitlement to water of the allottees or the United States, acting in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the allottees, for allotments shall be satisfied out of the water resources and other benefits granted, confirmed, or recognized by the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, this Act, the Bill Williams agreements, and the Bill Williams Act to or for the allottees and the United States, acting as trustee for the allottees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA894DEB6C1D46A49700CB444E47D0EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), nothing in this Act or the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement—</text><paragraph id="H07285F6CADBB43299153A6E716A134C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes or establishes any right of a member of the Hualapai Tribe or an allottee to water on Hualapai land; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DBD9E94B31C42E9979F49A179848A0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibits the Hualapai Tribe or an allottee from acquiring additional water rights by purchase of land, credits, or water rights.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFE67FFA9BD5D471199CFA40AD465B193"><enum>11.</enum><header>Land added to Hualapai reservation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following land in the State is added to the Hualapai Reservation:</text><paragraph id="HAF8777559D77467481595ECE8383C909"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public Law 93–560</header><text>The land held in trust by the United States for the Hualapai Tribe pursuant to the first section of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/560">Public Law 93–560</external-xref> (88 Stat. 1820).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D142A7CCAA49CF80A60D14C946CBD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>1947 judgment</header><text>The land deeded to the United States in the capacity of the United States as trustee for the Hualapai Tribe pursuant to the 1947 judgment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF595208634234CCA96C7B47635343C33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Truxton triangle</header><text>That portion of the S<fraction>1⁄2</fraction> sec. 3, lying south of the south boundary of the Hualapai Reservation and north of the north right-of-way boundary of Arizona Highway 66, and bounded by the west section line of that sec. 3 and the south section line of that sec. 3, T. 24 N., R. 12 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70DCA8A0125E412EAF9176EF1F83EF6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hunt parcel 4</header><text>SW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction>NE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 7, T. 25 N., R. 13 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5726EEAB376B4E92ADA8EAD76BD029EC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hunt parcels 1 and 2</header><text>In T. 26 N., R. 14 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona—</text><subparagraph id="H5C557A6E766A411DA3A344F3F1E80F51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>NE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction>SW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 9; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8876464910D54B9D83888063D33235CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>NW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction>SE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 27.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2662F6307AF94FC9A5A3535947BFF70A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hunt parcel 3</header><text>SW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction>NE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 25, T. 27 N., R. 15 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H840EAF37C47C41E2817EF29C448E2540"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Hunt parcel 5</header><text>In sec. 1, T. 25 N., R. 14 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona—</text><subparagraph id="HFC8460C76EFD43C39CF7CA8636ADF2B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FD54C50F42A422EA786970BE263131B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>E<fraction>1/2</fraction>SW<fraction>1/4</fraction>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F2CA1FB73C344DA8DA9F5D3CE0B4158"><enum>(C)</enum><text>SW<fraction>1/4</fraction>SW<fraction>1/4</fraction>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A28168748E246F7BEEB3B58D2B50D47"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Valentine cemetery parcel</header><text>W<fraction>1/2</fraction>W<fraction>1/4</fraction>SW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 22, T. 23 N., R. 13 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona, excepting and reserving to the United States a right-of-way for ditches or canals constructed by the authority of the United States, pursuant to the Act of August 30, 1890 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/945">43 U.S.C. 945</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0CFD54DB7EBA47EFB5ADC3B3F6584A8C"><enum>12.</enum><header>Trust land</header><subsection id="HDC84411179474313986C5E83D2B126FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land To be taken into trust</header><paragraph id="H6EF39974CFF44F60BE3AE6C3F45EB3FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary is authorized and directed to take legal title to the land described in paragraph (2) and hold such land in trust for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11D8F128D5F646E59BD6C9E9B6489BCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cholla canyon ranch parcels</header><text>The land referred to in paragraph (1) is, in T. 16 N., R. 13 W., Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian, Mohave County, Arizona—</text><subparagraph id="HD69034AA366343BBBEE8A9A187377CEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>SW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 25; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF3BC26F797840809CF8DC5576585062"><enum>(B)</enum><text>NE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> and NE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> SE<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 35.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4C8A06100BC48B98D8D039275C05753"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation status</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be part of the Hualapai Reservation and administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to land held in trust by the United States for an Indian Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8991697756714B90B44236EAE9A7C242"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Valid existing rights</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be subject to valid existing rights, including easements, rights-of-way, contracts, and management agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5455B6CF0AC34CC4A799F6CD331A11A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) affects—</text><paragraph id="H18AFE54BB7E1492DB5237708EB2FF99D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any water right of the Hualapai Tribe in existence under State law before the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D64060BEEB4442AB39347B84E66063E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any right or claim of the Hualapai Tribe to any land or interest in land in existence before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BE30DD471664EAC9BC9F993428E158E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Future trust land</header><paragraph id="H2A83A16E98D14349BB979A10F0A08E41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New statutory requirement</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and except as provided in subsection (a), any land located in the State outside the exterior boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation may only be taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe by an Act of Congress—</text><subparagraph id="H0EAB407E5AA445D4B9F497C6E2C694E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that specifically authorizes the transfer of the land for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H752E19C386AB42519302F131B8B0F61B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of enactment of which is after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E4917F8F6B4F9F96F840E6960222E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text>Any land taken into trust for the benefit of the Hualapai Tribe under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H4A57E20DB80243F983322BD72826F235"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include water rights only under State law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FEADAA4231D4D028CEE0BEA27E53A4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not include any federally reserved water rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H796FA290CD7B4D7DA3BC218055637574"><enum>13.</enum><header>Reallocation of CAP NIA priority water; firming; water delivery contract; Colorado River accounting</header><subsection id="H9456E53E48EA49C0AE27666387663E55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reallocation to the hualapai tribe</header><text>On the Enforceability Date, the Secretary shall reallocate to the Hualapai Tribe the Hualapai Tribe CAP water.</text></subsection><subsection id="H27A1864828CD4558871B43A2AB12E459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Firming</header><paragraph id="H74D72209BD1E46B29015F396482DB210"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe cap water</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c)(2)(H), the Hualapai Tribe CAP water shall be firmed as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HA09898E47D8D4888850F28ECC40BF6D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In accordance with section 105(b)(1)(B) of the Central Arizona Project Settlement Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/451">Public Law 108–451</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 3492), for the 100-year period beginning on January 1, 2008, the Secretary shall firm 557.50 AFY of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water to the equivalent of CAP M&amp;I priority water.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B06C71D230A4A87AFD4D99E32529B1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In accordance with section 105(b)(2)(B) of the Central Arizona Project Settlement Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/451">Public Law 108–451</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 3492), for the 100-year period beginning on January 1, 2008, the State shall firm 557.50 AFY of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water to the equivalent of CAP M&amp;I priority water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52623520A2064724A2A6425554707790"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional firming</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may, at the expense of the Hualapai Tribe, take additional actions to firm or supplement the Hualapai Tribe CAP water, including by entering into agreements for that purpose with the Central Arizona Water Conservation District, the Arizona Water Banking Authority, or any other lawful authority, in accordance with State law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAECC4E118C7418DB8182D020B165EFE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe water delivery contract</header><paragraph id="H29F87357CB294971A55C1B1542B8B3A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement and the requirements described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall enter into the Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H403B5FABC569437BAF05079C12933F84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB696D8F49B0647FFB4FBFC4688A8301F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract shall—</text><clause id="HB18D55D7A4D34533977E089D03286B07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be for permanent service (as that term is used in section 5 of the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/617d">43 U.S.C. 617d</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="H12E93A6083A94C26825C57A877DC180F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take effect on the Enforceability Date; and</text></clause><clause id="H5CD2A4A3FFF448119FF71CACDE997999"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be without limit as to term.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD7DC595EEDE4F3DB7040D7A5B11EAB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hualapai tribe cap water</header><clause id="HE1CBEC4739794B7F9EBBE97ECFB92A10"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe CAP water may be delivered for use in the lower basin in the State through—</text><subclause id="H43A4BB6988D54E61BD9B6CA7EFBF65F0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Hualapai Water Project; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB98E529525614E9598C95480AEC69100"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the CAP system.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H59F9DF634E374DE7AF996F2F29035D10"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Method of delivery</header><text>The Secretary shall authorize the delivery of Hualapai Tribe CAP water under this subparagraph to be effected by the diversion and use of water directly from the Colorado River in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H465CB49D0D934DEDB5FF968B62DACC51"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contractual delivery</header><text>The Secretary shall deliver the Hualapai Tribe CAP water to the Hualapai Tribe in accordance with the terms and conditions of the Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7848F40DCDCB47C2B7AB06900ABC0BD7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Distribution of cap nia priority water</header><clause id="H81F7B91F13E24831A1F520F62B73D167"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), if, for any year, the available CAP supply is insufficient to meet all demands under CAP contracts and CAP subcontracts for the delivery of CAP NIA priority water, the Secretary and the CAP operating agency shall prorate the available CAP NIA priority water among the CAP contractors and CAP subcontractors holding contractual entitlements to CAP NIA priority water on the basis of the quantity of CAP NIA priority water used by each such CAP contractor and CAP subcontractor in the last year in which the available CAP supply was sufficient to fill all orders for CAP NIA priority water.</text></clause><clause id="HBDA8C3A674BF43C8A5A0179765A71AC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><subclause id="H83D0D60ECDE24E98B22B53EF81088FA1"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), if the available CAP supply is insufficient to meet all demands under CAP contracts and CAP subcontracts for the delivery of CAP NIA priority water in the year following the year in which the Enforceability Date occurs, the Secretary shall assume that the Hualapai Tribe used the full volume of Hualapai Tribe CAP water in the last year in which the available CAP supply was sufficient to fill all orders for CAP NIA priority water.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF69BCBA69FB0475C9E0F71928B87BC3D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Continuation</header><text>The assumption described in subclause (I) shall continue until the available CAP supply is sufficient to meet all demands under CAP contracts and CAP subcontracts for the delivery of CAP NIA priority water.</text></subclause><subclause id="HB8D7E99901214C42B80884686B45ACC3"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the quantity of CAP NIA priority water used by the Gila River Indian Community and the Tohono O’odham Nation in the last year in which the available CAP supply was sufficient to fill all orders for CAP NIA priority water in a manner consistent with the settlement agreements with those Tribes.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79C89FE74C2E4857872153A251081FF5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Leases and exchanges of hualapai tribe cap water</header><text>On and after the date on which the Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract becomes effective, the Hualapai Tribe may, with the approval of the Secretary, enter into contracts or options to lease, or contracts or options to exchange, the Hualapai Tribe CAP water within the lower basin in the State, providing for the temporary delivery to other persons of any portion of Hualapai Tribe CAP water.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC55D8FB5885E45BC8F671C1ABCE5DEDB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Term of leases and exchanges</header><clause id="H05B3FA1E69D04896B6C9CA91B83AC28B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Leasing</header><text>Contracts or options to lease under subparagraph (E) shall be for a term of not more than 100 years.</text></clause><clause id="H199ACAE0564949C5BE577338B88B6333"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exchanging</header><text>Contracts or options to exchange under subparagraph (E) shall be for the term provided for in the contract or option, as applicable.</text></clause><clause id="HAB98614DE9EB4CFA9D16D93369F9D8D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Renegotiation</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may, with the approval of the Secretary, renegotiate any lease described in subparagraph (E), at any time during the term of the lease, if the term of the renegotiated lease does not exceed 100 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB94105CFBC344A59BA5ED68A48DB146C"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Prohibition on permanent alienation</header><text>No Hualapai Tribe CAP water may be permanently alienated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75031691259C4C96BB08A84D7EDD45D3"><enum>(H)</enum><header>No firming of leased water</header><text>The firming obligations described in subsection (b)(1) shall not apply to any Hualapai Tribe CAP water leased by the Hualapai Tribe to another person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A74424FC3704BEF8C8E99669C4EFA56"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Entitlement to lease and exchange funds; obligations of united states</header><clause id="HA8D6C4AC687A4774A22EA1EEAE095B23"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Entitlement</header><subclause id="H3C8D4059B60940A59F526C730D86C5C6"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe shall be entitled to all consideration due to the Hualapai Tribe under any contract to lease, option to lease, contract to exchange, or option to exchange the Hualapai Tribe CAP water entered into by the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subclause><subclause id="H663117AB2A654B6B8F879F892E325589"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The United States shall not, in any capacity, be entitled to the consideration described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H55748CEA86904369ADFACAED4717B619"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Obligations of united states</header><text>The United States shall not, in any capacity, have any trust or other obligation to monitor, administer, or account for, in any manner, any funds received by the Hualapai Tribe as consideration under any contract to lease, option to lease, contract to exchange, or option to exchange the Hualapai Tribe CAP water entered into by the Hualapai Tribe, except in a case in which the Hualapai Tribe deposits the proceeds of any lease, option to lease, contract to exchange, or option to exchange into an account held in trust for the Hualapai Tribe by the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F3DC58F4AFE4284B7706AEB2831E85A"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Water use and storage</header><clause id="H3EDD8DF24D8E427AA80A389F4E32D64B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may use the Hualapai Tribe CAP water on or off the Hualapai Reservation within the lower basin in the State for any purpose.</text></clause><clause id="HAD1FD8DBFE774795927F2846BC91907F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Storage</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe, in accordance with State law, may store the Hualapai Tribe CAP water at 1 or more underground storage facilities or groundwater savings facilities, subject to the condition that, if the Hualapai Tribe stores Hualapai Tribe CAP water that has been firmed pursuant to subsection (b)(1), the stored water may only be—</text><subclause id="H7F42A7D1A3324F5391B8BE27A8C1CDDE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>used by the Hualapai Tribe; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H185A3DA0D4494B1B9689D886986083A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>exchanged by the Hualapai Tribe for water that will be used by the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H50205308E87D47AABDBE275028B113FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe, in accordance with State law, may assign any long-term storage credit accrued as a result of storage described in clause (ii), subject to the condition that the Hualapai Tribe shall not assign any long-term storage credit accrued as a result of the storage of Hualapai Tribe CAP water that has been firmed pursuant to subsection (b)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C16BD4570B249DE89EFE463B9DF8518"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Use outside state</header><text>The Hualapai Tribe may not use, lease, exchange, forbear, or otherwise transfer any Hualapai Tribe CAP water for use directly or indirectly outside of the lower basin in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2952BD4B150E4ADFB68373F41166A25A"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Cap fixed om&amp;r charges</header><clause id="HE7A0CDAF2F0B44399CC8670489CB4D87"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The CAP operating agency shall be paid the CAP fixed OM&amp;R charges associated with the delivery of all Hualapai Tribe CAP water.</text></clause><clause id="HAF853D7D984E4D4989B16526A02254AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment of charges</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (O), all CAP fixed OM&amp;R charges associated with the delivery of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water to the Hualapai Tribe shall be paid by—</text><subclause id="H109246757BE14E6CB6980EC042F0904D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary, pursuant to section 403(f)(2)(A) of the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1543">43 U.S.C. 1543(f)(2)(A)</external-xref>), subject to the condition that funds for that payment are available in the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1147A75DA0254CA59274CC27473866D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the funds described in subclause (I) become unavailable, the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A2C44DD18704098BF7D867773B28264"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Cap pumping energy charges</header><clause id="H54A930212AA84761B732AB7305CF6073"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The CAP operating agency shall be paid the CAP pumping energy charges associated with the delivery of Hualapai Tribe CAP water only in cases in which the CAP system is used for the delivery of that water.</text></clause><clause id="H5F2F12D148A64C0E96B4AF30B0E0CFCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment of charges</header><text>Except for CAP water not delivered through the CAP system, which does not incur a CAP pumping energy charge, or water delivered to other persons as described in subparagraph (O), any applicable CAP pumping energy charges associated with the delivery of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water shall be paid by the Hualapai Tribe.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A014C98B5B44E898328EB57FB2DF544"><enum>(N)</enum><header>Waiver of property tax equivalency payments</header><text>No property tax or in-lieu property tax equivalency shall be due or payable by the Hualapai Tribe for the delivery of CAP water or for the storage of CAP water in an underground storage facility or groundwater savings facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA40F6F3BE99A41DA925ACD3CADB60A69"><enum>(O)</enum><header>Lessee responsibility for charges</header><clause id="H56B10D1E7EA5447783813FD9AEBD15EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any lease or option to lease providing for the temporary delivery to other persons of any Hualapai Tribe CAP water shall require the lessee to pay the CAP operating agency all CAP fixed OM&amp;R charges and all CAP pumping energy charges associated with the delivery of the leased water.</text></clause><clause id="H15E5B91D275C43658F9697E8CB88EC67"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No responsibility for payment</header><text>Neither the Hualapai Tribe nor the United States in any capacity shall be responsible for the payment of any charges associated with the delivery of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water leased to other persons.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DF06022C69649979083C86B28C30857"><enum>(P)</enum><header>Advance payment</header><text>No Hualapai Tribe CAP water shall be delivered unless the CAP fixed OM&amp;R charges and any applicable CAP pumping energy charges associated with the delivery of that water have been paid in advance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D3D70F15681495998E87256ADEA00C0"><enum>(Q)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text>The charges for delivery of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water pursuant to the Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract shall be calculated in accordance with the CAP repayment stipulation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16597EDD42374ECE995555241C8561FF"><enum>(R)</enum><header>Cap repayment</header><text>For purposes of determining the allocation and repayment of costs of any stages of the CAP system constructed after November 21, 2007, the costs associated with the delivery of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water, regardless of whether the Hualapai Tribe CAP water is delivered for use by the Hualapai Tribe or in accordance with any lease, option to lease, exchange, or option to exchange providing for the delivery to other persons of the Hualapai Tribe CAP water, shall be—</text><clause id="H3B943B19232E46869D971533EA974717"><enum>(i)</enum><text>nonreimbursable; and</text></clause><clause id="H996EE5C4C6ED40BAA3473307B1AD6561"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>excluded from the repayment obligation of the Central Arizona Water Conservation District.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FB2C99E39AD4A3092E5B31DE6404B20"><enum>(S)</enum><header>Nonreimbursable cap construction costs</header><clause id="H02CCF13DD7C341EE8A71E4CF20D21D9E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to the costs associated with the construction of the CAP system allocable to the Hualapai Tribe—</text><subclause id="H9CC88C993A91415F8FC229D855B3310A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs shall be nonreimbursable; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB31AF041A92549FBB76FC1C95553FE7B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribe shall have no repayment obligation for the costs.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2812A7A4C33F4A8FA593CCFBC61AB388"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Capital charges</header><text>No CAP water service capital charges shall be due or payable for the Hualapai Tribe CAP water, regardless of whether the Hualapai Tribe CAP water is delivered—</text><subclause id="HF94CB4A083824F79B048D9B06801AF48"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for use by the Hualapai Tribe; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9B88A0814A804D6A9C40D1C825D539AF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under any lease, option to lease, exchange, or option to exchange entered into by the Hualapai Tribe.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65AAB379B2674776B247301EE96641B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Colorado river accounting</header><text>All Hualapai Tribe CAP water diverted directly from the Colorado River shall be accounted for as deliveries of CAP water within the State.</text></subsection></section><section id="H204483072D0640D9808EDF03A50FBF4B"><enum>14.</enum><header>Enforceability date</header><subsection id="HAB8B489BDF274FDF8D4EF9B585AEECFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, including the waivers and releases of claims described in section 9, shall take effect and be fully enforceable on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a statement of findings that—</text><paragraph id="H54399F2D42E94C688C8064B36AF6EDC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement conflicts with this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HD0C1C973EE244239B6D5C08276DA6FB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement has been revised through an amendment to eliminate the conflict; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72002E1BB1994CFB90E88AB912FCE720"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the revised Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, including any exhibits requiring execution by any party to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, has been executed by the required party;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA0844231CFD475198E3122D8CA38621"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the waivers and releases of claims described in section 9 have been executed by the Hualapai Tribe and the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B99871351764C04920E9B2111CE1692"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the abstracts referred to in subparagraphs 4.8.1.2, 4.8.2.1, and 4.8.2.2 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement have been completed by the Hualapai Tribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFD1C03A5D5444DB7044EAECA194CDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the full amount described in section 7(a)(1), as adjusted by section 7(b), has been deposited in the Hualapai Water Trust Fund Account;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1D683D6EECA4FC9B37B4720CF67B835"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Gila River adjudication decree has been approved by the Gila River adjudication court substantially in the form of the judgment and decree attached to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement as Exhibit 3.1.43, as amended to ensure consistency with this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB95418D106944414B36565D80D7984F8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Secretary has executed the Hualapai Tribe water delivery contract described in section 13(c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A24F32793548C0AD12524F121A4386"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Secretary has issued the record of decision required by section 8(d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FDC1B18A2C44E08818229BE23B7367E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal on failure To meet enforceability date</header><paragraph id="H03F798979488446BB3A86EC881A5404E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), if the Secretary fails to publish in the Federal Register a statement of findings under subsection (a) by April 15, 2029, or such alternative later date as may be agreed to by the Hualapai Tribe, the Secretary, and the State—</text><subparagraph id="H0AD30A8416DC43159ECF8CDA9DA9B8F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act is repealed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H832D8693A288451096E34817FD0BA099"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any action taken by the Secretary and any contract or agreement entered into pursuant to this Act shall be void; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBF2D3500A634BFE8A6F18E1861E6C28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any amounts appropriated under section 7, together with any investment earnings on those amounts, less any amounts expended under section 6(a)(4)(B), shall revert immediately to the general fund of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD22648735AE24361A8E30C0377214081"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the Secretary fails to publish in the Federal Register a statement of findings under subsection (a) by April 15, 2029, or such alternative later date as may be agreed to by the Hualapai Tribe, the Secretary, and the State, section 11 and subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of section 12 shall remain in effect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09695F6268E643919138FBF20B54AD82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Right To offset</header><text>If the Secretary has not published in the Federal Register the statement of findings under subsection (a) by April 15, 2029, or such alternative later date as may be agreed to by the Hualapai Tribe, the Secretary, and the State, the United States shall be entitled to offset any Federal amounts made available under section 6(a)(4)(B) that were used or authorized for any use under that section against any claim asserted by the Hualapai Tribe against the United States described in section 9(a)(2)(A).</text></subsection><subsection id="H21445A35B1B04CD49FDF4409FA95B926"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bill williams river phase 2 enforceability date</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement (including the waivers and releases described in section 9(d) of this Act and section 5 of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement) shall take effect and become enforceable among the parties to the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement on the date on which all of the following conditions have occurred:</text><paragraph id="H93861576F1FF4703A5A85379038F5475"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement becomes enforceable pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD419767BAE4E8687814FAA333B6F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Freeport has submitted to the Arizona Department of Water Resources a conditional withdrawal of any objection to the Bill Williams River watershed instream flow applications pursuant to section 4.4(i) of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, which withdrawal shall take effect on the Bill Williams River Phase 2 Enforceability Date described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3160DA580D2F4C62BA87D303DA74A9E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than the Enforceability Date, the Arizona Department of Water Resources has issued an appealable, conditional decision and order for the Bill Williams River watershed instream flow applications pursuant to section 4.4(iii) of the Bill Williams River phase 2 water rights settlement agreement, which order shall become nonconditional and effective on the Bill Williams River Phase 2 Enforceability Date described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D891016942047DC98E5D4EC64C859D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The conditional decision and order described in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H8AA5D96ED9ED4526A48D7DC34EA7C8C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>becomes final; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E5E66464F834BB29EA5D7D4A4273DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not subject to any further appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8F0AB7FC116E4B169F9103D25B2C9096"><enum>15.</enum><header>Administration</header><subsection id="H7AB1F2BFBE9644EAA3DCF4434FC41367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limited waiver of sovereign immunity</header><paragraph id="HD576DCC146EC48EABA81BAC3EFB6FD59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver</header><subparagraph id="H89D8FC5D506344FE992668581103BA2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any circumstance described in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HC3F8B5CC11A1483FB175A427AB41BB8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States or the Hualapai Tribe may be joined in the action described in the applicable subparagraph of that paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H5E4E1DA572644E2B8AF0A02283AA7986"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), any claim by the United States or the Hualapai Tribe to sovereign immunity from the action is waived.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00EF05792C4C4E6F8E6EE603DCCDC6D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A waiver under subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text><clause id="H96547FA5731D48D883508B480B594573"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall only be for the limited and sole purpose of the interpretation or enforcement of—</text><subclause id="H65F9B85C1A204F85B17994F0F129395D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAFEA1CC477C5466E97D5DEBDC864C471"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement, as ratified by this Act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF947F15009FB4ACCB40B4AFB4CCA6222"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Bill Williams River phase 2 water right settlement agreement, as ratified by this Act; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H31AFA60D83844F43A5ACD07C7B81DC9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not include any award against the United States or the Hualapai Tribe for money damages, court costs, or attorney fees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59941CD98A2A444E92CD39669D5E5BBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text>A circumstance referred to in paragraph (1)(A) is any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1A9B553DD32A4348AE286546F82C7CDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any party to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement—</text><clause id="H9054917D3DBA4D87B4F86D262FCD6A85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>brings an action in any court of competent jurisdiction relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of—</text><subclause id="HC3AB4926D01E4E3FA000295501617B17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this Act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H15F641B6848846E193C0060AA47EC357"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1233360FC3C440EFA5114930A357FE1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>names the United States or the Hualapai Tribe as a party in that action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H301EFEA88EDA46BA81107EDF03451762"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any landowner or water user in the Verde River Watershed—</text><clause id="H4BC60C58AD27472B9353C331CA2B1972"><enum>(i)</enum><text>brings an action in any court of competent jurisdiction relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of—</text><subclause id="H4445DE16CC73481A83A76DF0F5B1AD14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>paragraph 10.0 of the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0560B024C1AA43839DD7B4D96A62E8D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Exhibit 3.1.43 to the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H673A4399CB5F4BBBB2B5D4C82B5CFD9F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>section 9; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H45D99C0A53374B2BA8E236DB21246DD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>names the United States or the Hualapai Tribe as a party in that action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02BBA108EC4A4FF18F55AE6ACFC8D62E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any party to the Bill Williams River phase 2 settlement agreement—</text><clause id="H0218BD71996C4EE4B96736DD5FF3FC1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>brings an action in any court of competent jurisdiction relating only and directly to the interpretation or enforcement of—</text><subclause id="H7E49F33C801F461AAD53E42F87D892BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this Act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA96DF29CF49C499CB091769960E88FBA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Bill Williams River phase 2 settlement agreement; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC83435ABB5E846FD8CD5684EDC32F2B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>names the United States or the Hualapai Tribe as a party in that action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70E465D349DF4C078147C7410620C6CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on current law</header><text>Nothing in this section alters the law with respect to pre-enforcement review of Federal environmental or safety-related enforcement actions.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBABACD1984FA40B2B1BA8D0C5E181A29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Basin groundwater withdrawal estimates</header><paragraph id="H151586399CED491BADDE16C774CDFEF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Groundwater withdrawal estimates</header><subparagraph id="H79B9F1EDA6A04AE38C95B8FE2B15EEA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the United States Geological Survey Water Use Program, shall issue an estimate for groundwater withdrawals in the Truxton Basin outside the boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4270F767B544716944BF1E9AEFFDCE3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual estimates</header><text>Each year after publication of the initial estimate required by subparagraph (A), the Secretary, acting through the United States Geological Survey Water Use Program, shall issue an estimate for groundwater withdrawals in the Truxton Basin outside the boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation until such time as the Secretary, after consultation with the Hualapai Tribe, determines that annual estimates are not warranted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D8CABDB1DE4FE2A2479CC9CCE44AD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to the state</header><text>Based on the estimates under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the State, in writing, if the total withdrawal of groundwater from the Truxton Basin outside the boundaries of the Hualapai Reservation exceeds the estimate prepared pursuant to that paragraph by 3,000 or more AFY, exclusive of any diversion or use of groundwater on Hualapai fee land and any land acquired by the Hualapai Tribe, including by a tribally owned corporation, in fee after the Enforceability Date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5716D5BBEC34E1DB825586881504D8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Antideficiency</header><text>Notwithstanding any authorization of appropriations to carry out this Act, the United States shall not be liable for any failure of the United States to carry out any obligation or activity authorized by this Act (including all agreements or exhibits ratified or confirmed by this Act) if—</text><paragraph id="H1BC84CD78C1D4EA3B5741FF7F9800587"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adequate appropriations are not provided expressly by Congress to carry out the purposes of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23F151B7D9A3425AA3B810550A4E8673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there are not enough monies available to carry out this Act in the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5CD2C93ECC042F0838329F113981E1C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of reclamation reform act of 1982</header><text>The Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390aa">43 U.S.C. 390aa et seq.</external-xref>) and any other acreage limitation or full-cost pricing provision of Federal law shall not apply to any person, entity, or tract of land solely on the basis of—</text><paragraph id="H07A9095D7AF84CAA971078421E6489C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receipt of any benefit under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0DA94F20AF41E9B61D4D93D6E1A503"><enum>(2)</enum><text>execution or performance of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F9358F6E4243A699A9E70D24B94C99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use, storage, delivery, lease, or exchange of CAP water.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2205E3D310A141C397969B55F4BF480F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect</header><paragraph id="H928A1BA683DB406AADB0609ACD11192E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No modification or preemption of other law</header><text>Unless expressly provided in this Act, nothing in this Act modifies, conflicts with, preempts, or otherwise affects—</text><subparagraph id="H88659983B10445228C670FAE6C9A7A61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Boulder Canyon Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/617">43 U.S.C. 617 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4364D40B774B493DA5321DCA32F0A808"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/618">43 U.S.C. 618 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D4017226300461686A75065FFC6BDF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Act of April 11, 1956 (commonly known as the <quote>Colorado River Storage Project Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/620">43 U.S.C. 620 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D46B2C955474CBDA46BD9AEF853F500"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Colorado River Basin Project Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/537">Public Law 90–537</external-xref>; 82 Stat. 885);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC83E036E324F4A93B4112334AA9BF8EF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Treaty between the United States of America and Mexico respecting utilization of waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, signed at Washington February 3, 1944 (59 Stat. 1219);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EE3C1F08184B4F8947F62A1040460E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Colorado River Compact;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB24B2B0C87B4A4CB93C4FD4F0460A62"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H149D861554974603BDFFE9E815AEB26A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 991); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H575F468E92FB441DB5C12B0A3895F510"><enum>(I)</enum><text>case law concerning water rights in the Colorado River system other than any case to enforce the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement or this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6775033F4E234932BD972E346309F6BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on agreements</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the Hualapai Tribe water rights settlement agreement limits the right of the Hualapai Tribe to enter into any agreement for the storage or banking of water in accordance with State law with—</text><subparagraph id="H4F06CF01A02647E4AAD500FF38C23EE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Arizona Water Banking Authority (or a successor agency or entity); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF317543737AD4806B56D22527E77DE3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other lawful authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A7F2A77B5B24A18871159A5C18257C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of act</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H6C148757168F4889A59E64D60CD77DEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>quantifies or otherwise affects the water rights, claims, or entitlements to water of any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7264E6E920F04C0EAA3A46132AF8D6E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affects the ability of the United States to take action on behalf of any Indian Tribe other than the Hualapai Tribe, the members of the Hualapai Tribe, and the allottees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10B215B31B214452B867BE9F4E166949"><enum>(C)</enum><text>limits the right of the Hualapai Tribe to use any water of the Hualapai Tribe in any location on the Hualapai Reservation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

