<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E6B9F3B338748A7AC31A1BC0D9BFA98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9184 IH: Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9184</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221014">October 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to conduct certain landscape-scale forest restoration projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H889A36D51D99415596548D2E8882A002" style="OLC"><section id="H50CEE1C39DF54ADDA9CD528BEF0D9BFA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H251FBD16905040E083046704E197474B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Root and Stem projects</header><subsection id="HE6AD1474167947FA9DC5484BA6E5A5D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA4108D12BD0D4B129C56DEEB271EA1B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collaborative process</header><text>The term <term>collaborative process</term> means a process that—</text><subparagraph id="HC9E5923347AD417B9F7944DE72353A59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DE161C381DD4B569BEA583D5641979B"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFCB7F86AF83741BE83277FD24FA0CE60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transparent and nonexclusive; or</text></clause><clause id="H1403F0DE9F0B45709650C1E914DC0E8D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of section 205 of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7125">16 U.S.C. 7125</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF9C22D122B04DEDAF3D248976184872"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H807A49DD4A0146E4A6B3BF8EDB262AFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land of the National Forest System (as defined in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF086A75795E842F282C84514085835BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public lands (as defined in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H380BBBCB00FA48378D3904A59D7D8C06"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="H838E64B050124CB89E61F6FF9C40AA54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19B6BA8FA09142DB8E843C53032C54E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D68CCC6D40B4793865E60A642A11E39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of contractors</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall—</text><paragraph id="HDF5E7FB3CDDF473AAE8FA434D7A83F3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain a list of non-Federal, third-party contractors that the Secretary concerned can hire in each State to complete the analysis described in subsection (c)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F21D2BC125F45B081C9445AA8B9B9CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 3 years thereafter, submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a copy of the list described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9D9A74E6F9641F2BB4084F49CB9A46B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>If a person submits to the Secretary concerned a proposal for a project on Federal land that was developed through a collaborative process and that meets local and rural community needs, the Secretary concerned may enter into an agreement with the person, under which—</text><paragraph id="H8750AF6D59AB4B779EE75E5990FD853A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the person initially provides to the Secretary concerned all, or a portion of, the funding necessary to complete any analysis that the Secretary concerned determines to be necessary under Federal law, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), for the consideration of the proposed project;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H953D0A8F72C64C339C29501B2639D47E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary concerned uses the funding provided under paragraph (1) to pay a contractor included on the list maintained under subsection (b)(1) to conduct the analysis described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCACE12699D3470CA2353E4F7EF9C98B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on completion of the analysis described in paragraph (1), if the Secretary concerned makes a decision to proceed with the project, the Secretary concerned—</text><subparagraph id="H188F38D14D01452DAC55A5800BEB5383"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicits bids to carry out the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F8BD92CAC6D48718ABFF1E67369877E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enters into a contract or agreement under section 604 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c</external-xref>) to carry out the project; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA859C54713674F4980624722535FAB55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>using any receipts described in subsection (d)(1), the Secretary concerned, to the maximum extent practicable, repays to the person the funding initially provided under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4725EBBBC30A4F369016103EFB1A0548"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional related authorities</header><paragraph id="HEA39A3ED6CFF413CAE4FF7897125BE69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of receipts</header><text>Any receipts that are generated by a project described in subsection (c) that are normally deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury shall be available for expenditure by the Secretary concerned, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, for the use described in subsection (c)(4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD4D28456944573867575F34926D00C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contractors</header><text>The Secretary concerned may noncompetitively hire a contractor included on the list maintained under subsection (b)(1) to conduct the analysis described in subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A53842A5DF84D4BA8279B22409C2061"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings clauses</header><paragraph id="HA9E49555C18147D78C489D25F3800BEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority of the Secretary concerned</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0E0B0EBDA6C943D6A5674ECD520A40C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the sufficiency of any documents prepared by a contractor under subsection (c)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6AC4B51B5AF4DC88F4333DFCA7E4CE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retain responsibility for any authorizing decision relating to a proposed project described in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40A7B80B7498415693AADE733FF67072"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review and approval of independent third parties</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall verify that there is no conflict of interest between—</text><subparagraph id="HE4CFA067F67F4D8C88D6E59868357744"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person that submits a proposal under subsection (c); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE17AD630146C489080A6FC6FEB9D5692"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a contractor that the Secretary concerned hires under paragraph (2) of that subsection to carry out an analysis with respect to that proposal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H998A846242B24411AC959725F227974E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary concerned—</text><subparagraph id="H0DB490FBC2144190BE18B00F48DBB1ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall only use the funding provided to the Secretary concerned under subsection (c)(1) to pay a contractor pursuant to subsection (c)(2); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H362DE96BF9864B24B9497755ACD7558A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not use any portion of the funding provided to the Secretary concerned under subsection (c)(1) to cover any other expense or cost incurred by the Secretary concerned, including administrative costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF45F144BFD3D4BA6B194241C7AD030B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations on reimbursements</header><text>If insufficient receipts are generated by a project described in subsection (c) to reimburse the person that provided funding under paragraph (1) of that subsection, the Secretary concerned shall not provide additional funding to the person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1EE07E466064A1E986B3EE9A85B8406"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Promotion</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned shall provide guidance to each local field office of the Secretary concerned for—</text><paragraph id="H6F73A4268D1C4D3582BCE0FD45C36C2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making stakeholders aware of the authority under this Act; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C6A1895F6BE4A41BF94F21D4D288F49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging use of that authority to meet land management goals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CC30E98C6714D96B6BFEDD4040D2B02"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment of collaborative members</header><text>For purposes of a civil action relating to a project described in subsection (c), any person that participated in the collaborative process to develop the proposal for the project shall be—</text><paragraph id="H2ED2FA429485446A975DAE414C2041F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entitled to intervene, as of right, in any subsequent civil action; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10028B9B01504E6E87C86E51E6636EC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considered to be a full participant in any settlement negotiation relating to the project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6B084087C024129B2CFB6594C451335"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The requirements described in subsection (b) and the authority to enter into an agreement under subsection (c) shall expire on January 1, 2033. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

