<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H332180EA7A244718902E9B1B32DB3048" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8526 IH: Office of Disaster Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8526</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish an Office of Disaster Recovery, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02C16F49672540A8BB231A27E7060489" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0E4F1130F42E45B18F5F6837EE0085E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Office of Disaster Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0172F5FFAAC649F99D57191A032B76E1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disaster recovery office</header> <subsection id="H503FBC3F69EB439F86317A69F492394F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title V of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3191">42 U.S.C. 3191 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H54E4E436F295434680FE3C0B5209B1ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H04C133AC394341A9B196B723EB9CF603"><enum>508.</enum><header>Disaster Recovery Office</header> 
<subsection id="H88DE2B93333C4125A5D70F4FBA8BDC9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaster recovery office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an Office of Disaster Recovery to direct and implement the Economic Development Administration’s post-disaster economic recovery responsibilities pursuant to sections 209(c)(2) and (e) and 703, economic recovery support function activities as directed under the National Disaster Recovery Framework, and as necessary to administer disaster appropriations made available for such purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0A89A41507B54AF79C3E669C31BE1077"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment and compensation</header> <paragraph id="H2E9AE18B63E3474B8AEE81CFB4663B12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to appoint such temporary personnel as may be necessary to implement post-disaster economic recovery responsibilities, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service and compensation of personnel.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC2EFAE85CD34E4DA553C67EA9E9FACA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conversion of employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, the Secretary is authorized to convert a temporary employee appointed under this subsection to a permanent appointment in the competitive service in the Economic Development Administration under merit promotion procedures if—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E4AFCF980014FFA861C9B17DC81F252"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee has served continuously for at least 2 years under one or more appointments under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1F61B609E674B6CB3D19419EDE6EBAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employee's performance has been at an acceptable level of performance throughout the period or periods referred to in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38A0EF678C954BA4B2925CFA1BD17326"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual converted under this subsection shall become a career-conditional employee, unless the employee has already completed the service requirements for career tenure.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0943AB3A713D4257AECAC4271AC93EBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for economic adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3149">42 U.S.C. 3149</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H53AA8FC758B1431ABE889D999DCB46CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HCFC2296DFEC14C4984836B61699ED85C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal share for disaster recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a grant provided under this section for a project for economic recovery in response to a major disaster or emergency declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary shall increase the Federal share to 100 percent of the cost of the project. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20FB688FB9A34DF0867AF6898EB806E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for disaster economic recovery activities</header><text>Section 703 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3233">42 U.S.C. 3233</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2FFEDBDFAD104EE18013D61C6660A15F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7DEC5549BF1341F391220CBB2777B782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule for Federal share of disaster recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project for economic recovery in response to a major disaster or emergency declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) funded with amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be 100 percent.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

