<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H0496B60F2D414624B3C4C938C75A3104" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6528 : Housing Temperature Safety Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6528</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require owners of covered federally assisted rental dwelling units to install temperature sensors in such units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HBC31F9883329453AA407B68E738A653E"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H4786C8ACA855480DAD51BD67265B532D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Temperature Safety Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDAB1D4C652C94F50A7C012D2E4A650B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Temperature Sensor Pilot Program</header><subsection id="H3ADB02386BA044A98B2A648E5C4F6F8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a temperature sensor 3-year pilot program to provide grants to public housing agencies and owners of covered federally assisted rental dwelling units to install and test the efficacy of temperature sensors in residential dwelling units to ensure such units remain in compliance with temperature requirements. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2E9ACD37AF384B118BA5692D9EAB1ED3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish eligibility criteria for participation in the pilot program established pursuant to subsection (a) and such criteria shall be designed to ensure—</text><paragraph id="H665A5211A5DF489DB68774F7F3B05AC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the pilot program includes a diverse range of participants that represent different geographic regions, climate regions, unit sizes and types of housing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC2ED92170FB4750933055551090FAF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the functionality of the temperature sensors that will be tested, including internet connectivity requirements. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A91295EA5E848859D6EEBE429EC8A99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Installation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public housing agency or owner of a covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit that receives one or more temperature sensors under this Act shall, after receiving written permission from the resident of a dwelling unit, install such temperature sensor and monitor the data from such temperature sensor.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFCEE87C0F0004CC0B27502917C9A2902"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection of complaint records</header><paragraph id="H2B66CAAD2D25440CAC9059149D053806"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each public housing agency or owner of a covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit that receives one or more temperature sensors under this Act shall collect and retain information about temperature-related complaints and violations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06BECB9E4685434CBEA5FAAE0C8E28D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The Secretary shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, define the terms temperature-related complaints and temperature-related violations for the purposes of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0E5FA0952AA4BE6AABB65FA77131E11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data collection</header><paragraph id="H98CCEECBB42B40E69341C091BDCAFC53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Data collected from temperature sensors provided to public housing agencies and owners of covered federally assisted rental dwelling units under this Act shall be retained until the Secretary notifies the public housing agency or owner that the pilot program and the evaluation of the pilot program are complete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A6D5CDD94564BC8BC813C343D7437B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The Secretary shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish standards for the protection of personally identifiably information collected during the pilot program by public housing agencies, owners of federally assisted rental dwelling units, and the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69C31549E854478F9DDD78B3E3EC8384"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Pilot program evaluation</header><paragraph id="H85C85616A5924772AC959DFEFF8429C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the establishment of the pilot program under this Act, the Secretary shall publicly publish and submit to the Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H405C2013B10D42DDB971A1550012D1AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examines the number of temperature-related complaints and violations in federally assisted rental dwelling units with temperature sensors, disaggregated by temperature sensor technology and climate region—</text><clause id="H291DE64C50464B34AA407A275574F197"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that occurred before the installation of such sensor, if known; and</text></clause><clause id="H2605B30B9B3A42748719B775A1719464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that occurred after the installation of such sensor; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F9CEF0C83744E39832F208A75930488"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies any barriers to full utility of temperature sensor capabilities, including broadband Internet access and tenant participation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD48DC861B41944468ADDC0908FBF90FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 36 months after the conclusion of the pilot program established by the Secretary under this Act, the Secretary shall publicly publish and submit to the Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H584585AABF954BC5B753141B5902188F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examines the number of temperature-related complaints and violations in federally assisted rental dwelling units with temperature sensors, disaggregated by temperature sensor technology and climate region—</text><clause id="HA169F1467E284593B066DF2DE455A898"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that occurred before the installation of such sensor; and</text></clause><clause id="H30B9E39BDCD4442B9CF679CF1E6ED37A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that occurred after the installation of such sensor;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB466A957E6F476B8DF3C58711F01EC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies any barriers to full utility of temperature sensor capabilities, including broadband Internet access and tenant participation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46C1D319CDF44B4E87058C6093439B69"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compare the utility of various temperature sensor technologies based on—</text><clause id="H6630DDF48BE1443D9A129EA2923B48E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>climate zones;</text></clause><clause id="HD488F92CBDF544CEA36154613ABA3953"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cost;</text></clause><clause id="H337590F344614D2BA38488C7299D1774"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>features; and</text></clause><clause id="H17B3D2AA0F4E4D1496529DBFE75BBA06"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other factors identified by the Secretary. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H277C1E1BBB254E94907D66FA2DCE29BB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H473AB027B3934D5A889B7376CD674975"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Temperature sensor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>temperature sensor</term> means an internet capable temperature reporting device able to measure ambient air temperature to the tenth degree Fahrenheit and Celsius.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H305548B458A848AE8F16C30D0BC06D8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered federally assisted housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit</term> means a residential dwelling unit that is made available for rental and for which assistance is provided, or that is part of a housing project for which assistance is provided, under—</text><subparagraph id="H7773A63A649A41CCB9036D2ABA77F027"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the program for project-based rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E7A2FB1C5CC4574849572A079C9A57D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31C78E8C53B04036B5DC23D12333B348"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8BA132B97A0448087A4888CB80AADBD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20FC1728CDA14FE5B9BFBEDC24248676"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>owner</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HEE1552B706434561964D4648AF52E2F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the program for project-based rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>), any private person or entity, including a cooperative, an agency of the Federal government, or a public housing agency, having the legal right to lease or sublease dwelling units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC414552CF8C44008F7A5AC586049CCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>), a public housing agency or an owner entity of public housing units as defined in section 905.108 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1C4793888D74693B4F18754C04FC676"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>), a private nonprofit organization as defined under section 202(k)(4) of the Housing Act of 1959; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3200790DAA94D3FBCFA7961A51A00F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>), a private nonprofit organization as defined under section 811(k)(5) of section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AD13193EA904B0ABF678A0A198D2FD8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F457A19A4E24BB188B03E2DA024F699"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HD8F489C07E91445EBF5141EB87396061"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for the Secretary to provide grants to owners of covered federally assisted rental dwelling units participating in the pilot program established under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB8604C849BE4FF4A5178B605A6928A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for the Secretary to administer the pilot program established under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65116CEBCCC2465CBCC138FF70DF26C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for the Secretary to provide technical assistance to owners of covered federally assisted rental dwelling units that are participating in the pilot program established under this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220726" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 26, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

