<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H13258A0E6F95420AB3B0480D9220AFD3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8111 IH: My Body, My Data Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8111</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Mrs. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To protect the privacy of personal reproductive or sexual health information, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H59190547BE4D4C30A5E7D4686B65B24A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAB1752FF29184A408EEBEE8BA69D0040" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>My Body, My Data Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H769C98E9DE6C42BF8FACA42B5B4A3206"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimization</header> <subsection id="H914AB65FA79644C29212C514AAEC6A8C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimization of collecting, retaining, using, and disclosing</header><text>A regulated entity may not collect, retain, use, or disclose personal reproductive or sexual health information except—</text> 
<paragraph id="H74D9E124B2244E75BAD7F2460FAE995C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with the express consent of the individual to whom such information relates; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6754CA6A1C574F03B9F18E858BA9D853" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as is strictly necessary to provide a product or service that the individual to whom such information relates has requested from such regulated entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2E53010531D49D88DC5B59C22D82F78" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimization of employee access</header><text>A regulated entity shall restrict access to personal reproductive or sexual health information by the employees or service providers of such regulated entity to such employees or service providers for which access is necessary to provide a product or service that the individual to whom such information relates has requested from such regulated entity.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0203648058A042B7820DB9BCB59F16A5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Right of access and deletion</header> <subsection id="HE3E3DEF6D10642BDA1B30F723A4E8DAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right of access</header> <paragraph id="H42C54418E15B43E09EBBF1A77AD77D10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A regulated entity shall make available a reasonable mechanism by which an individual, upon a verified request, may access—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H02577CE1DFBB445697FEAF2E10928708"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any personal reproductive or sexual health information relating to such individual that is retained by such regulated entity, including—</text> <clause id="HADAA626E870341588F1681B6DF7B178E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of such information that such regulated entity collected from third parties, how and from which specific third parties such regulated entity collected such information; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5BF68C202316467697EFA304CF0AFB74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such information that such regulated entity inferred about such individual; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED011C9E9BDE40E68BEA6A8A775C50E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of the specific third parties to which such regulated entity has disclosed any personal reproductive or sexual health information relating to such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF287F4655B542AEA770701259D96EDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format</header><text>A regulated entity shall make the information described in paragraph (1) available in both a human-readable format and a structured, interoperable, and machine-readable format.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7F5F8DA6C9214EF0902225D9E0D4A21F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right of deletion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A regulated entity shall make available a reasonable mechanism by which an individual, upon a verified request, may request the deletion of any personal reproductive or sexual health information relating to such individual that is retained by such regulated entity, including any such information that such regulated entity collected from a third party or inferred from other information retained by such regulated entity.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HED405354127543D19FCF7BA9C23059AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>General provisions</header> 
<paragraph id="H574340CC348A416E8027EB0CB2A1D8EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reasonable mechanism defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>reasonable mechanism</term> means, with respect to a regulated entity and a right under this section, a mechanism that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA828B092ECF41EBA76C5A9CA100FAED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is equivalent in availability and ease of use to that of other mechanisms for communicating or interacting with such regulated entity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DB358CCFF424260A2F88329B5BF8956"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an online means of exercising such right.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D84E7727E1A44ECB0373F1E98E9735C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline for complying with requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A regulated entity shall comply with a verified request received under this section without undue delay but not later than 15 days after the date on which such regulated entity receives such verified request.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DF76C3AD9314AA580EDBD1774681C9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fees prohibited</header><text>A regulated entity may not charge a fee to an individual for a request made under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C1E854D0EC44DEBA5553AC74CCD3B6B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a regulated entity to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAFB3D9D5DFE44968B36282950C96519E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take an action that would convert information that is not personal information into personal information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCB0B874E199459E9ED0FC78F7FD3FE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect or retain personal information that such regulated entity would otherwise not collect or retain; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93EC11786A2F45169C9A16DE3EA865A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain personal information longer than such regulated entity would otherwise retain such information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1F74E10BD81144D989225817F8429D51"><enum>4.</enum><header>Privacy policy</header> <subsection id="H34ED5F89AA6448B683B208EEB091FC21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy required</header><text>A regulated entity shall maintain a privacy policy relating to the practices of such regulated entity regarding the collecting, retaining, using, and disclosing of personal reproductive or sexual health information.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5C882F7910DD453F9F8C6C3798B36F92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication required</header><text>If a regulated entity has a website, such regulated entity shall prominently publish the privacy policy required by subsection (a) on such website.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC6F9A50C299E4BAEABE362A42EEB793F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The privacy policy required by subsection (a) shall be clear and conspicuous and shall contain, at a minimum, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7E35FA3D7EB41D39F2250F6F303618B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the practices of the regulated entity regarding the collecting, retaining, using, and disclosing of personal reproductive or sexual health information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD287C52E497241E08FC1F009B16ACE17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A clear and concise statement of the categories of such information collected, retained, used, or disclosed by the regulated entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34061B48DD734975B60FB945A7291B83"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A clear and concise statement of the purposes of the regulated entity for the collecting, retaining, using, or disclosing of such information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B9A8B0F5B904329A3EB7D4E83509E52"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of the specific third parties to which the regulated entity discloses such information, and a clear and concise statement of the purposes for which the regulated entity discloses such information, including how the information may be used by each such third party.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H973108A318FC42A096A21ED49FE11531"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of the specific third parties from which the regulated entity has collected such information, and a clear and concise statement of the purposes for which the regulated entity collects such information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BBC9F78CAD34820879AB4763A2441F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A clear and concise statement describing the extent to which individuals may exercise control over the collecting, retaining, using, and disclosing of personal reproductive or sexual health information by the regulated entity, and the steps an individual must take to implement such controls.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFCB0B6B4760450EB71E79E5DB61D5C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A clear and concise statement describing the efforts of the regulated entity to protect personal reproductive or sexual health information from unauthorized disclosure.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5AB678C2B2FF4A59BF9C677DC7C057EA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="H43F0A76430D24D9489D3DEA23AE5C92B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="HB1F2EDCB0DDE47C9B5E37BF2A36FBD9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77CCA05760D943D8B367DDFC8A3444B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 6(7)(A)(ii), the Commission shall enforce this Act and the regulations promulgated under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any regulated entity that violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5337DF8F921D42A0895F1AEB92A8E46E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Commission may promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to implement this Act. </text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H924350D695524E84BBEEAA2DFA8303D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by individuals</header> 
<paragraph id="H9DA3FCFF32CA4FF6ACE0D5B7403E81D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual alleging a violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1E323346B5C4CADA18D9EE439A8BD8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4175ACDD2DAA4319BA48D55BE37D14B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount not less than $100 and not greater than $1,000 per violation per day, or actual damages, whichever is greater;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC98458B5FC9A45589B659AB35539F653"><enum>(B)</enum><text>punitive damages;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7037744BE36A4F2F9D741B79F078BEBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable attorney’s fees and litigation costs; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD0BFC8257AE4B0AAB5224A1243E21F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other relief, including equitable or declaratory relief, that the court determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34F79EF4487E4DAAB6F8922D34BF87C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Injury in fact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, with respect to personal reproductive or sexual health information constitutes a concrete and particularized injury in fact to the individual to whom such information relates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B027C63E8C84AAC984DFD19D9B3764F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Invalidity of pre-dispute arbitration agreements and pre-dispute joint action waivers</header> <subparagraph id="H2ADD14C939B246A3B8BC286B315696FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to a dispute arising under this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H160A44B5C30A4002BE958D647B683CAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any determination as to whether or how this paragraph applies to any dispute shall be made by a court, rather than an arbitrator, without regard to whether such agreement purports to delegate such determination to an arbitrator. </text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B214D85D07440F999E418635F14607D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="H06D8C9E205D04DB8BA14F0C638D448EC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Pre-dispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>pre-dispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text> </clause> <clause id="H9CC6A04EB17447CB876C798D9837D1F2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Pre-dispute joint-action waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pre-dispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement that would prohibit a party from participating in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H69C7593DCFCF48CA99F0F19DEBD1D738"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6099106D771F402EB8D0C33235347AEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collect</header><text>The term <term>collect</term> means, with respect to personal reproductive or sexual health information, for a regulated entity to obtain such information in any manner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29363CED10E342B9AD44CF7223F98390"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC6BBCC74DA544458BC293C0BA850DEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>disclose</term> means, with respect to personal reproductive or sexual health information, for a regulated entity to release, transfer, sell, provide access to, license, or divulge such information in any manner to a third party or government entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD80F7FDBAC24551891CF0132C5590E8" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Express consent</header> 
<subparagraph id="H46F232E986854AB09ED7E49EC4611048" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>express consent</term> means, with respect to the collecting, retaining, using, or disclosing of personal reproductive or sexual health information, informed, opt-in, voluntary, specific, and unambiguous written consent (which may include written consent provided by electronic means) to such collecting, retaining, using, or disclosing of such information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EBF4B9CF75440D181780C2063AAD67D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>express consent</quote> does not include any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H603EAE104889413DB7FDEF48DDFD70BC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent secured without first providing to the individual a clear and conspicuous disclosure, apart from any privacy policy, terms of service, terms of use, general release, user agreement, or other similar document, of all information material to the provision of consent.</text></clause> <clause id="HF6C54E67CF324E6DA4D4F6937B577104" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hovering over, muting, pausing, or closing a given piece of content.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H70021F638307451BA4838809CEADE253" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agreement obtained through the use of a user interface designed or manipulated with the substantial effect of subverting or impairing user autonomy, decision making, or choice.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBD85C3952A1477198C2810987AC83A4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal information</term> means information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB1CC55DC9374345B1F0455CBFB3F5AC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Personal reproductive or sexual health information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal reproductive or sexual health information</term> means personal information relating to the past, present, or future reproductive or sexual health of an individual, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1A3F12C78774708B7D00732F3F0F9CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>efforts to research or obtain reproductive or sexual information services or supplies, including location information that might indicate an attempt to acquire or receive such information services or supplies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE419787685B40DD96D3D48303D6C8C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reproductive or sexual health conditions, status, diseases, or diagnoses, including pregnancy, menstruation, ovulation, ability to conceive a pregnancy, whether such individual is sexually active, and whether such individual is engaging in unprotected sex;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F1DFBDDB7104F71B19EAE5960F2A11D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reproductive- and sexual-health-related surgeries or procedures, such as termination of a pregnancy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4915265B86804DE7AAF34C3870CA32F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>use or purchase of contraceptives, birth control, or any medication related to reproductive health, including abortifacients;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0F968FE2F5F4D6D9FC893F2F219BD59"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bodily functions, vital signs, measurement, or symptoms related to menstruation or pregnancy, such as basal temperature, cramps, bodily discharge, or hormone levels;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5E7C4B3C76441E08ED638EDD0B15131"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any information about diagnoses or diagnostic testing, treatment, medications, or the use of any product or service relating to the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (E); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07B86B2A385242C0A15717EE6A63AB85"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any information described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) that is derived or extrapolated from non-health information (such as proxy, derivative, inferred, emergent, or algorithmic data).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5813283A2ACF496C9D1CE98E5D1C10B2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Regulated entity</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4FA516FBDDF74314B095AF156488C519"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>regulated entity</term> means any entity (to the extent such entity is engaged in activities in or affecting commerce (as defined in section 4 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>))) that is—</text> <clause id="H5715443209C04BDE9C0332A877367B35"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person, partnership, or corporation subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB2F109C2C3243AB975F01CC2A40F111"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>; 45(a)(2); 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission—</text> <subclause id="HC006BEF51FB44D0698E021A23C2C12D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a common carrier subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) and all Acts amendatory thereof and supplementary thereto; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF8332F635D4543D0AFF0D6866860A7CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an organization not organized to carry on business for its own profit or that of its members.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DBBB8C630AA49EDACC7EF3E3AD0210D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>regulated entity</term> does not include—</text> 
<clause id="HA750756BDEDE43C89D28F510DD334FEB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity that is a covered entity, as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor to such regulation), to the extent such entity is acting as a covered entity under the HIPAA privacy regulations (as defined in section 1180(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-9">42 U.S.C. 1320d–9(b)(3)</external-xref>));</text></clause> <clause id="H18159128A17A452697D5EDC237D719B4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity that is a business associate, as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor to such regulation), to the extent such entity is acting as a business associate under the HIPAA privacy regulations (as defined in such section 1180(b)(3)); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFC80896DCC7D4495934868576CE05073"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an entity that is subject to restrictions on disclosure of records under section 543 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-2">42 U.S.C. 290dd–2</external-xref>), to the extent such entity is acting in a capacity subject to such restrictions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79E0B4DD473349768A36DBDC55D46E18" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Service provider</header> <subparagraph id="HF43F810523134680B045AC8A48377B8E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>service provider</quote> means a person who—</text> 
<clause id="HD6A83618AB2041528727B72F1614C4DF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collects, retains, uses, or discloses personal reproductive or sexual health information for the sole purpose of, and only to the extent that such person is, conducting business activities on behalf of, for the benefit of, under instruction of, and under contractual agreement with a regulated entity and not any other individual or entity; and</text></clause> <clause id="H388FD7B46D7148308DC5F21147BC8919" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not divulge personal reproductive or sexual health information to any individual or entity other than such regulated entity or a contractor to such service provider bound to information processing terms no less restrictive than terms to which such service provider is bound.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB27B1642798E4DEBBC01AB724F1A7115" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation of application</header><text>Such person shall only be considered a service provider in the course of activities described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C8E6F2668814D429457C0FBCFEAB344" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Minimization by service providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of compliance with section 2 by a service provider of a regulated entity, a request from an individual to such regulated entity for a product or service, and an express consent from such individual to such regulated entity, shall be treated as having also been provided to such service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFEF474B405C494D91A6B08D1400A7AD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Third party</header><text>The term <term>third party</term> means, with respect to the disclosing or collecting of personal reproductive or sexual health information, any person who is not—</text> <subparagraph id="H3699D2F6946A47AC86B09CAA720E268B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulated entity that is disclosing or collecting such information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45280F38E8F7480082A5877A2B187972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual to whom such information relates; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDE4B54CFCD0478FA921455B15530246"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="HBD32326D730A440289E9880CBE3919F9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Exception for the publication of newsworthy information</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall apply with respect to personal reproductive or sexual health information that is collected, retained, used, or disclosed by a regulated entity for the publication of newsworthy information of legitimate public concern to the public, or to the collecting, retaining, using, or disclosing of such information by a regulated entity for that purpose, if such regulated entity has reasonable safeguards and processes that prevent the collecting, retaining, using, or disclosing of personal reproductive or sexual health information for commercial purposes other than the publication of newsworthy information of legitimate public concern.</text> </section> <section id="H4644204DEF7F43EBAC93D8FE523FF2B5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Relationship to Federal and State laws</header> <subsection id="H4D99B8816B174560A4814B476194044D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal law preservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to limit any other provision of Federal law, except as specifically provided in this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE455F4058A434158B1E954228686FACE" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State law preservation</header> 
<paragraph id="HFF42F443650242FBA79EF4D1405583F8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to preempt, displace, or supplant any State law, except to the extent that a provision of State law conflicts with a provision of this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, and then only to the extent of the conflict.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC72F524541254FBBBE9B87ADF9BCCD5D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Greater protection under State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a provision of State law does not conflict with a provision of this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, if such provision of State law provides greater privacy protection than the privacy protection provided by such provision of this Act or such regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H21DD8AEEB2294485A3FCD061EBA1BEFA"><enum>9.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law. Nothing in this Act, or a regulation promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to prohibit a regulated entity from disclosing personal reproductive or sexual health information to the Commission as required by law, in compliance with a court order, or in compliance with a civil investigative demand or similar process authorized under law.</text></section> <section id="HE6EE028D83EB400F929FE18988874CEE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Severability clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected by the invalidation.</text></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


