<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC89EFE2EABB44A5BA8A259FA047DDCD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8492 IH: Protecting Social Workers and Health Professionals from Workplace Violence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to States to provide safety measures to social workers, health workers, and human services professionals performing services placing such individuals in high-risk and potentially dangerous situations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB6B7C61C58D414CB5AFDD570FC0F2AB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3D9D255390184DEFAAD1F0F415F06077" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Social Workers and Health Professionals from Workplace Violence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H55727C36CC674D3D8E85F5780792F800"><enum>2.</enum><header>Workplace safety grant program</header> <subsection id="HD3C5CB75C6DC4CC8B5F657B9FF798E35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H42D27C129B1C43A1B8BA9CDC172C0F62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to States, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations to provide safety measures to social workers, health workers, and human services professionals (as designated by the Secretary), performing services placing such individuals in high-risk and potentially dangerous situations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AB9128455F3432F9D35EFEA831BA944"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary may consult with the Secretary of Labor and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H00F9F19677E24ABABE82C8F7C1D5B29D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under subsection (a) may be used to provide or support the following safety measures:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7CBDCA831C64A2B9ED43A352AB4F347"><enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC6CEB8F9C077494AA0EEC1062033803B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procurement and installation of safety equipment, including communications or recording systems, such as cell phones, wearable tracking devices with GPS/Bluetooth locator, or panic buttons, such as the equipment used for supervised foster care visits and other client visits, to assist entities employing social workers, health workers, and human services professionals described in subsection (a) in ensuring staff safety.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD52C0A853C5472E91BEEC1C531462C7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Technical assistance and training for safety communications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC597AA0F930243678254D2F9200664D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training sessions and exercises for self-defense and crisis management, provided together with such organizations as local law enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE07125CD2E9746D185F0B40F7578D611"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Facility safety improvements, such as barrier protection and security cameras.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H049FCAD3CD7D49BBAA50C1DE17012A99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Training in cultural competency, including linguistic training, and training on strategies for de-escalating conflict situations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF1D194DEB854BE4B29B6E166AF948C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Training to help social workers, health workers, and human services professionals, work with clients who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC4143D52A2204E978F310DBEB6CB2A24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have serious mental and substance use disorders; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69196845E8724D39B5A53B64F9DB68E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have behavioral problems and need help coping.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FA4718B81624171A02D14D67DE94D06"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Resources and materials to inform and educate staff on safety and awareness measures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD6DD3F42C24D8E994CC33CB44E0421"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Support services, counseling, and additional resources for social workers, health workers, and human services professionals, who have experienced safety issues or trauma-related incidents in the workplace.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48E20E587AE54654A975C55719D469CA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Installation of a local data incident tracking system to monitor, prevent, and mitigate violence against social workers, health workers, and human services professionals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD89F7FFCC28147259E39F3ECE8747F92"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Other prevention and mitigation measures determined appropriate by the Secretary for safety training, resources, and support for social workers, health workers, and human services professionals.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F78C4D28D094B5A8952F5C62B3D5141"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="H3B364471B10B47028FA4A21EADEE03BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, or urban Indian organization seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03BA95B9DF2B4914B527C11C6B64F0CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA7D3DE3AEE0B4C43A2CC9B67858B4EF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the type of entities that will receive funding through the grant and type of work to be done by such entities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC012D43039F146188E26CBE7A1C54CB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the specific activities for which the grant is sought and include a program budget; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4916875B64A54DB89EF45FE0410975FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain an assurance that the applicant will evaluate the effectiveness of the safety measures provided through the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFDA1607A1E6D411B9ADB8E1995DE0B71"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC360E120E8943558DF9A2ECEE22CBF3"><enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA838E791F916446ABEACB1A667384B3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate the greatest need based on documented incidents of violence against social workers, health workers, and human services professionals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB25F48F0E4454FF49DDF5FD54EA35E81" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to provide assistance to multiple entities employing social workers, health workers, and human services professionals performing services placing such individuals in high-risk and potentially dangerous situations; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE51AEEC067804DB6AA9D9191C2CF2255"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to enhance existing efforts by the applicant (existing on the date on which the applicant submits the application) to improve the safety of social workers, health workers, and human services professionals.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF11C778788E844778BAC662179D3D7DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quality assurance and cost effectiveness</header><text>The Secretary shall establish guidelines for ensuring the quality and cost effectiveness of the safety measures funded under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2DAF767AB6645118B037377BD447776"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to recipients of a grant under this section with respect to planning, developing, implementing, reporting, and sustaining safety measures through the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H505746614B9E49FBAA93650869D3377D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State, Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, or urban Indian organization receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary, not later than 2 years after receiving such grant, a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56F6DDDBA03A43B3A4582AAFC9992428"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the activities funded in whole or in part with funds awarded through the grant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B7C08BFDC1046BE8BAEA353679E39E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the range and scope of training opportunities provided through training programs funded in whole or in part with such funds, including the numbers and percentages of social workers, health workers, and human services professionals, engaged in such training programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDC6539ED6D144A88131106FEE91B63B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the incidence of threats to social workers, health workers, and human services professionals, if any, and the strategies used to address their safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDD7D08622C494DBC8CB0CD0DB9FAC596"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HAE62E0DA008A4777B8AA4156602CF275"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>health worker</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8A720948769942D79638A99D3B12C264"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Community Health Representative that has completed training under the Community Health Representative Program of the Indian Health Service under section 107 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616">25 U.S.C. 1616</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB81F91A6C8684FF6A7F2F8EE9725A44E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a health aide or community health practitioner certified under the Community Health Aide Program of the Indian Health Service under section 119 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616l">25 U.S.C. 1616l</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2F8481DC6B964FE6A3F6461CCEF2CA44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other behavioral health aides and mental health aides.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16C96590F51C43CE8B47E92794F599FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> and <quote>Tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21FE1ADAB0624049A8465D8C220C76C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A826185B1BA44E29A0FE2F11F98141F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>social work</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H02F4A785A81E4C4B8E9C4A663EF1D778"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applied science of helping individuals, groups, or communities to enhance or restore capacity for social and psychosocial functioning, and effecting societal changes favorable to such enhancement or restoration for all people; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61BCAEE2AC2F4D05B87E386BF38DCC5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the professional application of social work values, principles, and techniques related to the activities described in subparagraph (A), including—</text> <clause id="H26CF5C7464AE444581EB366D39E345A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>diagnosing mental and emotional disorders and providing counseling and psychotherapy services to individuals, families, or groups for such disorders; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD7733D48AC5240039894B1D254D2D325"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>helping individuals, families, or groups to obtain tangible services, including personal, protective, informational, advisory, community, housing, education, health, and mental health services in order to improve the overall well-being of individuals.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7C2A94D5F624C7DBE81FFA3CED96312"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>social worker</term> means an individual, with a baccalaureate, master’s, or doctoral degree in social work from an institution of higher education, who uses knowledge and skills to provide social work services for individuals, families, groups, communities, organizations, or society in general.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88FAF4283600440F831868C4B9A6B21B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H636B31852FCB4904AC13C89C3AEF4DB2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

