<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2FBA9F721381487591B0264DDBC501BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6446 IH: One Citizen One Vote Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6446</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the Election Assistance Commission from making payments under such Act to States and jurisdictions which fail to meet certain standards to protect the integrity and certainty of elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59CF9CF0B1724647A1C84C7BB3058A47" style="OLC"><section id="H06BC8C8B91A04B05BAB59ACA07922E29" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One Citizen One Vote Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H652D5706E88A42D2A96B43700B927652"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting payments to States failing to meet election integrity and certainty standards</header><subsection id="H48B9017317834473BE6C410AAF836CE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IX of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21141">52 U.S.C. 21141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H80E3BA176CEC498FA55DA21579D1EE72" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H06DE45AE50AE48D5A636C181334BD39E"><enum>907.</enum><header>Prohibiting payments to States and jurisdictions failing to meet election integrity and certainty standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission may not make any payment under this Act to any State or jurisdiction unless the State or jurisdiction certifies to the Commission each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H550A6E47EB22480FA1E4139B29529BC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State or jurisdiction does not permit an individual to cast a ballot in an election for Federal office unless—</text><subparagraph id="H6D4D6099204B46B2A79E4EBAA9F52909"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who desires to cast a ballot in person, the individual presents to the appropriate election official a current and valid photo identification of the individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85FFA55D5D4745ABA2AE509B5DF7AF03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who desires to cast a ballot by mail, the individual includes with the ballot a copy of a current and valid photo identification of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE938FDCC1CF64F90A5594A7A70721F27"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State or jurisdiction does not accept a voted absentee ballot in an election for Federal office which is delivered in person to an election official by any individual other than the voter to whom the ballot was transmitted, other than an individual described as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H2D3E188C8ED9492DB8A7DCE18A6ECADE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An election official while engaged in official duties as authorized by law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB291992B62004A728589CAC56D37750C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An employee of the United States Postal Service while engaged in official duties as authorized by law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BADAABF627946D39B998F6DA7ED02E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other individual who is allowed by law to collect and transmit United States mail, while engaged in official duties as authorized by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEED0C8042E843ECA79F14562D860993"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The State or jurisdiction does not provide any drop box into which an individual may deliver a voted ballot, other than a drop box which is located at the office of a State or local election official.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F91CD93068A456EBF8096801670B762"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The State or jurisdiction does not deliver an absentee or other mail-in ballot to any individual who does not request the delivery of such a ballot.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16C514291C64497BA04723C0A9156A3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State or jurisdiction does not permit any individual who is not a citizen of the United States to register to vote or vote in any election for public office, or any ballot initiative or referendum, held in the State or jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC20B2E642E03403893ACA2A1F8278C5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title IX the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8680E69F51D04BDF949CA1C5A1E8E079" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 907. Prohibiting payments to States and jurisdictions failing to meet election integrity and certainty standards.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H58DE688B78C14145A14E136B66C372A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to payments made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

