<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6731A2D445954F19A7E71634CA85C0AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7172 IH: Permanent Non-Trade Relations for Russia Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7172</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220318">March 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit products imported from Russia to receive normal trade relations treatment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H370B4AFD17EC41CDA4A70314A4FE1BA5" style="OLC"><section id="H18549491C60D45099A213A7AB4FD3245" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Permanent Non-Trade Relations for Russia Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>P.N.T.R. for Russia Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3AF382BE8EAF4B10966634E07139EA8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on extending normal trade relations treatment to Russia</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may not provide normal trade relations treatment to any article imported into the United States from the Russian Federation.</text></section><section id="H2BF65D45305D4ADD877ED2C6415945C2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The prohibition under section 2 shall begin on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to all articles imported into the United States from the Russian Federation on and after such date of enactment. Nothing in this Act may be construed to provide for any delay in such applicability after such date of enactment.</text></section><section id="H2EC10C0E9A4C495784763A2DA5D69C12"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H72934396FF9448559D6F028B896298D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the manner in which the Trade Representative plans to—</text><paragraph id="H86EBFED85E614E1D92601799F89894F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain the support of at least three-fourths of all countries that are members of the World Trade Organization to pursue the adoption of an amendment calling for the removal of the Russian Federation from such Organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5C5EA64B78043F9AB1FB46F4C85FF5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase international support among members of the Organization to remove normal trade relations status for the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC18B52789664B64BC4F8A945BAA58F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD014046E3D9A4253BB5E5E2879B21A7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H79FEE6CCF5774D59A13012F6E31C34EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E6F8F3209914E2897CB8C5882200CEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

