<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA03F050989546D58A3137FC3A8FAB4E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8801 IH: DHS Joint Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8801</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish stronger accountability mechanisms for Joint Task Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F1B44C6992B48C4B730920BC3079392" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD8792D752FBB42E3B21BF33EE5156FB3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Joint Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H725245AC9AD141E19D747FF6DBCD1634"><enum>2.</enum><header>Joint Task Forces of the Department of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 708 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/348">6 U.S.C. 348</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H963F87C95FF6445A87020C6F64F01CF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (8) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H6EF695C114004EDEAAC6B711F889C629" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HBFA713AFBDAF446C86571B8536EC439E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Joint Task Force staff</header> <subparagraph id="H1963E660DCCE4502B6A69A3491D8B97E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Joint Task Force shall have a staff, composed of officials from relevant components and offices of the Department, to assist the Director of such Joint Task Force in carrying out the mission and responsibilities of such Joint Task Force.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42845102434040B5BABACC436AFF6BFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the report submitted under paragraph (6)(F)—</text> <clause id="HB86F8C628F804EF5B512DAE51B8A040E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of personnel permanently assigned to each Joint Task Force by each component and office; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0736A184249E41A1AECA1C847F5BC339"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of personnel assigned on a temporary basis to each Joint Task Force by each component and office.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8C12F7FFDC497F957CB9AC9C49E86A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H820FC95213404A15BEBD6F1181CFCC2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">mission and</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Establishment of</header-in-text></quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31F4178C1101474ABAF395AA57D10F57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HBCD80F366FF24DBDBA5372781280219A" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H380B8C0997494BEB99A50E97CB3F6EE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using leading practices in performance management and lessons learned by other law enforcement task forces and joint operations, establish—</text> <clause id="H2D1FBB8B9CE64DE8A6F82EB4FC147E6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the mission, strategic goals, and objectives of each Joint Task Force;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA88B29677CAA4EF1BFAE41A66D723F36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criteria for terminating each Joint Task Force; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0C41D0C52D1E4E44BEC0D1E5939FD0B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>outcome-based and other appropriate performance metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of each Joint Task Force with respect to the mission, strategic goals, and objectives established pursuant to clause (i), including—</text> 
<subclause id="H62DE31E70BFC4F73A352DB696C28FFAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>targets for each such Joint Task Force to achieve by not later than one and three years after such establishment; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF934ADAA892E48BEBDD15AA0099F5D70"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of the methodology used to establish such metrics;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DE214CF73AD4F28A83675B39F585721"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H2D4F531C15AB43D7B4A92DA293B9DC16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>date of the enactment of this section</quote> and insert <quote>date of the enactment of the DHS Joint Task Forces Reauthorization Act of 2022</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF09C25EE050D4FAE800BD72EA07D53A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>mission, strategic goals, objectives, and</quote> before <quote>metrics</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA4B7FC396F434D3C8FD97E18D13F10DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9B9048981B2429CAA3DD1DEB0DA2306"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HB5E956C79F0A46B393F15661FF5AE27F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H73A034E34F134032A6563A2A81CB463D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the DHS Joint Task Forces Reauthorization Act of 2022 and annually thereafter, submit to the committees specified in subparagraph (B) a report that contains information on the progress in implementing the outcome-based and other appropriate performance metrics established pursuant to subparagraph (A)(iii).</text> </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15EDCCFD57F74FE3BA0488C1D77012EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC46EA10C29BA4DA49FD22F7AA015E9BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">or termination</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">formation</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H294537FFF42D4CBDAABEF0EC04006ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H605ABB3F3D944AB896D61BD8239850BC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5C65080DD8CA4312BCDD898D083A8486"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days before establishing or terminating a Joint Task Force under this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the majority leader of the Senate, the minority leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the majority leader of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a notification regarding such establishment or termination, as the case may be. The contents of any such notification shall include the following:</text> 
<clause id="H99A8EF7963504655B03EB772BFD4DE37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The criteria and conditions required to establish or terminate the Joint Task Force at issue.</text></clause> <clause id="H29CF536B13C94B919CD52FE75F110E03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The primary mission, strategic goals, objectives, and plan of operations of such Joint Task Force.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB25F2681EBFD445494B6170D4EE2EE51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If such notification is a notification of termination, information on the effectiveness of such Joint Task Force as measured by the outcome-based performance metrics and other appropriate performance metrics established pursuant to paragraph (9)(A)(iii).</text></clause> <clause id="HAE7653F20F6740C4A6F90241F8F65D7B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The funding and resources required to establish or terminate such Joint Task Force.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD4B75BA99A5F4DBCA101F697D0BFC973"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The number of personnel permanently assigned to such Joint Task Force from each component or office.</text></clause> <clause id="HD5164B82BEE9428FBDD64FE98F14B27A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The number of personnel assigned on a temporary basis to such Joint Task Force from each component or office.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H585B316910124451A4FF33587816D830" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>If such notification is a notification of establishment, the anticipated costs of establishing and operating such Joint Task Force.</text></clause> <clause id="HDDFB75A1A3284335891473491DC4C8DA" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>If such notification is a notification of termination, funding allocated in the immediately preceding fiscal year to such Joint Task Force for—</text> 
<subclause id="HA564A382CBF543C285D6004F3F185196" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>operations notwithstanding such termination; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE2EECAB9823F4557B27C1E08F027CFA8" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>activities associated with such termination.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HE08DA447C4584391ACCBA870DF32C6E9"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The anticipated establishment or termination date of such Joint Task Force, as the case may be.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65877C4FE12E4B419BF853494AC57240"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF3CC71FCF864A72AF9AC100550C4BFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HC76BEFFAA8CE4D6B988AE7D4C37E9FE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>January 31, 2018, and January 31, 2021, the Inspector General of the Department</quote> and inserting <quote>one year after the date of the enactment of the DHS Joint Task Forces Reauthorization Act of 2022, the Comptroller General of the United States</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9A3AAECA4694AAD8CD13DBDF7F908E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>an assessment of the effectiveness of the Secretary’s utilization of the authority provided under this section for the purposes set forth in subsection (b)(2) as among the range of options available to the Secretary to conduct joint operations among departmental components and offices and</quote> before <quote>a review of the Joint Task Forces</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H218041509E6F4FECAF1B517A35ED282D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> 
<clause id="H6BB07E586EEE4700BA577B7ACC933A76"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>reviews</quote> and inserting <quote>review</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE7148CEFB31749ADA0024CD104CA2B04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending clauses (i) and (ii) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H8A06F5BE851E4C7ABAAD9F3FE0FC4BC3" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="HE510D98466A440D88D3B081F923FA814"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of methodology utilized to determine whether to establish or terminate each Joint Task Force; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6FABFC8DCE6F414287240CE28CFBA591" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of oversight over each Joint Task Force with specificity regarding the Secretary’s utilization of outcome-based or other appropriate performance metrics established pursuant to paragraph (9)(A)(iii) to evaluate the effectiveness of each Joint Task Force in measuring progress with respect to the mission, strategic goals, and objectives established pursuant to paragraph (9)(A)(i) of such Joint Task Force.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H110DC7A8257E44219F7D06C04E330056"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2024</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

