<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3C19F5DE9BF443F99EABDD4B52BC140" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8822 IH: To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to support the placement of students and licensed professional social workers in public libraries, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8822</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220914">September 14, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to support the placement of students and licensed professional social workers in public libraries, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6CFD9E8B222C405099ECA097E2D4D4C1" style="OLC">
<section id="HD805843591824DDFA58270F23E67C5F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Grants for placement of students and social workers in public libraries</header>
<subsection id="HE0B951D3E0C04295B5609425ED8FA615"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education to support the placement of students and licensed professional social workers in public libraries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H74B91E4510F2473BBA4692C7D75CE81C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9FECB806AC8D431C8AD5113BC4B6A893"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with the Institute of Museum and Library Services in the development and review of grant applications under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7AF903D2DBBA4E79997184902E9DC870"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to carry out the following activities:</text>
<paragraph id="HC5735850D6E947DE831558FE963CFF50"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5E3ACA2B9CF34A3989136BB74A072FC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to employ one or more licensed professional social workers whom the institution shall seek to place on a full-time basis in public libraries in the geographic region surrounding the institution; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0184732E95544C1EB4D02D0558485619" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to arrange placements of one or more licensed professional social workers who are employed by other entities, whom the institution shall seek to place on a full-time basis in public libraries in the geographic region surrounding the institution; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC61438FFD088462F9964C0EB7A9BC9A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to arrange and fully fund internships and field placements at such libraries for students of the institution who are majoring in social work, including students pursuing a bachelor’s or master’s degree in social work.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H812057B453FE44FABC1EC5B042EBCC57"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header> <paragraph id="H2CEFE79C69B94411AD531B0CD9E51A5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment and supervision</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8D0ACEDB4B434140925D5E25AB48CB48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for the payment and employment-related administration of the social workers placed at public libraries pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A) and the interns placed at such libraries pursuant to subsection (d)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1721C39AD62F45BCB1BA8B429D3236BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pay a wage of not less than $15 per hour to each intern serving in a public library pursuant to subsection (d)(2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9067C3DAC80443490D39C3A3ED16934"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that each such intern is supervised by a licensed professional social worker (who may be a social worker employed by the institution or a social worker otherwise employed at the public library at which the intern serves). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9B868A66C904FFEA11B46CE3B9316DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of social workers</header> <subparagraph id="H744DE207D9BD42D3A913164F86C6AD8B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of a social worker placed at a public library pursuant to subsection (d)(1) shall be to provide library patrons with—</text>
<clause id="HEF0274E3F8614BA5A9AD10F7250053A7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information on health, nutrition, and other social services for which the patron may be eligible; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF1184DAE61674F4480DB727EE3CFD0C0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assistance in applying for and accessing such services.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEA13287233D8420FACE26D662152EB4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A licensed professional social worker or intern placed at a library pursuant to subsection (d)—</text> <clause id="HA5C70378E99C415E99CF2AB0D114E313"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be required to report an alien who is not in lawful immigration status to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and may provide such alien with appropriate professional services; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H636FD507C0254C18BF500B29162F21D7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be required to provide healthcare services directly to library patrons, such as the administration of diagnostic medical tests.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H14ADCE915CD84CD0894A08D6DA3077C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>National technical assistance center</header> <subsection id="H34053750009D4B7BA76D6BF435DDC108"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall establish an evaluation, documentation, dissemination, and technical assistance resource center to provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of States, federally recognized Indian Tribes, tribal organizations, institutions of higher education, State and local educational agencies, and individual students and educators with respect to hiring and retaining social workers in libraries.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC8FFEB97147F43959B4255D6E1A38B09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the center</header><text>The center established under subsection (a) shall conduct activities for the purpose of—</text> <paragraph id="HACFEDDAAD0964C78B1EA3519B28F7D61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing and continuing statewide or tribal strategies for improving the effectiveness of the social work workforce;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4920F92223304936A8F64C3786572D0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>studying the costs and effectiveness of library social work programs at institutions of higher education to identify areas of improvement and provide information on relevant issues of importance to State, Tribal, and national policymakers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H693783BE1C734AA8B8AB678B1D2B3BA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>working with Federal agencies and other State, Tribal, and national stakeholders to collect, evaluate, and disseminate data regarding social work ratios, outcomes and best practices of mental health services, and the impact of expanding the number of social workers within libraries; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15CBE801F0C645EC8AB24D9C63BB8E90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing partnerships among National, State, Tribal, and local governments, and local educational agencies, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and State and national trade associations for the purposes of—</text> <subparagraph id="H73B1652B3CDA48068C7A419B43456201"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data collection and dissemination;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4106F5F6EDF3405F985A3BF3381313D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a library social work workforce development program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC87D182C930243FEBCE8E7251D03243D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>documenting the success of library social work methods on a national level; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B2327E840FF4F7D9C1561F2B2CC5699"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducting other activities as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6AA94E9030914C409FEDE449D0BD2BCC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H4E98A8787221437A9A4FCF1344FBE792"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) acting through a school of social work within the institution that is accredited by the Council on Social Work Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1D4BE9C9AE547FE96C647585AC0BFFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>licensed professional social worker</term> means a social worker who has a master’s or doctoral degree in social work.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


