<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC025C8C19D148B6B90100C67AB235C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7088 IH: Defenders of Ukraine Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7088</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the Defenders of Ukraine, collectively, in recognition of their crucial role in the defense of the free democracy of Ukraine against Russia’s unprovoked war of aggression.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D1F107F6FFD42FBBE9CCEBEFFED7634" style="OLC"><section id="H2B13F8E74F80478C97597BE6706FE376" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defenders of Ukraine Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H87E723C6244F47ECBBEB09F9461715BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD94972F16C0548088D28DB4A04B518C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 1991, Ukraine declared independence from the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, key to the dissolution of the Soviet Union. Soon after, Ukraine disposed of the world’s third largest nuclear arsenal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF869D8A7EC24856B8A5EAE01550817E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In April 2014, the Russian Federation annexed Crimea and invaded the Donetsk and Luhansk regions of Eastern Ukraine; this initial conflict claimed approximately 14,000 lives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H618E7A34B6B8437196D4F18AE666EEDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On February 24, 2022, the Russian Federation expanded its war against Ukraine, launching a further unprovoked full-scale invasion of the peaceful, independent country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H214E8449C1AE41C1BD0B5EC624B53906"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In response to this unprovoked invasion, hundreds of thousands of Ukrainians have heroically volunteered to defend their country, joining its Armed Forces and taking up arms against Russian Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89F78401D7094A318C6CC981B6C6B733"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia’s unjustifiable invasion has claimed thousands of innocent lives, including children and the elderly, through the targeting of civilians and the destruction of civilian infrastructure including apartment buildings, schools, kindergartens, hotels, and hospitals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49D0A49D62294F1BBFD30B774AF16845"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Millions of Ukrainians have been forced to leave their homes and country behind.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECC0EEC9977442EDA68E81365F649F6B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ukrainian civilians, the Armed Forces of Ukraine, the democratic government, and its elected and civilian officials have been effective in disrupting the Russian invasion, blocking the enemy using a wide range of methods including direct combat, dismantling nearby road signs, using cranes to move cement blocks in the way, producing improvised petrol bombs, and setting up sandbags to block roadways.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1A2DD28864643CBA832BDF38D77A8FE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ukrainian civilians, both armed and unarmed, have shown immense bravery in their heroic attempts to disrupt the Russian war efforts, with little regard for their own safety.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E154555BA764B5395EC3A31357403C3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The courage and strength of Ukrainian citizens resisting their autocratic invaders has strengthened the resolve of the United States and their allies, increasing support for the provision of military and humanitarian aid.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4336E8FDED094879B3AC3D6E2BBF801F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="H9061F0B77DC1405BBFF635BEA0DB0C25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the Defenders of Ukraine, collectively, in recognition of their crucial role in the defense of the free democracy of Ukraine against Russia’s unprovoked war of aggression.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6962CA94E4174C0A9D205AA9EBDD8E1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A179DF0CD2748F6AA789FD07BD9920D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medal</header><text>Following the presentation under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H02A6F9EC08DE45149F7DC6375A363571"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give the gold medal to the Government of Ukraine; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H583CF981687F40F2A980AF697243A238"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary determines that Ukraine does not have a democratically elected government—</text><subparagraph id="HDBA4B1F41BDF4337B1EC732A14FAA326"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transfer the gold medal temporarily to the Smithsonian Institution for display; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4C125262AF43A49259E51B7777AB4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer the gold medal to Ukraine after determining that Ukraine does have a democratically elected government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3ADAF7BF696943A49A964F584B12EE4F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H34C6CABB536E4F2C8D4ECAC08B6397D7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H180D8472AFBA48ADAAD104827AE0BC37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC3BCC28BD5A4405A7C322D1F0A61784"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

