<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE748CC78D1E249CEB677854ACDD957D4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6498 IH: Promoting Peace, Education, And Cultural Exchange through Music Diplomacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6498</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220125">January 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize music-related exchange programs facilitated by the Department of State and relevant private sector partnerships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DC38FD548394E83B10F3AEDDC0A1E89" style="OLC"><section id="HDC6E0776B42546F28D3BCD21E2769530" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Peace, Education, And Cultural Exchange through Music Diplomacy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PEACE through Music Diplomacy Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF6C841ADA334437B9C2A0D20DC815587"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H2DD261ED1605464784079D197B9C2004"><enum>(1)</enum><text>music is an important conveyer of culture and can be used to communicate values and build understanding between communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8DF8E01BBCA4B078101DCC916F93441"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">music artists play a valuable role in cross-cultural exchange, and their works and performances can promote peacebuilding and conflict resolution efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H186DD924A6DE400F9DDBF70D8960D39E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the music industry in the United States has made important contributions to American society and culture, and musicians and industry professionals in the United States can offer valuable expertise to young music artists around the world; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81BC5DD390E74BC38E10C62A4250A929"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Government should promote exchange programs, especially programs that leverage the expertise and resources of the private sector, that give young music artists from around the world the chance to improve their skills, share ideas, learn about American culture, and develop the necessary skills to support conflict resolution and peacebuilding efforts in their communities and broader societies.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD3CD336A87444154B3556093254682F2" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of music-related exchange programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (commonly referred to as the Fulbright-Hays Act) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6B4F7FFF472B4EB4A35EBB9792BA015A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 102(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452">22 U.S.C. 2452(a)(2)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H018CF7EB63724266A9CC8BA8DC413C47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>assemblies;</quote> and inserting <quote>assemblies; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76EA59C6D15440AD8F4112D5F730E58E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv)—</text><clause id="H4F8DA6C1B4874BBE9927F3D178E0E679"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including in coordination and consultation with the private sector,</quote> before <quote>similar</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HBABE0731EF9640D885418B176892D80A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>national interest.</quote> and inserting <quote>national interest; and</quote>; and </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBED7C1E8F14843B85E75335B967C69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 112(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2460">22 U.S.C. 2460(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HD94AAEFAD1B94C8592E242E8D3190D81" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FBA9CBBB6FD4566A2F4019E983F9B72" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF31CF2ECCE2415D932AC4095451807A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H36083BCDC5314E70B6D1478A9F99584B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H344C28F0F7714112BB751F400BC0C3B2" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>exchange programs, including in coordination and consultation with the private sector, focused on music and the performing arts that provide opportunities for foreign nationals and Americans to build cross-cultural understanding and advance peace abroad.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H9CB5D159145D4D8D819673FB94D4DB8A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Private sector partnerships</header><subsection id="H37A9F46BB3EC48E6A5F2A040EBE7EDE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State should seek to partner with the private sector in support of music-related exchange programs implemented by the Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs (ECA), leverage private sector expertise in developing and implementing such programs, expand networking and mentorship opportunities for program participants, and identify private sector funding sources for travel and other program-related expenses where relevant. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7F5B677D158F4534A8BEC2A67E7B7967" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of certain partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to partner with the private sector, including through the granting of awards, to recognize musicians whose works or performances have advanced peace abroad and who could contribute to networking and mentorship opportunities for participants of music-related exchange programs implemented by ECA. </text></subsection></section><section id="H9E7EA98942F0493F9C8F68A1ECA7E0C0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Strategy</header><subsection id="HBDEF59E1163245AFB9B111A2E45A7893"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for advancing United States foreign policy goals, including conflict resolution and peacebuilding efforts, through music-related exchange programs implemented by ECA. Such strategy shall include—</text><paragraph id="H3785724618614707BC65FACFA70A18A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of clearly defined annual goals, targets, and planned outcomes for each music-related exchange program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA003F12692E4FD5BE22A525AA012881"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to monitor and evaluate each music-related exchange program and progress made toward achieving such goals, targets, and planned outcomes, including measurable benchmarks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B5584037F6C4668B23CD17D677BB08D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to ensure that music-related exchange programs are promoting United States foreign policy objectives, including ensuring such programs are clearly branded and paired with robust public diplomacy efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DC684BFF4CA4FD888E20D55A22F252F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan to pursue partnerships with the private sector while implementing music-related exchange programs, including leveraging industry expertise and expanding networking and mentorship opportunities for program participants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H754C543D954141CDBF64B028D3D44743"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92806D723B204C168EDCE77EE82A0CFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examples of how ECA’s music-related exchange programs have contributed to conflict resolution and peacebuilding efforts to date, including through participant and alumni actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FAC355629D5413D98D9399AADD20ABA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of lessons learned regarding how to better encourage conflict resolution and peacebuilding efforts through ECA’s music-related exchange programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7C4AB7714DB409E8C42715803B3E4FC" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan to incorporate such lessons learned into relevant current and future programming.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5CEFDCAE86A47EEA19D9D34E448170A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, as well as relevant private sector partners.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEEF573C02DD048F891FDE75987C1B401"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H7CA874658B4045DAA5456EE6F57055E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E409A8FDC3042E295CD495ACD123084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

