<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE5515F40C453446DBF1A0AEC2F3C2347" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 HR 8158 IH: Base Access Privileges Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8158</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220621">June 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to make certain improvements relating to access to military installations in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D58B10AA8BE4760B1B5FEC9128EF78B" style="OLC"><section id="H554221B03FC64BB4BF6A6B18C0AB09DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Base Access Privileges Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0895017CEA794A45A07B36D5DD08822B" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements relating to access to military installations in United States</header><subsection id="H5D24A2B6C5374BBB85C894135E70C997" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional categories for expedited access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/159">Chapter 159</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H201C6BE02DD84338882F55BD2773FE6A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H337C697C188B4321A212ADD52FC4F49C"><enum>2698.</enum><header>Access to military installations: standards for entry to military installations in United States</header><subsection id="H30EBB738271043AD862AF0163068BD02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to military installations in United States</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB5FCB063E71846238628AD2EDB07361A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall maintain access standards applicable to all military installations in the United States. Such standards shall require screening standards appropriate to the type of installation involved, the security level of the installation, the category of individuals authorized to visit the installation, and the level of access to be granted, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDDD028A21C8F484A9EE0CC6AC4E5B7EB" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protocols to determine the fitness of the individual to enter an installation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9907436BCC43455BA1F516B124DA4866" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>standards and methods for verifying the identity of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EE0D2BFE11F4DB2A811309B14522456" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the standards under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, with respect to military installations in the United States—</text><subparagraph id="HAA8BE21A6DE94F619E48EB9EDB12E91F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for expedited access to such military installations for covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H537E489AA51C4BD3AE26443172ED8B6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for closer scrutiny of categories of individuals determined by the Secretary of Defense to pose a higher potential security risk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD4FE77B097498C90B172EBFDA9F200"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of such a military installation that the Secretary determines contains particularly sensitive facilities, provide additional screening requirements, as well as physical and other security measures for the installation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB97DA76A29B2467AAD1CB5A0D6544DD7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prescribe regulations setting forth minimum criteria for the fitness of individuals to be granted unescorted access to such military installations, taking into account individuals who hold a covered Federally recognized access credential, and including a process by which such individuals may be eligible for expedited unescorted access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9603C730014F0CB3928422566625A7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon publication in the Federal Register of the final regulations under paragraph (2)(D), the Secretary shall publish the minimum criteria set forth therein on a publicly accessible Internet website of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F953F148A0042ABBE3AE032E168CA3D" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall seek to procure and field existing identification screening technology (including technology to enable the Secretary to validate other Federally recognized access credentials) and develop additional technology only to the extent necessary to assist commanders of military installations in the United States in implementing the standards under paragraph (1) at points of entry for such installations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15756C0E8B794EFD9890B84CBCD7C8B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific protocol for access to military installations in United States for certain deliveries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the standards under subsection (a) include a specific protocol for the screening, prior to any delivery of a freight shipment or shipment of household goods, of the identity, fitness, and purpose of any individual seeking access to a military installation in the United States for such delivery. Under such protocol—</text><paragraph id="H21397B334F3F4F6EBD0FD0FA5BFBFA2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the screening shall occur not less than 24 hours prior to the time of such delivery; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB73BF12F3A2F44FBA6943396E12FC41B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if an individual is determined fit to enter the installation pursuant to the screening, access may only be granted upon arrival at the military installation on the date of the delivery, following a verification of the identity of the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3D8FCFA54474D8B91C326C971DF93D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unescorted access to military installations in United States for certain civilians</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain guidance regarding the granting of unescorted access to military installations in the United States for covered civilians and ensure such guidance is circulated to the commanders of each such military installation. Such guidance shall—</text><paragraph id="H32E37BA439FD4EE9AD25F37ACA691CD9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify the categories of covered civilians that may obtain such unescorted access;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48E8FC57C335479FB74333F90310E0EF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a recommendation to issue access cards that expire on the date that is two years after the date of issuance, notwithstanding any change in the commander of the installation or delegation of authority letters issued by the previous commander;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6960DF2E0A54B0FBFB7F596A55E67D8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be consistent across military installations in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H436001529A7543CB9A685F47C0542862"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be in accordance with any privileges or benefits accorded under, procedures developed pursuant to, or requirements of, each covered provision and subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD6EA9C7F6D74A99915B19DEC3657C3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Access cards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall develop access cards to be issued to individuals granted access to military installations in the United States. To the extent practicable, such access cards shall be interoperable across the following:</text><paragraph id="H4B5208D106EB4C79A1585F73D27E8A28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Military installations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8FE43191924A09B47A5965AA07E5B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Military departments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF536479CB5AD41C1BCACCBEB995D025D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Defense Agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H202557CEC79A46E5A1ED739CEAEB246B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Physical entrances to certain military installations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable—</text><paragraph id="H99536A78B17C4A94B42F8DE6D6C42F6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each military installation in the United States has a designated main entrance that, at all times, is manned by at least one member of the armed forces or civilian employee of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37EC75C73458481FABAD04B7E8896619"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the location of each such designated main entrance is published on a publicly accessible Internet website of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7124C592BCF441B18D44DA9A422E1868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if a military installation in the United States has any additional entrance designated for commercial deliveries to the military installation, the location of such entrance (and any applicable days or hours of operation for such entrance) is published on the same Internet website specified in paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96746A3738CE4A37B50BEF6EABF24E0C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the information published on the Internet website specified in paragraph (2) is reviewed and, as necessary, updated on a basis that is not less frequent than annually.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42FE2548707A493AADF5E5E96448382E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reviews and submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a basis that is not less frequent than once every five years, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H74F2A1839B694BC2B32378DCBDC7B8A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the standards and guidance under this section, and make such updates as may be determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H263685D2EB124D62BC018EF04B995DE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate the most recently reviewed and, as applicable, updated version of such standards and guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5C924B6FB1E47FCA48109DF3EE28F96"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H29E2C1848E404B209467D3160FB6FC0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered civilian</quote> means an individual who is not a Department of Defense personnel or a dependent of such personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28D957CA20754F6A94FDBAD734E47571"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered Federally recognized access credential</quote> means a Federally recognized access credential the grant or recognition of which requires vetting at a level that the Secretary of Defense determines is commensurate with or greater than the level of vetting that would otherwise be required by the Secretary for the purpose concerned, and includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HCCA6C95195B346868CA04EA085B37D85" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A Transportation Worker Identification Credential.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39AA3018C73248D0B47B151A145A6B91" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A Secure Identification Display Area credential issued pursuant to section 1540.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation to such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FCDF03AF200455380A2722A2BEE1043" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A personnel identity verification credential issued pursuant to the Presidential directive of August 27, 2004, titled <quote>Homeland Security Presidential Directive–12</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H076B435012664B3286B9750ED4C0ACD8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A credential accepted for purposes of the Personnel Surety Program of the Chemical Facilities Anti-Terrorism Program under section 2102(d)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/622">6 U.S.C. 622(d)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1F0ED4243E4470FBC786BB51F62437C" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A credential issued for purposes of the access authorization program of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, or any successor to such program, in accordance with part 73 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E0CAAD07DF9426496D2EA0F1D6427E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means, with respect to a military installation in the United States, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H159DAFC91E424B72B2E87493CBD3CCC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the armed forces or civilian employee of the Department of Defense, or an employee or family member of such member or employee, who resides, attends school, receives health care services, or shops at a commissary or exchange store on the installation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4BA08A8D8DB4F9B9890BD5EADC9E37E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A retired member of the armed forces, including the reserve components, or a family member of such retired member, who resides, attend schools, receives health care services, or shops at a commissary or exchange store on the installation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FFA52767F15447794BF33B57F62A870"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A covered civilian performing work at the installation under a contract or subcontract (at any tier), including a military construction project, military family housing project, or a Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E9E697C32554FBDB01C8B45089028DD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motor carrier or household goods motor carrier providing transportation services for the United States Transportation Command.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52FCA01865CC439BAD93C32FAEE30AF0"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An official who is employed by an agency of the State in which the installation is located that enforces laws relating to workers’ compensation or minimum wage with respect to such State and who is seeking such access pertaining to a specific military construction project, military family housing project, or Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8DCFD9B0B114F2E806A231F3AB26B55" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A representative of any labor organization (as defined in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>)), including a member of any labor management committee described in section 205A of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/175a">29 U.S.C. 175a</external-xref>), who is—</text><clause id="HA6943E9AA2094EF1A0575CA731F8927B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeking access to a covered civilian performing work at the installation who is a member of such labor organization—</text><subclause id="HAA01CF04AC1041BB97A67297D6EB938B" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in connection with a specific military construction project, military family housing project, or Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization project; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H37BB3578BBBA4D9F99671969996D153C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to a concessions or service contract subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/67">chapter 67</external-xref> of title 41 (known as the <quote>McNamara-O'Hara Service Contract Act of 1965</quote>); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF0252D8A08AC4288A827D3DAC1BE1A63" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeking access to a covered civilian performing work at the installation for the purposes of soliciting such covered civilian to join such labor organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E501D353C064E5FACBD894C268272DF" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A representative of any labor organization (as defined in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>)), including a member of any labor management committee described in section 205A of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/175a">29 U.S.C. 175a</external-xref>), or a representative of a program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), conducting a vocational training, job fair, or similar workforce development event for members of the armed forces or veterans at the installation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D32FB440A4F41D8B490BD2939FAA1AB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered provision</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H671B3D3BEBDC4217AAE75FCF07F39596" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 54 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B76C9055E4D49D5870A762710D6C80E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 202 of the REAL ID Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/13">Public Law 109–13</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30301">49 U.S.C. 30301</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H558FC706A11B4684B425294D62B59EE4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2812 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 2150; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE7DF747D6C484F936B7C2E103C57D3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 346 and 1050 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF66F705963C141D6918EE2F70A572332" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 626 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1802; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78B1146D6F72406AB20DD6EF884984AD" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1090 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3879; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9651F47D95842CC86614968D9B592A5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federally recognized access credential</quote> means a credential authorized by Federal law or otherwise issued by the head of a Federal department or agency that requires the vetting of an individual for access to a facility, area, or program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00B0A470DF24493FBB17C5B892C37246"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The terms <quote>household goods</quote>, <quote>household goods motor carrier</quote>, and <quote>motor carrier</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 13102 of title 49.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B4CA4F1770F493DA08650D29759E20F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The terms <quote>labor organization</quote> and <quote>representative</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D6F9A7C38A46B38AF6979DD51317E7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <quote>military installation</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 2801 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H506A0D7B4CB748A0B4E1A9F0281F4E96" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H157561D8DEFE4C27A5848A4E8DBC0190"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Transportation Worker Identification Credential</quote> means a card issued pursuant to section 70105 of title 46, United States Code (also referred to as a ‘transportation security card’). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BDBA945E4642658753A89928F72B78"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The term <quote>United States</quote> includes each State, as such term is defined in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H052D4196D8064400A8031828EF42BF0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for first review and submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text><paragraph id="H3D1E4C10C27D4445AB2D3A349BF12B4D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct the first review of the standards and guidance required under section 2698 of title 10, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCAD6BE2FA0B44839C78C7E1B9F0A1D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate the reviewed and, as applicable, updated version of such standards and guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CEB61D4EC2E4D4EA87CEC905E0327AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification to certain notification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1090(b)(2)(B) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3879; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>is</quote> and inserting <quote>and, as appropriate, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, are</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1410D01067684EF78CDEF315B284D3F2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H4FAAAAEF7E7C49E4A5591E62FD3A837D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal of duplicate provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1069 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/181">Public Law 110–181</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 326) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H546731782B0045AF873058BD4CEDEECB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to prior National Defense Authorization Act</header><text>Section 1050 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note; 130 Stat. 2396) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HE46994615F6B4267A3465D07827BE01A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Department of Defense installations</quote> and inserting <quote>military installations in the United States</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512702726C2F4558BB45D1E2A97CA101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>Department of Defense facilities</quote> and inserting <quote>military installations in the United States</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE396A1246AA44E8B9CFE5C841A878D8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0A7BC1DAA80B4B5EBDBACA12312FF895" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HFC6137A616E047DC83A5F066C1EE73E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFF8C1D401B3E4BCE905EBA68532C16BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <quote>military installation</quote> and <quote>United States</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 2698(e) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H846883DC977F40DEBD04DF9D32969B90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Transportation Worker Identification Credential</quote> and <quote>TWIC</quote> mean a card issued pursuant to section 70105 of title 46, United States Code (also referred to as a ‘transportation security card’).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

