<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16091F18AC16401A87C422CD332680AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7943 IH: To permit Members of the House of Representatives to use the Members' Representational Allowance to continue to provide services for casework projects on behalf of former constituents who no longer reside in the Member's congressional district as the result of congressional redistricting.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7943</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220603">June 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permit Members of the House of Representatives to use the Members' Representational Allowance to continue to provide services for casework projects on behalf of former constituents who no longer reside in the Member's congressional district as the result of congressional redistricting.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H01D424406E824C038909F2239D9D8A76" style="OLC"><section id="H08FAE6CEF10E463F9B96856F5936DFD9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Members’ Representational Allowance to continue providing services for casework projects for former constituents affected by redistricting</header><subsection id="HD9EFF8A217664AEBA7273ED081B1DF4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5341">2 U.S.C. 5341</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2823DB5F117F44B184FD6B107972145F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (e) as subsections (d) through (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBA99F5AAF634712881A8A0AA228CA07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAF3AB6EA539040779696DB849E32E683" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H29DE676B23544B4493702655B9CE6222"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use for continuing casework services for certain former constituents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Member of the House of Representatives provides services for a casework project on behalf of an individual who is a constituent of the Member during a Congress but who is not a constituent during a succeeding Congress, the provision of casework services for that project on behalf of that individual by the Member during the first session of the succeeding Congress shall be considered as part of the Member’s official and representational duties during the first session of the succeeding Congress for purposes of this section if the individual would have been a constituent during the succeeding Congress but for the enactment of a congressional redistricting plan.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1ADC6C275FF64FD09626694DC031781A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to services provided during the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress and any succeeding Congress.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

