<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1CD1282D1CEA49DC8ED975113A1A1C4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8766 IH: Reserving Energy For Independence and Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8766</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220902">September 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to conduct studies relating to Strategic Petroleum Reserve levels, to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act with respect to such Reserve, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEF58789066E4247B2764D36C2690E65" style="OLC"><section id="H3C9CF3A859724867BA0DC20EF5DEBFFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reserving Energy For Independence and Empowerment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REFINE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6935E1B3124C4AF688CC407302A49DC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="HAB18DAEB27D24AB6B53F2E2CA1BCF516"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD80CA7F0C6B94862BD33795E45436337"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Strategic Petroleum Reserve was created through the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6231">42 U.S.C. 6231 et seq.</external-xref>) to address <quote>severe energy supply interruptions</quote> and provided the executive branch authority to draw down these reserves provided that specific conditions are met.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF386AE6617843E6A985D1764BBCF664"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the U.S. Energy Information Administration’s Annual Energy Outlook 2022, petroleum and natural gas will remain the most-consumed sources of energy in the United States through 2050.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43192715B9C347F88A12CB0F75DB89E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of August 19, 2022, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve fell to 453.1 million barrels, from a maximum capacity of 714 million barrels, which is the lowest level since 1985.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H645C0B9AD2F7469AB89553FD164CE8A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Emergency sales in 2022 from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve were purchased by Unipec, a subsidiary of Chinese oil giant Sinopec, and delivered to the People’s Republic of China, the principle strategic competitor to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5E2CE97430D4BA6AE61D1EA0AA18FEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H0C2C79797E764C5BA05CB7EDF24E7AC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continuing to limit energy production in the United States will only provide further leverage and funding for our adversaries and continue to weaken global security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8979E3DAFC8B4748B9C66460946C16E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the energy independence of the United States is critical to national security and should include the production of all available energy sources, including coal, natural gas, oil, nuclear, and renewables, as well as strategic minerals critical to electric vehicles and other clean energy sources.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H81423AA864F6440AB96F554FEDC22D82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategic Petroleum Reserve levels and emergency sales</header><subsection id="H4A0FD793AEF348FABFE92381A6F91D11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Studies and assessment</header><paragraph id="H8D1078D2B1D74DDEB982F35E321361C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="HDFF130E76F054176B123C253F7943E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of a study of metrics that may be used for determining the adequacy of the amounts of petroleum products stored in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to support United States energy security objectives, taking into consideration gross crude oil imports, net crude oil imports, and refining capacity and utilization, and a determination of which such metrics are the most appropriate for such purpose;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D8FFB3F90C34FB187021D45CFD1D14F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of a study and analysis of domestic crude oil refining capacity (including technical configuration of refineries, downstream charge capacity, and atmospheric crude distillation units) and issues relating to aging infrastructure that would inhibit the ability to meet production demand, and any recommendations for improvements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H482BA2EE9B614CF5843682F8224FBFD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of acquisition procedures and identification of any provisions of Federal law or regulation that either limit or prohibit accelerated replenishment of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve necessary to maintain and support United States energy security objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E08706D31404BD895E3D6029B1062B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C7C7C7FA1A347808587A12CFFF499A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H6AE3C62819AB46719F6EA71A3F40FA92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by inserting after section 163 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6243">42 U.S.C. 6243</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H29D99333E9C8424D9EB9A7505CFF17BB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H7DE114B0AF6E4004B1DA95EFD53DF32E"><enum>164.</enum><header>Prohibition on exports</header><subsection id="HB6029422B59346C19A4AFC7C77199C71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 101(b) of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212a">42 U.S.C. 6212a(b)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall issue regulations prohibiting the export of petroleum products drawn down and sold from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to—</text><paragraph id="H510206D6DE544D6F8FA88F5E35779D9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any country that is—</text><subparagraph id="H29E65A5690D44670B5FB11CA30DAF002"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to a United States arms embargo, as specified in list D:5 of Country Group D in Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1959981618364876B86E3082A3315781"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a state sponsor of terrorism; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F38EC5770014CB8BBD3A4F7F070D9FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that is wholly or partially owned by the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H143B478B95CD4245A2BD5813E029EDF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which has repeatedly provided support for international terrorism pursuant to—</text><paragraph id="HB05EA8A7B9924D018EDACAC5489FC1F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB494ADDB8F2E42AEAD712E0A836A7444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H787B772583214A9B8E7CDAA5BA8FDAA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB182CB7A0F7646E6B703FDCD9BCB893E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other applicable provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H87237A928BF7430E9CDB13E0A984205B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="H6B282A03719045A49A5FB344CF0B8C2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Drawdown and sale of petroleum products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 161(a) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and section 164</quote> before the period at the end. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5172BD10C6164E87AECD799763F3B0D8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 163 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3ECF223921BB4473A3CBCA240DA984BF"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 164. Prohibition on exports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE9D162354E91483A922CD2694430FF67"><enum>4.</enum><header>Domestic production response plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 161 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H83A354CF056F45C7BD0CD2DCF1BD46CA" style="OLC"><subsection id="H57FFC059835D41FA8C2DBC04AC81A964"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Plan</header><paragraph id="HB356028325EF4E109AEFFE349104EB47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except in the case of a severe energy supply interruption described in subsection (d), the Secretary may not execute the first drawdown of petroleum products in the Reserve after the date of enactment of this subsection, whether through sale, exchange, or loan, until the Secretary has developed a plan to increase the percentage of Federal land (including submerged land of the outer Continental Shelf) under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense leased for oil and gas production by the same percentage as the percentage of petroleum in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve that is to be drawn down in that first drawdown and subsequent drawdowns.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00090DA8C2C5472C97371E7799EC1615"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall prepare the plan under paragraph (1) in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC6FCD851ED3B40FD912E11F00C9C071D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Executive and agency action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H863BD611A5A841ADB4B8B4F1DAA0CBD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>rescind Executive Order 13990 (86 Fed. Reg. 7037; relating to protecting public health and the environment and restoring science to tackle the climate crisis); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E22E8D77AFB46CD94B616B894757AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>direct each Federal agency (including the Council on Environmental Quality) to, not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H7ADA6A19312E431EB24A4BDEB393CCAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and repeal any regulation promulgated by the Federal agency that has the intent or effect of substantially reducing the energy independence of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H734980873AE641858CB78342607C2FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issues regulations and guidance to—</text><clause id="H1646A0F2BD9D45B79C0E5DD65D60C07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce the regulatory burden for energy producers in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H28BBCCA241054E559253AABAB56FE801"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase the energy output by those producers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

