<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95DB744A675A4900A35553E4FBCDF321" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6521 IH: Supporting STEM Learning Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6521</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220128">January 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for hands-on learning opportunities in STEM education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA1F3C9E0F19043889B4AC389B28C126B" style="OLC"><section id="H4D1C1F84978F4B8F9B7A9132210B5CBB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting STEM Learning Opportunities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7C81B6B7962F44AF8782216071FB6696"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HED43FDF9112849E49FE00669DA3BF635"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing a robust, talented, and homegrown workforce, particularly in the fields of STEM, is critical to the success of the United States innovation economy. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792300DB57444D59BD14F114F3850637"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States educational system is not producing a sufficient number of workers with the necessary STEM expertise to meet the needs of the United States industry in STEM fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA36EE7DF1D047DF810374A4128690FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hands-on and experiential learning opportunities outside of the classroom are critical for student success in STEM subjects and careers, stimulating students’ interest, increasing confidence, and creating motivation to pursue a related career.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1285159FDA8B478DBE61845FD8A608E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hands-on and experiential learning opportunities can be particularly successful in inspiring interest in students who traditionally have been underrepresented in STEM fields, including girls, students of color, and students from disadvantaged backgrounds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79CDC87889E4BC2A0E3C75E5BD29DB4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An expansion of hands-on and experiential learning programs across the United States would expand the STEM workforce pipeline, developing and training students for careers in STEM fields. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HD83BF371D62447C4ADB5B917000E52F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hands-on learning opportunities in STEM education</header><subsection id="HC0C829471C95490CB92574D152F1C5EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9CE2B98F79334DC38A7C2F4D356D8063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>high school</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5785F19A7C1F4A4FA2FB839702AA27DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible nonprofit program</header><text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit program</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HDC439AF48D7749598D870A2DC1A993EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a nonprofit program serving prekindergarten, elementary school, or secondary school students; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAFE737F4F84110943A3FECB7056F95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a program described in subparagraph (A) that covers the continuum of education from prekindergarten through high school and is available in every State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD51C94C61674DA0B48262DF8B997FC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD04EB4BE73E44B4A8B5238CC22B290A6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA77F87E683754516BA0CA4A2A7640BD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are to—</text><paragraph id="H5BB45A088FA94FEB81C602BE32C1C618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide effective, compelling, and engaging means for teaching and reinforcing fundamental STEM concepts and inspiring the youth of the United States to pursue careers in STEM-related fields;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AB6A2F45E954DB9929CB5248B727DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand the STEM workforce pipeline by developing and training students for careers in United States STEM fields; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4394D41635E408184A62DDF47104539"><enum>(3)</enum><text>broaden participation in the STEM workforce by underrepresented population groups.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13920A2760604F979CC78A6481C153E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><paragraph id="H5767B4AA3D27487389D71E842C7CDCFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall, subject to the availability of appropriations for such purposes, provide grants to eligible nonprofit programs for supporting hands-on learning opportunities in STEM education, including via after-school activities and innovative learning opportunities such as robotics competitions and for the purposes of evaluating the impact of such programs on STEM learning and disseminating the results of such evaluations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ED0CEAD437A4C669450B31D7848C71C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under the program, the Director shall give priority to eligible nonprofit programs serving students that attend elementary schools or secondary schools (including high schools) that—</text><subparagraph id="H7BF195F45E4E4E82A8CDE144492B1D94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are implementing comprehensive support and improvement activities or targeted support and improvement activities under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1111(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13B5C55A99DA465BB4BFA5BA83CE35FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve high percentages of students who are eligible for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>) (which, in the case of a high school, may be calculated using comparable data from the schools that feed into the high school).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3D746EAFD5A472A8CA635D1C256CC9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

