<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECC124516B164A1EAE8D2A5213859B2B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 7234 IH: Summer Barrow Prevention, Treatment, and Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220328">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000377">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize certain programs with respect to mental health conditions and substance use disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1EEC7B066F64BE18C8A61367AB63876" style="OLC"><section id="H29AB2A3C58474FEB9E5F65E2A7F692A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Summer Barrow Prevention, Treatment, and Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6630E07619C44283AD2FE0F076D659DD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H29AB2A3C58474FEB9E5F65E2A7F692A5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6630E07619C44283AD2FE0F076D659DD" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDD9617761B394570AC5B4EE9928359B6" level="section">Sec. 3. Grants for the benefit of homeless individuals.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8232B0D589844D4E8F094C113EE426EC" level="section">Sec. 4. Priority substance abuse treatment needs of regional and national significance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H408028762E7949FD9E07B5C95504EC89" level="section">Sec. 5. Evidence-based prescription opioid and heroin treatment and interventions demonstration.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H92AB0A8251AD4F15A24D6806D8B205CB" level="section">Sec. 6. Priority substance use disorder prevention needs of regional and national significance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2F8544CBFA774456AC0E77B5FC50C573" level="section">Sec. 7. Sober Truth on Preventing (STOP) Underage Drinking Reauthorization.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H19952BE09ECF4BD0B63E0B819F32B196" level="section">Sec. 8. Grants for jail diversion programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H76B34FA697884730A0851DA1D5F737D9" level="section">Sec. 9. Formula grants to States.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H11246FBFDDEC4279A187CB39AD59E9D6" level="section">Sec. 10. Projects for Assistance in Transition From Homelessness.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3414F45FC32E4A9B81CBAF7F6E216980" level="section">Sec. 11. Grants for reducing overdose deaths.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H456D068997A74A529349022FC6DFE980" level="section">Sec. 12. Opioid overdose reversal medication access and education grant programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H13EEE3CB3E4242C58335160805F77DF6" level="section">Sec. 13. State demonstration grants for comprehensive opioid abuse response.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5AC6C3D0A5634BB5919FD2BEA7CFE572" level="section">Sec. 14. Emergency department alternatives to opioids.</toc-entry></toc></section><section id="HDD9617761B394570AC5B4EE9928359B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for the benefit of homeless individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 506(e) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa-5">42 U.S.C. 290aa–5(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></section><section id="H8232B0D589844D4E8F094C113EE426EC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Priority substance abuse treatment needs of regional and national significance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 509 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-2">42 U.S.C. 290bb–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE90643941DB44E58A3A5495E9A7DBDB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Abuse</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Use Disorder</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA448BEBD53B49F7B81F35F7B4A06316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HDE68AB29409D4094BFBED63DBB051A5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>tribes and tribal organizations</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Tribes and Tribal organizations</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF18BB941BDEA4018875CD1177B91F7C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>in substance abuse</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD69413417A3346F5B2EF90673C837E34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Abuse</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Use Disorder</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0E4F5C8A474E7BBE2CCDD20B230AD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>$333,806,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>$521,517,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H408028762E7949FD9E07B5C95504EC89"><enum>5.</enum><header>Evidence-based prescription opioid and heroin treatment and interventions demonstration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 514B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-10">42 U.S.C. 290bb–10</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H707970533B0F4521B1B28EB5BD31EE48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H39BE623D11274B62B48BA94F37764E65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>substance abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>substance use disorder</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D29ADA1E86B4585BD611225BD0B5CF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>tribes and tribal organizations</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribes and Tribal organizations</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C4559F1218B44808EE744457D0C45F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>addiction</quote> and inserting <quote>substance use disorders</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07955AE3A1E414F8852CF75C3C90701"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(3), by striking <quote>tribes and tribal organizations</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribes and Tribal organizations</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F006A1A29C44E41A131FEFB20B81651"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>2017 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H92AB0A8251AD4F15A24D6806D8B205CB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Priority substance use disorder prevention needs of regional and national significance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 516 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-22">42 U.S.C. 290bb–22</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1F65B0603AA2455BBEA3EF15C2917FAD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H1AB95E39E20445669CE7EC60D1592657"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F58E4DC87394221BDD13CDB3CD1D97B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (3), by striking <quote>tribes or tribal organizations</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Tribes or Tribal organizations</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1285AB7ECDB24F1789C580B4BEC4677B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Abuse</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Use Disorder</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19256399A7B7471BABEB1E66BFAB91D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>$211,148,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>$218,219,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2F8544CBFA774456AC0E77B5FC50C573"><enum>7.</enum><header> Sober Truth on Preventing (STOP) Underage Drinking Reauthorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 519B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-25b">42 U.S.C. 290bb–25b</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H630D4F539B2745DD826B65F5AABD347B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2D7DF5B0DB4F48B499348F1377069050"><enum>519B.</enum><header>Programs to reduce underage drinking</header><subsection id="HAA604E88720941A991220386D8C40184"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H488B4E15E1D342BF8F5056CCA1AC54B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>alcohol beverage industry</term> means the brewers, vintners, distillers, importers, distributors, and retail or online outlets that sell or serve beer, wine, and distilled spirits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E74B076CFE54DD5892E61C0BD61FB7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>school-based prevention</term> means programs, which are institutionalized, and run by staff members or school-designated persons or organizations in any grade of school, kindergarten through 12th grade.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4BC8F7680C54D0A8C23262204D73ED0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>youth</term> means persons under the age of 21.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BC4CD3F709D463F8FBCF7DB2AF1F185"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that:</text><paragraph id="HE490793351F5412A909F068608E6F7A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A multifaceted effort is needed to more successfully address the problem of underage drinking in the United States. A coordinated approach to prevention, intervention, treatment, enforcement, and research is key to making progress. This section recognizes the need for a focused national effort, and addresses particulars of the Federal portion of that effort, as well as Federal support for State activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A36BCAD4F2548498C97D1DDD8E5D953"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall continue to conduct research and collect data on the short- and long-range impact of alcohol use and abuse upon adolescent brain development and other organ systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3035E3F4F6FF4A70A7F6C3D3EFA50EA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>States and communities, including colleges and universities, are encouraged to adopt comprehensive prevention approaches, including—</text><subparagraph id="H948970ED0D9049F1952C4EA576D52128"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence-based screening, programs, and curricula;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H601C3E0076A349E5B1E74DC07024D121"><enum>(B)</enum><text>brief intervention strategies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H877AF2F7A04C4809AE45B06639F45F1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consistent policy enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEED2FBDC27542B08F7E654C1C11F1D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>science-based strategies to reduce underage drinking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB51C34209A54907A8F9EEA32347B397"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Public health groups, consumer groups, and the alcohol beverage industry should continue and expand evidence-based efforts to prevent and reduce underage drinking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC6909F06E6470AB8C8E31AE5D90C32"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The entertainment industries and social media platforms have a powerful impact on youth, and they should use rating systems and marketing codes to reduce the likelihood that underage audiences will be exposed to movies, recordings, television programs, or social media with unsuitable alcohol content.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67870CDD5DC14E2CBE8B56C0160F82D2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The National Collegiate Athletic Association, its member colleges and universities, and athletic conferences should affirm a commitment to a policy of discouraging alcohol use among underage students and other young fans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D552F976565428EB19C0035357DA6B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Alcohol is a unique product and should be regulated differently than other products by the States and Federal Government. States have primary authority to regulate alcohol distribution and sale, and the Federal Government should support and supplement these State efforts. States also have a responsibility to fight youth access to alcohol and reduce underage drinking. Continued State regulation and licensing of the manufacture, importation, sale, distribution, transportation, and storage of alcoholic beverages are clearly in the public interest and are critical to promoting responsible consumption, preventing illegal access to alcohol by persons under 21 years of age from commercial and noncommercial sources, maintaining industry integrity and an orderly marketplace, and furthering effective State tax collection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9BCCC91C6DA4577BB4833AF825762C9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The age-21 minimum drinking law, enacted in 1984, has been a remarkably effective public health and safety policy, as evidenced by the fact that the percentage of 12th graders who have drunk alcohol in the past month has fallen by one-half since the enactment of such law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0566E9B5ACF94D34BC18CBEAA617A815"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The age-21 law has also has been significantly effective in reducing drinking and driving traffic fatalities, as the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) estimates that the age-21 law has saved over 31,000 lives since its inception.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C86B07AB1841EDAA143C788B1EF0D5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Community awareness, support, and mobilization provide an important context for the effective enforcement of the age-21 minimum drinking law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21C4FF0FE01B41F9A3686D3D0DB39A49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency coordinating committee; annual report on State underage drinking prevention and enforcement activities</header><paragraph id="H0C5A258FBB7A45C4BAC11657B21A4EC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interagency coordinating committee on the prevention of underage drinking</header><subparagraph id="H2408A9D0E58348D3A5B1B409FCCB074C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Federal officials specified in subparagraph (B), shall continue to support and enhance the efforts of the interagency coordinating committee, that began operating in 2004, focusing on underage drinking (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB03460BF4544A87A9434696D6DF76FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The officials referred to in subparagraph (A) are the Secretary of Education, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Surgeon General, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Director of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the Assistant Secretary for Children and Families, the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission, and such other Federal officials as the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87F90106414C4B9ABAF4971C38121669"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall serve as the chair of the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF608AE49200348E4AA04C20B9D0CE469"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall guide policy and program development across the Federal Government with respect to underage drinking, provided, however, that nothing in this section shall be construed as transferring regulatory or program authority from an Agency to the Coordinating Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4D3FEE69E924C0FAA1A05077298831D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Committee shall actively seek the input of and shall consult with all appropriate and interested parties, including States, public health research and interest groups, foundations, and alcohol beverage industry trade associations and companies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A22B070E7A34F44B03883214772E8C1"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Annual report</header><clause id="H0ADF7D22B6B54EC4829C7CED882692CF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, on behalf of the Committee, shall annually submit to the Congress a report that summarizes—</text><subclause id="H3E9569722B124A74844853CF709A89F6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all programs and policies of Federal agencies designed to prevent and reduce underage drinking, focusing particularly on programs and policies that support the adoption and enforcement of State policies designed to prevent and reduce underage drinking as specified in paragraph (2);</text></subclause><subclause id="HFF1422B39B9044D4B2BC95919D42D322"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the extent of progress in preventing and reducing underage drinking at State and national levels;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD4A3BCBEA73F43B7946011097C3CB411"><enum>(III)</enum><text>data that the Secretary shall collect with respect to the information specified in clause (ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H61FA055B41274C5BB91886BD12AD07C7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other information regarding underage drinking as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE154D19A9C284F0AA782172740B5137B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain information</header><text>The report under clause (i) shall include information on the following:</text><subclause id="HAAABF1EEF7A94534AEBF9A0B1A9E0313"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Patterns and consequences of underage drinking as reported in research and surveys such as, but not limited to, Monitoring the Future, Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System, the National Survey on Drug Use and Health, and the Fatality Analysis Reporting System.</text></subclause><subclause id="HCD7F4E38A6F74C7DA7CD70B23EA7B581"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Measures of the availability of alcohol from commercial and non-commercial sources to underage populations.</text></subclause><subclause id="HDD93FCC8EC3D4631B50D2B5AD0871F28"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Measures of the exposure of underage populations to messages regarding alcohol in advertising, social media, and the entertainment media.</text></subclause><subclause id="H098FCD70528A406BB1C974ACBA9D9C6E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Surveillance data, including information on the onset and prevalence of underage drinking, consumption patterns, beverage preferences, prevalence of drinking among students at institutions of higher education, correlations between adult and youth drinking, and the means of underage access, including trends over time for these surveillance data. The Secretary shall develop a plan to improve the collection, measurement, and consistency of reporting Federal underage alcohol data.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF41DF3B120FB40739987ADF2F38D57B2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any additional findings resulting from research conducted or supported under subsection (f).</text></subclause><subclause id="H2B8EA0CB0D7B4CF0982F4718C943540A"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Evidence-based best practices to prevent and reduce underage drinking including a review of the research literature related to State laws, regulations, and policies designed to prevent and reduce underage drinking, as described in paragraph (2)(B)(i).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD654BA164FEA4B6EB73862935A7E7B94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report on State underage drinking prevention and enforcement activities</header><subparagraph id="H5D0937EBFA114A52A9CEBFE318B3C41F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, with input and collaboration from other appropriate Federal agencies, States, Indian Tribes, territories, and public health, consumer, and alcohol beverage industry groups, annually issue a report on each State’s performance in enacting, enforcing, and creating laws, regulations, and policies to prevent or reduce underage drinking based on an assessment of best practices developed pursuant to paragraph (1)(F)(ii)(VI) and subparagraph (B)(i). For purposes of this paragraph, each such report, with respect to a year, shall be referred to as the <quote>State Report</quote>. Each State Report shall be designed as a resource tool for Federal agencies assisting States in the their underage drinking prevention efforts, State public health and law enforcement agencies, State and local policymakers, and underage drinking prevention coalitions including those receiving grants pursuant to subsection (e).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H511776580DED432E86571137121C992A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State performance measures</header><clause id="HD3381429E88D4DDFA953696C5F899FAB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop, in consultation with the Committee, a set of measures to be used in preparing the State Report on best practices as they relate to State laws, regulations, policies, and enforcement practices.</text></clause><clause id="H8DFFAD3AB066406EAC305E0AAADCCD00"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>State report content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State Report shall include updates on State laws, regulations, and policies included in previous reports to Congress, including with respect to the following:</text><subclause id="H566BD5CD46DA4A7CAA57CCDA79BBDB00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether or not the State has comprehensive anti-underage drinking laws such as for the illegal sale, purchase, attempt to purchase, consumption, or possession of alcohol; illegal use of fraudulent ID; illegal furnishing or obtaining of alcohol for an individual under 21 years; the degree of strictness of the penalties for such offenses; and the prevalence of the enforcement of each of these infractions.</text></subclause><subclause id="H03B0ED0DA5344128A29AE76DFDEC68F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether or not the State has comprehensive liability statutes pertaining to underage access to alcohol such as dram shop, social host, and house party laws, and the prevalence of enforcement of each of these laws.</text></subclause><subclause id="HCC20276B10D64B06A70E102829771613"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether or not the State encourages and conducts comprehensive enforcement efforts to prevent underage access to alcohol at retail outlets, such as random compliance checks and shoulder tap programs, and the number of compliance checks within alcohol retail outlets measured against the number of total alcohol retail outlets in each State, and the result of such checks.</text></subclause><subclause id="H673FA319C6624F5392CED139CCEAFBBC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Whether or not the State encourages training on the proper selling and serving of alcohol for all sellers and servers of alcohol as a condition of employment.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF73EA7836A6A4CC28D600FA00687DF6F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Whether or not the State has policies and regulations with regard to direct sales to consumers and home delivery of alcoholic beverages.</text></subclause><subclause id="H9554BF3C9EFE4209ABB5F82670E944EA"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Whether or not the State has programs or laws to deter adults from purchasing alcohol for minors; and the number of adults targeted by these programs.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA7F8DFBA614248B589FE35CA93108072"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Whether or not the State has enacted graduated drivers licenses and the extent of those provisions.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7B330E8D171D4E6F85B97C849F778928"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional categories</header><text>In addition to the updates on State laws, regulations, and policies listed in clause (ii), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><subclause id="HCD4289C5664748ABB5DF9C0CEB8B1EED"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not States have adopted laws, regulations, and policies that deter underage alcohol use, as described in <quote>The Surgeon General’s Call to Action to Prevent and Reduce Underage Drinking</quote> issued in 2007 and <quote>Facing Addiction in America: The Surgeon General’s Report on Alcohol, Drugs and Health</quote> issued in 2016, including restrictions on low-price, high-volume drink specials, and wholesaler pricing provisions.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8756D4D27BC84DC584E779D13765504F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not States have adopted laws, regulations, and policies designed to reduce alcohol advertising messages attractive to youth and youth exposure to alcohol advertising and marketing in measured and unmeasured media and digital and social media.</text></subclause><subclause id="H3CCA76A4FACB4857A30250E3750468EC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether or not States have laws and policies that promote underage drinking prevention policy development by local jurisdictions.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC469AC70BF5D44B69DE65321C8D23018"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Whether or not States have adopted laws, regulations, and policies to restrict youth access to alcoholic beverages that may pose special risks to youth, including but not limited to alcoholic mists, gelatins, freezer pops, premixed caffeinated alcoholic beverages, and flavored malt beverages.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8F57412703DD46F1B25A01B11AB52CAD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Whether or not States have adopted uniform best practices protocols for conducting compliance checks and shoulder tap programs.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5EB193030B13470298CF2EAD84CACB15"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Whether or not States have adopted uniform best practices penalty protocols for violations of laws prohibiting retail licensees from selling or furnishing of alcohol to minors.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H46B5071541A94742A3E2B7E9B9EDAED2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Uniform data system</header><text>For performance measures related to enforcement of underage drinking laws as specified in clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary shall develop and test a uniform data system for reporting State enforcement data, including the development of a pilot program for this purpose. The pilot program shall include procedures for collecting enforcement data from both State and local law enforcement jurisdictions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5532EFFFB9D048E4BFBC0B94054C1534"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD23059C5A2E4C3487B22E61F7677201"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National media campaign To prevent underage drinking</header><paragraph id="H921CAF66BE97452B9D11F32FF1625CF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, shall develop an intensive, multifaceted, adult-oriented national media campaign to reduce underage drinking by influencing attitudes regarding underage drinking, increasing the willingness of adults to take actions to reduce underage drinking, and encouraging public policy changes known to decrease underage drinking rates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDEDBC31738E4BFEAD218584D86597CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the national media campaign described in this section shall be to achieve the following objectives:</text><subparagraph id="H2770FE215804411FACF795F750325A3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Instill a broad societal commitment to reduce underage drinking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCF2ED6B3C1409E95CD8FA915D560D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Increase specific actions by adults that are meant to discourage or inhibit underage drinking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB1A00DEB87142B6ADD1F74F0E135C4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Decrease adult conduct that tends to facilitate or condone underage drinking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF934DFA11925412E8EEC37BDA71DCBEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Components</header><text>When implementing the national media campaign described in this section, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5DB4653D2C1C47D7B0C5B8A3100FF9F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educate the public about the public health and safety benefits of evidence-based policies to reduce underage drinking, including minimum legal drinking age laws, and build public and parental support for and cooperation with enforcement of such policies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61F9FA46A7294BDCA5675E6F244CF21C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate the public about the negative consequences of underage drinking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA88A1D59C57C499E9B7E07A57849E5C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote specific actions by adults that are meant to discourage or inhibit underage drinking, including positive behavior modeling, general parental monitoring, and consistent and appropriate discipline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7770EE4A35D44D92AD2360E88B81423D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>discourage adult conduct that tends to facilitate underage drinking, including the hosting of underage parties with alcohol and the purchasing of alcoholic beverages on behalf of underage youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA8A841B2154AC28413F33BAA32CC8A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establish collaborative relationships with local and national organizations and institutions to further the goals of the campaign and assure that the messages of the campaign are disseminated from a variety of sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D45E381651B4A9EBEC21641BD13E77C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conduct the campaign through multi-media sources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71E7D753B1EF431FB9D56D9585B43358"><enum>(G)</enum><text>conduct the campaign with regard to changing demographics and cultural and linguistic factors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99608959ECC64DE4BF707B52E7D12C8C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and implementing the national media campaign described in this section, the Secretary shall consult recommendations for reducing underage drinking published by the National Academy of Sciences and the Surgeon General. The Secretary shall also consult with interested parties including medical, public health, and consumer and parent groups, law enforcement, institutions of higher education, community organizations and coalitions, and other stakeholders supportive of the goals of the campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEDFCA3DB18474CADE64E38871FB394"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall produce an annual report on the progress of the development or implementation of the media campaign described in this subsection, including expenses and projected costs, and, as such information is available, report on the effectiveness of such campaign in affecting adult attitudes toward underage drinking and adult willingness to take actions to decrease underage drinking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A1BBB7DB42498B8C3EA772FF6C51F9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Research on youth-oriented campaign</header><text>The Secretary may, based on the availability of funds, conduct research on the potential success of a youth-oriented national media campaign to reduce underage drinking. The Secretary shall report any such results to Congress with policy recommendations on establishing such a campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2BA92E2F3DC472780292458D61C92E3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary may enter into a subcontract with another Federal agency to delegate the authority for execution and administration of the adult-oriented national media campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72A2B27A9A6641A39B941DA24C0C7F9A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31A8AB4C4F564214B7E363B7DA7E0D9F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community-Based coalition enhancement grants To prevent underage drinking</header><paragraph id="H015C8229BBCF488FA5C454852725CF1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, in consultation with the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, shall award enhancement grants to eligible entities to design, implement, evaluate, and disseminate comprehensive strategies to maximize the effectiveness of community-wide approaches to preventing and reducing underage drinking. This subsection is subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE87EB4ECA8D41AB9A9DEBF3065504D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this subsection are to—</text><subparagraph id="HF78BD3A3EB894BD69572B44903D84A06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent and reduce alcohol use among youth in communities throughout the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85D420A4F4DC4F8C9FB33806345DA482"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthen collaboration among communities, the Federal Government, Tribal Governments, and State and local governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4656AA6245F455BA0B46543CDB326A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance intergovernmental cooperation and coordination on the issue of alcohol use among youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11591EE969144299912E69D59E67B3F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>serve as a catalyst for increased citizen participation and greater collaboration among all sectors and organizations of a community that first demonstrates a long-term commitment to reducing alcohol use among youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F5C734CD49418DA03EA8A6A0447FF5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement state-of-the-art science-based strategies to prevent and reduce underage drinking by changing local conditions in communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8BBE71B79F34BE69D2644B11835DF08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enhance, not supplant, effective local community initiatives for preventing and reducing alcohol use among youth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72213E24962049218AF7A74C0B4E4630"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity desiring an enhancement grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, and in such manner, and accompanied by such information and assurances, as the Assistant Secretary may require. Each application shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB4A2B70DE9BC4AF581FA7C7AD6F4910E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a complete description of the entity’s current underage alcohol use prevention initiatives and how the grant will appropriately enhance the focus on underage drinking issues; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2B80A1B964B4EE5BCD3C1A5D1A3AC05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a complete description of the entity’s current initiatives, and how it will use this grant to enhance those initiatives by adding a focus on underage drinking prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0616E2546304BD388D0025C355489D5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall use the grant funds to carry out the activities described in such entity’s application submitted pursuant to paragraph (3) and obtain specialized training and technical assistance by the entity funded under section 4 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/82">Public Law 107–82</external-xref>, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1521">21 U.S.C. 1521</external-xref> note). Grants under this subsection shall not exceed $60,000 per year and may not exceed four years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47798356B2DE4807813D849BC644B933"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this subsection shall be used to supplement, not supplant, Federal and non-Federal funds available for carrying out the activities described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8D96F4DF7B4B00A1524D8E8AE3D15A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Grants under this subsection shall be subject to the same evaluation requirements and procedures as the evaluation requirements and procedures imposed on recipients of drug-free community grants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4E1F20A6D24B24A11AFC3DB431859C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an organization that is currently receiving or has received grant funds under the Drug-Free Communities Act of 1997.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0706F91A39704571B56108DB4BF5C7A6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than 6 percent of a grant under this subsection may be expended for administrative expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H423461D3144C409F9C3F1D0973A181FF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $11,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98759A9F40D342C098754DA6DF980D54"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grants to professional pediatric provider organizations To reduce underage drinking through screening and brief interventions</header><paragraph id="H79EE4A3AD62E4813A9658EECBA6B596D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall make one or more grants to professional pediatric provider organizations to increase among the members of such organizations effective practices to reduce the prevalence of alcohol use among individuals under the age of 21, including college students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F0CD28C0C24D82A4C49AC3BE707D88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>Grants under this subsection shall be made to promote the practices of—</text><subparagraph id="HA455385363204257888D934160C9D472"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening children and adolescents for alcohol use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F16864D591F48CFB89A39C9AF1C685E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offering brief interventions to children and adolescents to discourage such use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8A308A9AEDE430CA4F426FCFA56A261"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educating parents about the dangers of and methods of discouraging such use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H374C31CD74074E289DBB20A74AF89447"><enum>(D)</enum><text>diagnosing and treating alcohol use disorders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EAD44F85BF144E393407404BD912647"><enum>(E)</enum><text>referring patients, when necessary, to other appropriate care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C04F68013E24A80B1BB58342819EE77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A professional pediatric provider organization receiving a grant under this section may use the grant funding to promote the practices specified in paragraph (2) among its members by—</text><subparagraph id="HDDE7FEBD7E284765BF19AF3C0C026EAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing training to health care providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB8D722FCD3F4EED9F076E8E2C28118B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminating best practices, including culturally and linguistically appropriate best practices, and developing, printing, and distributing materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FE64662A4D74C919A825AB044531E84"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting other activities approved by the Assistant Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DFFC6E3F7DB4F95BB414BF67C66EB83"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a professional pediatric provider organization shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, and in such manner, and accompanied by such information and assurances as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB1C412AE7FEB41DB9545A7736F793850"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the pediatric provider organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D24A7A846C541BE80A57EE3C71D208D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the activities to be completed that will promote the practices specified in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF2FC4E32E614176A09D6AF070F95203"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the organization’s qualifications for performing such practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDDADF59C94346EAA335DB14F5E42A2C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a timeline for the completion of such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BEDE2A8316482A93A046F56A3221C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purpose of this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HDE136BF6A6414695B06A5787334FA4B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Brief intervention</header><text>The term <term>brief intervention</term> means, after screening a patient, providing the patient with brief advice and other brief motivational enhancement techniques designed to increase the insight of the patient regarding the patient’s alcohol use, and any realized or potential consequences of such use to effect the desired related behavioral change.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H229380E625FA4B3B8B2DBCCAE46BD7FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Children and adolescents</header><text>The term <term>children and adolescents</term> means individuals under 21 years of age.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F78B8BD8E1D4E47A18C33B40EC1BD2D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Professional pediatric provider organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>professional pediatric provider organization</term> means an organization or association that—</text><clause id="H54024911DCC0493191683C8D0D5797A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consists of or represents pediatric health care providers; and</text></clause><clause id="H0E3C86C5E0034CF3A6CBB5F9EB7621FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is qualified to promote the practices specified in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10A1E1964A904C699E6C1582F4163396"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Screening</header><text>The term <term>screening</term> means using validated patient interview techniques to identify and assess the existence and extent of alcohol use in a patient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7EB0AA9A28492789CFED44C4F55D87"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02E416FED6FA4773910AFCFB537CD320"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Data collection and research</header><paragraph id="H8EC5C1B69A384033BAE269B6913E450F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional research on underage drinking</header><subparagraph id="H3681F951912A47B9B00D4BD3089AED78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, collect data, and conduct or support research that is not duplicative of research currently being conducted or supported by the Department of Health and Human Services, on underage drinking, with respect to the following:</text><clause id="HA7B1E2A646BB4FABA2992AFF8F4B66AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Improve data collection in support of evaluation of the effectiveness of comprehensive community-based programs or strategies and statewide systems to prevent and reduce underage drinking, across the underage years from early childhood to age 21, such as programs funded and implemented by governmental entities, public health interest groups and foundations, and alcohol beverage companies and trade associations, through the development of models of State-level epidemiological surveillance of underage drinking by funding in States or large metropolitan areas new epidemiologists focused on excessive drinking including underage alcohol use.</text></clause><clause id="H7B46962877B747DAB45FCEA43724D0EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Obtain and report more precise information than is currently collected on the scope of the underage drinking problem and patterns of underage alcohol consumption, including improved knowledge about the problem and progress in preventing, reducing, and treating underage drinking, as well as information on the rate of exposure of youth to advertising and other media messages encouraging and discouraging alcohol consumption.</text></clause><clause id="HD5D5C40F75B84D81801815F4705A2976"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Synthesize, expand on, and widely disseminate existing research on effective strategies for reducing underage drinking, including translational research, and make this research easily accessible to the general public.</text></clause><clause id="H91136C66B35C429BA6E98F58FF2D9D92"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Improve and conduct public health surveillance on alcohol use and alcohol-related conditions in States by increasing the use of surveys, such as the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, to monitor binge and excessive drinking and related harms among individuals who are at least 18 years of age, but not more than 20 years of age, including harm caused to self or others as a result of alcohol use that is not duplicative of research currently being conducted or supported by the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3574917BC594D2894FC0FE4A44E1BDA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H440ACD5C015A461E8740AF3B9F707B00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Academy of Sciences study</header><subparagraph id="H431A869037364137B63E7D7A7CB515BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the enactment of the <short-title>Sober Truth on Preventing Underage Drinking Reauthorization Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H66DB1F522AF240B5AA7D8FE346014557"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a review of the research literature regarding the influence of drinking alcohol on the development of the adolescent brain and the public policy implications of this research; and</text></clause><clause id="H643EB06D31A7486682EAA324B72C0B5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>report to the Congress on the results of such review.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5CA2397A5914F309D56C9878F0F1E3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph $500,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H19952BE09ECF4BD0B63E0B819F32B196"><enum>8.</enum><header>Grants for jail diversion programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520G of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-38">42 U.S.C. 290bb–38</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEF53D78954E741E1B8AB3C2DD4509277"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H7D54DC890B5B44709EA0C14F265109FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>up to</quote> and inserting <quote>at least</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86521692D56747AAB58330CE0EE4905B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>tribes and tribal organizations</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribes and Tribal organizations</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7436121E55144024AEEC0FC9B2E6D176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>tribes, and tribal organizations</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribes, and Tribal organizations</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34E32A9F72C54523A696678FCFD32282"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HB68979FA4B44497897436A5A7057FED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>tribe or tribal organization</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribe or Tribal organization</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80F678A1808D4E5EBDF875D060DBE141"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A)(iii), by striking <quote>tribe, or tribal organization</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribe, or Tribal organization</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA949A91BBD4900B1E8DDC2107472BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="HD4955810609C427D88A3FE39ADB47AB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>tribe, or tribal organization</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribe, or Tribal organization</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H591159EA9818418088C6AC4F2672C4C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or arrest</quote> and inserting <quote>, arrest, or release</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0331D3ED61D4946A77F389AA6828BAA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f), by striking <quote>tribe, or tribal organization</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Tribe, or Tribal organization</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H772AAF5A9CFA46ADB4B6C8D9B62E9B3F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h), by striking <quote>tribe, or tribal organization</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribe, or Tribal organization</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F59F87BA07D45BC9CC2E5C1E9F87912"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>$4,269,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>$18,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H76B34FA697884730A0851DA1D5F737D9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Formula grants to States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 521 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290cc-21">42 U.S.C. 290cc–21</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>. </text></section><section id="H11246FBFDDEC4279A187CB39AD59E9D6"><enum>10.</enum><header>Projects for Assistance in Transition From Homelessness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 535(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290cc-35">42 U.S.C. 290cc–35(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></section><section id="H3414F45FC32E4A9B81CBAF7F6E216980"><enum>11.</enum><header>Grants for reducing overdose deaths</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 544 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-3">42 U.S.C. 290dd–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8B5B7A4ACA124A9A97A0353012137F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DA4F5A320F14BDEA0D120B23AAD384D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>2017 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H456D068997A74A529349022FC6DFE980"><enum>12.</enum><header>Opioid overdose reversal medication access and education grant programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 545 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ee">42 U.S.C. 290ee</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF6FF6C47EDF640A79B08E62D966AEB00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B40103F1A47480A8F729FCAAB8D3256"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)(1), by striking <quote>2017 through 2019</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H13EEE3CB3E4242C58335160805F77DF6"><enum>13.</enum><header>State demonstration grants for comprehensive opioid abuse response</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 548 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ee-3">42 U.S.C. 290ee–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H80BE935AFA40426DA6C542A75135B439"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Abuse</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Use Disorder</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1D816351E74790BFED8C4EC96CEDAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H2AA29867B8934860BB974DCABB0302D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Abuse</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Use Disorder</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71D642492F344CBD840F4DAA1F847D12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5BAF127E9974BF0A3D88CD57BBB75D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HF1165F770BD84101966B372638267CEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HDD653D8F7B2846F6BD402D4E8731E128"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>opioid use, treatment, and addiction recovery</quote> and inserting <quote>opioid use disorders, and treatment for, and recovery from opioid use disorders</quote>; </text></clause><clause id="HF99ACE4DAEA34CF589ED1A73EBC2D9FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>addiction</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>use disorder</quote>; </text></clause><clause id="H7E49033977EC40638A8FC55BDB5F8E33"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H837FC38AEBF74CAA92601A26A59309C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC60889BD77DF49B39C8FCC8FFAC3152C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing, implementing, and expanding efforts to prevent overdose death from opioid or other prescription medication use disorders; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="HEEF48872DB674501A48951B41257440B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorders</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5E392F8C10543479BF6C9ABA267FAA8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>abuse</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>use disorders</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F6596C680746C791185669E29A5119"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2017 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5AC6C3D0A5634BB5919FD2BEA7CFE572"><enum>14.</enum><header>Emergency department alternatives to opioids</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7091 of the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/271">Public Law 115–271</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8E5F44D9F63E4F97B5DDBFB3FB7084A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Demonstration</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBFFAE584AE47EAA34D428D0A8DF0E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H81555B74CB6442F09EA1BC059DAF09A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending the subsection heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Grant program</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC46F0DC577214CC8B63AAE95D531F5E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>demonstration</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H434E4193BA29490195514821019A2830"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">demonstration</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EC4EEDD2EFF4C38998C9D75FF4A46A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(4), by striking <quote>tribal</quote> and inserting <quote>Tribal</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC38068D2E9C44FA99CBA0A4C54F677FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>Not later than 1 year after completion of the demonstration program under this section, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the results of the demonstration program</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than the end of each of fiscal years 2024 and 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of the program</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E15B152F03E40139FD554E74FD44581"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>2019 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

