<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H13576EBC1B97458BBF6EDDB69F02E4FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 HR 6552 IH: Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6552</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H179306986925460AA8E6E6D1CE733742" style="OLC"><section id="HF40B339ED6A74404B359FF78E9885351" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H789B497CB7144F2982EBAF7A6FAC9541"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HF40B339ED6A74404B359FF78E9885351" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H789B497CB7144F2982EBAF7A6FAC9541" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE73EBDF52C804A0BBAC75697C7D4D39B" level="title">Title I—Combating Trafficking in Persons in the United States</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H48BAAE81654C47729AB4073A066C8FC1" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Programs To Support Victims and Persons Vulnerable to Human Trafficking</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HACEDC93932274F14B636F9C33031AEBB" level="section">Sec. 101. Modifications to grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE7F4B3311ECC440DA12B177D4EB8540D" level="section">Sec. 102. Human trafficking survivors employment and education program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB1E904B3678F45ABBF3198129C86BF1F" level="section">Sec. 103. Extending sunset for Advisory Council on Human Trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H818A647E1F0D44AEBAC79D1FA6049823" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Governmental Efforts To Prevent Human Trafficking</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H991B7923F0E1417F91BB7FF52FC91C88" level="section">Sec. 121. Priority for accommodation in places with policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H26FC24E50BC846FAA94D240CC3739048" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Monitoring Child, Forced, and Slave Labor</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC6ED349E572F40BB880FBD12D36BAC12" level="section">Sec. 131. Amendments to Social Security Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9F51052C18B8408BBD7C5393C8B61FF6" level="section">Sec. 132. Sense of Congress on submission of Department of Justice reports on time.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4A6ADD4D74BC4C729D152B7B9FCF2DB2" level="section">Sec. 133. Sense of Congress on requiring child welfare agencies to report information on missing and abducted foster children and youth.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEA555F5BABA347EF9634D679CD76076E" level="title">Title II—Fighting Human Trafficking Abroad</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9BD8F6DF12C642808C446AF703F59A1C" level="section">Sec. 201. Amendments to the International Megan’s Law.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3A6E8EC994F04989B8B50E58EF3902C1" level="section">Sec. 202. Modifications to program to end modern slavery grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBBEC581632E44FE7B19FDC6584C9A7A8" level="section">Sec. 203. Amendments to tier standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H501DD92347F441558CAFF9D000FB52F6" level="section">Sec. 204. Expanding prevention efforts at the United States Agency for International Development.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8F4B4E190E4849EA815FDD7B92D03B4E" level="title">Title III—Authorization of Appropriations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H54F54D18520D4D69A9D58ABBB693C60F" level="section">Sec. 301. Extension of authorizations under the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H51EC5EAE3B2241A2AE56D98FCFB28745" level="section">Sec. 302. Extension of authorizations under the international Megan’s Law.</toc-entry></toc></section><title id="HE73EBDF52C804A0BBAC75697C7D4D39B"><enum>I</enum><header>Combating Trafficking in Persons in the United States</header><subtitle id="H48BAAE81654C47729AB4073A066C8FC1"><enum>A</enum><header>Programs To Support Victims and Persons Vulnerable to Human Trafficking</header><section id="HACEDC93932274F14B636F9C33031AEBB"><enum>101.</enum><header>Modifications to grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking</header><subsection id="H346DB824B5F84D658DC4601A848F7EA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to authorities To prevent trafficking</header><text>Section 106(b)(2) of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7104">22 U.S.C. 7104(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H20380B732FD14A07888F214135BBA4E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Grants to assist in the recognition of trafficking</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Frederick douglass human trafficking prevention education grants</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3834F09D9C814437A7B770E849DF838E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="HC3F306D1C49348F29B3270C9544B7567"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>under a program named <quote>Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grants</quote></quote> after <quote>may award grants</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12A0DF476E954FB784519D6E6B2FF499"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>, linguistically accessible, and culturally responsive</quote> after <quote>age-appropriate</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB45CFD80C14DE8A1C12EF30E866505"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the heading of subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">for frederick douglass human trafficking prevention education grants</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Program requirements</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87690B5BA890401D8CACEB50D79BDE20"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H49BD9D8471944731B542DBA6A3E6E7C9" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE3A4EE57AFA2496BAD907DF647E2294B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grants under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H0A4D93E8BEF24D429DEA229D77AB0617"><enum>(i)</enum><text>give priority to local educational agencies serving a high-intensity child sex trafficking area or an area with significant child labor trafficking;</text></clause><clause id="HFEA950749BE04476BCFA9515EC59A4D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>give additional priority to local educational agencies that partner with non-profit organizations specializing in human trafficking prevention education, law enforcement, and technology or social media companies, to assist in training efforts to protect children from labor trafficking and sexual exploitation and abuse including grooming, materials depicting the sexual abuse of children, and human trafficking transmitted through technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H86CA2887F1044F9086C3DE8B0AF20C24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consult, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Labor, and the Attorney General, to identify the geographic areas in the United States with the highest prevalence of underserved or at-risk populations, including children who are members of a racial or ethnic minority, homeless youth, foster youth, youth involved in the child welfare system, and children and youth who run away from home or an out-of-home placement.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D59392BDC9443B4B58C3559CB714E4C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB648E1E1EC394A7A850FF71B9ACF99C8" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H89507EC5528144629EAB7244E06913DC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Criteria for selection</header><text>Grantees should be selected based on their demonstrated ability to—</text><clause id="H606BE9CDEEB64E0A80B081412758DE66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage stakeholders, including survivors of human trafficking, and Federal, State, local, or Tribal partners, to develop the programs;</text></clause><clause id="H27F84A2556984C7C8A599D329C4DB8AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>train the trainers, guardians, K–12 students, teachers, and other school personnel in a linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed fashion; and</text></clause><clause id="H5584CDFF6B8B4442B302AF2752176F74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>create a scalable, repeatable program to prevent child labor trafficking and sexual exploitation and abuse including grooming, child sexual abuse materials, and trafficking transmitted through technology that—</text><subclause id="HCBA3F38D76E84A76A6EA4102E3969E86"><enum>(I)</enum><text>uses proven and tested best practices by university researchers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF97168343F0F45C3916367AE6D87A128"><enum>(II)</enum><text>employs appropriate technological tools and methodologies, including linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed approaches and measurement and training curricula adapted for trainers, guardians, educators, and K–12 students.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8542626DA82B49B585CEAEBAE1A8DA4C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Train the trainers</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (E), the term <term>train the trainers</term> means having experienced or master trainers coach new trainers who are less experienced with a particular topic or skill, or with training overall, who can then teach the material to others, creating a broader reach, sustainability, and making efforts cost- and time-efficient (commonly referred to as <quote>training of trainers</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFFB253DAA81418D95B6C84C08185338"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Education to determine the appropriate demographics of the recipients or of students at risk of being trafficked or exploited, to be collected and reported with respect to grants under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F39AB4CD5784D349C6D52C05BA438E3"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committees on Education and Labor, Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committees on the Judiciary and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report including data on the following:</text><clause id="HE2C75A1F8CCE47E59E6A5D02FC9E4B58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of entities that received a Frederick Douglass Human Trafficking Prevention Education Grant over the past year.</text></clause><clause id="HB35B7E0C8A364BFCBB443ACF55712851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total number of partnerships or consultants that included survivors, non-profit organizations specialized in human trafficking prevention education, law enforcement, and technology or social media companies.</text></clause><clause id="H7850BF0D80294880A517836D10174C62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The total number of elementary and secondary schools that established and implemented proper protocols and procedures through programs developed using such grants.</text></clause><clause id="H9093911BE5554E969A7E30186E3ECD29"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The total number and geographic distribution of trainers, guardians, students, teachers, and other school personnel trained using such grants pursuant to this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="H0F910027E41D43C1BB60BA0CE6C2890E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The results of pre-training and post-training surveys to gauge trainees’ increased understanding of the scope and signs of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse; how to interact with potential victims and survivors of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse using age-appropriate and trauma-informed approach; and the manner in which to respond to potential child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse.</text></clause><clause id="HF6E471AE79584E1F9D46453944EFAA0F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The number of potential victims and survivors of child trafficking and child sexual exploitation and abuse identified and served by grantees, excluding any individually identifiable information about such children and acting in full compliance with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H5ED4161EA8494329B6EEC51EF7B952DD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of students in elementary or secondary school identified by grantees as being at risk of being trafficked or sexually exploited and abused, excluding any individually identifiable information about such children.</text></clause><clause id="H13654BA9F1B04118ADB330235288AEB5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The demographic characteristics of child trafficking survivors and victims, sexually exploited and abused children, and students at risk of being trafficked or sexually exploited and abused described in clauses (vi) and (vii), excluding any individually identifiable information about such children and in accordance with the standards set forth by the Department of Education National Center for Education Statistics with respect to at-risk students.</text></clause><clause id="H466F8EE566C0423793920FD74EC77322"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any service gaps and best practices identified by grantees.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE7F4B3311ECC440DA12B177D4EB8540D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Human trafficking survivors employment and education program</header><subsection id="H5DEE06816BF64319B755D6D880963541"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may carry out a Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program to prevent the re-exploitation of eligible individuals who have been victims of trafficking, by assisting such individuals to integrate or reintegrate into society through social services support for the attainment of life-skills, employment, and education necessary to achieve self-sufficiency.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F01D1DC58F741CFA608D59309CBE94C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services provided</header><text>Services offered, provided, and funded by the Program shall include (as relevant to the victim of trafficking)—</text><paragraph id="H60BDC6C5256D4B8BAB7425D3F980D9D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enrollment and participation in—</text><subparagraph id="H8D163AC9C8DC494EABDD86F0C2F9A09A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>basic education, including literacy education and English as a second language education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8990B8A67D9F4F61B15317EFD420E1F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>job-related skills training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H191D28648B5F48C18E56CA9F7055B551"><enum>(C)</enum><text>vocational and certificate programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F6D733519646588557D5BE0541D9DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programs for attaining a regular high school diploma or its recognized equivalent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB4B20881873426FAF96825342A148E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>life-skill training programs, including management of personal finances, self-care, and parenting classes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC9D8D3E4034B378D2E6F9AD786882F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>résumé creation and review;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA56555D2C44048CAB1D98EA6CBC4990B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>interview coaching and counseling;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9ECED7FA7942CAB2DA1F3E9CE4AEE8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assistance with expungement of criminal records when such records are for nonviolent crimes that were committed as a consequence of the eligible individual’s victimization, including assistance with credit repair;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF916A7B7B5F646049BF392059FEA8991"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assistance with enrollment in college or technical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0763CEA7498C496B9639D458CE7241CA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>scholarship assistance for attending college or technical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE486DEF8E63942578CCCA29D630D068A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>professional coaching or professional development classes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDB080EFCC6E49319A29F89245F95431"><enum>(9)</enum><text>case management to develop an individualized plan with each survivor, based on each person’s needs and goals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E5431D911B48089E8C7FB876D8F342"><enum>(10)</enum><text>assistance with obtaining victim compensation, direct victim assistance, or other funds for mental health care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C5F3956A07465E8E57545D532AD7A1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>other programs and services that help eligible individuals to achieve self-sufficiency, such as wrap-around social services to assist survivors in meeting their basic needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FE2DD13A8BD49098FF760F961D82769"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Service period</header><text>Eligible individuals may receive services through the Program for a cumulative period of 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3899616EA6324E7F8EB3D07434B12997"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall enter into cooperative agreements with one or more eligible organizations to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3968502302954A22A7A5762DAAC172CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H78289F85FAF945779C094EC5B4A522B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means a domestic or foreign victim of trafficking who is eligible to receive services under section 107(b) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E5DA19535E431B8CA61D79A4FA6D50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text>The <quote>eligible organization</quote> may include a non-governmental organization and means a service provider that meets the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="H7D6C43698E9B4DE7B72404E3EA909412"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Experience in using national or local anti-trafficking networks to serve victims of trafficking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56DD61AFD8DC441DA8E58FBA194AE7FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Experience qualifying, providing, and coordinating services for victims of trafficking, as described in subsection (b), that is linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, age-appropriate, and trauma-informed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C99E21D77324E178CA64B52697DAF44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to a service provider for victims of trafficking served by the Program who are not United States citizens, a provider that has experience in identifying and assisting foreign-born victims of trafficking, including helping them qualify for Continued Presence, T–Visas, and other Federal, State, and local services and funding.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE43E28D0C55C4C848F4B5207AB388DA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>With respect to a service provider for victims of trafficking served by the Program who are United States citizens and legal permanent residents, a provider that has experience identifying and assisting victims of trafficking, as such term is defined in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>), especially youth and underserved populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5033A7BC80F24947AE96DE1624835B95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Human Trafficking Survivors Employment and Education Program established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEBC4D9797544AC882A81D2DBC64929D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB1E904B3678F45ABBF3198129C86BF1F" commented="no"><enum>103.</enum><header>Extending sunset for Advisory Council on Human Trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 115(h) of the Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2015 is amended by striking <quote>2020</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>.</text></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H818A647E1F0D44AEBAC79D1FA6049823"><enum>B</enum><header>Governmental Efforts To Prevent Human Trafficking</header><section id="H991B7923F0E1417F91BB7FF52FC91C88"><enum>121.</enum><header>Priority for accommodation in places with policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking</header><subsection id="H05ED9208C55A4C57A3F8E575E78C4F1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H26980134A9FE49F5A230A62381F62E64" style="USC"><section id="H3C5FF496719940BCBC4E7C1C75F72F34"><enum>5712.</enum><header>Priority for accommodation in places with certain policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking</header><subsection id="HFCB5C24256A64396BB71038D7DAA3F71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of making payments under this chapter for lodging expenses, each agency shall ensure that, to the greatest extent practicable, commercial-lodging room nights in the United States for employees of that agency are booked in a preferred place of accommodation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB78E0EB8A6B946C3998EE6888A5D3CDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility as a preferred place of accommodation</header><text>To be considered a preferred place of accommodation for the purposes of this section, a hotel or motel shall—</text><paragraph id="HAAE4E899BEB447AEBAE3E1B3A2566D14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enforce a zero-tolerance policy regarding severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103(11) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)</external-xref>)) made available by the Administrator of General Services under subsection (c)(1), or a similar zero-tolerance policy developed by the place of accommodation, demonstrated by—</text><subparagraph id="H6316C05F034C4D1D8AF0E53190993F97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>posting such policy in a nonpublic space within the place of accommodation that is accessible by all employees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC2399549763495A8602CB91510DC972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>including such policy in the employee handbook;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92D184EAE1D64A68B365E50CD15C8FB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have procedures in place, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, for employees to identify and report any such exploitation according to protocol identified in the employee training based on training materials developed under subsection (c)(3) to the appropriate law enforcement authorities, management of the preferred accommodation, or the National Human Trafficking Hotline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE722562608894C778A89235830B47A14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>post the informational materials made available under subsection (c)(3) in an appropriate nonpublic space within the place of accommodation that is accessible by all employees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CD7AC7EF8442B7B66FEB2910630146"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and update, as necessary, the zero-tolerance policy, procedures, and informational materials at least every two years prior to the due date for self-certifications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE843AD7B4A294CE8846CCA9E9D6C75C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>require each employee who is physically located at the place of accommodation and who is likely to interact with guests, including security, front desk, housekeeping, room service, and bell staff, to complete the training developed under subsection (c)(2), or a training developed pursuant to subsection (d), that shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD07BA2C047EF421C9250B06378573638"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take place not later than 90 days after the starting date of the new employee, or in the case of an employee hired before the effective date of this section, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H239D4A46EFEE43CF838717A14CF301C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include refresher trainings every two years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA488EBF1BD5E423EB05BE2F77F562CE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include training on the identification of possible cases of sexual exploitation of children and procedures to report suspected abuse to the appropriate authorities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H234CA1A720DF46C0870A77394C411F4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>include a notice to all independent contractors in any agreement affecting a property in the United States negotiated or renewed on or after the date of enactment of this section that states the following: <quote>Federal law prohibits the trafficking of humans under the Trafficking Victims Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H636FDD28091A48EB9E1590E0D085AB1B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that the place of accommodation does not retaliate against employees for reporting suspected cases of such exploitation if reported according to protocol identified in the employee training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74132198E0854D9D8C5705B0911496EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GSA requirements</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall—</text><paragraph id="HD2101F6FEFBC451DA6C9FF7E006C9F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available on the website of the General Services Administration, an up-to-date model zero tolerance policy for places of accommodation regarding severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103(11) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. (11))), including informational materials regarding such policy to be posted in places of accommodation in nonpublic spaces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H367734B60C544A51AECEF4DC05EE6670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make available on the website of the General Services Administration an up-to-date list of Department of Homeland Security, Department of Justice, and Department of State and privately produced training programs that address the identification of severe forms of human trafficking and reporting to law enforcement authorities or the National Human Trafficking Hotline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCBCE8A7D0E2433DBB9D0FB0AF2520CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security’s Blue Campaign, make available up-to-date training materials on preventing severe forms of human trafficking and informational materials to be posted in nonpublic spaces in places of accommodation on spotting the signs of severe forms of human trafficking and reporting possible incidences of such exploitation, except that the Administrator shall permit the use of substantially similar training materials or informational materials required by State or local law on identifying the signs of human trafficking and reporting possible incidences of such exploitation in lieu of materials developed under this paragraph; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB6E5A58302644308D2DDB5EB348A3C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maintain a list of each preferred place of accommodation that meets the requirements of subsection (b), beginning by examining places of accommodation that are—</text><subparagraph id="H67A738A445DE4C318F21A4E93AD5FEB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participating in government lodging programs such as FedRooms (or successor system);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38C8C11A30464F96B912E69CFE078762"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included on the FEMA Fire Safe List; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE62A92C46AE491AABC3183367DB2F58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise known to have received government travel business in the 2 years prior to enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B5BC9CE5B29405ABC4E584CB2B4318B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training programs</header><text>A place of accommodation or lodging company may use a training program developed or acquired by such place of accommodation or company to satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(4) if such training program—</text><paragraph id="H4FF143EAD7584A5DBAAAAA45C8E7616A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>focuses on identifying and reporting suspected cases of severe forms of human trafficking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H373AE653EDE540A6962ABF161CFA5CFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was developed in consultation with State governments, survivor leaders, survivor-led anti-trafficking organization, or a nationally recognized organization with expertise in anti-trafficking initiatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H798D1359B9244BDC8A98128C505DE73B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Previously trained employees</header><paragraph id="HF209CCA2F2AD440C96C0F8B17877073F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training prior to effective date</header><text>Any employee of a place of accommodation who has been trained to identify and report potential cases of severe forms of human trafficking during the 2-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this section shall be considered to have met the training requirement in subsection (b)(4) with respect to any employment at that place of accommodation or at any other place of accommodation managed by the same entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17616E876AF44576BCF282E92504CE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training prior to a transfer of employment</header><text>Any employee of a place of accommodation who has met the training requirements under subsection (b)(4) shall be considered to have met such requirements with respect to any employment at a place of accommodation managed by the same entity if such training occurred during the 2-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3256AB8219C4ED5949A222AEDC12D4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Property-by-Property Implementation</header><paragraph id="H0327B69E8F25496897953D0221DBFBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each preferred place of accommodation shall self-certify (in writing) to the Administrator of General Services that such place is in compliance with the requirements of this section. Such self-certification shall occur every 2 years beginning on the date of the enactment of this section. The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE7471987A2F64EB28DEE1848BCBF20CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide notice to each place of accommodation regarding any self-certification required under this subsection not later than the date that is 90 days before the due date of such self-certification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34DF47DC07B444F68E40751A9389C9C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section and every two years thereafter—</text><clause id="H64AED04A6A9C4C79BADFCF863CC71112"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each preferred places of accommodation that submitted and did not submit their self-certifications in the preceding 2 years; and</text></clause><clause id="H34B0333726E04E12ADAF573DA0CC9C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the corresponding total numbers of nights the government paid for Federal employees in self-certified preferred places of accommodation compared to preferred places of accommodation that did not report self-certification to the Administrator of General Services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72B5D4E2A4FC47259987A754A55351DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Group certification</header><text>A person or entity that manages or franchises multiple places of accommodation may provide a single notice with respect to self-certification under subsection (a) that each such place is in compliance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13AD76FA203D4E00A69A9F123C9C60A4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text>No provision in this section that applies to an employee of a place of accommodation shall be construed to apply to an individual who is an independent contractor or otherwise not directly employed by a place of accommodation, unless the contract is for housekeeping, security, front desk, room service, or bell staff, in which case it shall be the responsibility of the service provider to ensure compliance with the requirements set forth in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H788534D0904D4C94958C29F45D3635BA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5B75E186C20546FAA7C06B6917737E2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 5712(a) of title 5, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0B0F606D09334D5180AC8B8FA94118EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="HDDBE14DD88CC4E94A954469DF7475DA2" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">5712. Priority for accommodation in places with certain policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H26FC24E50BC846FAA94D240CC3739048"><enum>C</enum><header>Monitoring Child, Forced, and Slave Labor</header><section id="HC6ED349E572F40BB880FBD12D36BAC12"><enum>131.</enum><header>Amendments to Social Security Act</header><subsection id="HEEDA9B47BD49427CB17BEA0F29A414DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification to state plans</header><text>Section 471(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H95517B9F91C34AD98A57BF2A40E48A54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(C)(i)(I), by striking <quote>sex trafficking victim</quote> and inserting <quote>sex or labor trafficking victim</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69681F96DCD44A40ABDB4C2F3BA215F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (34), by striking <quote>sex trafficking victims</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>sex or labor trafficking victims</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFD9F17A30C47E9B33DBE2413E4E1AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (35)(A)(iii), by striking <quote>possible sex trafficking victim</quote> and inserting <quote>possible sex or labor trafficking victim</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35B9B550678E41049F4F85ABB337600C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (35)(B), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HECDCF30801DB421C8ED79F808E21B28C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>, the State agency shall maintain regular communication with law enforcement and the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children in efforts to provide a safe recovery of the missing child, including by sharing information pertaining to the child’s recovery and circumstances related to the recovery, and the State report submitted to law enforcement and NCMEC shall include where reasonably possible—</text><clause id="H940490D058EE4792B692977FAA49AF08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a photo of the missing child;</text></clause><clause id="H2AEEA504A5644EF4AA4AFD5F9EC07ED6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>physical features, such as height, weight, sex, ethnicity, race, hair color, and eye color; and</text></clause><clause id="HC8570823710947A18B8EDFBB2B77862C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>endangerment information, such as pregnancy status, prescription medications, suicidal tendencies, vulnerability to being sex trafficked, and other health or risk factors.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF250DD580DE469B92233B112A7BC865"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification to definitions</header><text>Paragraph (9) of section 475 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675">42 U.S.C. 675</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HDC9D4D5B89EC432799F6EF2776970AF1" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H8581350BD34548F3A0B163C76007A0A3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <term>sex or labor trafficking victim</term> has the meaning given the term <term>victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons</term> under section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H9F51052C18B8408BBD7C5393C8B61FF6"><enum>132.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on submission of Department of Justice reports on time</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Department of Justice has failed to meet reporting requirements under title IV of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7103">22 U.S.C. 7103(d)(7)</external-xref>) and that progress on critical data collection on human trafficking reporting are in jeopardy as a result of such failure and must be addressed immediately.</text></section><section id="H4A6ADD4D74BC4C729D152B7B9FCF2DB2"><enum>133.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on requiring child welfare agencies to report information on missing and abducted foster children and youth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H169A6B4D535249BAA19CCF5E44BF23D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each State child welfare agency should prioritize developing and implementing protocols to comply with section 471(1)(35)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(35)(B)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12874EEF785F4BBE84DC83CF0D9C89FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report the information it receives on missing or abducted foster children and youth to the National Center on Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) and to law enforcement authorities for inclusion in the FBI’s National Crime Information Center database, in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 471(a)(34) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(34)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B7E19A28E0F45768933525F1B07A598"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such reports must be made immediately (and in no case later than 24 hours) after the information is received; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D3FEBA55FE545DEA19CE8707D910FF8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such reports to the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services were required to start on September 30, 2016, and annual reports were required to start on September 30, 2017, by such section 471(a)(34), to provide the total number of children and youth who are sex trafficking victims.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle></title><title id="HEA555F5BABA347EF9634D679CD76076E"><enum>II</enum><header>Fighting Human Trafficking Abroad</header><section id="H9BD8F6DF12C642808C446AF703F59A1C"><enum>201.</enum><header>Amendments to the International Megan’s Law</header><subsection id="H7B4D15F2E7F44190ADA9DFA97E42CF1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Periodic information sharing</header><text>Section 4(e)(3) of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21503">34 U.S.C. 21503(e)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HB54AC10F485E4D2792E839A3F1050E20" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H246ACCBE25EC45468B03945098B3C2F3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Bi-annual information sharing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and each October 1 and April 1 thereafter, the Center shall obtain from each country participating in the visa waiver program a list of covered sex offenders who are citizens or nationals of such countries. Such information shall be obtained to the extent feasible with respect to both convicted and registered sex offenders. The Center may reciprocate, as appropriate, with such information relating to covered sex offenders who are citizens or nationals of the United States.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAEF1EBFA5579466CB5B4DD9758F6F0B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 4(f)(2) of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21503">34 U.S.C. 21503(f)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or would have to register if the individual returned to that jurisdiction after departing it to reside outside the United States,</quote> after <quote>jurisdiction</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB69511ACB2324006BADAA01681614436"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 240(b) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/212b">22 U.S.C. 212b(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8F59B06B542940BA889ADF5F6BCE8262" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H881D142092D34F01BDE83FB8DF75F9D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarification with respect to continuing registration</header><text>A person may not be issued or reissued a passport without a unique identifier solely because the person has moved or otherwise resides outside the United States.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H3A6E8EC994F04989B8B50E58EF3902C1" commented="no"><enum>202.</enum><header>Modifications to program to end modern slavery grants</header><subsection id="H5407ED62209545A5A5A7247F8F7A727B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1298 of the National Defense Authorization Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7114">22 U.S.C. 7114</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="HA8D4C499EC2C493D91D5AF319F8F1450" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In subsection (g)(2), by striking <quote>2020</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E7EEE6259EA45638945EC9384D10D6D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In subsection (h)(1), by striking <quote>Not later than September 30, 2018, and September 30, 2020</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than September 30, 2022, and September 30, 2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06352CBD70C040E58755B93690EF5325" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award of funds</header><text>All grants shall be awarded on a competitive basis.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBBEC581632E44FE7B19FDC6584C9A7A8"><enum>203.</enum><header>Amendments to tier standards</header><subsection id="H247FA62A335F4A86828F6E40833DEEF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modifications to tier 2 watch list</header><text>Subsection (b)(2) of section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>), is amended—</text><paragraph id="H12CEBE183DBA4437989CB617A103196D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Special</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Tier 2</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD68DE5B482A4A8E98CF57A3F666C70B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HD9DE629FE80F40BC864670AA01685B24" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HA539D6AC2D4F4EDE9C3C0D69AB326431"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of list</header><text>Not later than the date on which the determinations described in subsections (c) and (d) are submitted to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such subsections, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of countries that the Secretary determines requires special scrutiny during the following year. The list shall be composed of countries that have been listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) pursuant to the current annual report because—</text><clause id="H65803A93C1774A23807DEDA6929E6C0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the estimated number of victims of severe forms of trafficking is very significant or is significantly increasing and the country is not taking proportional concrete actions; or</text></clause><clause id="H113147F240BC4F51802D3FE4B0AB301E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there is a failure to provide evidence of increasing efforts to combat severe forms of trafficking in persons from the previous year, including increased investigations, prosecutions and convictions of trafficking crimes, increased assistance to victims, and decreasing evidence of complicity in severe forms of trafficking by government officials.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA42115764A2E4A59AE25E99F2031C0B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification to special rule for downgraded and reinstated countries</header><text>Subsection (b)(2)(F) of such section 110 is amended—</text><paragraph id="H02DF0A99A6684FDABEA83CB1E1A11DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>the special watch list</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the country—</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watchlist described in subparagraph (A) for more than 1 year immediately after the country consecutively—</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1E7E7FEE4E473A8EB353611D3C5205"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>the special watch list described in subparagraph (A)(iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watch list described in subparagraph (A)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE89421CEAE144728875E840553BB4D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>in the year following such waiver under subparagraph (D)(ii)</quote> before the period at the end.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E613761DCA94BD0B169D24EF82A48D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Subsection (b) of such section 110 is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="HC18DC5834C264D21889CCA62F1EC44C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In paragraph (2), as amended by subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HED09536C53634DFF946C9C854CFE884D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EDB475192FB49148203A7BC0C0007FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DB8416CC8B6426A92B206F75FD534B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text><clause id="H207B9C22D8CE49FAB0A01626884CF29F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">special watch list</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">tier 2 watch list</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H56E75FC3E73445FC8AEFBE4292FA4792"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>special watch list</quote> and inserting <quote>Tier 2 watch list</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA2FF7DE3DF7477AAA3E92B0ABC914FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In paragraph (3)(B), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H490ABA668ED549BC9D17F8D3026719CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H92F4AEFF6BAD44469B5937D2010F8394"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>each country described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>each country described in paragraph (2)(A)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF877670A860047CA969E8ABA53A27FFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>the Special Watch List under paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Tier 2 watch list under paragraph (2)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H501DD92347F441558CAFF9D000FB52F6"><enum>204.</enum><header>Expanding prevention efforts at the United States Agency for International Development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In order to increase the prevention efforts by the United States abroad, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall encourage integration of activities to counter trafficking in persons (C–TIP) into broader assistance programming. The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H360A391882E742099E22E50950A6DB37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine a reasonable definition for the term <term>C–TIP Integrated Development Programs</term>, which shall at a minimum include any programming to address health, economic development, education, democracy and governance, food security and humanitarian assistance that the Administrator determines includes a sufficient counter-trafficking in persons element integrated in the program design or delivery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53859D72674246C19A143B3BAEFE9F23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage that any program design or delivery that may directly serve victims and survivors of trafficking in persons is age-appropriate, linguistically accessible, culturally responsive, and survivor- and trauma-informed, and provides opportunities for anonymous and voluntary feedback from the beneficiaries receiving such services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA10A444279C841BD983EC16491DFCFB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage that each USAID mission integrates a counter-trafficking in persons perspective and specific approaches into development programs, project design, and methods for program monitoring and evaluation, when addressing a range of development issues, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2696240916324C82893EB2FEBF469D7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAB0543863FB43F5A557101558E589AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76BD7F098100407294E3793A61D59CE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF254DBB380044EB4BB2C83C5072F0EC4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>democracy and governance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F0AF9EBAE114C92AF80C29F6203A8BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>food security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90A05C58B0614530A810E1BDDF80B303"><enum>(F)</enum><text>humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAF2326327E940199A4F93FB690D5595"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implement robust training and disseminate tools around the integration of a counter-trafficking perspective and awareness in the day-to-day work of development professionals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72A6B22207F24A17A848AD5E22B96003"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourage subsequent Country Development Cooperation Strategies include a counter-trafficking in persons analytic component to guide future project design and promote the inclusion of counter-trafficking elements in project design, implementation, monitoring, and evaluation required for Tier 2 Watch List and Tier 3 countries (as such terms are defined for purposes of section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>), as amended).</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H8F4B4E190E4849EA815FDD7B92D03B4E"><enum>III</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><section id="H54F54D18520D4D69A9D58ABBB693C60F"><enum>301.</enum><header>Extension of authorizations under the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 113 of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7110">22 U.S.C. 7110</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE3D8280F14E64844BB249B525D977159"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>2018 through 2021, $13,822,000</quote> and inserting <quote>2022 through 2026, $16,000,000</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F0200885DBA4EAA948D50641BE0E01F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H6E0ADA49859C466E9100FE55C12F6D63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>To carry out the purposes of sections 106(b) and 107(b),</quote> and inserting <quote>To carry out the purposes of sections 106(b) and 107(b) of this Act and sections 101 and 102 of the Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2022,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB69E086AF2F147B4B8EF40C815F4860F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$19,500,000</quote> and all that follows, and inserting <quote>$25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2026, of which $5,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated in each fiscal year for the National Human Trafficking Hotline and for cybersecurity and public education campaigns, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, for identifying and responding as needed to cases of human trafficking.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H904AD1302E5D4EA88D41B5AACCB9732D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H058F4A4373B945068CCBFD8E9A4922C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2018 through 2021, $65,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>2022 through 2026, $89,500,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E7B9972B9FE45C5905E01B82EE2748C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6828E268D9D04EE69E4654007F185889"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9654EBFBAEF24F538F6EAD5FBAA36242"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H9A897E830B22412B919E16D2B270B92C" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5556D15923C74E1CBA31B1C989283A80"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to fund programs to end modern slavery, in an amount not to exceed $37,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3408FC91D5F04C99A15451C416D3DAD5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d) in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2018 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2022 through 2026, of which $35,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year for the Office of Victims of Crime Housing Assistance Grants for Victims of Human Trafficking</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H51EC5EAE3B2241A2AE56D98FCFB28745"><enum>302.</enum><header>Extension of authorizations under the international Megan’s Law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21509">34 U.S.C. 21509</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2018 through 2021</quote> and inserting <quote>2022 through 2026</quote>.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

