<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D3EA3EEF2BC42A383B1405817A4DA2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6571 IH: TSA Security Threat Assessment Application Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Transportation Security Administration to standardize the enrollment process for individuals applying for multiple TSA Security Threat Assessment programs, including the TWIC, HAZMAT Endorsement, and TSA PreCheck programs of the Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA114CCEAC2F4BFAAEC22D1D45DF49B3" style="OLC"><section id="H0EBECF402CCC49A28A21182418629D50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TSA Security Threat Assessment Application Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5501D40DDD8D4C56922FC56809A57AD8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Standardization of applications for certain programs of the Transportation Security Administration</header><subsection id="HA2FBABB37D804F34A89118BC5EAB1C54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standardization</header><paragraph id="HF998112E8646441DBCBB1058DCB21CBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall take such actions as are necessary to standardize the enrollment and renewal system for individuals applying for or renewing more than one TSA Security Threat Assessment program, including the TWIC, HAZMAT Endorsement, and TSA PreCheck programs of the Administration (or any related successor programs), to permit an individual to—</text><subparagraph id="HE048D50188B846939E3BB9489E79CAA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in paragraph (3), enroll at a TSA-designated universal enrollment center once and use the application, as well as the application generated by TSA’s vetting, including criminal history information, for one of such programs to enroll in two or more of such programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76EF28EC17524035A5C6C7D4C30C58CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply successful, valid clearance results from a TSA Security Threat Assessment to satisfy vetting requirements for participation in any TSA Security Threat Assessment program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE712DA90B2483285CCF7509B8898A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>undergo a streamlined and expeditious renewal process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06367C5DAD5A4D34B82CE89773075D3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Streamlining</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1)(B), the Administrator of the TSA shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA4F2349865B04A8B86CEB234D3BB5B8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>align the expiration of an individual’s successful, valid clearance results with the expiration of that individual’s eligibility to participate in TSA Security Threat Assessment programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE9461128A9B42A0AB11FF24C8043883"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enroll an individual in two or more TSA Security Threat Assessment programs without additional cost to the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H336FAB80CF3746129B753F9011DE4E28" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual under subsection (a) is at different times applying for or renewing enrollment in more than one TSA Security Threat Assessment program, such individual may be required to revisit a TSA-designated universal enrollment center for the collection of additional data, such as biometrics, necessary for any such program that were not so collected in connection with any other such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBF142083C8F466FB5BB195E1D49C605"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall post on a publicly available webpage of the Administration information relating to the standardization of the enrollment system for individuals applying for multiple TSA Security Threat Assessment programs described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H78F8EC0CF9BA4126AB6A9BDD84107874"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall brief Congress on progress made toward the implementation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE2AE6F671C6443ABACF3B689BFA71B09"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall complete the standardization of the enrollment and renewal system for individuals applying for or renewing multiple TSA Security Threat Assessment programs described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H50D2223F60454646956DD027053D5720"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H066B4DCA509342C783860E5D520C5807"><enum>(1)</enum><header>HAZMAT Endorsement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>HAZMAT Endorsement</quote> means a hazardous materials endorsement on a commercial driver’s license issued by a State under section 5103a of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82B69E86FDA646E093B4B334F4F57AB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>TSA PreCheck</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>TSA PreCheck</quote> means the trusted traveler program of the Transportation Security Administration under section 109(a)(3) of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/114">49 U.S.C. 114</external-xref> note) and section 44919 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H950EEAEED3454931A5D7A55F02464154"><enum>(3)</enum><header>TWIC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>TWIC</quote> means a valid transportation security card issued by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating under section 70105 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

