<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C34BB4B3CEC4145BA41A89B3EDC9DCB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7424 IH: Solitary Confinement Reform Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7424</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220406">April 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce instances of placement of inmates in restrictive housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H027C8ABDC04947E4854300C637FF2BAD" style="OLC"><section id="H4917FC6A2F2A437E818A159068A081D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Solitary Confinement Reform Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H61D436EACB5A48CA8EBF5D0CE1C441E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD12000989C3F4AFBB1BF96CD19417661"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Restrictive housing takes many forms, and the experience in segregation can vary considerably depending on certain external factors, such as the length of stay, conditions of confinement, and degree of social isolation, as well as factors specific to each confined person, such as age and psychological resiliency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40184440FA794E46BDCB4F0AD3653CE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Confined individuals located in restrictive housing broadly express severe psychological disturbances with lasting detrimental consequences as a result of their experience in security housing units. The Stanford Lab’s interviews revealed a range of common impairments and adverse consequences associated with long-term, indefinite incarceration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A745C1A7CB641BBB2E1B4E813398642"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The majority of confined members endorsed feeling mood symptoms consistent with the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM 5) diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder, including depressed mood, hopelessness, anger, irritability, anhedonia, anger, fatigue, feelings of guilt, loss of appetite, and insomnia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5924BB2A19CC4B41813216D309810CA0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nearly all members also endorsed a sense of anxiety symptoms characteristic of DSM 5 diagnoses of panic disorder, traumatic stress disorders, and/or obsessive-compulsive disorders, such as nervousness, worry, increased heart rate and respiration, sweating, muscle tension, hyperarousal, paranoia, nightmares, intrusive thoughts, and fear of losing control.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB510635D3F740AA9F7C21E3D0D57F81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Psychiatric symptoms and diminished capacity for socialization continue to cause psychological suffering and problems with social function for most of the men now in general population.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA7E775CC2AE4D47A96E3C19BE4469AF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Confined members cited emotional numbing and desensitization as some of the most common responses to living in SHU.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D82D77AB10B4443A60B02CACFA54C25"><enum>(7)</enum><text>This sense of emotional suppression and dysregulation continues to be problematic for prisoners following the transition to the general population. Class members also reported significant alterations in cognition and perception.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F05BC47A6743F1ADD829C5E0216788"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Problems with attention, concentration, and memory were common, and described as persistent and worsening.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2DFCC77B5B74FE3808D595B76B10651"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Some of the most pronounced and enduring effects of long-term isolation appeared to have resulted from relational estrangement and social isolation; prisoners frequently reported losing, over time, the motivation to seek social connection.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEA181E5C28F14DCBA789C6813FA5F010"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations on confinement</header><subsection id="HE3D923C58DE14F33AD4C6006A97BBAC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Inmates shall be housed in the least restrictive setting necessary to ensure their own safety, as well as the safety of staff, other inmates, and the public.</text></subsection><subsection id="H39267C10B1844F0EBFE6B1149A0AD70D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reasoning</header><text>The head of a covered facility shall clearly articulate each specific reason for an inmate’s placement and retention in restrictive housing. Each such reason shall be supported by objective evidence that such placement and retention is necessary—</text><paragraph id="H416C3F888A3A4EA084600F4EF76033B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for prison safety or order;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF273E41ADB904136977D4A55DF419224"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent gang influence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD413B1B32F84D4A9A4BAE6188EFFB39"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for inmate or staff protection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2DE1A4B744F4C438C44D0F5C202B560"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other penological purpose as the head of such facility may determine is appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD37BBABD4D3D42E2B9C769E6598D44CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penological purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Restrictive housing may only be used to eliminate or mitigate a specific facility threat such as a fight between inmates or the threat of imminent danger to inmates or staff.</text></subsection><subsection id="H193BEC70178441D08508430FFA24A10D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="HBD1B2308B88446BA8945BA1D7019D8E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Inmates shall remain in restrictive housing for no longer than necessary to address each specific reason for such placement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44B1A26908154354BA06D840F4F13C7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Punishment</header><text>Inmates may not be placed in restrictive housing—</text><subparagraph id="HDA77ADAE3DDB4CBAAD0E176F38E1A213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as a form of punishment or deterrence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7D60CBFB08D47A591B2FADEB4C9EDE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for low-level offenses that do not involve physical violence to staff or inmates; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1116102AA0434C36850A8B8C75C82CA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for more than 5 days as a part of a routine investigation or more than 15 days as part of a non-routine investigation, as determined by the Official concerned, absent documented extenuating circumstances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6225C579263343BFB528258101F3D816"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review of placement</header><subsection id="H33F7FDF2D85245148EB3A8F60AD117FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institutional review panel of a covered facility shall review the placement of an inmate in restrictive housing not later than 15 days after such placement and not less than every 15 days thereafter until such time as the inmate is removed from restrictive housing.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE631C79DF2B4C598E8936C08618A543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each covered facility shall make a plan for the return of the inmate to less restrictive conditions and shall share such plan with the inmate, unless sharing such plan would put the health and safety of the inmate, staff, other inmates, or the public at risk.</text></subsection></section><section id="H628F6B5E5F7E421582B74B536AF51B77"><enum>5.</enum><header>Employee training</header><subsection id="HF91A72F9783D42FE873994B16D9FBA1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Official concerned shall ensure that the staff of each facility is trained on use of force and restrictive housing policies not less than quarterly.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC44517209F4240FF8B8E58EE4F91DC16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Housing policy training</header><text>The Official concerned shall ensure that the staff of each covered facility complies with restrictive housing policies and that such policies are reflected in employee evaluation systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3CDFE9CAE4144A9AEB380BC628C82C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standing committees</header><paragraph id="HB2594B1FA67D4EDABDFB6BEE578101CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Official concerned shall establish in each covered facility a standing committee, consisting of high-level correctional officials, active or retired, to regularly evaluate existing restrictive housing policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H522EEAA9704F41B7BB12AF461B0A8F34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each standing committee shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0D42F37DC7284234845DFCB00875BADB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review use of force and abuse allegations to include body cam footage and closed-circuit video footage of any use of force or abuse allegation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE4295D37EFB4585B9A29F7D2176E116"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit redacted written recommendations on preventing unlawful use of force or abuse to—</text><clause id="HA0F6B843B87546FBA14B8BC129359BFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></clause><clause id="H60B28B02C86A443089CCA1AB171A6E0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="HB5D5D0D0F74F451A8F3445170EDC6FDC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H596CDD648D3F4B7AA21A04A64151261F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assist covered facilities in developing safe and effective alternatives to restrictive housing and share with other covered facilities and State prison facilities best practices for use of force to ensure safety for staff and confined individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H57A3D257675647CFAF39694A3025450E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Gradual return to general population</header><subsection id="H21B140CAF386472BA3B8CBFD73F3F3FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Absent a compelling reason as determined by the Official concerned, the head of a covered facility may not release inmates directly from restrictive housing to the general inmate population.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7A362F953ECC4C87969F06D4A2E91DE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Graduated system</header><text>The head of a covered facility shall consult with mental health professionals to ensure that shock of removal from isolation will not cause harm to the confined individual or the general inmate population.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB2B3B03CE86C424B9955713953A89AC4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enrichment opportunities</header><subsection id="H08F587D392FA4366B0004B36567DD352"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, each Official concerned shall establish policies to increase the minimum amount of time inmates in restrictive housing spend outside their cells to 3 hours per day, including weekends and holidays, and to offer enhanced in-cell opportunities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H01C1F318C25E4594A249C81B2A5AF399"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum restraint</header><text>The Official concerned shall afford to individuals in restrictive housing educational opportunities, using the minimum amount of protective restraint necessary to ensure safety of staff, population, and educational professionals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H53D91D8838624F5C8CD398669715452B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Out-of-Cell time</header><text>The Official concerned shall make available to the inmates opportunities for recreation, education, clinically appropriate treatment therapies, skill-building, and social interaction with staff and other inmates.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9015DD6AE2244F8BB68DFE71CA118F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lower-Risk individuals</header><text>The Official concerned shall ensure that lower-risk individuals may conduct recreation time in such group size as the facility determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H63AA16284E8F4DBDB7698A80C39D014E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expansion</header><text>The Official concerned shall increase the ability of covered facilities to divert inmates with serious mental illness to mental health treatment programs or facilities when needed to serve the interest of the facility and the inmate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC6F76C87A3D543F2A07B78CAE031F0CB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Final days of imprisonment</header><text>The Official concerned shall establish policies to—</text><paragraph id="HA0AC18A481FA4F52AA59AAEF5C9708B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit the placement of inmates in restrictive housing during the final 180 days of the term of imprisonment of such inmate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC08A00F398F54B7397F9954D26B24425"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide targeted re-entry programming for inmates who require restrictive housing during the such final 180-day period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B640BB9780040ABA8FD3A58FE36C7A2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Posting policies</header><text>The head of each covered facility shall post the policies established under subsection (a) in an area of the facility that is frequented by inmates and staff.</text></subsection><subsection id="H866D39AB5D724DAD90CCA1E0B7A4AB35"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Statistics</header><text>The Official concerned shall publish system-wide restrictive housing statistics on a monthly basis on the website of the agency under that Official’s jurisdiction and on websites for effected covered facilities. The statistics shall include the total number of inmates in restrictive housing, disaggregated by—</text><paragraph id="HB8E85E709AFE4547B7B04CB75E050C2D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of inmates who—</text><subparagraph id="H12DCE1AB9D914116A2886E2980142B69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remained in such housing for more than 90 days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H102952C9A9A64FEE9D02012838FA589C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remained in such housing for more than 180 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H969F16A981144538B2BD28CE25B8906D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remained in such housing for more than 364 days; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA143F3AEC72473B8F48014FF3CE443E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of inmates in disciplinary segregation and the number of inmates in administrative detention.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC2865660729944B9B52C83193BD32489"><enum>8.</enum><header>Confinement requirements</header><subsection id="H98D0261FD02B4FDEB1EBE41A4FAB91C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Official concerned and the head of any State prison used for the detention of persons held under authority of any Act of Congress, shall—</text><paragraph id="HD75390147D60434DB18DD52956375163"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit data on restrictive housing to the Department of Justice and the Committees on Armed Services and on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives on a quarterly basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D3C2E5FF5F54AAD9890A6AB22DF9DF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>finalize upgrades in data collection software to improve tracking of restrictive housing inmates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE2B650567994B5B880DE6C30C2F9D0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require body cams to be worn by correctional staff interacting with confined population in restrictive housing for any forced movement or physical interaction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75F9D7DA2FA543A98E44494390DA5C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether placement in restrictive housing is appropriate, it shall be presumed that an inmate shall be housed in the least restrictive setting necessary to ensure safety, and that inmates in restrictive housing shall be returned to general population as soon as it is safe to do so.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3D412C619E6B40268B6B3C687CC2D271"><enum>9.</enum><header>Violations</header><subsection id="H937A06D28440472A9225E2D2C86C399B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HEB2F60C4E255474AA3F668EF564FA18D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>BOP Violations</header><text>In the case of a Bureau of Prisons facility that violates the policy established by the Attorney General under section 7, the Attorney General may—</text><subparagraph id="H295C7DD204624CB0807B4884E73C4F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce the funding provided to the violating facility by such amount as the Attorney General determines appropriate and increase the amount provided to facilities in compliance by an amount that is equal to the amount of such reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC64B0E7039E4B8B92A63A9ACF437DA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suspend staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy with or without pay; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93E63D63036A4F08AEC9DCF1566A9392"><enum>(C)</enum><text>terminate staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy if such violation is considered substantially detrimental to the goals of such policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB234E7E5B16F457EAF50FE2F26D541B5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>DOD Violations</header><text>In the case of a prison facility of the Department of Defense that violates the policy established by the Secretary of Defense under section 7, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="H119741E82E424AE28021E221512F6359"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce the funding provided to the violating facility by such amount as the Secretary determines appropriate and increase the amount provided to facilities in compliance by an amount that is equal to the amount of such reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38C12C042CB7449E97D53494328D4AE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suspend staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy with or without pay; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB65BC3AF94CD4831980E8FC897A4197D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>terminate staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy if such violation is considered substantially detrimental to the goals of such policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD30D7CAA3B1B43A6A2A3FDC9CD9BE357"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other prison facility violations</header><text>In the case of a covered facility described in section 11(1)(C) that violates the policy established by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons under section 7, the Attorney General may—</text><subparagraph id="HA45100A8D4DB4BE8922E485791FE9EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of—</text><clause id="HEEE804ACFC404F4F9156CCAC6A8B9026"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a facility described in clause (i) of such section, decline to extend or renew any contract or agreement with the prison facility or condition such an extension or renewal on compliance with such policy; or</text></clause><clause id="H18A54D94143A44E68B98A921A8470243"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a facility described in clause (ii) of such section, reduce the funding provided to the violating facility by such amount as the Attorney General determines appropriate and increase the amount provided to facilities in compliance by an amount that is equal to the amount of such reduction;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31CB8C602DCC4A47B5E35F81142261F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>call for the suspension of staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy with or without pay; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45D374E3C17E4213832569995BCBE477"><enum>(C)</enum><text>call for the termination of staff found to be involved in a violation of such policy if such violation is considered substantially detrimental goals of such policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C00ABC210AB482C8B21D4269BDEEC75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjudication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered facility or employee accused of a violation of the policy established by the Official concerned under section 7 shall, after notice and an opportunity to be heard by the standing committee of such facility and subject to approval by such Official, be subject to the penalties under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8038A68D6E3A41E4BBA866130AFA1170"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text>Any conflicted parties shall recuse themselves from the proceeding before the standing committee and a new impartial member shall be appointed to the committee to serve in this capacity for the duration of the proceeding. Any conflict of interest shall be disclosed in writing and preserved within the recommendation notes.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB721806B403A4EA99B0B8F142513CC74"><enum>10.</enum><header>Revision of Department of Defense policies and guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall revise Department of Defense Instruction 1325.07 (Administration of Military Correctional Facilities and Clemency and Parole Authority), and any related policies and guidance of the Department, to conform to the requirements of this Act.</text></section><section id="H3B3D67BAD1FD4957917AF64705F399A2"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H57B9C6626B8040488A336E351DF26FCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H566D3C04FE804FD8AE3F46A001402620"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a prison facility under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5ECB069581D471DB85058307E6A91B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prison facility under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7255E5F18F14DCBA153B127EEF7755E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any prison facility under the jurisdiction of a State or unit of local government—</text><clause id="H0AE30E48D6F5443F9F87CDE01B250C43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which persons are held in custody pursuant to a contract or agreement with the Federal Government; and</text></clause><clause id="H84F5BC7D0C9C45C68F6E8396070CC04E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that receives Federal funds for law enforcement purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BC28C9D35B34BE3ACA30921C559CA84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inmate</header><text>The term <term>inmate</term> means an inmate serving a term of imprisonment in a covered facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA9455E298EA4B0AA57AF3AD7DFA8FF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institutional review panel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institutional review panel</term> means a panel composed of—</text><subparagraph id="H06AAC3864A814013BE62E36A0DE1799D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the leadership of a covered facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2605E74C8EB4CC9AFAB7EB381ABE9A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>medical professionals and mental health professionals who are employed by and work outside of such facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C23D3F9F38D4591871E294D1F972BCC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-routine investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-routine investigation</term> means any investigation that addresses a grave risk of safety and security of the facility, such as a riot, killing, or terror attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FF933F4333941F0B7657D22538BB8E7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Official concerned</header><text>The term <term>Official concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC892BCD4AD6E4055B30157428CA39267"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, with respect to prison facilities under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC71ED8C79A04F828EB54A4DF376A67B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense, with respect to prison facilities under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7305F56AB0F416C84FB4B4733555D08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the chief executive of a State or unit of local government, with respect to prison facilities under the jurisdiction of such State or unit of local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H913BD570CEC5400887B4611DA8C2F5A0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>The term <term>restrictive housing</term> means any housing in which an inmate is removed from general population housing to housing with little to no contact with others for a disciplinary purpose.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

