<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B7C3D4C3C7B4406A8B4263ECCEF4122" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7763 IH: To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to support and incentivize domestic activities to address fertilizer shortages and deficiencies, diversify fertilizer sources, and reduce dependency on foreign sources for fertilizer, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7763</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to support and incentivize domestic activities to address fertilizer shortages and deficiencies, diversify fertilizer sources, and reduce dependency on foreign sources for fertilizer, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAFA61B66FDA54A739CB2A5D581653304" style="OLC"><section id="HB279D0AECD874802B7B568AC1E139326" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Addressing fertilizer shortages</header><subsection id="H68AA0CF20ADF40878663AB0EBF80E6FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall support and incentivize domestic activities through grants, loans, and other forms of assistance, to address fertilizer shortages and deficiencies, diversify fertilizer sources, and reduce dependency on foreign sources for fertilizer, including by—</text><paragraph id="H50942EA566EE45E3820F194EC5564587"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the availability of innovative fertilizer and fertilizer alternatives, including nitrogen, phosphate, potassium, biological products and technologies, and other nutrients that may assist in the production of agricultural commodities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F6242751BA4B978FB13512C6A43D43"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing materials or tools that reduce the need for fertilizer or support the more efficient use of fertilizer, including nitrogen, phosphate, potassium, biological products and technologies, and other nutrients that may assist in the production of agricultural commodities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H816FC94EFC4A4487AD76FB933F894BF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting materials and facilities and research and development, that may support the activities carried out pursuant to this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8ACBEF89F5EA45469BFAF6ED5F88ADCF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting sustainable agriculture production through the use of—</text><subparagraph id="H60B965521C2F4806B7ADD5CD32C602F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sustainable fertilizer produced in, or used in a manner that, reduces the greenhouse gas impact; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE98A69452C8460FB4F3821AAEB21159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fertilizer produced through the use of renewable energy sources, including incentivizing greater precision in fertilizer use; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6929385C22294F82885D096D63F527ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting activities or other measures that may otherwise address competition-related challenges in the United States fertilizer market and obstacles to producers in obtaining affordable, responsibly manufactured fertilizer as referred to in the notice entitled <quote>Access to Fertilizer: Competition and Supply Chain Concerns</quote> published by the Department of Agriculture in the Federal Register on March 17, 2022 (87 Fed Reg. 15191 et seq.); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7872519E2CBD4502A8722681D9632678"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the facilities and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation and the authorities under section 1473H of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3319k">7 U.S.C. 3319k</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6815047216304B44ABCC8B646C136247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority Applicants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting activities to support under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to applications for such support containing proposals that the Secretary determines will most quickly address fertilizer shortages in the near term and mid-term.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4B5FF3ECFB104F7F82E7BF2080F68AA8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic></italic>Funding made available to carry out this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local public funds provided for activities described in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA8978DD2B9AE4E8EAE43FFFADFF2E196"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out this section is in addition to other authorities of the Secretary. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC486AF0CEF89444AAE9CD0F5EE20713F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Streamlined process</header><text>In providing assistance pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall ensure that such assistance be provided through a streamlined and expedient process (as determined necessary by the Secretary) to quickly address fertilizer shortages.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3D73FBC4F84A45719EA4B5A37A15EF05"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 3 percent of the funding provided under this section may be used by the Secretary for administrative purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H68F9F12690CE4337884AC22B97A2F043"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $100,000,000, to remain available until expended. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

