<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H67809F7F2D064D98A740D0EEA6AEB5D0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9000 IH: Hydrogen for Industry Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to establish a Hydrogen Technologies for Heavy Industry Grant Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H349F5FD947B244958340224EA561C989" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7CAEFCF03A84493080D53ECBBDB96EC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hydrogen for Industry Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H210D820C600E4E8AAEBE586699BF260C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hydrogen Technologies for Heavy Industry Grant Program</header> <subsection id="H7C0AA8265FA24965B2B0080F9A8B762C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emission reduction program</header><text>Subtitle F of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16291">42 U.S.C. 16291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD271830EEC9644A2A6200DCF3F15B294">
<section id="HC0898EB63BF044C38093286DAC39D954"><enum>969E.</enum><header>Hydrogen technologies for heavy industry grant program</header>
<subsection id="H0C19166F852C4852BE0F9587540F9AA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of low-Income or disadvantaged community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income or disadvantaged community</term> means a community (including a city, town, county, or reasonably isolated and divisible segment of a larger municipality) with an annual median household income that is less than 100 percent of the statewide annual median household income for the State in which the community is located, according to the most recent decennial census.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H732220219EAE4B29AD44E8AB7D70C130"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Hydrogen for Industry Act of 2022</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Hydrogen Technologies for Heavy Industry Grant Program</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>), under which the Secretary shall award grants to demonstrate industrial end-use applications of hydrogen for—</text>
<paragraph id="H190D3365FF9F466BAFB074C867916EB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>iron, steel, and metals manufacturing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29CBD11F1D0647E09DF27E56627D1798"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cement manufacturing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27E7AC14C61348E3B643D58D7D277689"><enum>(3)</enum><text>glass manufacturing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H647ED9F3B3264A9487604E966513050C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ammonia and fertilizer production;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H512F9F481E7B4EB8834F946FE0056EB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>industrial food processes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3231B24A3C0F4124BFC56FCC472952B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>production of synthetic fuels from hydrogen, including with carbon oxides;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2DE8BBEB50E748F8BEB57D3BD4555A3D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>fuel refining, including biorefining;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5E7B1AA1DD04353B0393058E3C108A3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>chemical synthesis, including synthesis of methanol and ethylene;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1ADDF4E05697412DB15E751D8A83CA87"><enum>(9)</enum><text>process heaters, including hydrogen combustion with environmental controls; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H192C5CBC77124BEAA9F11937DF5BA86F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>any other use of hydrogen for heavy industry, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H07B3343EECD74D1DA4731DAEF0E52CC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program is to support the adoption of hydrogen as an emissions reduction technology for heavy industry, including in applications where hydrogen is blended with other fuels or feedstocks.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H88F7C5C2865B456BA12A53C05EC12A37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Demonstration projects and other authorized projects</header> <paragraph id="H94DBC1F7280E4C5F96EE400893DCF8FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide grants to commercial-scale demonstration projects for end-use applications of hydrogen and other authorized projects, as described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBDF3AEE07761423ABB90E4C3491F72F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text>The amount of a grant provided under this subsection shall be not more than $400,000,000. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26E7AA7D6C634E6E90E6CC2BFA574485"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking a grant to conduct a demonstration project or other authorized project under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of the manner in which the project—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE14327C2F0CE4438AFF6102E8909D960"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will contribute to the reduction of carbon emissions at the applicable facility; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H244077E58701414D8EEDC5889DA79A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a project for industrial end-use application that already uses hydrogen at scale, will reduce or avoid emissions of greenhouse gases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H729F2BCE3C3C409F934AA82FE7CF789C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection</header>
<subparagraph id="HE7B6E94467E8449D854C385F592D0D8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Secretary shall only provide a grant under this subsection after reviewing each applicant and application under paragraph (3) with respect to—</text> <clause id="HC149BC36C6854BECAC440EF271470150"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the financial strength of the applicant;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFE0E399B6EED4D53BE27389691F907CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proposed construction schedule;</text></clause> <clause id="H836DF9246B9F4FDC90E4727AA09CAED1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the market risk of the technology that the applicant seeks to demonstrate, as applicable; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H4E07C8E3A75A40DFAF146F60257851C8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the contractor history of the applicant. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBA248FB625246789F43F58B3468234C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In providing grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that will provide greater net impact in avoiding or reducing emissions of greenhouse gases. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEEE732B27D7B40718413DA12E06BDE56"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other considerations</header><text>In providing grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, award grants for projects that—</text> <clause id="H1F3A0775789A4CD08F8B065F096BFD0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represent a variety of end uses of hydrogen;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC7B91371877146E89D37F4EE0CD7243C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will use at least 50 percent hydrogen blends;</text></clause> <clause id="H99EA0532DE0F4131AFC2B0D7BD9A9D0E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>will generate the greatest benefit to low-income or disadvantaged communities; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC955F857D7354E9EABC48151EC1FBDF1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>will maximize creation or retention of domestic jobs and provide the highest job quality.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H044735FF3BE443D4B9C52594E2EA9150"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorized projects</header><text>Grant amounts provided under this subsection may be used—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC45DAF55886D4E6E940D85D16622B465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out demonstration projects for end uses of hydrogen;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADE26017428E4EB9B5345006D80B658E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to construct a new commercial-scale facility that will use hydrogen as a fuel or feedstock; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB1A65A1A3E24C78B750876A2F2519E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to retool, retrofit, or expand an existing facility determined to be qualified by the Secretary to enable use of hydrogen as a fuel or feedstock in industrial end-use applications of hydrogen, including at multiple points within a larger facility. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3581152E48824805A00097E4C37DF90D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A demonstration project receiving a grant under this subsection shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7286C1620B4744B190D6DD36029F6C92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use technologies that have completed pilot-scale testing or the equivalent, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E8A60D8C9F74CA5912F41395AFB6C6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on completion, demonstrate hydrogen technologies used by heavy industry; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDE552B38B085433BB1A2AE26388DD712"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct hydrogen leakage monitoring, reporting, and verification programs and leak detection and repair programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3CBDEE0BFB142939360B625C08ACD63"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of a demonstration project carried out using a grant under this subsection shall be not less than 20 percent.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF5707B5F7744EF9A376EFAA1086E47F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Engineering and design studies</header><text>The Secretary may fund front-end engineering and design studies in addition to, or in advance of, providing a grant for a demonstration project or other authorized project under this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H17427C59A7094AEBA1635863E30D6665"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>No technology, or level of emission reduction, shall be treated as adequately demonstrated for purposes of section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>), achievable for purposes of best available control technologies (as defined in section 169 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7479">42 U.S.C. 7479</external-xref>)), or achievable in practice for purposes of the terms defined in section 171 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7501">42 U.S.C. 7501</external-xref>) solely by reason of the identification of that technology or level of emission reduction in programs established under this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE0E518CEB9044694A959994352729664"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the Program $1,200,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7CE971ACFF3440649D0EC4CAA6438A80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/58">Public Law 109–58</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 600) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 969D the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H890787821DA94EC5A9E06FC594C237F8">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 969E. Hydrogen Technologies for Heavy Industry Grant Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H57A4AD9EB32B4B32833CC4325CBC40DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study</header>
<subsection id="HAFA4D974EC584F809B58B4F0124BA269"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Transportation shall jointly conduct and submit to Congress a report describing the results of a study—</text> <paragraph id="H407871A97D354826B12D0CDD78CAC824"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to examine the potential for emissions reductions at industrial facilities through hydrogen applications, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H83587E0AD8BC4706AA5F235ECBDF8DF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential use of levelized cost of carbon abatement, or a similar metric, in analyzing industrial uses of hydrogen; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8C0B8E0090F4BB1AD65B9F72E6F151B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility and impact of incorporating levelized cost of carbon abatement to compare the costs of technology options to reduce emissions across a range of industrial applications;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD7392EA3D014422A328F95367C70368"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to fully address existing challenges with respect to ensuring the safe use and handling of hydrogen and hydrogen-based fuels in industrial systems, including health and environmental impacts associated with the leakage of hydrogen and hydrogen carriers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H244C0AE1A46D4825BA61CD406E6EE1F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to identify and evaluate the feasibility, safety, and best practices of the use of hydrogen and ammonia as industrial fuel and feedstock;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3EFD24336B14D75820215AF870D7367"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to examine the feasibility of blending increasing levels of hydrogen with natural gas to supplement process heat requirements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30CEF23C10AC4967A48A5FD0171D6B6B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to examine the environmental impacts of hydrogen combustion in hydrogen-fueled gas turbines as pure hydrogen or at different ratios if used in blended fuel; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD2C48D8F11B496EB0092C0AED16A889"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to identify and evaluate considerations for transport and storage of hydrogen and hydrogen carriers, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B86D64E6A1F44C8B8B4E104A1B51358"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at industrial facilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04B0CB7E3A2940FDB3A50A025EEDFDD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in salt caverns, hard rock caverns, and other dedicated geological storage systems; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D8BF9B9068446B893BC4D28E74B3124"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in pipelines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H51BC22808F6940C4B1CF01372001C270"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Commerce shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB8C44D96FCBA4E5B93B147D4F899F629"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into account lessons learned from demonstration projects in other industries and projects in other countries; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H980B73C71AB84298A5CAD6041B545F01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the applicability of the lessons described in paragraph (1) to the use of hydrogen in industrial applications.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

