<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4DB544F0DA8347FF8BFB0772F2761A44" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8865 IH: National Sepsis Data Research, Outcomes, and Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national sepsis data trust, and to fund State-based pilots and programs to establish interoperable State-based sepsis data trusts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB6B53B0A0EF49CCA8C187F0DE596AC0" style="OLC"><section id="H64F6EE7EC03747E8AD6CF957C0DA91C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Sepsis Data Research, Outcomes, and Innovation Act</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>LuLu’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3EE80623E5354BC98D3A7FE5410B0ED5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treating and Eliminating the Burden of Sepsis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H03D5238BB5B241DB88FD55FD6764F9AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE1E9AFF89C1E4BD58027F30B96998378"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Treating and Eliminating the Burden of Sepsis</header><subsection id="H78ABDD1B08BF4CBD8B21F97FDE519AD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition; designation</header><paragraph id="H15E157D4066242BDABE291AC0E7F88D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of sepsis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the National Sepsis Data Research, Outcomes, and Innovation Act, the Secretary shall issue a rule specifying a definition of sepsis. Such definition may specify that sepsis is a life-threatening organ dysfunction caused by a dysregulated host response to infection. Such definition shall be standardized across departments, agencies, and other entities within the Department of Health of Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBF2381956748B8A5EA099E930B27EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nationally notifiable disease</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall take such steps as may be necessary to include sepsis on the list of nationally notifiable diseases published by the Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC79DB1C0607247A3B4C9452FFF52791C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National strategy</header><paragraph id="H322C8270D4ED4E15A463B8B1729C4304"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a national strategy—</text><subparagraph id="HBCA4DC71AD634CFA9852F170F6597560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to treat and eliminate the burden of sepsis, with the specific goals of, with respect to sepsis—</text><clause id="H80FCA92D01A24BEDB16F9319866A7141"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinating data (including through the data trust established under subsection (d));</text></clause><clause id="HEAC55A42F59A4F16823DA961EBE12D6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>spurring research; and</text></clause><clause id="H82A039E4C51040BB9C574BE04E8A1F2D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing diagnostic tools and treatments; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8D5E7F5E4584A6DA42A09558D0C1306"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to decrease instances of sepsis and mitigate long-term health effects of sepsis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E7D1DD362D14BEABC0344C91983246E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes specific actions to be taken to treat and eliminate the burden of sepsis among at-risk populations identified pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H354DA34874F64BC59E251D967EC6FB00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coodination</header><text>The Secretary may, in developing the strategy under paragraph (1), coordinate among agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services and other Federal agencies, academic institutions, and non-profit organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB42BEC8F74E4E7B8FB50A37A78639A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>At-risk populations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall identify population groups the Secretary determines to be at a higher risk for contracting sepsis, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H2C9C298B7D3F48B09DF344551F88538C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D638518A5F444D7AA0E808A8815B4D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pregnant women or women in the one year postpartum period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H493A0B5CC1DB485CA3207F0209A26975"><enum>(C)</enum><text>active servicemembers and veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E73B20F57949CD9012E29C428836C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>disabled and elderly individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A2DA77F4D84BB8B85EB0AA367F9AB4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>individuals residing on federally recognized tribal lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4CBFD3D34FA48B5B20C43F026736AB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State-Based sepsis data trust pilot programs</header><paragraph id="HB5D85DCA883D47C6B3732B79314CD23D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall award grants to not more than 5 States to establish pilot programs—</text><subparagraph id="H8521D0EE8EFB4412B7EE0060708CCD63"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect into State-based sepsis data trusts that use standardized data formats and coding (as determined by the Secretary) de-identified patient data concerning—</text><clause id="H382432FE1ACF4CA99A076EB71716DDD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demographic information about each case of sepsis in each such State;</text></clause><clause id="H441BB55FBDF344AD8E3A73538D39881B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administrative information with respect to each such case, including the date of diagnosis and the source of information;</text></clause><clause id="HC7B35040EAC041C8912641FF08DAE97B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pathological and genetic material characterizing each such case (including deoxyribonucleic acids (DNA), ribonucleic acids (RNA), single cell RNA, genes, chromosomes, genotype, alleles, epigenetic alteration or modifications to DNA or RNA, single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs), uninterpreted data that results from analysis of a biological sample from a diagnosed sepsis patient or other source, and any information extrapolated, derived, or inferred therefrom); </text></clause><clause id="H650EE96A91134359A589D53D69C3E64A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clinical information, including relevant diagnoses, treatment, and patient-reported outcomes of the individuals with sepsis and sepsis survivors;</text></clause><clause id="HFD773E6A89B7416283E30F7D8F111AC6"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each case of sepsis in each such State, the number of staff working in the relevant unit of the health care provider involved;</text></clause><clause id="H23D53D96DFFA4A19940B9512AA0F950E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provider payments that result from a sepsis diagnosis; and</text></clause><clause id="H5429740396214453A65C44397F6FE4D3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other elements determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84AEEA731EF54CE09655800810963014"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to combine and connect data so collected among such States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE18E45FC42B49A0A37798C3A439348C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data trust guidelines</header><subparagraph id="HAA8205DD16CD42F6B8977D79AA2650E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish governance guidelines, data access requirements, privacy and security protocols, and other such standards as may be required to support the establishment of interoperable State-based sepsis data trusts for purposes of the national sepsis data trust to be established under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F1172BA0CD14107AC09909F9EFCCC81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data sharing</header><text>The guidelines established under subparagraph (A) shall specify that—</text><clause id="H396B43B3CC444E79974941E977F005DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no entity participating in the date trust may share patient data with any entity not participating in the data trust; and</text></clause><clause id="H19AC938B6E89433589669284C226BDC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity shall agree, as a condition on participation in the data trust to not share any patient data with any entity not participating in the data trust.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C155C7C19F461295ACE3F20973ED28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing applications submitted by States for grants under this section, the Secretary shall take into consideration whether the States submitting such applications demonstrate established partnerships with a range of public and private stakeholders. The Secretary shall, of the States that demonstrate such partnerships, select—</text><subparagraph id="HEABE4FA30C12492B8AE3701194D21D64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one State that has a death rate from septicemia of greater than 15 people per 100,000 people per year and 1,500 deaths per year for the 5 calendar years preceding the declaration of the public health emergency with respect to COVID–19;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DE6B88009C241ABA6C0CFD2D08119D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one rural State with above average sepsis mortality rate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C4122B502704596B51DAEB7E1A3C900"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a diverse array of other States in such a manor as to ensure diversity of population density, geographic location, and general healthcare access and infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE72312B6CD294974AC8874E9DDBEDC2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other States in such a matter as to 10 ensure geographic and population diversity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE10C0808C77421995F207F65CDA2102"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Alternative criteria</header><text>If no State meeting the criteria specified in paragraph (3) establishes a pilot program in coordination with the Secretary within 36 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary may identify alternative requirements for such States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11321CD416F74EDBA6428FCA2D21B0AE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date on which a State successfully (as determined by the Secretary) establishes a State-based sepsis data trust using funds received through a grant under this subsection, the State shall submit to the Secretary a report. Such report shall include, with respect to the State-based sepsis data trust involved—</text><subparagraph id="H0DD75C7081EB41E182FEC7AFE2131ABF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the process by which the State established the data trust;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9E35366006F40E88FA902CBEC04ED1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the process by which data was collected, de-identified, and standardized across multiple data systems; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B262E7CD75C4509939F2C16D12919EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>implementation barriers experienced and the course of corrective action taken to address these barriers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3603F4B26FD744D58C034374FD8F0991"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lessons learned through the establishment of the data trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36BD8374BA84AED8F6070E858B08C70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10E256B06D86482FBC9CDCE389347482"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National Sepsis Data Trust</header><paragraph id="H3EEDB12A9F9940E89AFDE9F3FD7BF21A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a national sepsis data trust to improve research, outcomes, and innovation in support of the national strategy developed under subsection (b) (including the actions to be taken pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) of such subsection). Such national sepsis data trust shall—</text><subparagraph id="H226C109B41CA4D20B1DC2FA095AC1B12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accelerate innovation that seeks to improve sepsis prevention, diagnosis, treatment, outcomes, and survivor support, including through—</text><clause id="HA5434FED36AE4D1ABDF26BB93C448485"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing the pace of academic research; and</text></clause><clause id="H63FD86C2748943CD98FEAC207AD6441C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>catalyzing more investment in mechanisms that provide promise in the early recognition and expeditious treatment of sepsis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEAE00569480422C8D9DE60EC0395B1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support public health efforts to improve sepsis care, particularly in underserved geographic areas and among at-risk and underserved communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H259FDFBAF8394B4CBB16129B931A8966"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve the targeting of antimicrobial drugs and other substances for the treatment of sepsis, promoting both better care and improved antimicrobial stewardship; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53D9CC079591498B93D0954FFB8CFDC7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate and integrate the development of State-based sepsis data trusts, including by defining data elements to be included in State-based sepsis data trusts, including self-reported data on age, race, ethnicity, primary language, membership in a federally recognized tribe, status as a member of the armed services, status as a veteran, status as pregnant or recently pregnant, and any other data determined to be appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D388DDB8A204C6CAFA188CAEAD8E408"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for appropriate privacy and security of de-identified data in the data trust by—</text><clause id="HC93A329250C24604B69FB941D32B2455"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibiting any entity participating in the data trust from sharing patient data with any entity not participating in the data trust; and</text></clause><clause id="H81560DCDD9D6447EA8016A9EF20507B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that an entity agrees, as a condition on participation in the data trust to not share any patient data with any entity not participating in the data trust; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5B9AB2455074251B011F55CBFDA1BB0"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow access to data de-identified data in the data trust by health care providers and other entities participating in the data trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E4EEF58E144BDC9DF590B1C60488E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State grants</header><subparagraph id="H405D922F95B848718D416189B72C7C38"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to awarding grants under subsection (c), the Secretary may make grants directly to States to support the development and operation of State-based sepsis data trusts (or make grants, or enter into contracts with academic or nonprofit organizations designated by a State to operate the State-based sepsis data trust involved) to combine and connect data collected by the State concerning—</text><clause id="HA8DBE41C985C49F9BDE88B48B94463E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demographic information about each case of sepsis in each such State;</text></clause><clause id="HB681C6C976BD46A9AB907A41F43FB767"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administrative information with respect to each such case, including the date of diagnosis and the source of information;</text></clause><clause id="HEE8FB73C408B41AFB6B117F745663874"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>pathological and genetic data characterizing each such case; </text></clause><clause id="H7A2C2CD2F50348B2BF0CFC0D277B9730"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>clinical information, including relevant diagnoses, treatment, and patient-reported outcomes of the individuals with sepsis and sepsis survivors; and</text></clause><clause id="H248A55EF0BF84EC0A62E1A88A722FAA9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other elements determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D465D298B114DBFACCAE57FFF141A7B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make a grant under paragraph (1) only if the State involved (or the academic or nonprofit private organization designated by a State to operate the State-based sepsis data trust involved) agrees, with respect to the costs of the program to be funded through the grant, to make available (directly or through donations from public or private entities) non-Federal contributions toward such costs in an amount that is not less than 25 percent of such costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9CA78019EB94245B4DA8C37D7586ACD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Data trust guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines developed under subsection (c)(2) shall apply with respect to State-based sepsis data trusts established under this paragraph in the same manner and to the same extent as such guidelines apply with respect to State-based sepsis data trusts established under subsection (c) (including the data sharing limitations specified in paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10E407C62174499BA9CBF91C100DCBDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on government sepsis data activities and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate a report containing the following: </text><subparagraph id="HC255E3AC3F744537804D673E9ACF8F16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An outline of existing Federal efforts to collect and make available data on sepsis and its associated conditions, including existing Federal repositories of sepsis-relevant de-identified patient data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6384E0E6DDAB48ACBBB12A66BC7D7AE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of the use of these sepsis data by third parties, including public health professionals, physicians and nurses, and researchers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ADF0F58E38A46BF83F4479CE2D5E70B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of Federal efforts to improve care related to sepsis and infection in underserved populations and communities that experience disproportionately poor health outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4410511CB016427D98252F08DBD3B318"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HABB640FE0EA84515B43B7C5510BE9EBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>De-identified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>de-identified</quote> means, with respect to data in a data trust established under or pursuant to this section, information that has been de-identified (and remains de-identified) in accordance with the applicable requirements of section 164.514 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B1DB330E25448B68D2A7DBF745DF1A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National sepsis data trust</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>national sepsis data trust</quote> means an interoperable, de-identified, privacy-protected collection system that contains de-identified data from a variety of sources established by individual States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

