<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H784F4F38B0C64C7189D68466F7107F89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7490 IH: Investigating Russian Ambitions in Nuclear Negotiations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7490</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220411">April 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the President to submit to Congress a report on benefits to the Russian Federation as a result of an agreement with Iran relating to the nuclear program of Iran.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE43E0BBE8A2435C9A91EBAEB23C6674" style="OLC"><section id="HEDE6BFD425A64769A6474E1C4E9AB5FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investigating Russian Ambitions in Nuclear Negotiations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IRAN Negotiations Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC5B11DDFA4F6495781AF51DFF5B1BA3A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on benefits to the Russian Federation as a result of an agreement with Iran relating to the nuclear program of Iran</header><subsection id="H08B6F46BCA62471FB981BF473D52D6EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 calendar days after reaching an agreement with Iran relating to the nuclear program of Iran, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report describing the benefits that will accrue to the Russian Federation as a result of such agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93BCAA2FA7A648EE856872C7F4ECA4F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HF68F18930B124D44BCC283679571C1D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the role Russian negotiators played in developing and negotiating the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA499B40B4954A79B7A9A54C18AD2199"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the expected economic benefits likely to accrue to the Russian economy as a result of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F4A01038D894BB683C61783FE6E3157"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the expected economic and technical benefits likely to be experienced by the Russian defense and nuclear energy sector, including known, planned contracts between Russian and Iranian entities, as a result of cooperation made possible by the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA037BE5C7B244EDA8184DE1BE3895A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of new avenues for sanctions evasion made available to Russia as a result of the agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5BC1DB3E10F4CC4AA0E55E7BB915B56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

