<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BC3EB631F63434AB1AD00F04778C950" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6373 IH: Digital Literacy and Equity Commission</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6373</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Digital Literacy and Equity Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68199D2766274A8493F654E1017A3EF7" style="OLC"><section id="HBB2DECC57DC24E71B90D5162C63BBC11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established a commission to be known as the <quote><short-title>Digital Literacy and Equity Commission</short-title></quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></section><section id="HDB494BDC552F4401A8EF4901D18D1190"><enum>2.</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall conduct a study on digital literacy and equity, including—</text><paragraph id="H64BF2A6EB10E4DB6A00FA773C9BAA1D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the state of digital literacy and information literacy in the United States, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5BB78B3CE4934FC593DFBADD6F9CB0E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local programs aimed at increasing digital literacy and information literacy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B568CABDAA5492A9AC247369C83907E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of digital literacy and information literacy in low-income areas and disadvantaged areas; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H565AAFE7D2DA43B8A1A744A82F12672F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs in other countries with the goal of increasing digital literacy and information literacy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792FCED2A1AF40CA81B44A3A5E34F430"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the identification of strategies and best practices to maintain increased levels of digital literacy and information literacy in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5127411926AB407D946FF4BB733B01C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Membership</header><subsection id="H634A59CAA4CF45C98B8DF9D57B3CF654"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of—</text><paragraph id="HC2C0EB442DCF42C39CE6DBC03CBE8A34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information or the delegate of the Assistant Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H847665C430F7429399BF1D1ED55AFE2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chairperson of the Federal Communications Commission or the delegate of the Chairperson of the Federal Communications Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE18E02F532456A85945374C06B18A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Chief of the Wireless Telecommunications Bureau of the Federal Communications Commission or the delegate of the Chief;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA211A2C36735438C97E001EF2510F2DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Services or the delegate of the Director;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E5367A4C374C8ABB65F8E2D74852C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education or the delegate of the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0EB41CB54A45889A6E8DF835D27EED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services or the delegate of the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB89F931C8B0A4D1398F5D689AAB208B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the delegate of the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H211977D61F1E4E46B5D8BC891538DFAA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>3 members appointed by the Chairperson of the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="HC46A9D47B3734EE8899DF2E83C6D4316"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with knowledge or expertise in digital literacy and equity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A693EBF42E440E08F89E188CB818142"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from the public or private sector, including—</text><clause id="HDC362A85B5834357824D6C42725971D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal, State, or local employees;</text></clause><clause id="H75271B5E49ED47A09708AF900CF7F13C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>former Members of Congress; or</text></clause><clause id="H8076B4B8B0824C0BB023564B2B556675"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employees of academic institutions and non-governmental organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA2DDBBD98046E2B3A14DF01DE20FB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who represent diverse economic, professional, and cultural backgrounds; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E8E2007A96479692A025129E656041"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 5 members appointed by the President, from among the heads of Federal agencies, or delegates of the heads of Federal agencies, who the President determines would be beneficial to the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F9992FC531B496FAF40429F2C8AD37D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairperson; vice chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education or the delegate of the Secretary shall serve as the Chairperson of the Commission, and the Chairperson of the Federal Communications Commission or the delegate of the Chairperson of the Federal Communications Commission shall serve as the Vice Chairperson of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F3412C82FFF45269A42311163930F87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HC66CD1065EC8425EB57E7A4FD111E745"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chairperson of the Commission shall hold a meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6CABB95BA57498FB2E57F0400B6412A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall meet not less than once every 4 months at a time and place determined by the Chairperson of the Commission, and may hold such other meetings as the Chairperson of the Commission determines are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8748F68382A4BDD9B7AF140E43FAECD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>All meetings of the Commission shall be open to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCD71A4EC66247E58C520D64586A26F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4F8853E7D3A940AFAD2E5B649D09B6F3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subsection id="HF5DE5B25B02F410D8851116C3EA1C00B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H82D2ADA01A4D440F85A6A6F952264EF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of members and agents</header><text>Any member or agent of the Commission may, if authorized by the Commission, take any action that the Commission is authorized to take by this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="H368FC898227A4F8AA9BA9ED042DBD975"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 2 years after the appointment of the members of the Commission, the Chairperson of the Commission shall submit to the Congress a report that contains—</text><paragraph id="H3182EB2A838148BA8F57CE8CC4E86732"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study required by section 2;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB7982E9EB34CE8BD01892BDB9007B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on how to improve and maintain the digital literacy and information literacy of individuals in the United States and education in the United States relating to digital literacy and information literacy through early education and community outreach, with a particular focus on increasing equity in the availability of digital literacy and information literacy resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C87BE31FE942A9B984D8B8FA3DEADB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for the Federal Government to create and implement a method to measure digital literacy in the United States, in order to aid future efforts to address digital literacy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08DFA29CE228450AAD551E536EBDB04F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to increase inter-agency coordination to improve digital literacy services provided by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9D7B3702D25F423C81D88F5142B7CFB1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H35E8EE649E05449EBE5ED81867FD33B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital literacy</header><text>The term <quote>digital literacy</quote> means the ability to use information and communication technologies to find, evaluate, create, and communicate information, requiring both cognitive and technical skills.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H980612DBC049413E92CA9AF46A375043"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information literacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>information literacy</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1BFFA196B6E14DA2B35DD37CA4576496"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability to recognize when information is needed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCDF4A3DE88B4674B653D56F8122F88D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability to locate, evaluate, and use needed information effectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3963EDEAFA5049CEB7963919474EBB63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-income</header><text>The term <quote>low-income</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1303 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4502">12 U.S.C. 4502</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76E30EBE4C694937BE388B4A55A121E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disadvantaged area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>disadvantaged area</quote> means a community with an annual median household income that is less than 80 percent of the statewide annual median household income, determined on the basis of the latest available decennial census of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

