<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H121E59B92342407CA3CF1714E7E99B46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8299 IH: To allow for devices with a predetermined change control plan to be marketed without submitting a supplemental application or premarket notification if the changes to such devices are consistent with such plan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8299</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow for devices with a predetermined change control plan to be marketed without submitting a supplemental application or premarket notification if the changes to such devices are consistent with such plan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5B291B40FA24DF5BE7D46B0B9AC8F8F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7B4B1583F29C4E1E8417C25BFB3C4C52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Predetermined change control plans for devices</header>
<subsection id="HDCC52311F1FF428F9951616423C416E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 515B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e-3">21 U.S.C. 360e–3</external-xref>) the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55602C1F954E49C985FA267CF274AA6F"> <section id="H2F710EBFCDB14BE0BF02A95568A3780A"><enum>515C.</enum><header>Predetermined change control plans for devices</header> <subsection id="HAFC02FA6FDE44F1EBDEDFAB20686A380"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Approved devices</header> <paragraph id="H151C03FE92624EEF912D9B3F4E3A516C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 515(d)(5)(A), a supplemental application shall not be required for a change to a device approved under section 515, if such change is consistent with a predetermined change control plan that is approved pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBE0C376BACE74277BB9B8963427AE0C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Predetermined change control plan</header><text>The Secretary may approve a predetermined change control plan submitted in an application, including a supplemental application, under section 515 that describes planned changes that may be made to the device (and that would otherwise require a supplemental application under section 515), if the device remains safe and effective without any change.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD58DF7C464A45A39E94CEBEF3DFFA19"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary may require that a change control plan include labeling required for safe and effective use of the device as such device changes pursuant to such plan, notification requirements if the device does not function as intended pursuant to such plan, and performance requirements for changes made under the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H31AAAC0B478B47B990B9AC2B599B7242"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cleared devices</header>
<paragraph id="H37EF651BDD6C4F9982D2FC48D3CF1C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 510(k), a premarket notification shall not be required for a change to a device cleared under section 510(k), if such change is consistent with an established predetermined change control plan granted pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H772364AC9D5042A0AE0857B3C7BE09A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Predetermined change control plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may clear a predetermined change control plan submitted in a notification submitted under section 510(k) that describes planned changes that may be made to the device (and that would otherwise require a new notification), if—</text>
<subparagraph id="H68940C4AB05D4C6FB8698B6428012B7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the device remains safe and effective without any such change; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE00912A3256E405EA447E42D79B4E59A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the device would remain substantially equivalent to the predicate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47424E6559E0467B8ECFA7B7EC65A17E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary may require that a change control plan include labeling required for safe and effective use of the device as such device changes pursuant to such plan, notification requirements if the device does not function as intended pursuant to such plan, and performance requirements for changes made under the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8D93E2FE24ED4DDEA0A5EAA6675468A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Predicate devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination of substantial equivalence pursuant to section 513(i), the Secretary shall not compare a device to changed versions of a device implemented in accordance with an established predetermined change control plan as a predicate device. Only the version of the device cleared or approved, prior to changes made under the predetermined change control plan, may be used by a sponsor as a predicate device.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H206E7D9C21AE49E48493C99EC8D579C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
<paragraph id="H19233C78FF1449F4BC3E358CFF56C20C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cleared devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 510(l)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(l)(1)</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, or with respect to a change that is consistent with a predetermined change control plan cleared under section 515C</quote> before the period at the end.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD39AAA73D8B44CAC98BF032245498B43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 515(d)(5)(A)(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e">21 U.S.C. 360e(d)(5)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>A supplemental</quote> and inserting <quote>Unless the change is consistent with a predetermined change control plan approved under section 515C, a supplemental</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48F378C0BFCD4D5889F4E1EB639334EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Documentation of rationale for significant decisions</header><text>Section 517A(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360g-1">21 U.S.C. 360g–1(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8246E86BDBA4BCB829CBA6FA5599AC9"> <paragraph id="H4FFE97EABCD043C7949454E94E8EFE87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide a substantive summary of the scientific and regulatory rationale for any significant decision of the Center for Devices and Radiological Health regarding submission or review of a report under section 510(k), a petition for classification under section 513(f), an application under section 515, or an application for an exemption under section 520(g), including documentation of significant controversies or differences of opinion and the resolution of such controversies or differences of opinion.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

