<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0B1B20B09090420DA8008520EBE3ACF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>107 HR 7629 IH: Satellite Cybersecurity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7629</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on Federal support to the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, establish a commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD127B4EC6A5940A2B354E1860C9D2EC1" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7BD0178469304D509FBBEBEBF2BE3AC5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Satellite Cybersecurity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6499926F6FD24CD599353746619EDF87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on commercial satellite cybersecurity; CISA commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse</header><subsection id="H6B3927DA1C514691A9B352E8344EFF41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="H5C2DF1A821CD4E51AB569E244AD0B9B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the actions the Federal Government has taken to support the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, including as part of any action to address the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure sectors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD825B19B93894C25B9FF1DDB9EC50B59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to Congress on the study conducted under paragraph (1), which shall include information on—</text><subparagraph id="H35643ACC08354949A32B4FADED3D85F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of efforts of the Federal Government in improving the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC13E96CC4956437B9351BCCEC4B6B71C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the resources made available to the public, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, by Federal agencies to address cybersecurity risks and cybersecurity threats to commercial satellite systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC89B96C9E24D19844B3E959075918F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which commercial satellite systems are reliant on or are relied on by critical infrastructure and an analysis of how commercial satellite systems, and the cybersecurity threats to such systems, are integrated into Federal and non-Federal critical infrastructure risk analyses and protection plans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B0856998413473991F229FB1651AE9F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which Federal agencies are reliant on commercial satellite systems and how Federal agencies mitigate cybersecurity risks associated with those systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD76D9ED7D8A34A75A8F8DBDB2C4FA9E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which Federal agencies coordinate or duplicate authorities and take other actions focused on the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6562BEDA2045CEBB8B3C84D8DA20AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2), the Comptroller General of the United States shall coordinate with appropriate Federal agencies, including—</text><subparagraph id="H54AEA819368344B8931E6FF325EE5AD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF14CFCC0E7D046B9A18DE7ED846590F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA5F02F5C9743D8920CE02A42A9F4B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A9A7D8925F44BB98B784106CDDC0E76"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84BFF84A087C4C1282062AE30502102A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63B5622A86B94D1ABDDA9F46E251CE8E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC504977A25944CA5863D6ED6D2BAFA53"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the National Executive Committee for Space-Based Positioning, Navigation, and Timing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H049D69A6F3C946268B9E1CCC1A7DD633" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide a briefing to Congress relating to carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D760BB684F34EF2945425CB7CA7069B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Classification</header><text>The report under paragraph (2) shall be unclassified but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA77ADCF31BB54D3A977182E22DD11C73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CISA commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse</header><paragraph id="H9EA48591F2464988BE371ABC5CE3A5B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph id="HEE9C8F277CD74F2895EB0B3636D07DE2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DDE1ABC855A4982B41AF839006B4A59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The clearinghouse shall—</text><clause id="HF5A340F1726F444EA79D21F6CCDDB81D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be publicly available online;</text></clause><clause id="H947431005B6C4D0AA6410FCCD3478A7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contain current, relevant, and publicly available commercial satellite system cybersecurity resources, including the recommendations consolidated under paragraph (2), and any other appropriate materials for reference by entities that develop commercial satellite systems; and</text></clause><clause id="HF0BC131A050C48B49A6F00BE19065B58"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include materials specifically aimed at assisting small business concerns with the secure development, operation, and maintenance of commercial satellite systems.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763AEC060CD944FAA552DC7C4E8C4B8E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Existing platform or website</header><text>The Director may establish the clearinghouse on an online platform or a website that is in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE04D3FC056DF4463A3E507F1F9A95FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidation of commercial satellite system cybersecurity recommendations</header><subparagraph id="H58F4CF630D644D4DA1A627794E6002BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall consolidate voluntary cybersecurity recommendations designed to assist in the development, maintenance, and operation of commercial satellite systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B916A8C7C36413EA7B2EC1C9BF4F4CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The recommendations consolidated under subparagraph (A) shall include, to the greatest extent practicable, materials addressing the following:</text><clause id="H5FD7EDC88CA740C490DA2885ADA785A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Risk-based, cybersecurity-informed engineering, including continuous monitoring and resiliency.</text></clause><clause id="HD63AD26BE9FF4648B3BA467005F4AFDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Planning for retention or recovery of positive control of commercial satellite systems in the event of a cybersecurity incident.</text></clause><clause id="H550BA8DEA79943C3916F3959FB3472C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Protection against unauthorized access to vital commercial satellite system functions.</text></clause><clause id="H13219FDA815B4A178DDE973C3F0EC4F9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Physical protection measures designed to reduce the vulnerabilities of a commercial satellite system’s command, control, or telemetry receiver systems.</text></clause><clause id="HA2C4B5D3DABD4273A902C6F6AAF60A23" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Protection against jamming or spoofing.</text></clause><clause id="H5E24D494D7324A9BA72BCB396DDCA0A8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Security against threats throughout a commercial satellite system’s mission lifetime.</text></clause><clause id="H2CE8B294BF0E4B06A38BB1FD15488F81"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Management of supply chain risks that affect the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems.</text></clause><clause id="H12548E3B79E145BC837D2DAD92C8DDDC" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As appropriate, and as applicable pursuant to the requirement under paragraph (1)(b)(ii) (relating to the clearinghouse containing current, relevant, and publicly available commercial satellite system cybersecurity resources), the findings and recommendations from the study conducted by the Comptroller General of the United States under subsection (a)(1).</text></clause><clause id="H0AE10350650B4BE3B387C9A8637124C7"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other recommendations to ensure the confidentiality, availability, and integrity of data residing on or in transit through commercial satellite systems.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H581428F1235E4406BF9400BC8751D4B8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In implementing this subsection, the Director shall—</text><subparagraph id="H24DA8DF8BF0E4A5C83104D4B77B81C74" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, carry out such implementation as a public-private partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD69FBDF083634367BD66801133C4E9B8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies with expertise and experience in satellite operations, including the entities described in subsection (a)(3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H805CFAC755944AD3A27D644A5DB21931" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consult with non-Federal entities developing commercial satellite systems or otherwise supporting the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, including private, consensus organizations that develop relevant standards. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5D47F4277954473BC754E3055C6EE12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE6B4DAD94C4642F5BBFFC7F4EB782E40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text>The term <term>clearinghouse</term> means the commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse required to be developed and maintained under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4847B2493384BDCBF995855F2918D61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commercial satellite system</header><text>The term <term>commercial satellite system</term> means an earth satellite owned and operated by a non-Federal entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FE1E9B9E07F41DD9074FB8A82B1FA1A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1016(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/56">Public Law 107–56</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H964D661C0F1F47248E705C887E974F22" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cybersecurity risk</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity risk</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2209 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/659">6 U.S.C. 659</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAD73B00C76742758DA0FBD64A170795"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cybersecurity threat</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity threat</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C13C5D691F4118B3857C9C2BCA4007"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1D39BA55901419886A3BDF3C78F8F40"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

