<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD19215F94E594078AE0A33517A5747C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4046 RH: NTIA Policy and Cybersecurity Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 487</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4046</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–668]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210622">June 22, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger </cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="D000630"> Mr. Delgado</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 22, 2021</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to establish the Office of Policy Development and Cybersecurity, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HIF00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H73B4FFE490214DE6807042A3D11DE5CD"><section id="H1D76F2ACEB8D44FB8F18672496C6239A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NTIA Policy and Cybersecurity Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1B0B77D185BD4BD79DCC00BFBEDA6D83"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy development and cybersecurity</header><subsection id="HE2C54A5D7192483ABF4F8E3A4C2E532B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of policy development and cybersecurity</header><text>Part A of title I of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/901">47 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6BE1B10DAC3B44F9BD684B408EAD5540" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="H27D71E77DC8B4EA08E8B12A4BF2271C3"><enum>106.</enum><header>Office of Policy Development and Cybersecurity</header><subsection id="H52AF0D8801ED4FDF96614CFF4DB573CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be within the NTIA an office to be known as the Office of Policy Development and Cybersecurity (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9A6B17D37514171A52E71DA5DAFAC0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Associate Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Office shall be an Associate Administrator for Policy Development and Cybersecurity (in this section referred to as the <quote>Associate Administrator</quote>), who shall report to the Assistant Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D9B0BD002CC46D99F175603A9BBAED9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="HF4AC61988B794D788232F8A607C67AE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall oversee and conduct national communications and information policy analysis and development for the internet and communications technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B051AC5688E4B6FAD6BD5279054DCFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Particular duties</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Office shall—</text><subparagraph id="H29CCD0CAF61049EA80C40B753E8B0C56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop, analyze, and advocate for market-based policies that promote innovation, competition, consumer access, digital inclusion, workforce development, and economic growth in the communications, media, and technology markets;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6150CEEEE3624E95A003E698B8C09B06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue studies, as delegated by the Assistant Secretary or required by Congress, on how individuals in the United States access and use the internet, wireline and wireless telephony, mass media, other digital services, and video services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCDC67534E5B4B7AA65E8092F0258EB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinate transparent, consensus-based, multistakeholder processes to create guidance or to support the development and implementation of cybersecurity and privacy policies with respect to the internet and other communications networks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91BC8452A02D4E539FF809C9C4B384A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote increased collaboration between security researchers and providers of communications services and software system developers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C5E63AD777B4FCFA32FF3E78FB658C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>perform such duties as the Assistant Secretary considers appropriate relating to the program for preventing future vulnerabilities established under section 8(a) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1607">47 U.S.C. 1607(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C0373C477694B61A7F9F42FAA149045"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advocate for policies that promote the security and resilience to cybersecurity incidents of communications networks while fostering innovation, including policies that promote secure communications network supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA647D79BA3E645B0855C405348A3D078"><enum>(G)</enum><text>at the direction of the Assistant Secretary, present security of the digital economy and infrastructure and cybersecurity policy efforts before the Commission, Congress, and elsewhere;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833451C0FD7A4C769BC0D41884B3DFF0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>provide advice and assistance to the Assistant Secretary in carrying out the policy responsibilities of the NTIA with respect to cybersecurity policy matters, including the evaluation of the impact of cybersecurity matters pending before the Commission, other Federal agencies, and Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H369729E48D7446DF936B1271D2C1692B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in addition to the duties described in subparagraph (H), perform such other duties regarding the policy responsibilities of the NTIA with respect to cybersecurity policy matters as the Assistant Secretary considers appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7475961413FA4BD295C0AFD1D3E31ECD"><enum>(J)</enum><text>develop policies to accelerate innovation and commercialization with respect to advances in technological understanding of communications technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C84729609B84626BA173A3A8A26C34C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>identify barriers to trust, security, innovation, and commercialization with respect to communications technologies, including access to capital and other resources, and ways to overcome such barriers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H975611B390C74C8FBEA99855814276C8"><enum>(L)</enum><text>provide public access to relevant data, research, and technical assistance on innovation and commercialization with respect to communications technologies, consistent with the protection of classified information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11C5104E39CC4B80B86AF4CD5A96296A"><enum>(M)</enum><text>strengthen collaboration on and coordination of policies relating to innovation and commercialization with respect to communications technologies, including policies focused on the needs of small businesses and rural communities—</text><clause id="H73D1377151D541D9AAE0284766191B91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within the Department of Commerce; </text></clause><clause id="HD80DA5775D6E43D59F7E6E17D4FB90C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>between the Department of Commerce and State government agencies, as appropriate; and</text></clause><clause id="HB9486E61DB584738A7E1A5C1B9A9AA4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between the Department of Commerce and the Commission or any other Federal agency the Assistant Secretary determines to be necessary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E05C7467004BFBBFD2244DA73D12BA"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit and consider feedback from small and rural communications service providers, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE42A83080B844AE9B3EF6B6997B777E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transitional rules</header><paragraph id="HCE8358D7D40D4DF188267BCEAA40FE14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Redesignation of associate administrator; continuation of service</header><subparagraph id="HEE06C330F9AF4E6EB8DFFCE204B2724D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>The position of Associate Administrator for Policy Analysis and Development at the NTIA is hereby redesignated as the position of Associate Administrator for Policy Development and Cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB355B66A610548DEA08F01255B433411"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuation of service</header><text>The individual serving as Associate Administrator for Policy Analysis and Development at the NTIA on the date of the enactment of this Act shall become, as of such date, the Associate Administrator for Policy Development and Cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF576A804A0E149F7BDDC4703485B6332"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NTIA defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>NTIA</term> means the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

