<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB854DBD35167413E893F4C973340C032" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7516 IH: Get the Lead Out of Assisted Housing Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7516</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the removal of lead from drinking water in public housing.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H597260FCFB8D40DA850D981FF6B704B5" style="OLC"><section id="HDA0D87A3D8BE416F965570014B9CB41E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Get the Lead Out of Assisted Housing Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H46A898F4C0BB42DE96974F285F2923FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72A6EB2D5D2B4120B8216DE3F3D81AE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C949F046F8B42588E9D97BF95DB58B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7D979B810248FDA3ED2AC6EC877E1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lead service line</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lead service line</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1459B(a) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (42 U.S.C. 300j–19b(a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E47BD59C294822B4A79438BB62FA47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the program for providing grants established under section 6(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CACC137CF8F4349ACF14DC486C893AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H71276679EDF24DEC8DCA098132BFF091"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H342E3C5F83814634A885BDF8A5CAA2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lead is a dangerous neurotoxin that can permanently impact brain development, especially in young children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A332CFB80FB43AC8EFB38BDE0109BD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control, the Environmental Protection Agency, the American Association of Pediatrics, and many other entities have determined that there is no safe level of lead exposure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF67A2A612446778D488E59175C7023"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for vulnerable populations like young children, pregnant mothers, and the elderly, exposure to lead can be life altering;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FE7172A32A84744BEF35B56DF3183A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evidence is mounting that the lead in drinking water problem in the United States is grossly underestimated and inadequately addressed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A02BB5920BF4D57A0365E6B91E48CBF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>according to the Environmental Protection Agency, lead service lines are the single largest source of lead in drinking water; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3946F9F8F45D45B6AD8334114F287C70"><enum>(6)</enum><text>partial lead service line replacement, where only a portion of a lead service line is replaced, can increase lead exposure.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3FCE88128BC048C5B20730BF45B11CB4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Uniform physical condition standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall amend the physical condition standards set forth in section 5.703 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, to require that—</text><paragraph id="HE4A973A7E8774A3EB0ED061325400D68"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entities responsible for maintaining housing inspect building systems to determine, using tests that incorporate the best available technology and science, if—</text><subparagraph id="H81B632355E364F8397234702FBEAAD90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there are lead service lines; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9794DEA541974C5CA364930439785A46"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is lead in the interior plumbing; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD17FF1DE7024211BA2FEEE50FF30DFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a lead service line is found or lead is found in a service line that connects to the interior plumbing of the housing at the water meter, the entity responsible for maintaining the housing shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3A63C86F82A048EEAFB1DC53C4C58AD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 day after the date on which the lead is found, notify each tenant of the housing that the lead was found and of precautions that should be taken to reduce exposure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDC614999FCA4A778DB1292163D50DC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclose that information within 30 days to any drinking water provider relevant to the housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H289DA56EA1754482AB5411783888E19D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide necessary interim measures to reduce exposure to the lead, such as water filters designed to remove lead and other innovative technologies, based on guidance from the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5060980D71384A8B81FCF8C49FAC8A9D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prohibit the partial replacement of lead service lines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HF6C09F663FB44B06A773DFA5E410D3A6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to inspect all sources of lead</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may inspect all sources of lead contamination in housing assisted by a program of the Department and work in coordination with the Environmental Protection Agency to mitigate sources of lead exposure, including as a result of water from the public water supply, and ambient air levels, or industrial emissions.</text></section><section id="H8F11481A54F34D8587B6D1DCA7A5C629"><enum>6.</enum><header>Healthy homes lead in drinking water pilot program</header><subsection id="H0532963D905C409284016B7F857B73AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="HE1D3D716B8A54FA18FED61127EB23757"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall begin providing grants to State and local governments responsible for developing consolidated plans under part 91 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H854BF258031040B29EE8F4147F2AA672"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Secretary shall design the grants under the pilot program to—</text><subparagraph id="H718CEADABB1B4D049D9A5FF80024F386"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify lead service lines and other sources of lead in drinking water serving housing units and take steps to remediate those threats; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52B91B0C93C244589F37A6A9E0216BA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>optimize corrosion control treatment in public water systems serving housing units.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8146A65ECAC143E8838E690AEEAF24F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>A State or local government receiving a grant under the pilot program shall prioritize the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H9E2892E688C0407487DC5ABD7D35E848"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Creating an inventory of lead service lines, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA19393D67C9F4805B67D15746FD97B0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be published on the website of the State or local government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H252866F8F9BF4A4BB4C10A8B9FDC0806"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involve—</text><clause id="H8FB139E71BB24E52B80A5C3900456CC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working with public water systems (as such term is defined in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref>)) that may have a similar inventory;</text></clause><clause id="HE45DD425D67C4D01A974869505B443BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>inspecting for lead service lines at their entry point into a building using methods that do not disturb the pipe;</text></clause><clause id="H5BD9A489573D42C68BC0158E9323B58A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conducting an inspection of visible pipes at all access points; and</text></clause><clause id="H647943CC5D304BB6888C25C2944BD629"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>prioritizing buildings based on the age of the building, historical records, and the size of the service line.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44705C95270D4CE6BC4829DC1E366C25"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Testing for lead in the drinking water at child care facilities and schools, providing interim measures to reduce exposure to the lead, and providing remediation, when appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60B2075CDF3E48A0BB69F0B1552BB520"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Testing for lead in the drinking water at water fountains in public facilities, providing interim measures to reduce exposure to the lead, and providing remediation, when appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9760EBEB9B0E4CB08815EB6DB1FAE636"><enum>7.</enum><header>Healthy homes and lead hazard control office</header><subsection id="HA7A1B73E636E48C6BDD65F8FB01901D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes of the Department shall, when providing grants for lead-based paint hazard reduction in target housing under section 1011 of the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4852">42 U.S.C. 4852</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph id="H6E23002E36A247A8BE1A9D198ADC0D32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that testing for lead in drinking water is conducted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H019F499F7F64453583B744E63B499A4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require notification of tenants of the level of lead in drinking water found; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H332266C11ACD46AAB78B543151E84883"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offer interim controls, such as the installation of water filters known to remove lead.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC65AF6DBEBF04E05A0E8F32101D6A071"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds for replacement</header><text>The Secretary shall allow recipients of assistance from the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes of the Department or another program of the Department to use the funds to replace leaded water fixtures and lead service lines.</text></subsection></section><section id="H77AF58E7873E476D9AC9917D8CD25FE3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

