<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FBCBE129F544F68BD2C083BFA9D9590" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6729 IH: STOP China’s Abuse of International Financing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on the People’s Republic of China’s use of international financial institutions, to set United States policy regarding the identification of the People’s Republic of China as a <quote>developing nation</quote> and address this matter in regional multilateral financial institutions, to prohibit the use of Federal funds to purchase certain goods from the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H314F12645B7F4B39840B7C645618BC36" style="OLC"><section id="H8806E7E43E194CD7AFF34372A5BE39C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Transparent Operations to Prevent China’s Abuse of International Financing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>STOP China’s Abuse of International Financing Act</quote>.</text></section><section id="HDD469937BCA14A8898245AFFC78A397E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on the People’s Republic of China’s use of and influence in international financial institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a written report on the ways that the People’s Republic of China has used its role in international financial institutions to influence the policies of the institutions and advance its diplomatic objectives during the period that begins with calendar year 2000 and ends with the present, including—</text><paragraph id="H54170AC13A4E41F49B488B4C246EA5C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of the percentage of funds donated to each international financial institution during that period, that is represented by donations from the People’s Republic of China, and how each such percentage has changed during that period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF53A8F51138447FB5E33D1B27287A5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of the percentage of capital loaned to the People’s Republic of China during that period that is represented by loans from each international financial institution, and how each such percentage has changed during that period, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDFA518FF1D4445AFA93E779E37BC7D41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the People’s Republic of China used financing from any institution in the World Bank Group for projects which the People’s Republic of China did not finance internally; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47C237DC95040798FF16FFE1BE3250B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how United States technical assistance has been used by each institution of the World Bank Group in evaluating loans to the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45694D8112F84023B77FAFBD71815E66"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of the percentage of the staff of each international financial institution who identify as Chinese nationals, and how each such percentage has changed during that period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE96991301843424EA6FEC83CC79D5F35"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of the involvement of enterprises controlled by, or whose headquarters are in, the People’s Republic of China in bidding on contracts offered by any international financial institution during that period, and the percentage of the contracts that were awarded to any such enterprise, including—</text><subparagraph id="HAE1FF8D0B1784934B5746F5A9D5423D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the People’s Republic of China subsidizes the enterprises in order to drive down bid prices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD48767EA98C74A19824CAA1032D390C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the criteria necessary for a transparent bidding process for contracts offered by any such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA75CEEE0393A47099E0D5B381B8E10B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><subsection id="H693386F2284643FFBF61AE84C502C8E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that international financial institutions, related trade groups, and multilateral organizations should not consider the People’s Republic of China to be a developing nation for any purpose.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD8968B04716C4B6781DB10AAB7613BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures of world organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States representatives to the United Nations, the World Trade Organization, and the international financial institutions shall pursue changes in the procedures of their respective institutions to ensure that their respective institutions do not consider the People’s Republic of China to be a developing nation for any purpose.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9BE5FBACB7B144B297364834E0C50624"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report from United States Trade Representative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to Congress a report that describes the manner in which the Trade Representative plans to pursue a strategy with respect to the World Trade Organization (WTO) to carry out and achieve the following:</text><paragraph id="HB6320CE5378F4350B3E720E7716F35F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Facilitate the full implementation of currently negotiated and possible future agreements of the WTO.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B2C7F29A6C446CFAE75BF8220BB18E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enable the maximum benefits from trade to accrue to members of the WTO that face the greatest difficulty integrating into multilateral and regional trade institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H055318991D1847798734C315B4EAD40C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ensure that none of the following members of the WTO receives <quote>special and differential</quote> treatment in currently negotiated or possible future agreements of the WTO:</text><subparagraph id="H34BBDD5B56484101B683BBC3C29B1E5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Members that are also members of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) or begun the accession process to OECD.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H926DE59F039D4C8CA73E33368453CC9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Members that are also members of the G20.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC087123E7C34274AB441B456DE1BED1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Members that are classified as <quote>high income</quote> countries by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H31DB3A9BC435419A8942F0EF7F13E648"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds provided to international financial institutions for goods from China</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall direct the United States representatives to the United Nations, the World Trade Organization, and the international financial institutions to use the voice and vote of the United States to prevent the institutions from using any contribution made on behalf of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="H14C742AC517345D5987081DB216D69B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure goods from, or sourced in, the People’s Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B67EAC4638744AA97E44DB0D93662ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fulfill any contract awarded by the Bank to any enterprise controlled by, or whose headquarters is in, the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H174CD54E51064084ADB2BD4A9CC5A7A8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definition of international financial institution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>international financial institution</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HF26241CAAB074BA5A54FE0E5ED292543"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each institution of the World Bank Group;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64EEEA8C346A4126A826117C09B9CD17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the African Development Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D570FCBF8B844829B6D050A6B56DF70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Asian Development Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4F8C3989F3C4B85ABADB250F3C64CD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Caribbean Development Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2C3192A8504EA2BDA5ED615A55901E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0C1074EB902451B934DFA1075B77D47"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Inter-American Development Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A9742A9B8F042BAACB274D0C997ACFD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Arab Fund for Economic and Social Development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8305E9446E0E44218F87C44B23060911"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the European Investment Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB331E41E48964D6498CFBEAA3C1A2619"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Global Environment Facility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFFCFCAD38FE4F729CB73E57DE07A973"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Islamic Development Bank;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99EBB5EAF57141E6A411BAA56343D521"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the North American Development Bank; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AE8B3588EA245F988A07D218718D17A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Organization of American States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

