<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H685BF6663F264FEC86EB1E85542FCE40" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6639 IH: Protect Children Through Safe Gun Ownership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6639</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220208">February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to require adequate supervision before a juvenile can possess a firearm, to require the safe storage of firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2B91CA492D64DB2893DD082309A407D" style="OLC"><section id="H221F512837484305AFBB6FB8D85F10CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Children Through Safe Gun Ownership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F3A6391661C4900A4AD50B4B8B30F78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on written consent to permit a juvenile to possess a handgun</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922(x) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2E634CDE4FC84C6E835A8896D39A74EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3E7B7EB4381D4D2681107648B4946E03" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any parent or guardian to provide written consent under paragraph (3) unless the parent or guardian has actual knowledge that the possession or use of the handgun by the juvenile will be in the presence and under the active supervision of the transferor or another adult who is not prohibited by Federal, State, or local law from possessing a firearm.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6D9E58D7C3DC47F38EC396C1D770BC32"><enum>3.</enum><header>Secure gun storage or safety device</header><subsection id="H2E39EE126E584717A94E27D6C67FD158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 922(z) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1AA7C7D7696C46AEA813F0B9160C4F2B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H5500C685856F49CE8795626B256AE9A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secure gun storage by owners</header><subparagraph id="H2D60B35E59F14911BE3520AC335EDBAD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Offense</header><clause id="H20647A7F160E4386809638B38FBD7A58"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person to keep, leave, or store any unsecured firearm that has moved in, or that has otherwise affected, interstate or foreign commerce, unless the person carries the firearm on his or her person or within such close proximity thereto that the person can readily retrieve and use the firearm as if the person carried the firearm on his or her person.</text></clause><clause id="HC4B501FEA0924F269DEEE9BF872315D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Unsecured firearm</header><text>In clause (i), the term <term>unsecured firearm</term> means a firearm that is not secured by a secure gun storage or safety device.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD26399E6EF7248C9B9159EE0DF6A0083"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><clause id="H95817543F12248049A7EA7D21EA7E6C5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual who is injured as a result of a violation of subparagraph (A) (or, in the case of an individual who has died as a result of such a violation, a member of the family of, or the estate of, the individual) may bring a civil action against the violator or any other person who, when the violation occurred, was in control of any premises on which the violation occurred if the violator or the person in control of the premises knew or should have known that there was an unsecured firearm on the premises, in a court of competent jurisdiction, for compensatory and punitive damages, injunctive and declaratory relief, and such other relief as the court deems appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="H672A6857C8304F5D8BCBC18082D91847"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text>In an action described in clause (i), the liability of all defendants shall be joint and several.</text></clause><clause id="H654BAEC307904C41B3E5396100BDE3A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Rule of interpretation</header><text>For purposes of any determination of liability covered by any contract of insurance entered into after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, a violation of subparagraph (A) shall not solely be considered an intentional action.</text></clause><clause id="HF1E5F986A66C4CA3A4A866DFCDAB0F12"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No effect on State law</header><text>This subparagraph shall not be interpreted to preempt, supplant, or displace any claim brought under State statutory law or common law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5465181A7B8444A087C6997DCEB8EEF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 924 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0C3A61CD6D804ED28C1E49630367947E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HFCC3DC6766694918A6701C519FD720EA"><enum>(q)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a violation of section 922(z), the Attorney General shall, after notice and opportunity for a hearing—</text><paragraph id="H6EA76865360844AE91CCDDFF36C1C339"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H94B80B25E1E34503B80A0AB8329DE41D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a 1st violation, subject the person to a civil money penalty of not more than $1,000; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F369EA7A0C84C10A2BF0CA07F90BB10" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a 2nd or subsequent violation, subject the person to a civil money penalty of not more than $5,000; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB97FEB0F6684A0E820C90C313D8D1A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any violation, notify the person of the prohibitions set forth in section 922(d)(10).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA333BEA1E99A4526A186461BF7532949"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 922(d) of such title is amended in the 1st sentence—</text><paragraph id="H91AAEB799B5F49538F453B10E651BCF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51926FA9EE764355AD2CE76E57FE26F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H533D9A0CC3DE40538BCAB37BC0FC6016"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA94FC9ECA50B4C93838658FA05039E39" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H85C1CD201B504A5180D6B210CA1B3474"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been assessed a civil money penalty for a violation of subsection (z)(4) within the preceding 5 years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A259A28B47B4AE199FA017CFBC02EDF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall promulgate such rules as are necessary to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="HCA2011869FE94D698D063D1C5FDE31D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act denies the transfer of a firearm to a person who has been assessed a civil money penalty for a violation of section 922(z)(4) of title 18, United States Code, in the 5-year period ending with the date of the proposed transfer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35D1058055854A05925ED82AA1AC308E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each person licensed under chapter 44 of such title provides notice of the penalties for violating such section 922(z)(4) to any person not licensed under such chapter who seeks to acquire a firearm from the licensee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEFC624E7DD454117AA457E5368B26FA6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program for safe storage education</header><subsection id="H31DE0033C6384724999FDAD540309384"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary of Education shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible local educational agencies to provide parents with educational materials on gun safety and the importance and necessity of secure gun storage.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF47AB93038C416C998A96C294E1F716"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible local educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA7A4D13E1ED048E7861317F5E1597576"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized uses of funds</header><text>In addition to using a grant received under this section for the purposes described in subsection (a), an eligible local educational agency may use such grant to—</text><paragraph id="HAF82E2F8E42247A0A7CB738DDD80C9C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide educational materials on gun safety for parents, including best practices on how to keep guns secure from children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B9ED1B60E044AB89FF46E29B44E92D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct information sessions on gun safety that are publicly accessible; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35D4BC70A09B4408A320175FAB7BE79F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hire or assign an individual to monitor the activities carried out under the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0F62085E5494629B56E5C2BBC71246B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days before the first grant is awarded under this section, the Secretary shall issue guidance on best practices on—</text><paragraph id="H8063DEEBAEC44EFAAEAB13FB481DD6AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>keeping children secure from guns; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB55D213760B42639660193CCF98B694"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provision, by local educational agencies, of age-appropriate education on gun safety for parents.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA99C934438A7422A8D63E1991708DB00"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1AA76DF0A4ED42C48690D18035646C14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that is located in a State with a secure gun storage law similar to paragraph (4) of section 922(z) of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA673FE54ABA43419AA636DAA0424949"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>parent</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73D3B654FEC042538319C6BC246AFBC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H957D14EFFFD24EF3A2E3900EB5C466F1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a written report to the Congress on the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including a disaggregation of the application of the amendments to individuals by sex, race, age, ethnicity, national origin, and English language proficiency.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

