<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H156BC0B1ACA44D939F32A5A6063B62CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>96 HR 8495 IH: Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8495</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to transition the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA018E1828DF04C9C803DC9E8C555DC4E" style="OLC"><section id="H0E7F2A37D4814E9DA640C5A4C619FA2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2B1D410B76664BD5A5C3E1F8CA03E805"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008</header><subsection id="H1CA18F9821684AF4BC86F2F1A5A205E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H00E52A7089FF4DF7AA451E3BBFB7793E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (r) by inserting <quote>Puerto Rico,</quote> after <quote>Guam,</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42FA818B7D334924AA5E89CE8F95E9C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (u)(2) by inserting <quote>, Puerto Rico,</quote> after <quote>Hawaii</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17F20B6890A346CEBF1794C321A5CF80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible households</header><text>Section 5 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDC385379D9F841F2AE70C2C44B506A28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b) by inserting <quote>Puerto Rico,</quote> after <quote>Guam,</quote>,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD54DF0381D74D3691ED61B4D2A1FB6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1) by striking <quote>and Guam</quote> and inserting <quote>Guam, and Puerto Rico</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA43231CCC2F2466B9101461C835C9E90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="HB041C20E737E49DFA3E98DC617230C7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A) by inserting <quote>Puerto Rico,</quote> after <quote>Hawaii,</quote> each place it appears, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFC72103C2E940FCA01353AD53107E72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)(B) by inserting <quote>Puerto Rico,</quote> after <quote>Guam,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H83FCED1C77A04428982C3B13E79FF03B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Submission of plan of operation; technical assistance; determination and certification by Secretary of Agriculture</header><subsection id="HF59D4574F96742CB9FAFB70B4C73242F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of plan of operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On designating an agency of the kind described in section 3(s)(1) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012(s)(1)</external-xref>), the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall have 60 days to submit to the Secretary of Agriculture (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) its plan of operation, including a plan to transition to the supplemental nutrition assistance program under section 4(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5">7 U.S.C. 5(a)</external-xref>) as a request to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program under of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE6B2CB6EA27A45F883766F427AC45CED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>Within the 60-day period specified in subsection (a) and upon request from the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Secretary shall provide appropriate training and technical assistance to enable the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to formulate a plan of operation described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA62B1DF7FD4C45AD917B01B45DF56492"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination by the Secretary of Agriculture</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a plan of operation described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall approve if such plan satisfies the requirements for a supplemental nutrition assistance program State plan in accordance with subsections (d) and (e) of section 11 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>). If the Secretary does not approve such plan, the Secretary shall provide, not later than 30 days after disapproval, a statement that specifies each of the requirements that were not satisfied by such plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H15063AD1F67A49AF87E722BEFB6FE68C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification by the Secretary of Agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary approves the plan submitted by the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, not later than 60 days thereafter, a certification that the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico qualifies to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program as a State as defined in section 3(r) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012(r)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HC912386FCC454E21922952532FEA6632"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transition from the consolidated block grant for Puerto Rico</header><subsection id="H0EC8B1E138294BF0923814AAC5055A56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may continue to implement the then most recent approved consolidated block grant specified in section 19(b)(1)(A) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2028">7 U.S.C. 2028(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) for a period ending no later than 5 years after the effective date of the amendments made by this Act, or on the date the Secretary determines that the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico no longer needs to operate the consolidated block grant to complete the transition described in section 3(a), whichever occurs first.</text></subsection><subsection id="H176C0B5B6FDF45368D86A0C5D304349E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year a plan is continued under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the operation of such plan. The Secretary shall include in such report information related to increases in funding that are required to accommodate the transition of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico from the receipt of block grant payments to the implementation of supplemental nutrition assistance program.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFBB407DC4B3D449E8799D8F4BA721761" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consolidated block grant for Puerto Rico and American Samoa</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 19 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2028">7 U.S.C. 2028</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2F02E7611C5E40F1B5F6B92B84F31B70" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H722B38EEF63D4B88A82941787F61D529" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A) by inserting <quote>until the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022,</quote> after <quote>(A)</quote>,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22295EC9D235406BB3773811D8DC2FF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HA888B26979AC4AA69815CC43DB841CD3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="HDB2701D3A0E74BF5861FE0EB8A176BD9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (i) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC8824ED5CE9418192388037EFDAE29B" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><item id="H2D24BD4D6F3440E8A86DDB5781335DA7" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and ending on the date he Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</quote> after <quote>thereafter</quote>,</text></item><item id="H237571CD4CF64F8D95A164DAFFA22395" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>, and</text></item><item id="HF71302103B0E4095A02D8DDBF05C4431" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA11CA14E407F49B4B039AD5FC24D5E4B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H6CA095A984204C008F13FAB57702A0FB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to the availability of appropriations under section 18(a), for each fiscal year beginning after the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022, 0.4 percent of the aggregate amount specified in clause (i) and adjusted under clause (ii), as further adjusted by the percentage by which the thrifty food plan has been adjusted under section 3(u)(4) between June 30 of the penultimate fiscal year preceding such effective date and June 30 of the fiscal year for which the adjustment is made under this clause.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HCEB52459B9CF48E5ACF590C212408C28" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i) by inserting <quote>ending on the date the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</quote> after <quote>thereafter</quote>, and</text></clause><clause id="HCBD6B2B5F0554E9FB074EE42C5661F4C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subclause id="HF91F0254CCF44194A7F7A02B5B4E8664" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text> by striking <quote>For</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDC0E2EE8E7A2426BB5852285DBB23B10" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H132ECDF7856240488838AB8B1730283A" commented="no"><enum> (i)</enum><header>For</header></clause><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="H9297BAA1A52D45B18926D7482D5780CB" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>ending on the date the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</quote> after <quote>thereafter</quote>, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H87E4C422384E482FBA4C1F16841B1CF4" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following:</text><quoted-block id="H970F938B1BB24BF0A52AB5C4D52EDC12" style="OLC"><clause id="HE7193C4C3BF74C09B1CF2DD402C262B3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year beginning after the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022, the Secretary shall use 100 percent of the funds made available under subparagraph (A) for payment to American Samoa to pay 100 percent of the expenditures by American Samoa for a nutrition assistance program extended under section 601(c) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/597">Public Law 96–597</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/1469d">48 U.S.C. 1469d(c)</external-xref>).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C44689C674B4ACCACDF3E516CA099FC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking <quote>year,</quote> and inserting <quote>year ending on the date the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022, and</quote> after <quote>year</quote>, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B78E654FD049B682AFA8070ABC8234" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A) by inserting <quote>and ending on the date the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan under section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022</quote> after <quote>year</quote> the first place it appears.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD38FB1A9C4D84872BEDF2FA2837CABFD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary until the Secretary terminates the implementation of the plan described on section 4(a) of the Puerto Rico Nutrition Assistance Fairness Act of 2022.</text></section><section id="HA3816FBBEA4A4691AA18CC81DDBA7A1D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective dates</header><subsection id="H3A620F243DA44A0D905770B59C381665"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA97E6B5EF2B84C5F92907D09316B013C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date of amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on October 1 of the 1st fiscal year that begins 1 year after the Secretary submits to Congress the certification described in section 3(d) of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

