<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H615FA6D395244036848DF03C5ECBF838" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3485 RH: Global Respect Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 166</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3485</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–224, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210525">May 25, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220110">January 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HFA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220110">January 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Referral to the Committee on<committee-name committee-id="HJU00"> the Judiciary</committee-name> extended for a period ending not later than February 4, 2022</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220121">January 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220121">January 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 25, 2021</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on foreign persons responsible for violations of internationally recognized human rights against lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer and intersex (LGBTQI) individuals, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HFA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HAACBD1F468944D3CBBCED7F97E0BAE4E"><section id="HCCBAA2BF65564752B8E5897A3F336452" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Respect Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCE0D4613C0604604A236EE69249CBAB6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H9DFE0D30C8FB4BA79D29C6F0CC9F827A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dignity, freedom, and equality of all human beings are fundamental to a thriving global community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72C3D7F6332F4153B70E8501FFC2E4F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The rights to life, liberty, and security of the person, the right to privacy, and the right to freedom of expression and association are fundamental human rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B9B47BE8F54A4A85B7A183441ECB20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An alarming trend of violence directed at LGBTQI individuals around the world continues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9408851D6644E0F807D9EF049722A71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Approximately one-third of all countries have laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations, and many have enacted policies or laws that would further target LGBTQI individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9617919F47A4145B398E441097A246E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Every year thousands of individuals around the world are targeted for harassment, attack, arrest, and murder on the basis of their sexual orientation or gender identity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36D9A7AC0EF1461D95442108ADD764C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Those who commit crimes against LGBTQI individuals often do so with impunity, and are not held accountable for their crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AFE2D498EEB4F2289265AF4C6DE5B52"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In many instances police, prison, military, and civilian government authorities have been directly complicit in abuses aimed at LGBTQI citizens, including arbitrary arrest, torture, and sexual abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D4620BFC5914D9393C72FBE8BDE621A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Celebrations of LGBTQI individuals and communities, such as film festivals, Pride events, and demonstrations are often forced underground due to inaction on the part of, or harassment by, local law enforcement and government officials, in violation of freedoms of assembly and expression.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C66DC616A944A88B364702ABA90C2F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations severely hinder access to HIV/AIDS treatment, information, and preventive measures for LGBTQI individuals and families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H730C751720054509A23594C655B5A63D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Many countries are making positive developments in the protection of the basic human rights of LGBTQI individuals.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0B68802EE40942F782036A3C642C7ECE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions on individuals responsible for violations of human rights against LGBTQI people</header><subsection id="H4772ACDAC08946418494A4371C611FE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and biannually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of each foreign person the President determines, based on credible information, including information obtained by other countries or by nongovernmental organizations that monitor violations of human rights—</text><paragraph id="HF5C7AB26832748D2BEA6912DD5EAE9C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in, with respect to persons based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics—</text><subparagraph id="H2208966CB2764547A0499E55750DF5C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D68AC6CB0284CDE8C7ED87B38211B29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prolonged detention without charges and trial;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB87B2E29CEE467BA9162F9B67CD45DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>causing the disappearance of such persons by the abduction and clandestine detention of such persons; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8036C15E06E84A7790B5B04F16F8BC23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other flagrant denial of the right to life, liberty, or the security of such persons;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA63945A6A4943099F75ABBCEB0C5425"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acted as an agent of or on behalf of a foreign person in a matter relating to an activity described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6062811522743A58956356CE9986329"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in inciting a foreign person to engage in an activity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94F50C780DF9425580EFDF7C3C55E217"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form; updates; removal</header><paragraph id="HED87138C4F3A4445B446FF2BD82DBD20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The list required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted in unclassified form and published in the Federal Register without regard to the requirements of section 222(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1202">8 U.S.C. 1202(f)</external-xref>) with respect to confidentiality of records pertaining to the issuance or refusal of visas or permits to enter the United States, except that the President may include a foreign person in a classified, unpublished annex to such list if the President—</text><subparagraph id="H42CA79C56E6D421BAA6E0CB1F5085E85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that—</text><clause id="H7185B376B99D43F286C34243B9B28F38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is vital for the national security interests of the United States to do so; and</text></clause><clause id="HB609CF324624496B8F8673BFAF3C719F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of such annex, and the inclusion of such person in such annex, would not undermine the overall purpose of this section to publicly identify foreign persons engaging in the conduct described in subsection (a) in order to increase accountability for such conduct; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCC56A73667F4CF9992E6AC86FF9F313"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 15 days before including such person in a classified annex, provides to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, including or continuing to include each foreign person in such annex despite the existence of any publicly available credible information indicating that each such foreign person engaged in an activity described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A0EE551CBE14309B483899A325B362A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the list required by subsection (a) as new information becomes available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB48F47305648139CC0DD3A1E84CBA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>A foreign person may be removed from the list required by subsection (a) if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the removal of such person from such list that—</text><subparagraph id="HAFFB059720F84661A102C67C93855E74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>credible information exists that such person did not engage in the activity for which the person was included in such list;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0477F1FD0F7C4A48909CA831AAE14DFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such person has been prosecuted appropriately for the activity in which such person engaged; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5BB9DE956140CEAEC228FD1CE9F59A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activities in which such person engaged, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB874713C197C44C4A12AC27F3597705A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public submission of information</header><text>The President shall issue public guidance, including through United States diplomatic and consular posts, setting forth the manner by which the names of foreign persons that may meet the criteria to be included on the list required by subsection (a) may be submitted to the Department of State for evaluation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF423DADB0EAA48F0A4EBBB5AD692A421"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requests from chair and ranking member of appropriate congressional committees</header><paragraph id="H6EEF4AD530264771B63B79D272BE9853"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration of information</header><text>In addition to the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (c), the President shall also consider information provided by the Chair or Ranking Member of each of the appropriate congressional committees in determining whether to include a foreign person in the list required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3653953A574F4202BD0E45C9B79E52F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests</header><text>Not later than 120 days after receiving a written request from the Chair or Ranking Member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a foreign person meets the criteria for being included in the list required by subsection (a), the President shall transmit a response to such Chair or Ranking Member, as the case may be, with respect to the President’s determination relating to such foreign person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F76D70AD90747E19655623EE40EECC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>If the President removes from the list required by subsection (a) a foreign person that had been included in such list pursuant to a request under paragraph (2), the President shall provide to the relevant Chair or Ranking Member of one of the appropriate congressional committees any information that contributed to such decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE2896AD01C48D0B358E2C04D5E951D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The President may transmit a response required by paragraph (2) or paragraph (3) in classified form if the President determines that it is necessary for the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03F39A407D0A42D5AA7B87E2ECF69661"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header><paragraph id="H7C259AA4C0C249BC8617C206CD8684D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas and admission to the united states</header><text>A foreign person on the list required by subsection (a), and each immediate family member of such person, is—</text><subparagraph id="HA4173325C549490D9F55EB16D0A32493"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C35C1631E1465A81FAB9F97F9331C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7A84925E9624A899366A6231BD5F609"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CFCD759DCF4470BAE8BC26B50FBBED8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph id="H7825E1910A774455B3A868DF14BEE496"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer or the Secretary of State, (or a designee of the Secretary of State) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to a foreign person on the list required by subsection (a) and to each immediate family member of such person regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D91D2AC8D794B90A60A568C12BB899A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="H57FF5C02704D4827B759CDE31FB5A69F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause id="H38DA4F46673047ED879B811CD852BDB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign person’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC31509DCEE0741DA82232AD09EE7DBAA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC633230701B945D893ECB8269AB2D8BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sense of congress with respect to additional sanctions</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the President should impose additional targeted sanctions with respect to foreign persons on the list required by subsection (a) to push for accountability for flagrant denials of the right to life, liberty, or the security of the person, through the use of designations and targeted sanctions provided for such conduct under other existing authorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC0A7D1DE3B04AF6A91F230D28888815"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waivers in the interest of national security</header><subparagraph id="H9C5AF700395D47078009127B3C81ECE3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the application of paragraph (1) or (2) with respect to a foreign person included in the list required by subsection (a) if the President determines and transmits to the appropriate congressional committees notice and justification, that such a waiver—</text><clause id="HD0D5E95D40C143D990841AD2155CDBAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="H460D2A2BB22E4595A028769BC63E91A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FF9589BEDBC48539F1ABD5FE90B73E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of certain waivers</header><text>A waiver pursuant to a determination under clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be transmitted not later than 15 days before the granting of such waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BC026E3F0304845A9B0BDCE81E85988"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text><paragraph id="HF921D9118B204955997C1CC74DBED426"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actions taken to carry out this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7BD00385340140FD92394C177E4B8E9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of foreign persons added to or removed from the list required by subsection (a) during the year preceding each such report, the dates on which such persons were so added or removed, and the reasons for so adding or removing such persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C170EBC7E5F4A639F5EE50E185D4C35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis that compares increases or decreases in the number of such persons added or removed year-over-year and the reasons therefor; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BBB5821F154CEA953D3265B7B2BE37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any efforts by the President to coordinate with the governments of other countries, as appropriate, to impose sanctions that are similar to the sanctions imposed under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAE58EB875ED47EA8E2BE43CBE28D9C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA32D5A1EF282435C8CAFB799083B053F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA4BD990FDBBB43D095004FBA56BB2F72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H493EBEEE9D1D4C9AB4D44C9F6DE36F3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19EE7635E0D34F87982880B5A2A710C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <quote>immediate family member</quote> has the meaning given such term for purposes of section 7031(c) of division K of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3BF55E0F56754CD7AAD48EA75765768C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Discrimination related to sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics</header><subsection id="H658338C1DE7945F29E4573A71A7A4E32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking violence or criminalization related to sexual orientation or gender identity</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor shall designate a Bureau-based senior officer or officers who shall be responsible for tracking violence, criminalization, and restrictions on the enjoyment of fundamental freedoms in foreign countries based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F9DB3B53F09483C8EC7D019B4EE1510"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual country reports on human rights practices</header><text>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text><paragraph id="H07402D89966E4D608978161F271093C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 116(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HD5CEC590834A4887AC6A7A3AE48BDF0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB937107BCAD84D5B8B8494A60F209C31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)—</text><clause id="H4B5A3F653C5E44978C5041C39BB3084A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></clause><clause id="HDFD8304D4239450FA4BC2F707CDCC795"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA83A3A1AF8F34F3E86DE4D341C8DB84E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H66FE4AC09D624836820B3C159588EE9C" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HFA00"><paragraph id="H3473CE32E7034B39A1F85BF5B9E28B03"><enum>(13)</enum><text>wherever applicable, information relating to violence or discrimination that affects fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly, of individuals in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H193306E8294449679CCD8FCF402E5F7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 502B(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(b)</external-xref>), by inserting after the ninth sentence the following new sentence: <quote>Wherever applicable, such report shall also include information relating to violence or discrimination that affects the fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly, of individuals in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220121">January 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

