<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H88A0B3ED6A0A490CBD029178860EA0C0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7447 IH: Modernizing Aeronautical Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7447</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to conduct a study on the modernization of aeronautical standards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H615B1B63B0E54158AC8ECC52256E7835" style="OLC"><section id="H9B78B00569E6499C8136C336AB918964" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Aeronautical Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7614942FFC4140F98E8EF526CDC3080D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modernizing Aeronautical Standards</header><subsection id="HFAF0EF7890B746889293C940AD9A4DFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H3E42F43C8687453A929DEDD2AE8F468B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The work of the U.S. Committee on Extension to the Standard Atmosphere, established in 1953, led to the 1958, 1962, 1966, and 1976 versions of the U.S. Standard Atmosphere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07DFE10DC76641F189984C854B706422"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These models were published in book form jointly by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the U.S. Air Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D0C22E1611A4FA1A871AFBDB3D06535"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The U.S. Standard Atmosphere is widely used as a basis for the design, testing, and operation of aircraft and other equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAAA29DBC45C4F10BD4C2113E702E458"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Defense has supplemented the standard atmosphere with data models of climatic extremes, most recently with MIL–HDBK–310, Climatic Information to Determine Design and Test Requirements for Military Systems and Equipment, which was published in 1997 and <quote>provides climatic data primarily for use in engineering analyses to develop and test military equipment and materiel</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB13B8EBC834380B7EF7175B3017382"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The most recent standard atmosphere published in 1976 assumed a standard sea-level temperature of 59 degrees Fahrenheit in continuation of the assumption established in 1924 by Resolution 192 of the International Commission for Air Navigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3185E5455C2C4E94B404A4951DD0AFCA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Between 1924 and 1976, the average global sea-level temperature rose by 0.5 degree Fahrenheit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A06B3412E64B45B60E96AD3D924771"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Since 1976, the average global sea-level temperature has risen by more than 1.5 degrees Fahrenheit, the five warmest years in the modern record have all occurred since 2015, and nine of the 10 warmest years have occurred since 2005.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB70F88F2E69D417AB074301014C52E14"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Under the Fifth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (AR5 IPCC), all scenarios considered result in an average global temperature rise in 2040 by more than 2.5 degrees Fahrenheit since 1976, with the most extreme scenario resulting in a temperature rise of 3.5 degrees Fahrenheit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B331B6799364B008C047CA0E82068E1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>By 2100, the IPCC projects that the global mean temperature will increase by more than 4 degrees Fahrenheit under moderate scenarios, with the potential to exceed 7.5 degrees Fahrenheit under the most extreme scenarios.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H514F7D81DEC64CF7AFAA8D47906ED04E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Aircraft performance is negatively affected by increased temperatures, resulting in lower payload capacity, increased runway requirements, reduced range, slower climb out speeds, and negative impacts to environmental performance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D1BCF049C34AD7A3AA8C93889FEB5E"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For existing aircraft and engine designs, the increase to ambient temperature will result in impacts to operations to account for the lower engine and aircraft performance, which may include increased noise exposure, increased operations, increase to emissions, and degradation of air quality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B376DC2D024D8CB8461DF64635163F"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For new aircraft and engine designs, the increase to ambient temperature will require improved engine designs that provide required thrust at higher ambient temperatures to meet mission requirements, which may result in de-rating at airports with excess runway length, resulting in lower operational noise compared to current levels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97CB335E02F84761B33DEF39639E54DC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The military and commercial aircraft being designed today are expected to be in operation for thirty to fifty years, with an expected end of life between 2050 to 2070.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H931FEE78E87147BE9A0D28FAC97F30DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on aeronautical standards</header><paragraph id="H2B7878EA0DEA4BEDB77EFC88B3CF67B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall conduct a study on the modernization of aeronautical standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9718E23D377E48C9A259CED2D00B3465"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>Modernization of Aeronautical Standards and Aircraft Performance Study</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6563F2BDF8F34E4D9400CBE09EEE7450"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7938D4B01D52400BAF71A2D5127B767E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of differences between the current atmospheric conditions and the baseline atmospheric conditions, to include both the mean and extreme values.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E7686225D8E4610B5C8EEBFC4655214"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the impacts to operation, maintenance, and sustainment costs of covered commercial aircraft due to the differences identified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED07EBDE0684642AFE590A010584AA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An estimation of the number of weight restriction hours for the covered commercial aircraft at the covered commercial airports under the baseline, current, and projected atmospheric conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C2E6D9ECC9C42D18BE5D1261DA2804F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the required infrastructure investment at the covered commercial airports such that the number of weight restriction hours under the projected atmospheric conditions is equivalent to the number of weight restriction hours with the current infrastructure and route structure under the baseline and current atmospheric conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEE357B567D3469EB3830D83FD97DB47"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recommendations for atmospheric and climatic design requirements for future commercial aircraft to account for projected atmospheric conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8A413E799E24D4AB7C38A2C67FF3979"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An analysis of the impacts to operation, maintenance, and sustainment costs and aircraft performance of military aircraft due to the differences identified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6A0597F83D64289918FAD1BF7CFDC96"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Atmospheric and climatic design requirements for military aircraft, or other equipment, which should be updated to account for current and projected atmospheric conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EFF488BBFD14E86B27CBE28B9139605"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommended updates or supplements to the atmospheric standards due to current atmospheric conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H386DA9342A1F4542A6CF0E41391F47E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criteria under which future updates or supplements to the atmospheric standards should be made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H453E9700F36847898F338084E7B94F89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall transmit the results of the study to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the congressional defense committees not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE543D835CB3344F1BCB8ED9722456AB1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H9049D0E8873E4A0581DA89250B7630FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>atmospheric standards</quote> means—</text><clause id="HCE5E55C71A644A8C8910B3961CFD4CA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States Standard Atmosphere of 1976;</text></clause><clause id="H032A11C60DDC4C43A41AE800092425AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>MIL–HDBK–310, Climatic Information to Determine Design and Test Requirements for Military Systems and Equipment; and</text></clause><clause id="H77065AC30FC5419AAF25C7B38689FCD2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other standard as determined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F083FD3DB2D438F94ECC4DF9B2F8DE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>baseline atmospheric conditions</quote> means the atmospheric conditions referred to in the most recent release of an atmospheric standard.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF209BE9796704025B64E2AC0A537C8D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>current atmospheric conditions</quote> means the atmospheric conditions observed in the 5 most recent calendar years ending before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H674A38A5570B4CD3AFA1941114210F54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>projected atmospheric conditions</quote> means the mean atmospheric conditions projected by the International Panel on Climate Change under the Sixth Assessment Report in scenarios—</text><clause id="HAF600B98A235439EA8566D797CEB39C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">SSP1–1.9;</text></clause><clause id="H6074D0AA209945F59F2EA7FA9A90C2C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">SSP1–2.6;</text></clause><clause id="HFDF3864E7B0445FB9703CDB05DE207BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">SSP2–4.5;</text></clause><clause id="H934EFFD8A9CC4E29BE287B9BEC03350C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">SSP3–7.0; and</text></clause><clause id="HDC2D01272A924CE88E051747108A6CBC"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">SSP5–8.5.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68AC3CE719A44A57ACDF3A146ACC2C09"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>aircraft performance</quote> includes—</text><clause id="HF8291B8D93CF4C05AA27973F4E5201C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>range;</text></clause><clause id="HBDBC387F41604C55A658B9A8199CA6A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>payload capacity;</text></clause><clause id="HE5E78C725AE146E3B63CED21F9073020"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>runway length requirement;</text></clause><clause id="HB8EE3166F45B49C5957C9472E676DCA6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>climb rate;</text></clause><clause id="H920307D1673C4A5F919B60A254DD3179"><enum>(v)</enum><text>turn rate;</text></clause><clause id="HBCF29663ED5A41F9B1DAA2961F1259D8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>operating altitude; and</text></clause><clause id="HB6294F2B365542959270FCBDD6921701"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>acceleration.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70C87BC58352404AADA1F53290489183" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered commercial airports</quote> means—</text><clause id="H14A9B728C3E04C2381727E88CC7495B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the 30 commercial service airports (as defined in section 47102(7) of title 49, United States Code) with the most passenger boardings in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H6A370B867A904012878078AE311886FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the 5 public airports (as defined in section 47102(21) of title 49, United States Code) not covered by clause (i) with the highest all-cargo landed weight in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86EB24FCE60464C839168C48BFE082E" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered commercial aircraft</quote> means the 10 aircraft types still in production with the highest number of operations at covered commercial airports in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B6337F306C94112B4DB4C907CB121F2"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>commercial aircraft</quote> means an air carrier operating under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F938F05C5F44CFB5FF2E34E10CA575"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>passenger boardings</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 47102(15) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A95E19DB2724F308FD8F222D1F3855E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The term <quote>military aircraft</quote> means an aircraft that—</text><clause id="H78D9FF989948463D8CE1EDA941D6C9D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is currently being developed, procured, or operated by the Department of Defense; and</text></clause><clause id="H22895B39D02C4EE49C96F177B365EC63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a bomber, fighter, attack helicopter, transport helicopter, strategic transport, tactical transport, or surveillance aircraft.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44EFEF6FD87A47E98632766E74F6010D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The term <quote>weight restriction day</quote> means a day when the daily maximum temperature matches or exceeds the weight-restriction temperature threshold for a specific aircraft.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H399AFEEE918F47A5908608FE1BC469A1"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

