<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H132C629AA2664C0684D7657A83C18FC5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7711 IH: Promoting Healthier Lifelong Improvements in Food and Exercise Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national program to conduct and support activities toward the goal of significantly reducing the number of cases of overweight and obesity among individuals in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6553507FBF324FDF98DA64D45065F3DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0358A83DE8444D5D8944D8FACEA3C9CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Healthier Lifelong Improvements in Food and Exercise Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LIFE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEFC5B5E763D347E79E057ECA78AB346E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reduction in prevalence of overweight and obesity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317U the following section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H5D8C5EE78ED04B0089747716378E6A7A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAA762FF8DC2E42FA9B420029F929BBCC"><enum>317V.</enum><header>Reduction in prevalence of overweight and obesity</header> 
<subsection id="H0EE7DC7FBF414AC4935EFB173F90342B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall carry out a national program to conduct and support activities regarding individuals who are overweight or obese in order to make progress toward the goal of significantly reducing the number of cases of overweight and obesity among individuals in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1CFA9CDF69E0429C881605B8541ED0CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain activities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall (directly or through grants or contracts) carry out the following with respect to individuals who are overweight or obese:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2CECB8E3044B4D069587D1499CE79A70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Activities to train health professionals to recognize that patients are overweight or obese and to recommend prevention activities regarding such condition, including educating patients on—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C8487F5CF0A4803B921E37A1F777702"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the relationship between such condition and cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and other health conditions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52BB348D6192400F845EA8ECED166D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the benefits of proper nutrition and regular physical activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88F39D7DDDF8435AA5C0CD5A7E399F24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Activities to educate the public with respect to the condition of being overweight or obese, including the development of a strategy for a public awareness campaign.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8DC983EBA1541D09B889399B5192239"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The development and demonstration of intervention strategies for use at worksites and in community settings such as hospitals and community health centers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H987E519E885C4613B433F09ED7E84C3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2024 and 2025.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

