<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0FB1820D2A424EC9BE2899E53BC12CE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8436 IH: Accurate Pricing for Investors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8436</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220720">July 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to carry out a study on the need to revise the current tick size regime, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7787D5409E06489E81BE3A1849AA662B" style="OLC"><section id="H1A7C1A2DC5B9432B9A2FFCE269F71DDD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accurate Pricing for Investors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCF2F2108E27347F8A82D3ECC80879037"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on the need to revise the current tick size regime</header><subsection id="HBBFC3788F8B745D4B9599707AD8A2A46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission shall carry out a study to—</text><paragraph id="H15E272D0BFB94083BD8B4224AD9C2CEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the need to revise the current tick size regime, particularly for stocks that data suggests may be tick-constrained, to improve public price discovery and facilitate fair competition between exchange and non-exchange markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0366E3E7507242D1A4D0E798CE7CBA4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the impacts of artificially wide spreads that are a function of the tick size regime and their impacts on—</text><subparagraph id="HC673B8A3DCB04EF0B062E0DACB3A702C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public price discovery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB73F40D033CF4E8F8C9EDB141A1EA110"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating fair competition between exchange and non-exchange markets;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA689858154124066B6F9E0CD4A1BC1EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>examine whether reducing the tick size for some stocks may lower execution costs for retail investors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5634017634574926AADA23B8266533F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine whether identifying non-exchange market centers in trade reports published on the consolidated tape would enhance public price discovery and address market fragmentation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC31F100AF9344EFAA817F572DA3C462"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

