<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE3858EC0B1D4B6DAD4023139D8C02DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8662 IH: Military Data Privacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on the purchase and use by the Department of Defense of certain location data and internet metadata data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F5E7E59FC584B28AC89250C25881B39" style="OLC"><section id="H15FE0BFA6F0E45F08DED6721D24E9E6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Data Privacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HABF98C5FBDBD4B039427BB8C46DC39BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on purchase and use by Department of Defense of location data generated by Americans’ phones and their internet metadata</header><subsection id="H03FEDD205DA24831B00731A26AD6850B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees and make available to the public on an internet website of the Department of Defense a report that—</text><paragraph id="HD4BBCC2D767A469190DB913354EED5ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies each covered entity that is currently, or during the five-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act was, without a court order—</text><subparagraph id="H52474FDC9BF746EF86CCC5D98B0BB566"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtaining in exchange for anything of value any covered records; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H941B81A1A02040B280331BB3F75E9799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intentionally retaining or intentionally using such covered records; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A46ED76E40F4F8B9E5549BD8D75BDB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each covered entity identified pursuant to paragraph (1), identifies—</text><subparagraph id="HF235E420B671430291F8D773CCC0548B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each category of covered record the covered entity, without a court order, is obtaining or obtained, in exchange for anything of value;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD9A581949D94E479215639DF9988285"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the covered entity intentionally retained or is intentionally retaining each category of covered records pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB549DBCD8773410FBBD0AC59A24AA477"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the covered entity intentionally uses or used each category of covered records identified pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33EB28402D7A442E8F0CFD311F5CF796"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether such obtaining, retention, and use ceased before the date of the enactment of this Act or is ongoing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H963C1F35E6914EEF9EE18C1EC68219D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0780A1107DC6465B985D208D26EB24F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of parties to a communication</header><text>In determining under this section whether a party to a communication is likely to be located inside or outside the United States, the Secretary shall consider the Internet Protocol (IP) address used by the party to the communication, but may also consider other information known to the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDBB1090A45704D12B6CAEC77A3507F90"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAA46B30F3F9D439BA1A30CC63E4AF43B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD395DE1C02A940FEAE1F836F1F3B7F68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered entities</term> means the Defense Agencies, Department of Defense activities, and components of the Department that—</text><subparagraph id="H2967B70E56B649458E184D3166AD1E37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are under the authority, direction, and control of the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80D74CAA65ED40E295BF9143CF37BC9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>over which the Under Secretary exercises planning, policy, funding, or strategic oversight authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA54B61A9CBB4414CBE635E701F7A6A46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered records</term> includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFF74CC7AEAFA42AAAA22F5823A7F1802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Location data generated by phones that are likely to be located in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E9F07C0027D43ECA46E8DE421FDE893"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Domestic phone call records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD06C6EA8EFF34132A592ED62E6C80DD1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>International phone call records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67FB5D46BA14461D8B78B02B472CDD8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Domestic text message records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC21215C4CA5E4C368E037A94AECC9309"><enum>(E)</enum><text>International text message records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67CA00F37DF34CE9A31BC9B10271547D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Domestic netflow records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1B0E40F70C0470BB049FFFE4413E330"><enum>(G)</enum><text>International netflow records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02D6BB2AA20344AF905525480C56958B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Domestic Domain Name System records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A7BDA0E795F4A0F81C8FE4B2CE3A2A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>International Domain Name System records.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H960D802AC3CD467BAEBA6872CF14B558"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Other types of domestic internet metadata.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A2DBC4878449F0A2C030666FD2AEA8"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Other types of international internet metadata.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6674E4B93B45A5864EA47F6D5614CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>domestic</term> means a telephone or an internet communication in which all parties to the communication are likely to be located in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H002811D9A3FC454DA4E10F45BEEA5A5C"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H52B78FC1175E40CEB4500DBEE9CED2E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>international</term> means a telephone or an internet communication in which one or more parties to the communication are likely to be located in the United States and one or more parties to the communication are likely to be located outside the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F6DDA848C234A5D928E3300C6B43DEB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>international</term> does not include a telephone or an internet communication in which all parties to the communication are likely to be located outside the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB0F852EAEC042A1B59FBB029BAD36B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>obtain in exchange for anything of value</term> means to obtain by purchasing, to receive in connection with services being provided for consideration, or to otherwise obtain in exchange for consideration, including an access fee, service fee, maintenance fee, or licensing fee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H859CDF80C9EC42DE8018C1D5481EAD62"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFFE9902568EE4FFB987DC3A006303858"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>retain</term> means the storage of a covered record.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H998A046127FC4D55AC0E9708ECA4AFA3" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>retain</term> does not include the temporary storage of a covered record that will be, but has not yet been, subjected to a process in which the covered record, which is part of a larger compilation containing records that are not covered records, are identified and deleted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D185AFE5E3141619961724DC0369545"><enum>(8)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAD3005C4CFB540EA91D5D32C4479CA6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>use</term>, with respect to a covered record, includes analyzing, processing, or sharing the covered record.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DA3FD92F02B4312879C38E8D79A712F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>use</term> does not include subjecting the covered record to a process in which the covered record, which is part of a larger compilation containing records that are not covered records, are identified and deleted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

