<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF476FA9244F34C08B663A30DA80A42F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6884 IH: American Energy Independence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6884</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prioritize United States energy independence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6E57FDB7651A4AD2AED189239075A295" style="OLC"><section id="H014D172EFA1E4A28A3B0FB4C236C132A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Energy Independence Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H58DFF392E4FC4F8F9559695B69F0E743"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H05A504B499854027BCD06276F172475F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to secure energy independence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CC5AA60B4F843D9B38BE055D2A3CCE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide people in the United States with stable, affordable, and reliable energy prices, including gasoline, diesel, electricity, natural gas, and propane;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H620D9F57E9914A9C9941952B245A833C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to lift regulations on United States energy producers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16B0580BE3FB45BC89AB015A7EB7448B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to address the impending energy crisis caused by the illegal invasion by Russia of Ukraine. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HA1228885FD3142538E2FBF58568E295D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prioritization of United States energy independence</header><subsection id="H826F9EA5A69342868850E6CE34FEC55E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>President</header><text>The President shall—</text><paragraph id="H4E9FCC9A79994A67B274F7A38791505D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of the Interior to prioritize United States energy independence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF69DBEE3187F4A6B8531250B0E143AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, develop and submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a plan for the United States to achieve energy independence by 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F0B5EDE6DDB4051A876C3DE1C61C65D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary of Energy</header><paragraph id="H910814AA8AA049F3A8EA131D002BC841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall develop a program, promulgate rules, and issue guidance to ensure that the United States is—</text><subparagraph id="H16398A5E7A514C479A5B65EA87D15969"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy independent by 2024; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H052FC123A3EE45DA96598C992401012B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a net exporter of energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H786ABAD6BB674DCFB985A9130AEC797A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hydraulic fracturing</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall review existing programs of the Department of Energy and promulgate regulations to reduce the regulatory burden on private United States entities harvesting energy through hydraulic fracturing. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H516456FBB4B342ECB6E00CB9A348C40C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Domestic energy independence</header><paragraph id="HF360BC60C5FC4EE6B0BF3684FA63B360"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H37F903ACDF914E5780667C0EDAF72A17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and repeal any regulations promulgated by the Administrator during the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act that have the intent or effect of substantially reducing the energy independence of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC0248FA2FDA415CBFB0984901489737"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promulgate regulations and issue guidance relating to—</text><clause id="H78F6F47BEB084BB28DCBA38A970694D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reducing the regulatory burden for energy producers in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H5BA12DF0C48A418E83E2B81D87571454"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing the energy output by those producers; and</text></clause><clause id="H18AD9D8170B740E0BCA5014F2600852D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>setting the social cost of carbon to $0 per metric ton.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A9937F66014A118539785A889F3084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Administrator shall not propose, finalize, or issue any regulation relating to climate change if the Administrator determines that such a regulation will—</text><subparagraph id="H3F6DD0972FD745AB9B4DB0D380FFF3AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce the energy security of the United States; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2E8342CFDD94CD2B84E9ADA24825F3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase energy costs for consumers in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD968CC1D19D541DD8595480C54053892"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Transportation</header><paragraph id="H8AB82118A7744189AFB47587527B1472"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review and report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFFB94AD93E75461B821144451F5812D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review of all existing programs of the Department of Transportation relating to transportation prices in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD71C295EA93045238A87BE8698A50666"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the stability of transportation prices and the affordability of transportation in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B17CAB11B84EA6A17F00250C476078"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate regulations and issue guidance to promote stable and affordable gasoline and diesel prices for commuters in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H998D4AD01B8F4413B4C8C7BFF4F6B277"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Department of Defense report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report reviewing the national security implications of the dependence of the United States and allied countries on Russian energy exports.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCCB21CE15D0F4B0FAB52C3BE4B18ABAA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Leasing of Federal land for oil and natural gas production</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall—</text><paragraph id="H46E5AAFEB2EA4BAEACCB5BA713F98411"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of existing Federal programs relating to the leasing of Federal land for oil and natural gas production; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF005AA063324AC5805DE7C0548B3050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>based on the review, promulgate regulations and issue guidance—</text><subparagraph id="HF7C8B52AD37E4A5B9CF76EF63963F05D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote the leasing of Federal land for oil and natural gas production; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AC92B6C3B3D4B0FAB9460F0C5693535" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reduce regulatory burdens on energy companies in the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10CC64A0BF7A46ACABDA91F359B0474F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</header><paragraph id="H8BBAF11389A84A5FADC28F2BC7810244"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H0C2ABEA6BBD44E17884FA11910872693"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81FF98C1ED064F0C8A6848A391C83107"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered application</header><text>The term <term>covered application</term> means an application submitted to the Commission relating to the construction, leasing, or operation of 1 or more pipelines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB255C810CD483FBD65937DA2E4E679"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of covered applications previously denied</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall review and reconsider, in light of the national security implications of the energy independence of the United States, all covered applications denied by the Commission during the 10-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE64F014E5D44B93AAEF09B1F9664C60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumption applicable to covered applications</header><subparagraph id="HDF34ED2FC2384D8893A6637C4E2CC4BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Commission shall—</text><clause id="H3B83E98234694009BF7C297AA8101725"><enum>(i)</enum><text>presume that all covered applications received by the Commission during the period beginning on the date that is 1 year before the date of enactment of this Act and ending on January 1, 2024, will have a positive effect on national security by contributing to the energy independence of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H3877F5463AC84CFC91A8338415638E93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consider those covered applications to be granted, based on that presumption.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H747F5E5A077848639314AF116A61230F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rebuttal</header><text>The Commission may overcome the presumption described in subparagraph (A) and deny a covered application considered to be granted under that subparagraph if the Commission makes competing findings under any other Act with respect to the national security implications of the covered application. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H430F1347897E4837A7C9ADD21C56DA1B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Abrogation of energy policies</header><subsection id="HDCDB4903E2B94EE98012796509836D99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds To implement the Paris Agreement</header><paragraph id="H2F392F826EFF472F991D1F59567FB955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><subparagraph id="H847D4E7824D84C42B89A545E3C4C71A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No funds appropriated or otherwise made available for fiscal year 2021 or any fiscal year thereafter may be used to implement the Paris Agreement. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75A75EAB5423434EA6F415511E030D5F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The prohibition under subparagraph (A) includes the use of funds for the following: </text><clause id="HB7BBB0576CEE4A9D8CF51BB17CAAC85A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Preparing, communicating, or maintaining nationally determined contributions.</text></clause><clause id="H1F12CE7EAA1B4307AAF66687C57AE79C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Funding emissions reductions of developing countries.</text></clause><clause id="H5E05447268004BC0A89C0F321430A24A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Developing financial mechanisms that incentivize offshoring of jobs. </text></clause><clause id="H8706DF310EFC445D98033FDACA790AFF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Green Climate Fund. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D0909147154712B0840F4B392486F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of prohibition</header><text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date on which the Senate provides advice and consent to the ratification of the Paris Agreement pursuant to section 2 of article II of the Constitution of the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41B987D41F464B3996B135FB4F0BB150"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of Paris Agreement</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Paris Agreement</term> means the decision by the 21st Conference of the Parties of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change in Paris, France, adopted December 12, 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H326FCB6A228645AB94BB0CC057055458"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of Keystone XL pipeline</header><paragraph id="H75F6F96F58254A92ADD2682BD634EA14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. may construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline facilities at the international border of the United States and Canada at Phillips County, Montana, for the import of oil from Canada to the United States as described in the Presidential Permit of March 29, 2019 (84 Fed. Reg. 13101 (April 3, 2019)). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72E11580313640F49C946D7C0A637830"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No Presidential Permit Required</header><text>No Presidential permit (or similar permit) under Executive Order 13867 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/301">3 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note; relating to the issuance of permits with respect to facilities and land transportation crossings at the international boundaries of the United States), Executive Order 12038 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7151">42 U.S.C. 7151</external-xref> note; relating to the transfer of certain functions to the Secretary of Energy), Executive Order 10485 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref> note; relating to the performance of functions respecting electric power and natural gas facilities located on United States borders), or any other Executive order shall be required for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of the pipeline facilities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EE782DDDFCF4C78A41A168B071AF684"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nullification of climate crisis executive order</header><text>Executive Order 14008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> note; relating to tackling the climate crisis at home and abroad) is rescinded and shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB962325CE99342BC8F56609A8C17BE6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waters of the United States</header><paragraph id="H8AD5AC90E59B48A3A7A66A2761ECB39D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The definitions of the term <term>waters of the United States</term> and the other terms defined in section 328.3 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on June 22, 2020), are enacted into law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H017BF5D5D9C74E7A998A2E2A6857F955"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Codification of navigable waters protection rule</header><text>The final rule of the Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>The Navigable Waters Protection Rule: Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote></quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 22250 (April 21, 2020)) is enacted into law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D08DECAA72C47B4BF8AC6F22A342024"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Abrogation of proposed rule</header><text>The proposed rule of the Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Revised Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote></quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 69372 (December 7, 2021)) is rescinded and shall have no force or effect. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B615416A0BE4621AF4EB593AB8D0C07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Abrogation of methane rule</header><text>The proposed rule of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Standards of Performance for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources and Emissions Guidelines for Existing Sources: Oil and Natural Gas Sector Climate Review</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 63110 (November 15, 2021)) is rescinded and shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD77E6D7530B344DF913166E5BE338EE5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="H18CE0BF7258C4DB09C362223B9B8CFDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the status of United States dependence on foreign countries for energy needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72DB444D035342E8ABA330970C1828BE"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF6AE27BD1C414CD79B679652B97EA9A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the compliance of applicable Federal agencies with this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6118B9AD17A4333B4126F41F24868BC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluates the effect of that compliance on United States energy independence; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2108B73856E046BCB52D9F5F312C67A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluates the stability and affordability of energy prices for United States consumers.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

