<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A70348FE2354A3EA4D6B113D72C48B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8636 IH: Preventing PLA Acquisition of United States Technology Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8636</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220802">August 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To counter the military-civil fusion strategy of the Chinese Communist Party and prevent United States contributions to the development of dual-use technology in China.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H530E3DB875CE4C0AB97987A492A47A05" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD9E3323D26D1402B9B0FC909184A85F8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing PLA Acquisition of United States Technology Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF0332B8F043D40A897DDA34B6E9918A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Countering the military-civil fusion strategy of the Chinese Communist Party</header><subsection id="H697DE2ACEC9C4859B9466B3650D97FEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB9D902F286624C688917EDD10B5FA5ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chinese entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>Chinese entity of concern</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H346C5FAD6A854052A3988D80CF69EC02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any college or university in the People's Republic of China that is determined by the Secretary of Defense to be involved in the implementation of the military-civil fusion strategy, including—</text><clause id="H2CB091CED1E1421C9FFF5AA1683C5880"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any college or university known as the <quote>Seven Sons of National Defense</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H132EC8015FE74F4EB07C9F312657993A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any college or university that receives funding from—</text><subclause id="H2ADE66D4ABFC46F696853C875DE83924"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the People's Liberation Army; or </text></subclause><subclause id="HC75D6468CBC84279A1F40B0251269FDD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Equipment Development Department, or the Science and Technology Commission, of the Central Military Commission;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H556DA949D0164E13947C7070B9CE84E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any college or university in the People's Republic of China involved in military training and education, including any such college or university in partnership with the People's Liberation Army;</text></clause><clause id="H680C50A5873B4E9C8D1EE9A4B7231D50"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any college or university in the People's Republic of China that conducts military research or hosts dedicated military initiatives or laboratories, including such a college or university designated under the <quote>double first-class university plan</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HFDF3986F53674ADA835063BE2E3BDA8B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any college or university in the People's Republic of China that is designated by the State Administration for Science, Technology, and Industry for the National Defense to host <quote>joint construction</quote> programs; </text></clause><clause id="H968764F20E0C4A9791FDCC3CF37D71E5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any college or university in the People's Republic of China that has launched a platform for military-civil fusion or created national defense laboratories; and</text></clause><clause id="HEEED5BE653CA4DD1AB47678254209344"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any college or university in the People’s Republic of China that conducts research or hosts dedicated initiatives or laboratories for any other related security entity beyond the People’s Liberation Army, including the People’s Armed Police, the Ministry of Public Security, and the Ministry of State Security; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBF2FB10B23E4BA2B1DC2C8787AA4625"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any enterprise for which the majority shareholder or ultimate parent entity is the Government of the People’s Republic of China at any level of that government; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AA67831545549D6A005EB08E355FC87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any privately owned company in the People's Republic of China—</text><clause id="H7FFB5A88B46748AF9BC95D63969BA467"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has received a military production license, such as the Weapons and Equipment Research and Production Certificate, the Equipment Manufacturing Unit Qualification, the Weapons and Equipment Quality Management System Certificate, or the Weapons and Equipment Research and Production Unit Classified Qualification Permit;</text></clause><clause id="HB0C6FCEFBAD045DCBF6778B188427916"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is otherwise known to have set up mechanisms for engaging in activity in support of military initiatives; </text></clause><clause id="H384BE3677E9A42048B0C6D3EF7DEE1EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has a history of subcontracting for the People's Liberation Army or its affiliates;</text></clause><clause id="HBA7D35CE1D1844BBB602589A166783E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that is participating in, or receiving benefits under, a military-civil fusion demonstration base; or </text></clause><clause id="H14CA659DA3664A69964246796D812F37"><enum>(v)</enum><text>that has an owner, director, or a senior management official who has served as a delegate to the National People’s Congress, a member of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, or a member of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D6BF560E4DD43BCA5AA73D4267BB608"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any entity that—</text><clause id="H242930D3F69D4B28BC5E061799B6FA62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is identified by the Secretary of Defense under section 1260H(a) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note) as a Chinese military company; and</text></clause><clause id="H085333924BE24BA6B8115CECB94EEBFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is included in the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List published by the Department of the Treasury.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE6CC115C63A4DB0A3F9DF47C9209ECB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H3A6D604569624E6287D5688E3F06C5B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any Federal agency that engages in research or provides funding for research, including the National Science Foundation and the National Institutes of Health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F103333BA4348F6B69F0A15FBFC89F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any institution of higher education, or any other private research institution, that receives any Federal financial assistance; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB02D9C27B797492FA25254D5A9138E82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any private company headquartered in the United States that receives Federal financial assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC75EE455BC4890A3C39B8D1C7EDE6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial assistance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 200.1 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6AA307766E04998AA483167BF649D22"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Military-civil fusion strategy</header><text>The term <term>military-civil fusion strategy</term> means the strategy of the Chinese Communist Party aiming to mobilize non-military resources and expertise for military application, including the development of technology, improvements in logistics, and other uses by the People’s Liberation Army. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31101572B62947FAB22BE8D5EDB3BE81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><paragraph id="H212AEE0A8D084BAA9B91558807721F57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No covered entity may engage with a Chinese entity of concern in any scientific research or technical exchange that has a direct bearing on, or the potential for dual use in, the development of technologies that the Chinese Communist Party has identified as a priority of its national strategy of military-civil fusion and that are listed on the website under subsection (c)(1)(A). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF81577D8304947A902F9FA0409978E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private partnerships</header><text>No covered entity described in subsection (a)(2)(C) may form a partnership or joint venture with another such covered entity for the purpose of engaging in any scientific research or technical exchange described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DBD9894F54F492AB8168D0A6BC1A01D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Website</header><paragraph id="HDCF217A0B76E4F15BEF5AF7232EB5DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Commerce, shall establish, and periodically update not less than twice a year, a website that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H14ACBF58CC994AA586CBEB177FDED091"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the specific areas of scientific research or technical exchange for which the prohibitions under subsection (b) apply, which shall initially include some or all aspects of the fields of quantum computing, photonics and lasers, robotics, big data analytics, semiconductors, new and advanced materials, biotechnology (including synthetic biology and genetic engineering), 5G and all future generations of telecommunications, advanced nuclear technology (including nuclear power and energy storage), aerospace technology, and artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C2D1A969C549DE830142FD4553D5E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, a list of all Chinese entities of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF97DA9A3A8E64260B52B61ACF3A9DF9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of specific areas</header><text>In developing the list under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary of Defense shall monitor and consider the fields identified by the State Administration for Science, Technology, and Industry for the National Defense of the People's Republic of China as defense-relevant and consider, including the more than 280 fields of study designated as of the date of enactment of this Act, and any others designated thereafter, as disciplines with national defense characteristics that have the potential to support military-civil fusion. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABA606D503FC4498BE63D0AC253476A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>In establishing the website under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may use as a model any existing resources, such as the China Defense Universities Tracker maintained by the Australian Strategic Policy Institute, subject to any other laws applicable to such resources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC95F7F1DE954F31BC3987188C1FDA04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibitions under subsection (b) shall not apply to any collaborative study or research project in fields involving information that would not contribute substantially to the goals of the military‑civil fusion strategy, as determined by regulations issued by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60275D826C644A0BBDF3FD991788F780"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="HDB71C9FB1C1245BF9CAFEE4C631EED06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and December 31 of each year thereafter, each covered entity shall submit to the Secretary of Defense a report that discloses—</text><subparagraph id="H6D6335CC26064CBEB4312E1607B6FD65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any research relationships the covered entity has with a Chinese entity of concern or has had during the previous year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C8552E2D98E427D95D068D0EB3ED422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any research relationships the covered entity has considered with a Chinese entity of concern during the previous year and declined; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H237B228A0D0542AD93A66ED1261832EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any research relationships the covered entity has terminated with a Chinese entity of concern during the previous year because the relationship violates subsection (b) or as a result of related concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24C62B0BAF7C4A8C94C1D56D72FA89DF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may enter into a contract with an independent entity to conduct an audit of any report submitted under paragraph (1) to ensure compliance with the requirements of such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C8DEC3C732840E69F45AD5561CD3B0B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H9D78EB38A7054D5E9D4F42E14AF24DC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a covered entity described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(2) that violates a prohibition under subsection (b), or violates subsection (e), on or after the date of enactment of this Act shall be precluded from receiving any Federal financial assistance on or after the date of such violation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAF0C7DFC8140859281E8D07C800A7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB401079AE0934FECB3062DAE1BCC6961"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promulgate regulations to enforce the prohibitions under subsection (b), the auditing requirements under subsection (e), and the requirement under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC20455994CD40A4BFFC83381E7F7A03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with the heads of other Federal agencies to ensure the enforcement of such prohibitions and requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

