<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE9967D65A4124FCE94B2B40D845417AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6624 IH: Transatlantic Legislators’ Dialogue Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6624</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220207">February 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Transatlantic Legislators’ Dialogue (United States-European Union Interparliamentary Group), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H27990D347546483690971CB367129E75" style="OLC"><section id="H363D1EB7F73A47C199E8DC39BC6E6811" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transatlantic Legislators’ Dialogue Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H462013B586C94F508E1C57D414C515D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transatlantic Legislators’ Dialogue (United States-European Union Interparliamentary Group)</header><subsection id="HD16862D5297943E2985CBC9B34ABCF17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and meetings</header><paragraph id="H59D0E8AEE6DD4C5AB43701466A203B97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not to exceed 24 Members of Congress shall be appointed to meet not less than twice annually with representatives of the European Parliament for discussions of common problems in the interest of relations between the United States and the European Union.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2C2D7C97DB4E9C89D2A173418FC04A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>The Members of Congress appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be referred to as the <quote>United States Delegation</quote> of the Transatlantic Legislators’ Dialogue (United States-European Union Interparliamentary Group).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A2BB39258C7489EA775A84A01984F77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment and members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the Members of Congress appointed for purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HB1244E621FC24D0389D1E3BBA515A9D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>half shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the minority leader of the House, from among Members of the House (not less than 4 of whom shall be members of the Committee on Foreign Affairs); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H706A1072729C44C1837A1AB89B117E45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>half shall be appointed by the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, upon recommendations of the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, from among Members of the Senate (not less than 4 of whom shall be members of the Committee on Foreign Relations) unless the majority and minority leaders of the Senate determine otherwise.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3CF4B02D6DB49E2BC9D4C0AFCD28486"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson and ranking member</header><paragraph id="H2E57F781F3E74CDBB4A1D4A42DB2C1A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>House</header><text>The Chair and Vice Chair of the House Group shall be designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the minority leader of the House.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBCCAA9AA4D84D4B8D13A7C8738221B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President Pro Tempore of the Senate shall designate the Chair or Vice Chair of the Senate group of the United States Delegation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H665593377A304D23A5088BD92065110F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States group shall submit to the Congress a report for each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made for the United States Delegation, which shall include its expenditures under such appropriation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

