<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA503D2D376ED4A1A94021C895F3EE792" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>102 HR 8676 IH: Salton Sea Public Health and Environmental Protection Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior to take certain measures with respect to protecting the Salton Sea, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H087E237F93684E0DBC90062737145011" style="OLC"><section id="H4BD602BA23314C31A30C7DD569B38AA1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Salton Sea Public Health and Environmental Protection Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF5FC69956A8F41F58531183360C51281"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Salton Sea Management Acres</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XI of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/575">Public Law 102–575</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC8ED21AE3FF4A5AA904FBDD55906545" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H17372901230242F7BFE1BBFD2EB5076A"><enum>1102.</enum><header>Restoration program</header><subsection id="HDA5C405EB40F4359BC383146472A6F69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoration program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, shall provide for a program within the Bureau’s Salton Sea Program Office to improve water quality, provide for dust mitigation, protect the public’s health, and provide for environmental and habitat restoration at the Salton Sea in California.</text></subsection><subsection id="H52D26B7AA5C64A79B4F23FFB34A596BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Salton Sea Management Acres</header><paragraph id="HB2CF219D23F64ED580A2FA4E3882F201"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall provide for such measures as such Secretary determines appropriate for dust control and habitat conservation, consistent with State and local requirements, with respect to an acreage within the Salton Sea of the same size as the acreage for which the State of California provides for dust control and habitat conservation under the Salton Sea Management Program and the State Water Board Order. Such Secretary shall, to the maximum extent possible when carrying out this requirement, provide such measures for an equivalent number of acres of dust control and of habitat conservation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H706469EA51A849268E11A7D607627F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may calculate the satisfaction of the Federal Salton Sea Management Acres obligation described in paragraph (1) in three-year increments to account for variability in acres available and appropriate for management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE95C313AA3486890ADA537ABA84A03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with the State of California</header><subparagraph id="HE4714FCC718A422ABEE47A91FCA4133E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall seek to conclude a memorandum of understanding with the State of California and the Salton Sea Authority to coordinate Federal and State activities relating to the construction, operation, and maintenance of Federal Salton Sea Management Acres and Salton Sea Management Program activities. Such memorandum of understanding shall include a schedule delineating the timeframe for the accomplishment of the establishment of Salton Sea Management Acres and consideration of the effects of such memorandum of understanding on affected disadvantaged communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H812DE7143E774D559A53F90C708A87EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall make Federal lands within the Salton Sea available to the State of California for activities under the Salton Sea Management Program and the State Water Board Order and shall give priority to such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H749AF55F93054AB385EA0215D548E239"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall modify the State of California’s responsibilities or associated timelines under the State Water Board Order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C1EACE4AEDB4EEAA179AE80DB9481B0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Support from the Secretary of Agriculture</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall, in issuing funding or other types of support under such authority as is available to such Secretary, prioritize support and funding to assist the Secretary of the Interior in fulfilling the responsibilities described in this subsection. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52D2FAFC012A456CB5EFED1B59671FC5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Delegation to the State of California</header><subparagraph id="H6FEA727AEA2645D784B5EFC8F7045AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may delegate such Secretary’s responsibilities under this subsection to the State of California through a cooperative agreement or other contractual agreement only upon the provision by such Secretary to the State of adequate Federal funding to assure the requirements of this section are met, including funding for operations and maintenance of Federal Salton Sea Management Acres. Such Secretary may award grants to the State for completion of this responsibility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57D523A158B540FE86DF2C4C15A32567"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agreement pending funding not restricted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from entering such an agreement prior to the provision of such adequate Federal funding. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80CCDEAE1CE34D72AA8B7ACDC98BCA70"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Not a Special Aquatic Site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the construction, operation, and maintenance of Federal Salton Sea Management Acres and Salton Sea Management Program activities, lakebed exposed as the Salton Sea recedes shall not be considered a Special Aquatic Site for the purposes of determining jurisdiction under section 404 of the Clean Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBD29D0E576844B3AC3CDBA58655805A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall report to Congress annually identifying—</text><subparagraph id="H5EDF1A9293A34C86ADB495E0A5751275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of acres under management by such Secretary or funding provided to the State of California under paragraph (6);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H994960B2A691446FAE0A180624E786D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of management applied to Federal Salton Sea Management Acres, and whether such management is dust suppression or habitat restoration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EC8823C06AE4C7086D3D71294C0B691"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such Secretary has not met such Secretary’s responsibility under paragraph (1) over the current three-year period under paragraph (2), a plan for coming into compliance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31466F0B86C948548177E5385AB20061"><enum>(D)</enum><text>additional funding needed to meet such obligation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2141F29E4134466D8329E3535628548C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following terms have the meaning given to such terms in section 5 of the <short-title>Salton Sea Public Health and Environmental Protection Act of 2022</short-title>:</text><paragraph id="H3A166351CA544179B35E3DA9C5E5F489"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>Federal Salton Sea Management Acres</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD19828B3C8BE4A13BD9ABA02F8312340"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>Salton Sea Authority</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1748FF3B6ACD4C5AB64335C81110A25D"><enum>(3)</enum><text><quote>Salton Sea Management Program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA6DF23B871476FA4E286C0986C437F"><enum>(4)</enum><text><quote>State Water Board Order</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H343106C1C9B943DE8A9A1CC84C6EBF3B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Salton Sea Management Council</header><subsection id="HD7BE93F27EF9446886ED43B3FB9701E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Federal Salton Sea Council</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall establish a Salton Sea Council with the goal of coordinating interagency Salton Sea projects, expediting permits, coordinating environmental review, streamlining funding of projects associated with the Salton Sea Management Program and Federal Salton Sea Management Acres, and coordinating such goals with the State of California and the Salton Sea Authority. </text></subsection><subsection id="H286F9E58BFF343B4B8A86AD38BA2C394"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Council shall consist of the following and shall be chaired by the Secretary of the Interior: </text><paragraph id="HD8E73E886FAD4BBB8B3CE1E6A3260EF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, or a representative of such Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5D5AC65FEB446FA934B99D4838A1B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Army or a representative of such Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H638554604F2F4296924CDD9DA77CB3F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or a representative of such Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5FDCF6A617C4A5282D223BBD757E4B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation or a representative of such Commissioner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09BE81A1ACEE436CA6391B0B77807E55"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or a representative of such Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H570FC8293DEE422B8301B8BD5075722A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the United States Geological Survey or a representative of such Director. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D4E623CAD7547B993A998BD0536180B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Council shall—</text><paragraph id="HD10D0E99D69945F89E9562BEC20CBE66"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convene and establish a process for collaboration among the members of the Council, the State of California, the Salton Sea Authority, local communities, Tribal governments, the South Coast Air Quality Management District, the Imperial County Air Pollution Control District, and other persons, including holding at least one annual public meeting at the Salton Sea to receive feedback from local stakeholders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE59656B4440A4281A5145BED3DF1493F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a Federal funding plan across Federal agencies with jurisdiction at the Salton Sea to assist the Secretary in meeting the Salton Sea Management Acres obligation and associated operations and maintenance costs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94D06AA993324484A11C8EC66C1C1463"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify and implement measures to expedite and streamline Federal permitting of Salton Sea management undertaken by the State of California’s Salton Sea Management Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDAA1F6B136D4D51A0A1213EC610FB7A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Production of Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Council shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="H73647E43EDC442E2826140E87AFA0CC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies Federal and State funding sources and previous funding for projects and studies related to potentially benefitting or impacting the Salton Sea;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F7C1ACE1E624AAFA297C67E26791008"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzes how Federal and State funding sources can be matched or paired to reach acreage goals; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A729444DBAF44D9BADE0B68211600E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies additional Federal resources including resources for technical assistance and project permitting assistance that could be applied to the management of the Salton Sea.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAE8244FC356A4980A649D31E9CB1A878"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public health reporting requirement</header><subsection id="HFF792D2437E249389896FB1C965A1F39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall publish an annual report on air quality surrounding the Salton Sea, including an analysis of the presence of pollutants, salinity levels, and agricultural chemicals present in the exposed lakebed on Federal lands. Such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HDA1F78A73806455C8BAC80BC2B08919E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the change in number of acres of Federal land that is exposed lakebed and land with respect to which such Secretary has taken corrective action, either through habitat restoration or dust suppression; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79EAA6EB9ED842A492130EC0BAD10EB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any associated health risks with particulate matter pollution and any chemicals present.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E0A25154F55440E9EC33CE450C4B613"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Population health study</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may partner with a university or research institution to conduct a long-term population health study on individuals with extended exposure to the Salton Sea. </text></subsection><subsection id="HDF0DAD59C7884BF09DFC11920660E71B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional air monitors</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall take such measures as the Administrator determines necessary to monitor the air quality in population centers near the Salton Sea.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD4352E22942A46CC8B679B7B5EB021BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD188F281CCB84A9B89E696492A0DE7C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Salton Sea Management Acres</header><text>The term <quote>Federal Salton Sea Management Acres</quote> means the Salton Sea exposed lakebed acres required to be managed by the Secretary of the Interior for dust control or habitat in consultation with the State of California and Salton Sea Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DDB88A4D7CD4613B41007FC8004FBCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Salton Sea Authority</header><text>The term <quote>Salton Sea Authority</quote> means a Joint Powers Authority composed of member agencies including the Torres Martinez Desert Cahuilla Tribe, County of Imperial, the County of Riverside, the Coachella Valley Water District, and the Imperial Irrigation District, established to work in coordination with the State of California to oversee the comprehensive restoration of the Salton Sea. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12C9116B48E744B0AB1B961DC9E18AE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Salton Sea Management Program</header><text>The term <quote>Salton Sea Management Program</quote> means the program created by the State of California to address air quality and ecological threats at the Salton Sea.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB83AC7B942E4A4F8DFDB7BE33C5A970"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Salton Sea 10-Year Plan</header><text>The term <quote>Salton Sea 10-Year Plan</quote> means the State of California’s Salton Sea Management Program Phase 1: 10-year plan to provide for the construction of 30,000 acres of air quality and habitat projects at the Salton Sea.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39BEF3B2FB0046C28B299C247CD879A8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State Water Board Order</header><text>The term <quote>State Water Board Order</quote> means California State Water Board Order 2017–0134 entitled <quote>ORDER ACCEPTING AND REVISING STATE WATER BOARD REVISED ORDER WRO 2002–0013</quote> issued on November 7, 2017, establishing Salton Sea management acre milestones for the State of California.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

