<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAEEC904F60F04545B4064AFFA240ED8F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8689 IH: Commercial Space Transportation Safety Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8689</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to clarify the authority of the National Transportation Safety Board to investigate commercial space transportation accidents, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCC984B352773497486D5B8595C3733B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7B99C31473754EDAB307BAAA0755020B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commercial Space Transportation Safety Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDD5D406AB03D44D588668C4F87230657" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>General authority of the National Transportation Safety Board</header> <subsection id="H29C26E1C605E47189450A227062337EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1131(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H98FA31E178A2452B850D5BA97C063DEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD91494BBEC3C4E78821CC6BEA3351F30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63A6A91AE9E8414B95C7A1013BF98840"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H47D6E28FB9EF4979846DFDCB742EA402" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5E9BB68E25EF4252B0ED8A38B503EC99" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a commercial space transportation accident in which there is—</text> 
<clause id="H285A262DF71947FC90353C6C3A62176C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a fatality or significant injury of any individual, regardless of whether the individual was on board the commercial launch vehicle at the time of the accident; or</text></clause> <clause id="H34BABCF8DEE14B228443EEFCAE148207"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantial damage to property that is not associated with commercial space launch activities and that is not located at the launch site; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE4A0C8F4E8E7409387A7E3148551A056"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other investigative agencies</header><text>Section 1131(a)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H29FD357154744D5491E397C1694CC831" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="HD81DA34F5BA84E7BA8D96E0C30D2888B" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall seek to enter into a memorandum of agreement with any Government agency with the authority to certify a commercial space transportation operation or investigate a commercial space transportation accident. Such memoranda shall delineate the conditions under and manner in which—</text> 
<clause id="HB27C58500A6B4A7DAB48850EEFA9D394"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a commercial space transportation accident that may be investigated by the Board under subparagraph (F) or (G) of paragraph (1) will instead be investigated by the other Government agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCF50CED23B124CCBB2F0A713AD399FB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Board will participate in such other Government agency’s investigation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31D2255292AE4ACE8E01E5BEE274E347" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an occurrence in commercial space transportation other than an accident described in paragraph (1)(F), the Board may only investigate such occurrence—</text> <clause id="H7258B831DA674287816FD9F6BA3B4A6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with the terms of a memorandum of agreement with another Government agency described in subparagraph (D); or </text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E9C5CEEAC4B41C2A329C79847527AA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the agreement of the Government agency responsible for investigating such occurrence.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1B59F24EC5F6449E9CC18E6348EAEC6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical corrections</header><text>Section 1131(a)(2)(A) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or (F)</quote> and inserting <quote>(F), or (G)</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBDCC43ECC1E4685B201D57D5F3363BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>None of the amendments made by subsection (a) or (b) shall be construed to limit the authority of the National Transportation Safety Board to investigate any other commercial space transportation accident that, in the judgement of the Board, falls under the authority of the Board under section 1131(a)(1)(G) (as redesignated by this Act).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

