<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA036D8E82477479BBD214845874A2B93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7591 IH: Health Equity and Middle Eastern and North African Community Inclusion Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to include Middle Easterners and North Africans in the statutory definition of a <quote>racial and ethnic minority group</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF994D9E58BD84BF986DDBE3F504BA479" style="OLC"><section id="H72B6A313B7414D9285CA64A90D5C5FB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Equity and Middle Eastern and North African Community Inclusion Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Health Equity and MENA Community Inclusion Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC581236BC1824D489B446E587F6F4085"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of Middle Easterners and North Africans in definition of racial and ethnic minority groups</header><subsection id="HE370A3900BC24C719639B84BFA6603AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1707(g)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and Hispanics</quote> and inserting <quote>Hispanics, and Middle Easterners and North Africans</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H148A25CE0A5440FEAB6326FCE5C893F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specified, any reference to the term <quote>racial and ethnic minority group</quote> in any Federal regulation, guidance, order, or document for establishment or implementation of any federally conducted or supported health care or public health program, activity, or survey shall be treated as having the definition given to such term in section 1707(g)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)(1)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F13DB51862C4B2784D1F5E5A2F05435"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that subsections (a) and (b) should be implemented so as to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H671AF04A1ABD485BBF47FC962BFC0CC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the definition of a <quote>racial and ethnic minority group</quote> in section 1707(g)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is applied in the implementation and execution of Federal programs and activities that reference such definition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CAAF1B4EEDF4FC3BF2C9FCFFAD2B1B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no racial and ethnic minority group served by such programs and activities is negatively impacted by subsection (a) or (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7506EA7B384645EA95AF9513411005DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the level of funding authorized for such programs and activities in connection with communities of Middle Easterners and North Africans is commensurate with the level of funding authorized for such programs and activities in connection with other racial and ethnic minority groups, taking into consideration the size and needs of the respective populations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

