<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0694FA45B96E4148950BBEB701F9982B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7969 IH: To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on disaster spending and strategies for reducing the need for such spending, to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for certain activities relating to disasters and hazard mitigation, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7969</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on disaster spending and strategies for reducing the need for such spending, to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for certain activities relating to disasters and hazard mitigation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C291E9B12FA4BC29899B5814FA34C1D" style="OLC"><section id="H74D9BB666C8B4CA98E1FD83BC98F0744" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office study on disaster spending</header><subsection id="H50608FED0DB34E6AA3279679A6F617F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to identify the following:</text><paragraph id="H1BCF0270EF3244DB9381B9847C69F436"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the 5-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HB687E9810737452AA057521848A0FBF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of Federal funds spent in response to major disasters and emergencies declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEE3D64223C04393B90ADF1BA6C2946E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of State and Indian tribal government funds spent in response to such major disasters and emergencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F2603BA314241C0B43051A4BC9FF2C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 proposed Federal actions, to include reinsurance, that, if implemented, would most effectively reduce the need for spending related to such major disasters or emergencies. Such actions shall be listed in order of priority under criteria established by the Comptroller General, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H99022D2261B8485CBDEAC6F76AF02FED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cost effectiveness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD6B24FFB10E4D2D843252319E0B9D60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Return on investment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E1884C29F664BEBBE97505B856054FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Simplicity or speed of implementation using existing resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H819F5861E6BB4A0DA39051CF4E48E9C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The effect that using blockchain may have on delivering disaster assistance to State and Indian tribal governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88294FA3723C4C6896886CEDB7D0244D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether insurance protection against wildfires will remain available and affordable to homeowners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E8CEFFFBE0A4AFE845DD9245663F057"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the covered entities a report containing the results of the study.</text></subsection><subsection id="H412ACF723DCA4E39B87DFD42408F70BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2358E60CD74D49549A70C887B5AA5233"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entities</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6DE474612EEC456FAF9DD5C8FB11156B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9F692034ABE45C39C05AC89EAD57CA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDEA8AAEACE94415B19DFF13C1F4E93E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each State and Indian tribal government, the head of the agency for such State or Indian tribal government with jurisdiction over disaster response activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB14FF23D72D040D6B1A4E7CA39789A6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Indian tribal government</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAA97E719D9A64C569B2573B1B748850C"><enum>2.</enum><header>State disaster plan updates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB110C12757AA483C9A260F166D5DDABE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA5D8C3F2856B4F69916403744B38F0C9"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to State plans developed under this section, the President shall coordinate with each State to update such plans to incorporate strategies that decrease the time required to prepare for disasters, including the time to evacuate individuals.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7E6B7D32AAC2472E88CBA650FCEEF3B1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to entities for establishment of hazard mitigation revolving loan funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205(f) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5135">42 U.S.C. 5135(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEA4BE58EF920401282322185E3E52BA8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDB0C5D05AB9949738CEDE854EE3324A8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Set aside for certain projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participating entity shall ensure that at least 10 percent of the total dollar amount of the loans made by such entity under this subsection each fiscal year assist projects or activities that reduce risks, for residential structures, related to the natural hazards described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

