<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HACFAD1FBD7494B28B8234C4BF69CD644" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2026 RH: Global Amphibian Protection Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 408</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2026</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–567]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210318">March 18, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 18, 2021</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assist in the conservation of highly endangered amphibian species in foreign countries, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HD5B784EF1D3D42FB9D29CE01B4D2B657"><section id="H4578CA82B4294C9394DA1C318B96E574" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Amphibian Protection Act of 2021</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="HBAE575B94D324086A329C987C4337FFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H90E21366CBEB40DE9D9B86E87AC845E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Convention</header><text>The term <term>Convention</term> means the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora (27 UST 1087; TIAS 8249).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H549D9BBBB61A41B1BFB71479CD6FB82E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conservation</header><text>The term <term>conservation</term> means the protection and restoration of species and the habitat of such species.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB777D33BC4064A0DAFCC0ABD23F46197"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Highly Endangered Amphibians Conservation Fund established by section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DFD3B3C4A724BB0B5ACEE78A6BD2DD7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Highly endangered amphibian species</header><subparagraph id="H90A2D6ED98DC4172909E166BE98CB49B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>highly endangered amphibian species</term> means—</text><clause id="H0F19DB7C0AEE4CD2B006EF0A6858AE90"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amphibian species categorized on the International Union for Conservation of Nature Red List of Threatened Species as Endangered, Critically Endangered, or Extinct in the Wild; and</text></clause><clause id="H0CE88A4312E2488787CE6C309C58EF64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other amphibian species categorized on the International Union for Conservation of Nature Red List of Threatened Species as Data Deficient or under a threat category lower than Endangered if the Secretary determines that—</text><subclause id="HF2997724573A45B4B8D9D282CA88238C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the most recent International Union for Conservation of Nature Red List assessment indicates that the population is decreasing; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HFD72CE2A5C8849B9B84F05F72B40D8CB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such species is facing new or emerging threats.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01E99C66A8134A37AAF7E0BFC6760B1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>highly endangered amphibian species</term> includes—</text><clause id="H5EA944451D8247649C8D0FAA442DEC3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>live specimens, at all lifecycle stages, of species described in subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="HF094788F9D55431F9C425428A07C2B5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dead specimens, or parts or products thereof, of such species.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C552EBFF7A04219B1DB648E25DC9890"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Multinational species conservation fund</header><text>The term <term>Multinational Species Conservation Fund</term> means the fund established under the heading <quote>multinational species conservation fund</quote> in title I of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4246">16 U.S.C. 4246</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1517F6C0F8764412A086D1812A346033"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0FF1A435241741E394D385842B3B02BA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Highly endangered amphibian species assistance</header><subsection id="HA0AB4C3865F84B2F9DBDA73C63EE66AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In consultation with other Federal officials, the Secretary shall use amounts in the Fund to carry out a competitive grant program to provide financial assistance for the conservation of highly endangered amphibian species.</text></subsection><subsection id="H422BAFFDE39544B89237580D2D4A1C48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project proposals</header><paragraph id="HD6ECEA19B97F493D80EC09CE8FC316A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>A proposal for a grant under subsection (a) may be submitted to the Secretary by—</text><subparagraph id="H3ABE7BA4C7ED40D0B5F5DA40F1014CCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any wildlife management authority of a foreign country that has within its boundaries natural habitat of a highly endangered amphibian species if the activities of the authority directly or indirectly benefit that species’ conservation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC23D00BEBBF44B47A702064489387D23"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other person or group with the demonstrated expertise and capacity required for the conservation of a highly endangered amphibian species.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7059CB3E19B847668994D21F18F036AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required elements</header><text>A project proposal shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H8A7B43D36FA84F31A7B4C26164454BBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence of support for the project by appropriate governmental entities of the country in which the project will be conducted, if the Secretary determines that such support is required for the success of the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33CB0557F30B4006A5D5DA5BD100E65B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence of sensitivity to local historic and cultural resources and compliance with applicable laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21134359A1804B75BD6869D7E46E5A26"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence of free, prior, and informed consent by indigenous peoples and local communities in the areas the project will be conducted, if the Secretary, based on the nature of the project, determines that such consent is required for the success of the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A040C70BABC4114A124D80A726A3300"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information regarding the source and amount of matching funding available for the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E8F29948A14F7EADD2560E07C2966D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H14D018B0909C4EE786448806E17DC3E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation and Approval</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC8FCB9E1994444CBE849679D38A5C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The Secretary may approve a proposal under this section if the project will—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H89A1AC3D483C44F58DCF879F94CA526A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help recover and sustain viable populations in the wild of a highly endangered amphibian species with a range that is, in whole or in part, outside of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA656ED7AD616498DACC8A62BD64F5CD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance compliance with provisions of the Convention and laws of the United States or a foreign country related to the conservation of a highly endangered amphibian species; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAF4608C6CA644FE5873AFCBA2D14BC96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop sound scientific information on that species’ habitat, population numbers and trends, reproduction, mortality, and other threats to survival.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2DFA158D99DD49EC8764A5DF8D652B87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may approve a proposal under this section if the proposal would achieve one of the goals set forth in paragraph (1) through—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9B5C1E944D8446DB9FBF4190606F9BB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protection, restoration, and management of habitat;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H53A6CDED9DD04FE8B770E01BAF90A19F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in situ research and monitoring of populations, habitats, annual reproduction, and species population trends;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3D04254F8614F71ACC72D865233EB8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">development, implementation, and improvement of national and regional management plans for a highly endangered amphibian species and the habitat of such species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H39646C7B65834CF991C80AE1EEFFF226"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enforcement and implementation of the Convention or the law of a foreign country to—</text><clause commented="no" id="H839FE5511FEA493B9715A0ED322D5433"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect and manage a highly endangered amphibian species or the habitat of such species;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9D883240F6B94E28A44F1F76D5651E0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent illegal or unsustainable removal of a highly endangered amphibian species from the wild; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFB657732E0FB45E5AC6F3133E84DACE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent illegal trade of a highly endangered amphibian species;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H70BFE63D125447E8866E63895CF35630"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training and capacity building for local law enforcement officials in the interdiction and prevention of the illegal killing, removal from the wild, or trade of a highly endangered amphibian species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H843C4681CAE342A78905198C9A13DBCF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an initiative to resolve a conflict between humans and a highly endangered amphibian species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H837A11342976432C9F9E755821582DFF"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research and implementation of projects to address disease and threats to the health of a highly endangered amphibian species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8700848163664B4AB42AF70D45C91EAF"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community outreach and education on conservation of a highly endangered amphibian species and the habitat of such species; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H00F226B460494736841251D3C6927191"><enum>(I)</enum><text>strengthening the ability of local communities to implement a conservation program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6426286BA74570B300096C92C77F07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, prior to approving any proposal under this section, consult with each of the following with respect to such proposal:</text><subparagraph id="HCB06FCE148D54D0AAD04C14EEC0280C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Government of each country in which such proposal will be carried out.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69C103971AA64FB3B7BCF45BDDFC3590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any other Federal agency the Secretary determines is appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE684643A9EE34FEEB6C3FF8D848BEAEE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preferential consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to approve a proposal, the Secretary shall give preference to a proposal that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H08FB6ABBB2034CB18EA4693798A2F037"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed to ensure effective, long-term conservation of highly endangered amphibian species and their habitats; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB0CEBC150A644AC2BD71D42DC5D0623E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has matching funds available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAB07269F7E444AD19104CF886F927079"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The Secretary shall, within 180 days of receiving a proposal under this section, approve or disapprove of the proposal and provide written notification of such approval or disapproval to—</text><subparagraph id="HF4CA3BD334574A3EB5D8BE1EC373B8FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person who submitted such proposal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC66674E9C140A5BD46F9353CDA8874"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal agency the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B5972BF5FF49E0BFE9ACAC54D0003C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the foreign country in which such proposal would be carried out.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8D69EB9EF614CF7A1CE23851B28DDC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project reporting</header><paragraph id="HA9928AB755C0490DB77449EF74961FF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall require each person that receives assistance under this section to submit periodic reports including such information as the Secretary may require in order to evaluate the progress and success of each grant issued under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56A215680833432A9EDDB0632F570BA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>Reports under paragraph (1), and any other documents relating to projects for which financial assistance is provided under this Act except for documents that the Secretary determines to be confidential in nature, shall be made available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42BCC9AA83EA40BAB8B4E4D88D0DB84B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations on use for captive breeding</header><text>Amounts provided as a grant under this Act—</text><paragraph id="H360DC060C3474CC682A3B2096E59BDE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be used for captive breeding of highly endangered amphibian species other than for captive breeding designed for release into the wild; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07BC601A94BE4657A57B7CCE162E5E6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be used for captive breeding of a species for release into the wild only if no other conservation method for the species is biologically or technically feasible.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFBB84A2748AE47EE8888D06E36CE93F9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Highly Endangered Amphibian Species Conservation fund</header><subsection id="HC79591C938424F5398010350462786D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Multinational Species Conservation Fund a separate account to be known as the <quote>Highly Endangered Amphibian Species Conservation Fund</quote>, consisting of—</text><paragraph id="H7B28893054F74164BF1821DA78A2732C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amounts transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit into the Fund under subsections (d) and (e);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D8C7F41148A46A9AA192618787BEF54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>amounts appropriated to the Fund under section 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E94D81DF3F7486ABA8674E2E77F43E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Fund under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F0964D771904B88A912E905839F1ED1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenditures from fund</header><paragraph id="HBBA7AA6884DC40CD874C7258778DA310"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), at the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the Fund to the Secretary, without further appropriation, such amounts as the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDE188799E674670A832471E0474E056"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the amounts in the account available for each fiscal year, the Secretary may expend not more than 3 percent, or up to $150,000, whichever is greater, to pay the administrative expenses necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2B6339FD1274C48A82EF502C25C7E4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header><paragraph id="H097AA46017D944BCA9387BBD72421A42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury, required to meet current withdrawals. Investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E979DB67DD0473F91262DE464E3465C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisition of obligations</header><text>For the purpose of investments under paragraph (1), obligations may be acquired—</text><subparagraph id="HAF0858EC590D453DA4B228E27B53550D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on original issue at the issue price; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E4B146828064290BAF431879457FC5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by purchase of outstanding obligations at market price.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C544AD67AFE44EA82CAEF8DFF153277"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sale of obligations</header><text>Any obligation acquired by the Fund may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at market price.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CDB9449F51648B2A6A9FC3111C5E1A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Credits to fund</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F2698E5317943BBA7CCC3D1F4203A1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfers of amounts</header><paragraph id="H4E1842B3FD604053BE7730D087214379"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amounts required to be transferred to the Fund under this section shall be transferred at least monthly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8421793175AF48B28EEA9FD5C12FA2E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>Proper adjustment shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB06B01AD203744F99556FEA3D6A2CCF9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acceptance and use of donations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may accept and use donations to provide assistance under section 3. Amounts received by the Secretary in the form of donations shall be transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit in the Fund. The Secretary may reject a gift under this section when the rejection is in the interest of the Government.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1452FBFB61E9418AB07195AAB504E5AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027.</text></section><section id="H99E0A401FD4F4C8D9F67DA0DA0B9AA99"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results and effectiveness of the program carried out under this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

