<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HFB59FBAB19D84C05A164385D71349E87" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8466 : Chai Suthammanont Healthy Federal Workplaces Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8466</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221011">October 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the head of each agency to establish a plan relating to the safety of Federal employees and contractors physically present at certain worksites during a nationwide public health emergency declared for an infectious disease, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA1419279239947509820BB0FD26020A9" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HEF716B4B9B7542D596CBBA0697DBFEFB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chai Suthammanont Healthy Federal Workplaces Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7D61C51801304EFDB6EE876499CD8734"><enum>2.</enum><header>Worksite safety for Federal employees and contractors</header><subsection id="H35127C84DE114068A331D4C8316FA45C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance of policies and procedures by agencies</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each agency, in consultation with the Chief Human Capital Officer of the agency and the Assistant Director of Administration of the agency (or any individual holding an equivalent position), shall—</text><paragraph id="H37CBC77AE3724E96BE697012CFB783C0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a plan containing procedures and policies for the safety of covered individuals physically present at worksites during a covered period that includes measures to ensure the continuity of operations of the agency, including how consistent agency mission and program performance and customer service levels will be sustained through the covered period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA5F8309A5B348738EEEA621005FC3E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such plan available to the public by including a prominent link to such plan on the home page of the website of the agency; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF055AF7CBB448BA94BF51732FD4293D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide a link to such plan to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget for inclusion on the web page of the Office in accordance with subsection (c); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA60308248BF4D5F887E467843403077" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>communicate such plan to each covered individual in such a manner as to ensure that each such covered individual acknowledges receipt and understanding of the plan. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7AE4CB99508448CBD4EC29313DAB6F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>The plan required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, include the following:</text><paragraph id="HC9106F71C25C45C3A352077FFEF1EABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the efforts the agency plans to take with respect to mitigating a nationwide public health emergency declared for an infectious disease at worksites, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8D3E09D84D4E440AB022FDB8DE6C8DE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of any personal protective equipment that is being or will be provided by the agency to any covered individual physically present at a worksite during a covered period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB222780C25C41E6A8B8E73F4B6AC3C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any procedures established by the agency for—</text><clause id="H185A6373A4C640B8B7B40A153608EC12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>testing covered individuals at worksites for a covered condition;</text></clause><clause id="HFB4BEBE29CC74B328823D6296BC55410" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying covered individuals potentially exposed to an individual who is diagnosed with a covered condition, and notifying such individuals of such potential exposure; and</text></clause><clause id="HE777B1D0BD8A4B6788220389CA7D1DD3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing differences in data, such as the number of cases, hospitalizations, and deaths, in regions and localities if an agency has covered worksites in more than one region.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC510AEC0C7C544F29D7406B93CF98E12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Guidance on—</text><subparagraph id="H2CF6961DD1904CB1B2DC38B3C9A7A830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any cleaning protocols to be implemented at covered worksites;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDBF6666991944B4A796EE477A92FA80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>occupancy limits for covered worksites; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E9A3C4387F40D6AC134F8062B93795"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of personal protective equipment, such as appropriate face coverings, by covered individuals while physically present at a worksite.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8163F4D6DF44D5CBE83E1A80C1971D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the actions the agency is or will be taking to protect employees of the agency who conduct activities in an official capacity while not physically present at a covered worksite, including employees—</text><subparagraph id="HC650E576465947CFB04FF566197DCA2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who are required to travel in an official capacity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5312FD5EC58748E399F360B69926248B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>perform audits or inspections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59AD223BF9E34D02BB668AB07C87CD81"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any requirements that members of the public are required to meet in order to enter a facility in which covered worksites are located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA64966BF8D324945A2654820A4B76BA1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of any alternative option to being physically present at a covered worksite that is available for employees of the agency who—</text><subparagraph id="HE9B88E076A02409AA24F4F3F254C2CCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a high risk of contracting a covered condition (as determined by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E43BE4D70D54B298E1265DC4A6D07C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>live in a household with individuals who have a high risk of contracting a covered condition (as determined by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC3F211A153649B989180F690B92BBD1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Protocols that ensure the continuity of operations of the agency, including how consistent agency mission and program performance and customer service levels will be sustained through the covered period, to include if the agency adopts enhanced and temporary telework and remote work practices as a result of an increase in the severity of the nationwide public health emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7450227CA25C4CEF83C1DD558AD2042A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The hotline website and hotline telephone number of the Inspector General of the agency for covered individuals to report to the Inspector General any instance in which the agency is not implementing the plan required by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF8CEE729594B16B3909CB4AFC3EF23" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The hotline website and hotline telephone number of the Office of Special Counsel to report a substantial and specific danger to public health and safety or whistleblower retaliation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9304D762B886455D9EE4B843AAF809C9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall make available to the public on a single web page of the Office—</text><paragraph id="H9615E183A83E48E09EB3F261214D8885" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>links to each plan provided to the Director pursuant to subsection (a)(3); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E81234513747CBA3031D89D229B7C1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list identifying any agency that has not provided a link pursuant to such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8CB65C6EE16435EA45FA1E5012AA4C9" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Communication of plan to new employees, contractors, and subcontractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of an agency shall communicate the plan required by subsection (a), in the manner described under such subsection, to—</text><paragraph id="HB0685E5AB06E47CFA717DE416C5E0911" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any new employee of the agency, not later than 30 days after the date on which such employee is hired; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D5E229C2524B0E8A9A68431B865F5D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any individual or entity that enters into a contract with the agency after such date, not later than 30 days after the contract is entered into; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80139112DB04D21B0DE6CFE73ECFE43"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual or entity that enters into a subcontract at any tier of a contract with the agency after such date, not later than 30 days after the subcontract is entered into. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F05139A180D4395A5782854E6CDA014"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inspectors general reports</header><paragraph id="H8E11AAA1F3874EA2946AEA42578C9038"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on implementation of this section</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of each agency shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the implementation of this section, including whether each agency involved has published and communicated the plan required by subsection (a) in accordance with this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD456515DE6E74CF18623C0A5A4EF5E70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on implementation of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the head of an agency begins to implement a plan required under subsection (a) with respect to a covered condition, the Inspector General of each agency shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on—</text><subparagraph id="H24D397DD16E144CDA616CB24F121A65B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which each agency has implemented the plan, including identifying any concerns for the safety of covered individuals at covered worksites that the agency has not fully addressed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBDBE300C7AA41B0AFB204C1EAFFE525"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which such plan incorporated best practices to contain the spread of such covered condition. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EF68EC49C5D41B1AEE4808FA21BBB55"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on lessons learned by agencies and covered individuals during the COVID–19 pandemic to further improve the policies and procedures of such agencies with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H1A5C7446EEE1437B8A5972A1065C8ECA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the health and safety of covered individuals during nationwide public health emergencies declared for infectious diseases; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97B868E5CE0D4F48A3548D1F0198567E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communication to covered individuals during nationwide public health emergencies declared for infectious diseases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H573104578F0D43939370CE5AF115B76E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter or otherwise limit the rights and obligations afforded under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79831B011E7043C18BB7F928318EFA69"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB2E6D1487C814642849B574E020662ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H202C6CD8E5AC4D79AB3FA6C80FF9997B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered condition</header><text>The term <quote>covered condition</quote> means an infectious disease that is the subject of a nationwide public health emergency. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3988A5D0E1B44A085C7E1FC13AD0E50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text>The term <quote>covered period</quote> means a period during which a nationwide public health emergency declared for an infectious disease is in effect. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8FF4788EE14749807F8BBF1CD3728A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8D9A07CE7104438FBB0B2B427B3E3E51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of the agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55F1B13CAB224FE29F35D0F8E37BFFF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contractors of the agency, and subcontractors thereof at any tier. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0168978417B4AA6856319133F942DFA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered worksite</header><text>The term <quote>covered worksite</quote> means a worksite at which a covered individual is required to be present during a covered period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H708E6FFDFC9D429ABFD1169B91317641"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <quote>employee</quote> means any employee occupying a position in the civil service (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) at an agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9644A642C958456C8D1C8683153CCEE7" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nationwide public health emergency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nationwide public health emergency</quote> means a nationwide public health emergency declared by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247">42 U.S.C. 247</external-xref>), including any renewal thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11051781119F4888A0F9C493E6D2727D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Worksite</header><text>The term <quote>worksite</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBFEA074DE6C74E43B4126BEFA78E00A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an employee of the agency, the location of the employee’s position of record where the employee regularly performs his or her duties, but does not include any location where the employee teleworks (as that term is defined in section 6501 of title 5, United States Code); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F0809C1FC82486B87078594856ABCB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a contractor of the agency (or subcontractor thereof at any tier), the location in a facility of the agency where the contractor or subcontractor performs his or her duties under a contract with the agency, or a subcontract thereof at any tier, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8D9826C4E6D9447CB1D1B060624DD86B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220928" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 29, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

