<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7F95E1B403649DEA7A511AD93A83992" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>105 HR 6962 IH: District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6962</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide information on certain persons under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7108E8A28C344982A27220FE9282F88A" style="OLC"><section id="HF774C5CA7F054C539AE435473BD39B72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H54294027BC364A0CBDC89C6EC4106B47"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of information to the Mayor of the District of Columbia related to certain persons under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of law described in section 3, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide to the Mayor of the District of Columbia for each person under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons pursuant to the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/33">Public Law 105–33</external-xref>), the following:</text><paragraph id="H90B3BFA76EC64A5C8809AD06EE71F273"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annually, the following information:</text><subparagraph id="HA28DAC7D72D14932A3E42C08952A51DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name, date of birth, and Federal Register Number of the person. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0693699CF328469A8E6A4EA639F592DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Bureau of Prisons facility where the person is housed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H364A829A35F54F85B9BD0877F8456AEA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The scheduled release date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B13106BD2DC42348F63E8CECE4F8636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon the request of the Mayor, the information that the Director provides for such person to the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2D57B2999A014E349FFB5428F232E077"><enum>3.</enum><header>Provisions of law described</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of law described in this section are as follows:</text><paragraph id="HB87026FEF21545B8BDCA63D1B1CA1851"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Title II of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (including parts 160 and 165 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF03FC774D04092963CCB06B2E9E3E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 543 of the Public Health Service Act (including part 2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B8EE50077EF4D48A1B8179923EDF690"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Privacy Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H041D6A609E844CE7A45513A25B8E7E12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other provision of Federal law that provides substantially similar protections for the privacy of information as the provisions of law described in paragraphs (1) through (3).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE8F634E0D546442F9C562034C7E249E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application of Privacy Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provision of information under this Act shall be deemed to be a lawful disclosure under section 552a(b)(7) of title 5, United States Code.</text></section><section id="H983968A6D189487D8C4708306615838E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on District of Columbia disclosure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mayor of the District of Columbia may not disclose the information provided pursuant to this Act outside of the District of Columbia government, except that the Mayor may provide the information provided under paragraph (1) of section 2 to counsel for the detained individuals, and to organizations that provide legal representation to individuals in criminal or post-conviction matters, or in matters related to re-entry.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

