<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74963B58D3664C21929DF0B4E46366D8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8840 IH: Improving Access to Advanced Care Planning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8840</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to waive cost-sharing for advance care planning services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7D731FD628A44B2BBF25D86E20815292" style="OLC"><section id="H8265E77F7FE14E28963064A45AE3B9B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Access to Advanced Care Planning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA8671F425777481897623348B5785704"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare coverage of advance care planning services</header><subsection id="HB2F0978F6F8E483EBE9E2E8CB1F766AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advance care planning services defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H361EE18E0565422DA43147CDDCC516BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEF46D2AA883D4A8CA5733617131017B3"><enum>(lll)</enum><header>Advance care planning services</header><paragraph id="id43D50431DCC941ED901ED2D8941A4922" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>advance care planning services</quote> means a visit between an eligible practitioner (as defined in paragraph (2)) enrolled under section 1866(j) and an individual, a family member of such individual, or a surrogate designated by such individual, to discuss—</text><subparagraph id="H9C6C5C0551184372817C5ADE29D39895" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the health care preferences of such individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H346730B147444273A0F97C1098A2A941" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>future health care decisions that may need to be made by, or on behalf of, such individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2C7716409384E829F76A2F51C5C0995" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advance directives or other standard forms, which may be completed by, or on behalf of, such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC21630E3352248E6BC77E90A23468A02" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>eligible practitioner</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD7BB531CF734450BA594B9D335D68639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a physician (as defined in subsection (r));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD01CDDD136C84BBABB9A71730C57A184"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a physician assistant (as defined in subsection (aa)(5));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF48CB9F5044773BB84E65541B05A1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nurse practitioner (as defined in subsection (aa)(5));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EB9A25EEA414B5EB603B6000065E101"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a clinical nurse specialist (as defined in subsection (aa)(5)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45344025DCDE45F4A9625E7BC37BBA6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a clinical social worker (as defined in subsection (hh)(1)) that possesses—</text><clause id="HAC0EA37B98F24126818EDA19FCF0CE66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a relevant care planning certification; or</text></clause><clause id="H9BE039D0BC5C417DB915CBB065DC3D55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>experience providing care planning conversations or similar services, as defined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3253038F60B24DC7A31D5C88EB89EAB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No application of coinsurance or deductible under part B</header><paragraph id="H867AB9872C094A658D0F66F1AFFDD2FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC3E018094E1E4079BB1B13A8E542CC71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (DD)</quote> and inserting <quote>(DD)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82FEB1F75DEB43B391A4BC70E2275104"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>and (EE) with respect to advance care planning services (as defined in section 1861(lll)), the amounts paid shall be 100 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for the services or the amount determined under the fee schedule established under section 1848(b)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AACAD7C1B2F4978B5F14E4EB2A15091"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver of application of deductible</header><text>The first sentence of section 1833(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HFD7214FC72454510B5DE76050ECB6E07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (12)</quote> and inserting <quote>(12)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4913D5E46EC94AD5A9D94CFF87DDF3C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and (13) such deductible shall not apply with respect to advance care planning services (as defined in section 1861(lll))</quote> after <quote>section 1861(s)(10)(A)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H581F604E7A5B42A4B94EE829D635A17A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to advance care planning services furnished on or after January 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF080A6CDB50B4976AC11392E2C69DB73"><enum>3.</enum><header>HHS provider outreach and report</header><subsection id="H691AA06D6EB24C7593D12B11CF7B8EB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct outreach to physicians and appropriate non-physician practitioners participating under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to Medicare payment for advance care planning counseling services furnished to individuals to discuss their health care preferences, identified by HCPCS codes 99497 and 99498 (or any successor to such codes). Such outreach shall include a new, comprehensive, one-time education initiative to inform such physicians and practitioners of the addition of such services as a covered benefit under the Medicare program, including the eligibility requirements for such services.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD65E2C9E35BB45189DBAFD18E1526DE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>HHS report on provider outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the outreach conducted under subsection (a). Such report shall include a description of the methods used for such outreach.</text></subsection></section><section id="H06E84DBFE32F439A843AF9DAA1BC0F73" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>MedPAC study and report on provision of advance care planning services and use of advance care planning codes</header><subsection id="HE6001939B46143E8AF417B73E355BF66" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall conduct a study on advance care planning services under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) analyzing—</text><paragraph id="H1D9730DE97414293863078EEDE01ADDA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the furnishing of advance care planning services to Medicare beneficiaries, including—</text><subparagraph id="H8FBD50735AA44DE5BF8C566813146DDA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which providers are trained to provide such services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF72DBB188548D486B969D14FDC2759" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which providers are eligible to provide such services under the Medicare program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB83D68B1583A4FFE890827F76414C617" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length and frequency of the visits for furnishing such services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B742F1F3F344497A12974C878B31238" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any barriers related to providers furnishing, or beneficiaries being furnished, such services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H981F111BDBDD4D7FB5D61BA79267C5C5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of advance care planning Current Procedural Terminology (CPT) codes to bill for the furnishing of advance care planning services to Medicare beneficiaries, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5141DF2DB50B49C89102A37E4BD2A26E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">circumstances under which codes other than advance care planning CPT codes are used to bill for such services under the Medicare program and why providers do not use advance care planning CPT codes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EADE6868FB44331B3C2535FBB7E84C8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any barriers to providers using advance care planning CPT codes to bill for such services under the Medicare program; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD09E5707400D4D0F91B1C8BAB2FD6E88" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other items determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADF58154457C48488992A9A20DB9EFCF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2024, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, a report on the study conducted under subsection (a), including recommendations for legislative and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

