<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H20BC2B9F168845FB85C971456A33E0BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7896 IH: No ESG at TSP Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7896</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit investments under the Thrift Savings Plan in certain mutual funds that make investment decisions based primarily on environmental, social, or governance criteria.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H93B231288B3C4687BD96DF3C5608A3ED" style="OLC"><section id="HE3EFF85EB2234BD9B2C1A9B41F078303" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No ESG at TSP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H060609C5F4494D629A9086CBE7B1DDF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain mutual funds under the Thrift Savings Plan</header><subsection id="H0448D9D28E2942EDB6CB27F5B3F8D85B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8438(b)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0B5DF2D548F14289A6170E644F5AD73C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H5E25C774C9E94B62AD9C82E405C05587" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may not offer through the mutual fund window any mutual fund, exchange traded fund (as defined in section 270.6c–11 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations), or other investment vehicle that invests in bonds or equities that is invested based on any one or more of the following criteria to the extent that such criteria are unrelated to maximizing monetary returns for investors:</text><clause id="H96D02625F3284EF2B3F0249BED655910"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Environmental criteria, including—</text><subclause id="H3329D1B7A6DC4D09A11EAF95603720A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>emissions, climate change, sustainability, environmental justice, pollution, or conservation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3BA441A66D164A3FB1CF59E2C3A52AD8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether a company is engaged in the exploration, production, utilization, transportation, sale, or manufacturing of fossil fuel-based energy.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H64A04D073F264FE49FA13059F117707E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Social criteria, including—</text><subclause id="H98F089ADBF214DEFB945009E25BA2DD3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">diversity criteria, including—</text><item id="H7A133ACD01824765A35F847277D5F93B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the race, ethnicity, gender identity, sexual orientation, or socioeconomic status of the owners, board members, employees, or customers of companies; or</text></item><item id="HCA4D077AE7914867B90C950E1A323B21"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whether such board members, employees, or customers are members of a labor organization (as such term is defined in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>)); or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H73235BB2CE3C421DAD62A9B0B9E5D678"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether a company is engaged in the manufacture, transportation, or sale of firearms, firearms accessories, or ammunition.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF147875FD59E423EAC1BDE8F4041A9FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Political criteria, including the perceived or actual political affiliations, donations, or associations of companies.</text></clause><clause id="H4E12CF5414BC4AD8A68523AE2BA5F3C1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Criteria for corporate governance standards that differ from the applicable standards required under State and Federal law as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD81E2E1570094DF49B149CDF86080021" indent="up2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may not offer through the mutual fund window any mutual fund, exchange traded fund (as defined in section 270.6c–11 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations), or other investment vehicle that is marketed as being invested based on environmental, social, or governance criteria, commonly known as <quote>ESG criteria</quote>.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H282A2556A2944A2B81DD981D33830EBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing investments in impermissible mutual funds</header><paragraph id="HB9B5189B97F1410A869EBCEDCBFCF91A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee or Member (or former employee or Member) may elect to have any covered sums credited to the account of such individual in the Thrift Savings Fund reinvested in accordance with section 8438 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14149AD6286740DFA53C89E2C567E90C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board shall notify each employee or Member (or former employee or Member) that may make an election under paragraph (1) of the option to make such election.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A730E97D864EAC9A296B18F5B4EF50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mandatory reinvestment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which notice is provided under paragraph (2) to an employee or Member (or former employee or Member), the Board shall reinvest, in accordance with section 8438 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by this Act, any covered sums credited to the account of such individual in the Thrift Savings Fund with respect to which such individual has not made an election under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H614AB057429D41ED998473A2A6F5F460"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H11A34B5A7CA34B90A068441C4734628F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Board; employee; Member</header><text>The terms <term>Board</term>, <term>employee</term>, and <term>Member</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8401 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34ABCB34F9BD45CEB72B5087DCA1CDF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered sums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered sum</term> means any sums of the Thrift Savings Fund that, on the date of the enactment of this Act, are invested in a mutual described in section 8438(b)(5)(E) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD01C5A0F5FFF47D3A0C2410B485423ED"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Thrift Savings Fund</header><text>The term <term>Thrift Savings Fund</term> means the fund established under section 8437 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

