<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H70E4C7F1B9434FE48782CBE1BFF76C1A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7556 IH: Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220421">April 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43BD4D2AA6F145EA9E29A54D1F652E24" style="OLC"><section id="H33C27946DFE54222BAA27EC7165F9A4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H9475C1EF4BDA4D6D87ACB960D573F81A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCBE13FE9AD494F1185F79883F40F5D97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H33C27946DFE54222BAA27EC7165F9A4B">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC235A6EBC08D46FCB15C2AFB621E04F3">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HF46A79AD43564B4DA40CA29AF092AEF7">TITLE I—Board of Veterans' Appeals matters</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H39DE16E3A7194118969EECC580EC6160">Sec. 101. Board of Veterans' Appeals internship program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HEA987914540C41EFAA0DE0ECA667E595">Sec. 102. Pilot program on establishment of Board of Veterans' Appeals honors program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2D277CE6C77D459B8C6D1F11A4A0283E">Sec. 103. Report on improving access to Board of Veterans' Appeals telehearings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HB9227CE55C944BAC909C0E109A50AC63">TITLE II—Medical disability exam matters</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE67CEFC7517D42F8A4F09BFEE87884D3">Sec. 201. Improving requirement to publish disability benefit questionnaire forms of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC32EB88ABDA548E08765F2D21680B14F">Sec. 202. Report on improving medical disability examinations for veterans who live abroad.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H008F30BA1FC64D67B234355FB667E10D">Sec. 203. Department of Veterans Affairs requirement for communication by contractors providing covered medical disability examinations with persons recognized by power of attorney for preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H53ED146217494E66838BB07A2606E88F">Sec. 204. Department of Veterans Affairs outreach regarding contact information for contractors providing covered medical disability examinations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H16CB9E3936D24FA19FD0A2EB71945C70">TITLE III—Other matters</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2DD24935F5794A39940F320BFDE62107">Sec. 301. Report on supporting governmental veterans service officers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA76AA50EB4B14A1E88213AD342520E93">Sec. 302. Electronic notification of decisions and other electronic communications.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HBBB82C2D5A1046969E420D22CD6187F9">Sec. 303. Facilitating Department of Veterans Affairs contractor access to Federal tax return information necessary for claims processing.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HC235A6EBC08D46FCB15C2AFB621E04F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="H8211B627B6B74224BE5A30738ADD4AA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claimant</header><text>The term <term>claimant</term> has the meaning given that term in section 5100 of title 38, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H024E01DACF0F4CE7ADF086082FC18920"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Veterans Affairs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F390CBC1DD347B4B6C1EEB7492C328F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. </text></paragraph></section><title id="HF46A79AD43564B4DA40CA29AF092AEF7" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Board of Veterans' Appeals matters</header><section id="H39DE16E3A7194118969EECC580EC6160"><enum>101.</enum><header>Board of Veterans' Appeals internship program</header><subsection id="HC6333067BAAF4396A99CCFF002F874D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section: </text><quoted-block id="H465553D289DB41299FB1834FBCF1F824" style="USC" act-name=""><section id="H1277A8D811D9453ABCF0E6BC284B9E71" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7114.</enum><header>Internship program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a competitive internship program within the Department for the purpose of providing an opportunity for high-achieving students at law schools accredited by the American Bar Association to gain experience with the Board.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3EB10D37EE674CAA8B4161D6F8E14EBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2472E55EE4FF4E6DB049EBD4CADAEA1D"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">7114. Internship program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0A3683CD6BF14F5DBD27BBE6147EF942"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the internship program required by section 7114 of such title, as added by subsection (a), not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="HEA987914540C41EFAA0DE0ECA667E595"><enum>102.</enum><header>Pilot program on establishment of Board of Veterans' Appeals honors program</header><subsection id="H8B275AC7114B4FD5B91542E21015B60F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of establishing a competitive honors program within the Department for the purpose of recruiting high-achieving law school students, recent law school graduates, and entry-level attorneys for employment with the Board.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB50B22B9A05D40AFA17A5C19FEC6236E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program required by subsection (a) during the nine-year period beginning on the date of the establishment of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H057D7F5574924626B3D1520501545D30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Honors program</header><paragraph id="HC4B43BE5784D407793C66B1A1A186041"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the pilot program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out a competitive honors program as described in such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF8B1F67ACE4843B6A7A6EC50A774F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall give priority consideration in application for the honors program to individuals who successfully complete the internship program established under section 7114 of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 101(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71318E20C7DB4097A4007673C7CAD31D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student loan repayment benefits</header><subparagraph id="HB88BEDFD7DEC422CA17959D633EC3C79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide student loan repayment benefits under section 5379 of title 5, United States Code, to each participant in the pilot program who is eligible for student loan repayment benefits under such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE63358F30F40269D43A779B555B9EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with each participant in the pilot program who will receive benefits described in subparagraph (A), in accordance with such section. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFE385F36312468DB01D1A6EA885FCE4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commitment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement described in subparagraph (B) shall include a requirement that the participant will remain in the service of the Department for a period of not less than three years, unless involuntarily separated, in accordance with subsection (c) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB68CFA855345E5B19597984698859B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Professional development activities</header><subparagraph id="H206953F960994E70B45D1FFC22F3A7C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assignment of mentors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which an individual begins participating in the pilot program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall assign the participant a mentor who is a managerial employee of the Department outside the participant's chain of command. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28FBF29CA81B4381B885E8AEE1921151"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assignments to Office of General Counsel</header><clause id="H8296AEAF0A8744638F0BCC26B6802425"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide each participant in the pilot program at least one assignment within the Office of General Counsel of the Department that includes full-time legal responsibilities in order to further the professional development of the participant.</text></clause><clause id="H651C9A9FE6B0481CBDBE15AA8C4139ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Period of assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assignment provided under clause (i) shall be for a period of not less than 120 days and not more than 180 days, or longer at the discretion of the Secretary. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D94CA3E799F4545A9273F77A3A55528"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other rotational assignments</header><clause id="HFD18E22A04A64BCEBAD9F5CC9823FA62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide a participant in the pilot program one or more other short-term rotational assignments.</text></clause><clause id="H96961C32FFCC4F6AA106EAAEC9D83ACE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Period of assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assignment provided under clause (i) shall be for a period of not less than 30 days and not more than 180 days, at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21AF3AE07C974CF1B862FF946F9943B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><paragraph id="HFD6CBA03E9CA475D9577C7A3AD62C4D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than three years after the date on which the Secretary first accepts a participant into the honors program carried out under subsection (c)(1) and not less frequently than once every three years thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the Secretary with respect to the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD970F8B8B299483AAAB20686880A5DD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBCC99561A79B43C6B8B202DFA9153913"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings of the Secretary with respect to the feasibility and advisability of establishing a competitive honors program as described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71B7BEA37B194B0C94B562C50E59AAAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action to improve recruitment and retention of staff at the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2D277CE6C77D459B8C6D1F11A4A0283E"><enum>103.</enum><header>Report on improving access to Board of Veterans' Appeals telehearings</header><subsection id="HE45B5719BFC341A198E51399E1DEDE87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on improving access to hearings before the Board of Veterans’ Appeals held by picture and voice transmission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1676E5D9D14C4D27A055A232A0D551E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HD9BBB2A7980F4AF9953636239A1B057F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recommendations on the feasibility and advisability of reimbursing veterans for expenses incurred for travel from the home of a veteran to the location at which a hearing before the Board of Veterans’ Appeals is held by picture and voice transmission, if the Secretary determines that travel to such location is reasonably necessary for such a hearing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FE4DE63DC15400C90FE2A647C553A70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations on establishment of pilot programs to assess the feasibility and advisability of using other methods that could improve veteran access to hearings before the Board of Veterans’ Appeals held by picture and voice transmission from a veteran’s home.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H686435A71C9A41E9B387F436AA29619E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such other recommendations to improve access to hearings before the Board of Veterans’ Appeals held by picture and voice transmission as the Secretary may receive from stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HB9227CE55C944BAC909C0E109A50AC63" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Medical disability exam matters</header><section id="HE67CEFC7517D42F8A4F09BFEE87884D3"><enum>201.</enum><header>Improving requirement to publish disability benefit questionnaire forms of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5101(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6C816A3500B542AB99B417A1F913C0B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting “, including (except as provided in paragraph (4)(A))—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H869EF99B22F44164AF4AFEA1494D92B9"><clause id="HF56F01A378A74CDE8FC720629291670E" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all disability benefit questionnaire forms available to personnel of the Veterans Health Administration and contracted personnel for the completion of compensation and pension examinations; and</text></clause><clause id="H113C931E4CB14B2896996B7A686C41EF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all factsheets available to such personnel to inform completion of such examinations; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A8DA81848D84EA090B2E17058AA569C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E110B71C4B2443EB81717BAD73CCB9A"><paragraph id="HE89C1E9676B64BD0AF9DE8EA9FB37A49" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E87307489D244558905C788F0885F44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary may exclude from publication under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) any form described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph that the Secretary determines could not reasonably be completed to a clinically acceptable standard by someone not an employee or a contractor of the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H9AB1B02D1E4A43B89B4DBD302419029E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A form described in this subparagraph is a form that—</text><clause id="H1A43C130DEC8462A8D166BD2E25E1A60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was in effect after January 1, 2020; and</text></clause><clause id="H9344A2CF70A34ABBA12F829C6A80DFFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not been published under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H4B76E06F3B7B46EBAD48C9B892DA6782"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For each form excluded under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H4B1A68F525C34A22BE213B0A3B32CD55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>list the form on the same internet website as the forms published under paragraph (1)(A) with an indication that the form has been excluded; and</text></clause><clause id="H3818871D643D4E8293C7FBE38153C3CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide with such listing a justification for such exclusion.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HC32EB88ABDA548E08765F2D21680B14F"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on improving medical disability examinations for veterans who live abroad</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the efforts of the Secretary to provide reimbursement for a veteran’s travel to a Department facility or a facility of a Department-contracted provider, regardless of whether the facility is inside or outside the United States, when such travel is incident to a scheduled compensation and pension examination.</text></section><section id="H008F30BA1FC64D67B234355FB667E10D"><enum>203.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs requirement for communication by contractors providing covered medical disability examinations with persons recognized by power of attorney for preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims</header><subsection id="HECC722EE086545BEA8F14BFA2B1EFF7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In each contract entered into by the Secretary after the date of the enactment of this Act for the provision by a contractor of a covered medical disability examination, the Secretary shall include a requirement that every communication from a contractor to a veteran regarding the scheduling of a covered medical disability examination be contemporaneously transmitted to the person recognized by a power of attorney executed under sections 5902, 5903, and 5904 of title 38, United States Code, for the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEC74EC2735F54E33B74E9C82421A54A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered medical disability examination</term> means a medical examination that the Secretary determines necessary for the purposes of adjudicating a benefit under chapter 11 or 15 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="H53ED146217494E66838BB07A2606E88F"><enum>204.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs outreach regarding contact information for contractors providing covered medical disability examinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in partnership with veterans service organizations and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers relevant and appropriate, implement an informative outreach program for veterans regarding the following:</text><paragraph id="H9C8883A5F80D401B88F3A8FD4705D25D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Contact information for contractors providing covered medical disability examinations, including the telephone numbers from which such contractors may contact veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6430EC65C1954886AD0E3B2E640DA41C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The requirement for veterans to provide personally identifiable information when contacted by such contractors in order to verify their identity.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H16CB9E3936D24FA19FD0A2EB71945C70" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Other matters</header><section id="H2DD24935F5794A39940F320BFDE62107"><enum>301.</enum><header>Report on supporting governmental veterans service officers</header><subsection id="H94AF2804354C46649BAB9F99F21D8B85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and after consulting veterans service organizations and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers relevant and appropriate, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on improving the support by the Department of Veterans Affairs of governmental veterans service officers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H747221D980BC47ABA17B1A373CDA14A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HD7053942E02142F7901005960AB64528"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enhanced access to systems</header><text>An assessment of the feasibility and current technical limitations of providing governmental veterans service officers enhanced access to certain Department systems to better serve veterans those governmental service officers may not have authorization to represent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD345FC0227D46C3A0CC2AB985876FFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intergovernmental liaisons</header><text>An assessment as to whether the Department would benefit from the establishment or designation of an office or working group within the Department to serve as an intergovernmental liaison between the Department and governmental veterans service officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95121CF950834462BB4B79FAD8AA074E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other</header><text>Any other recommendations to improve how the Department monitors, coordinates with, or provides support to governmental veterans service officers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BCF1DF3FF4C42E9A8DE5F0BCE7B8D25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2A97775CD5B142E4BE8FB45D99DA97BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Governmental veterans service officer</header><text>The term <term>governmental veterans service officer</term> means an employee of a State, county, municipal, or Tribal government—</text><subparagraph id="H5A7C1B588ED0498192B3D3447EE0FAF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is accredited by at least one veterans service organization to serve as a veterans service officer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB406C75F29742C099F9044ADBA9D58A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose primary responsibilities include working as such an officer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00908668741B46589DEDC43EA45531D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA76AA50EB4B14A1E88213AD342520E93"><enum>302.</enum><header>Electronic notification of decisions and other electronic communications</header><subsection id="H8618BF0E4FC14A4983608AAFE72D868A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice defined</header><text>Section 5100 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE072140C02C041FF9B337564CD1D697F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="section">Definition of “claimant”</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="section">Definitions</header-in-text></quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4835E579522452FA74090233D6171A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this chapter, the term</quote> and inserting “this chapter: </text><quoted-block id="H165F24CDD7874D89B4BF8E5FC0A5B198" style="USC" act-name=""><paragraph id="HA5491F6F6A4B4DE3A0B9962547E3F112"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF693B9E4634F02A3EAF6E3333FCE11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H359E5D4EDCBB409F85E5885B592F72C7"><paragraph id="H32D4D132925D4AAA9E30A94B09938AAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>notice</term> means a communication delivered through a method determined appropriate by the Secretary, which may include electronic notification in accordance with section 5104(c) of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9724A7DE70064DDCA7FC61E3949031CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice of decisions of Secretary of Veterans Affairs regarding benefits</header><text>Section 5104 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D80FD57D5EC449E930FFC9B75F27910"><subsection id="HFAF50EDAA8424877A480DAF9F13B18CA"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFDF944D2791A4C34A6771CFDA1110A63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide notice to a person under subsection (a) of this section and under section 7104(e) of this title electronically, but only after the person affirmatively consents to electronic notification for all decisions requiring notice under this section, including section 7104 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD3B0C4995924D4BAF1DBF915FE494B8" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H81F28FE31E8A4446A47CED7C74C9641C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may revoke consent to electronic notification under paragraph (1) at any time by informing the Secretary of such revocation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H0FDF95A4DE0B4CB29DAAD6D470743052"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A revocation under this paragraph is effective upon a person's submission of such revocation, whether by electronic means or by mail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H2FA807AD5377438F92B24ED69A548426"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, on an annual basis—</text><subparagraph id="H1F1472C4C19F449A9FB479BDA79D05AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit input from stakeholders for recommendations to improve how the Department issues notifications under this section, including section 7104 of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE32DCE8DDEB94FA7A6B721EB1A7BD0DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly publish responses to such input on a website of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5B67AEEC227041AB935ED2969999F34D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of higher-Level review decision by agency of original jurisdiction</header><text>Section 5104B(c) of such title is amended by striking <quote>in writing</quote> and inserting <quote>to the claimant and the claimant’s representative</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7907A84B0C74478C87F45E35B191D153"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of decisions by Board of Veterans' Appeals</header><text>Section 7104 of such title is amended by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE8A4366DA0347F9A0CAD2EBEE3D3FC6"><subsection id="H6EFA8F49FF054523A5BE5C48C31D6E63"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Subject to section 5104(c) of this title, after reaching a decision on a case, the Board shall promptly provide notice (as that term is defined in section 5100 of this title) of such decision to the following:</text><paragraph id="HCAD30C120D294E3C9BE0EF6021551F5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The claimant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB108DB4D6DAE4AC69143D23A901F3028"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any other party with a right to notice of such decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE922DA74F4C840EB8183DD59F3B9B9D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any authorized representative of the appellant or party described in subparagraph (B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFACE2CD89DF24A71B779B2BF21BA8F00"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice of disagreement</header><text>Section 7105(b)(1)(A) of such title is amended by striking <quote>mailing</quote> and inserting <quote>provision</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBBB82C2D5A1046969E420D22CD6187F9"><enum>303.</enum><header>Facilitating Department of Veterans Affairs contractor access to Federal tax return information necessary for claims processing</header><subsection id="HB67736F333A7469683345EF32C68D930"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85515AF67FCF4DFD9A0B02A2A4B8DF33"><subparagraph id="HD6C0A866CBDB41049FBAC9CBEFD54C2B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Redisclosures</header><clause id="H713D2EFDE8324AE781E9A3CF4ECDCDBE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Officers and employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are specifically designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may redisclose return information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) to contractors of such Department administering (or assisting in administering) a program listed in subparagraph (D)(viii).</text></clause><clause id="HABEEAF0184484611B41EA99D7D6FA914"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restrictions on use of information</header><text>Information disclosed under this subparagraph shall be disclosed only for purposes of, and to the extent necessary in, determining eligibility for, or the correct amount of, benefits under a program listed in subparagraph (D)(viii).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H59166BDFC8834ADF9983AC7EFC9DE56C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6103(a)(3) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(7)(E),</quote> after <quote>(6),</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4B08882D9B34D34ADD77F98694DA54A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safeguards</header><text>Section 6103(p)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subsection (l)(10)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (l)(7), (10)</quote>. </text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

