<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7764 IH: To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to provide additional payments under the environmental quality incentives program for implementation of a nutrient management practice, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7764</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to provide additional payments under the environmental quality incentives program for implementation of a nutrient management practice, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H51B3C13027D74EB5B8343E2EA6A2B687" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="HC8808302347C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Additional nutrient management assistance</header><subsection id="H2A5E027C8C7F4CEA8AF8BDE7671633E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this section and ending on September 30, 2023, the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide payments under this section to producers that have entered into contracts with the Secretary under the environmental quality incentives program to implement the nutrient management practice.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDA64B325B774A7FB4F789A16903B865"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A payment to a producer under this section shall be in an amount that, in combination with the applicable payment under section 1240B(d) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839aa-2">16 U.S.C. 3839aa–2(d)</external-xref>), does not exceed 100 percent of the costs of implementing the nutrient management practice.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2CB49FC645B34E8D8F198FB9D71012AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HB3E6F0C41DAC4F2E935A939670A457F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $750,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 and 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0EEFD9E264A4FA9A26638B868E40E8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may use up to 5 percent of funds made available pursuant to paragraph (1) to provide technical assistance under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22A566C4888540859328862CF61994EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC1EDD41281614DBA94234A1391D8318B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Environmental quality incentives program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental quality incentives program</term> means the environmental quality incentives program established under subchapter A of chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839aa">16 U.S.C. 3839aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0E365790294FCE80A9639844742EFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nutrient management practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nutrient management practice</term> means the practice described in the conservation practice standard for nutrient management established by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, code 590, dated May, 2019, or any successor conservation practice standard for nutrient management established by the Natural Resources Conservation Service pursuant to title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3801">16 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

