<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89647C70C36F4FF3AA640600C99D9AE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9197 IH: Stop the Sexualization of Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9197</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221018">October 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000479">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds to develop, implement, facilitate, or fund any sexually oriented program, event, or literature for children under the age of 10, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EDCBACE068041EE80E6F280F8BDC096" style="OLC"><section id="HB7324CDFC3014E3D88132E92EA9C61B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Sexualization of Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H02BE18B0B74D4B75BFA5004DD8B29A0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HE8738E77ABCC488598D68FE591052FEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Certain school districts that receive Federal grants have implemented sexual education for children under 10 years of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73D4AB3EE594A469817504CDB76F179"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many newly implemented sexual education curriculums encourage discussions of sexuality, sexual orientation, transgenderism, and gender ideology as early as kindergarten.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD6B41CD81224655B46D1987FDF60F29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State and local library systems, museums, and other educational institutions that receive Federal grants have purchased sexually oriented literature and materials that target preadolescent children and teach them about concepts like masturbation, pornography, sexual acts, and gender transition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B5070DAF418471CA0E7AB0CEAE7E85D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Private organizations, State government agencies, and local government agencies have made use of Federal grants to host and promote sexually oriented events like drag queen story hours and burlesque shows.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A37FB142A5D45C4BBB5D8E40651CF5E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Federal agencies like the Department of Defense have used Federal funds to promote and host burlesque shows and drag shows on Federal property during family-oriented events.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD3D99678AE9C4087B61B5D9E0200B424"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H0FC587118ED74F02B073123D4B88A353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>parents and legal guardians have the right and responsibility to determine where, if, when, and how their children are exposed to material of a sexual nature; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBD542FD506847D283B4F55DF2B7902C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal funds should not be used to expose children under 10 years of age to sexually oriented material.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7811309EF9B947BC9D145D77FDE21552"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibiting the presentation of sexually oriented materials to children under the age of 10</header><subsection id="HD987EF9E45114123BF9958DB659D8E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal funds limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be made available to develop, implement, facilitate, or fund any sexually oriented program, event, or literature for children under the age of 10, including hosting or promoting any program, event, or literature involving sexually oriented material, or any program, event, or literature that exposes children under the age of 10 to nude adults, individuals who are stripping, or lewd or lascivious dancing.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0566061365B2454395F15A1B7EDB9E0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition at Federal facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A federally owned facility or property may not be used to host or promote any sexually oriented program, event, or literature for children under the age of 10, including any program, event, or literature listed in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD5DA1EBF69D423EBBC33F99E34A106D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="HA24C3425F19C4F26BC78D01044BD6473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A parent or legal guardian of a child may bring a civil action for injunctive relief in any Federal district court of appropriate jurisdiction against a government official, government agency, or private entity for a violation of subsection (a) or subsection (b) by such an official, agency, or entity if the child was—</text><subparagraph id="H3500130BBB184DA1ABC457277878DC2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exposed to sexually oriented material funded in part or in whole by Federal funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0609A4B2F9C4AB39F673F78B0A59C45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under the age of 10 at the time that such exposure occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E5BACE38B9C4984960B9889BFF94531"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>An action under this subsection may commence not later than 1 year after a violation occurs under subsection (a) or (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD43803687C344ED7A901D5EDAEC0B419"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees and other costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under this subsection, the court, in its discretion, may award a prevailing plaintiff reasonable attorney’s fees, expert witness fees, and other costs of litigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE5876DAC1234817B3BA0CE85A01FD95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funds</header><paragraph id="H787313D9641642CA88447FCD5668A390"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency may not disburse Federal funds to any Federal program, State or local government agency, or private entity for 3 fiscal years if that entity receives 2 or more injunctions for violations of subsection (a) or (b) in a 5-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB1DEC9521248F78E055AE00AED2A70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The appropriate head of a Federal agency shall submit to a government agency or private entity written notice of the prohibition on the disbursement of Federal funds under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45545C124AE64C2FB40F1183438BCC93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a notice pursuant to paragraph (2), a government agency or private entity may appeal a prohibition on the disbursement of Federal funds under paragraph (1) in an administrative hearing of the appropriate agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3772A0C8E2E14F76A7572FEEE88BAB96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H55A15E47552E44239693499C70154452"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sexually oriented material</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>sexually oriented material</quote> means any depiction, description, or simulation of sexual activity, any lewd or lascivious depiction or description of human genitals, or any topic involving gender identity, gender dysphoria, transgenderism, sexual orientation, or related subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D813B5C8C84485BBF82C87842C63075"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stripping</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>stripping</quote> means any act which involves the removal or simulated removal of clothing in a sexual manner for the entertainment of one or more individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

