<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E46B053FBA04EAE9D8B56A10F1862BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9604 IH: Expanding Disability Access to Higher Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to promote the matriculation, and increase in the graduation rates, of individuals with disabilities within higher education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD13DBAF3AB414C4A94DFB63B751D91C2" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H197F85611B6A488E9CF5FE34DAB3A746"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Disability Access to Higher Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF41F1DDC5B4A42468B66FF07FF7E6CD3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="H1214CD58D51349D99856C2F7C47E6A51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCDC5D4C40CBE463290BAFDBD37E0364E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Students who are low income attend institutions of higher education at a rate significantly lower than middle- and high-income students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D894A909B3E484894F928E22786844A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Similarly, students who are first-generation college students or are from minority backgrounds attend institutions of higher education at lower rates than the general public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F48460D3A9247B88484270E51468455"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many students who are low income, first generation, or minorities also have a disability.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB9C460D5BCD4FFBBEB5F0950AC1BB83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the last decade, both high school and postsecondary graduation rates for students with disabilities were significantly lower than for students without disabilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C6709A9BD144D11ACA467F99C6A8FF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2015, approximately 65 percent of the total population of adults 25 to 34 years old had completed some postsecondary education compared with approximately 44 percent of adults with disabilities in the same age range.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H120B3A4385224667A8FF182DB4A51EE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For students with disabilities who do attend an institution of higher education, only half will receive a diploma compared to 72 percent of students without disabilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77A882FF40364CAFAF04D4FD4745719F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Many researchers cite lack of support, such as in-class accommodations, accessible housing, and accessible technology, as a significant challenge as students with disabilities transition from high school to postsecondary education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F591E440A14405FACC05A58306B8A07"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As with their peers without disabilities who are first-generation students or come from low-income backgrounds, students who are first-generation or low-income students with disabilities who receive mentoring and support services can successfully prepare for, enroll in, and graduate from postsecondary education programs and gain greater economic control of their lives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HABCF8C4CA1E344B5A1FF171D84A7D733"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that individuals with disabilities, particularly those who are low income or first generation, should be able to attend institutions of higher education at the same rate as their peers in the general population.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1FE3353A40E94F39A88EEE85BEB28499"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAAD9D8178D7A44448E9CD4AFA48517B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide first-generation or low-income students with disabilities with information, support, and resources to matriculate and complete a course of study at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBEAC1B88770492DA33E0780281B67AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To encourage and support first-generation or low-income students with disabilities to achieve postsecondary credentials that benefit them and their communities both socially and economically.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1463289ACAFB4B5482FDEF05A74A142B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To increase the number of faculty with disabilities in institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E34C5E672A943188E751D1BBF231BB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To provide programs authorized under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>) with the resources necessary to support first-generation or low-income students with disabilities to prepare for, enroll in, and graduate from institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA0D1CC8780C947348210C467521373B4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preparing and supporting students with disabilities for postsecondary education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402A of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3901FD8BFD9A433C9566DD4ED6A10686"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(4)(A), by striking <quote>, and Native American Pacific Islanders (including Native Hawaiians),</quote> and inserting <quote>, Native American Pacific Islanders (including Native Hawaiians), and individuals with a disability (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)),</quote>; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19484E916A6C475B87767ABAB2B2A388"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g), by inserting <quote>(except subsection (i))</quote> after <quote>For the purpose of making grants and contracts under this chapter</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5563D20A6A3E42D792B248CBBF2C58FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H718CB6A6CF5F474484825F8EEF3C9FFF"> 
<subsection id="H0B1F9347A86646A3B57865243062E05A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Preparing and supporting students with disabilities for postsecondary education</header> 
<paragraph id="HBFE3568BA90C4FBF925E047D788D67CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Funds for Federal TRIO programs</header> 
<subparagraph id="H407E45746ED0485AA137D5FF231B5DDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<clause id="HAEB356F6F6D14058BF15DBC244D8DE9D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary shall award funds under this paragraph, on a competitive basis, to an eligible entity that applies for a grant or contract for a program under this chapter (except section 402E) and also applies for such funds under this paragraph in order to serve eligible students, as described in clause (ii). The period for such award of funds under this paragraph shall be the same period for the associated grant or contract for a program under this chapter (except section 402E) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>associated program</quote>).</text></clause> <clause id="HD4689FFBCA16494F89E2A8BAEBF21421"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligible students</header><text>An eligible student is described in this clause if the student—</text> 
<subclause id="H3C21406E071E4615AB10D9038D7F99B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is eligible to receive assistance under a program authorized under this chapter (except section 402E); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE71985237B754B2ABB3AD9C6681B2A5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has an individualized education program, as defined in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, is covered under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), or has other documentation establishing the student's disability (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)), such as— </text> 
<item id="H6DBE71FA4294426B8F24AC5E9B696199"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a cognitive or learning disability;</text></item> <item id="HF3A46989A3A84330A4AAD77AFFB19898"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a sensory disability;</text></item> 
<item id="HD16121B7924F49C6AB2A32263D18021F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a physical or medical disability;</text></item> <item id="H0CF8A9812870415A83B57196486B2D86"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a mental health disability; or</text></item> 
<item id="H9B9E448D1A2C4BA49B69C869E175594D"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>another disability. </text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0166AC21EB24FCCBD12C986F801D5A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header> <clause id="H4FA82FFEF1604D698A349FE3E7C1DDC3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an applicant for a grant or contract for a program under this chapter (except section 402E) that desires to receive funds under this paragraph shall submit an application for such funds to the Secretary at the same time such applicant submits an application for the grant or contract for a program under this chapter (except section 402E) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>associated application</quote>).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD17D918A92141A886F46EAF8ECAAFCD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application mid-cycle</header><text>An applicant that desires to receive funds under this paragraph that, at the time such applicant desires to apply for such funds, has a grant or contract for a program under this chapter (except section 402E) that is in existence may submit an application for such funds to the Secretary independent of an associated application.</text></clause> <clause id="H6F90468B2CD74D45BE4446CE9D6D832D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Content of application</header><text>An application for funds under this paragraph shall include the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H6E8E4A9D340D4E5E82C2924CB87F0A30"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A description of any programs being carried out under this chapter by the applicant on the date of the application, including the number of existing students served.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCF2C6D1A63E14380A4FD81E131D30F63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The number of eligible students proposed to be served with funds received under this paragraph.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H78F7FC919A174A4DBC22A200405E72E6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The cost of serving such students proposed to be served, including a description of expenditures.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8C8E2703B1C2461292EC5F1E3818C500"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>An explanation of how funds received under this paragraph will be used for such students.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H18C92AF2350F4E9FA09D984997E84CE1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>An explanation of how such students proposed to be served will be identified and enrolled.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H36E7F271FB81423B943D6767213C6072" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>An explanation of how the program will work with disability student support services and other services that support students with disabilities. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H776A2B642018421D892A8A916E529607"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Awarding of funds</header> 
<clause id="HF55F69C6855A4FACAD59DF8D41489B8F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding funds under this paragraph, the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that—</text> <subclause id="HB8BB9BB073D24088A909D94A7E391E76"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have established programs funded under this chapter; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8AAF9CDE6626463DB7A196D71F0A6453"><enum>(II)</enum><text>describe how eligible students proposed to be served will be included in the established associated program.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5C1EFC00E4A24A77BB9631FC0CCA095B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The Secretary shall award funds under this paragraph to an applicant in an amount that maximizes the number of eligible students served in a manner that meets such students' needs for successful programmatic outcomes.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1DD6B959F5FD4915AE4A07D4DE9FBBD8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall award funds under this paragraph—</text> <subclause id="H079A5F1EE8884904A5607AC6213722EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to not less than 10 percent of all the eligible entities that, on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Expanding Disability Access to Higher Education Act</short-title>, have a grant or contract awarded under this chapter (except section 402E); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H29C669ED06E2412FB5BAE8C5303A9587"><enum>(II)</enum><text>across—</text> <item id="H0E635C2C5C3A442FB524EC5C637BDA4F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>geographic regions; and</text></item> 
<item id="HA9E156AA41EA4D24B631962F7FEA1778"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>sizes of programs.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H188137D9790C4F21952663F401181083"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In awarding funds under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H2B2D85E52930469590526D42E831550B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require an assurance that—</text> <item id="HB5C57D242BB6424DB15BEE1D8DD6BD2F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case in which the associated program is under section 402B, not less than two-thirds of the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals who are first-generation college students;</text></item> 
<item id="H975581257FDC4A43AA9D6B75B7E6215D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case in which the associated program is under section 402C—</text> <subitem id="HA7082FEE4BC94D0A9E1D867C7A51527B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>not less than two-thirds of the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals who are first-generation college students; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HCEB21E2AEE0342F484738E98BBAB461E"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the remaining eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals or first-generation college students;</text></subitem></item> <item id="H50CE09DF9E824EA78CCCF71055F7BD1B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case in which the associated program is under section 402D—</text> 
<subitem id="H28F042FA317347B393E9B305F557F557"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>not less than two-thirds of the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals who are first-generation college students; and</text></subitem> <subitem id="HE37250F33522498D94A6280325F3B17A"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the remaining eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals or first-generation college students; and</text></subitem></item> 
<item id="H06C52F72923842668927E6F7D9BF6749"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in the case in which the associated program is under section 402F—</text> <subitem id="HB2C31BAB633244E982A6F31E4AAD79E8"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>not less than two-thirds of the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals who are first-generation college students; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H79BF14FB5E584C3D98B4A454FC0E049B"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph are at least nineteen years of age, unless the imposition of such limitation with respect to any person would defeat the purposes of this paragraph;</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause id="HC8B3F49B4B694A3EB67473EDC04AF3AE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>require an assurance that such eligible students who are served do not have access to services from another program funded under this chapter;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7E350E34658A4FCF971E9182317DCB6E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>require an assurance that the program funded under this paragraph and the associated program will—</text> <item id="H2B67B4AB79C242209D03E0D25EE5AC35"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>be accessible to the eligible students proposed to be served by the program;</text></item> 
<item id="HF8CEE934D7BC43ABA26641177EB55854"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>serve all students, including eligible students;</text></item> <item id="H972FC896A7B849C8B68554967F8BB5FE"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>incorporate universal design for learning; and</text></item> 
<item id="H80A879ABCA6E4DAB8AE5F8751591B697" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>ensure that accommodations are provided as needed for eligible students and address how the program plans to enroll such students;</text></item></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HC3EA84C3BA4D4E18BFE600B7E5B7CA5C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>require the program funded under this paragraph—</text> 
<item commented="no" id="H4AC1E18D0CDD41E6BA8F4F2C4763B4B4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to comply with all program requirements of the associated program; and</text></item> <item commented="no" id="HB4834057C4E541628E896C982AD419FE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to include educational assistance as determined necessary for eligible students to transition to postsecondary education, such as—</text> 
<subitem id="H87516E50E29E4F01A77D62CAF72F504E"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>academic and social supports;</text></subitem> <subitem id="HBE401CCE92FA408A954C2F24D14AA72C"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>student advising and family engagement;</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H5E81723B850A41278FC3AD343D14F08D"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>college search and application processes;</text></subitem> <subitem id="H1ABB3FEF109A4184AFA618DBB519C988"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>financial planning; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H7D9B4296BC284A20BD41071E8225EC5E"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>targeted learning programs;</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H75F12FB2C2034BDA99C0C60984AE3F9E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>require an assurance that the applicant will serve a number of eligible students with the funds under this paragraph that is not less than the number determined under subparagraph (D); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6E2411C41EF6455EBF48068FB28D0C93"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>require an assurance that—</text> <item id="H6589DA235BC141B7B09B5B16A69066D3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the funds under this paragraph and funds provided under the associated program will be used to incorporate eligible students into the associated program; and</text></item> 
<item id="HD29FA8783161415DB9F9FDF7BFB393E1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such eligible students have access to all the program services of the associated program, as well as any additional services they require to be full participants in the associated program.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBBE7EC9BE4E04DC4BB7C356A5AEBF9AD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Number of eligible students to be served</header> <clause id="H9777B336D9F841D5942B549306CD73FD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An applicant that receives funds under this paragraph shall use such funds to serve eligible students who are in addition to the students served through the associated program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA8E8AA855CAB4019B46FBC9878460B4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Number of students to be served</header><text>The number of eligible students to be served with funds under this paragraph shall be the number that maximizes the number of eligible students served in a manner that meets such students' needs for successful programmatic outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE5B64C3C47914CE79809ABBEDE5D9BF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postbaccalaureate achievement program</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA113F27315AE4665B4B77CD5477A8F62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award funds under this paragraph, on a competitive basis, to an eligible entity that applies for assistance for a project under section 402E and also applies for such funds under this paragraph in order to serve eligible students, as described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H50ADE134A81C49E1B241AA7B60F6FA79"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible students</header><text>An eligible student is described in this subparagraph if the student—</text> <clause id="H827ED95BBC2844FDB52806293D543CC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is eligible to receive assistance under a project assisted under section 402E;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA835ED2474E44B65821F4B98DEF2BE35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has an individualized education program, as defined in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, is covered under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), or has other documentation establishing the student's disability (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)), such as—</text> <subclause id="H5D4394B00D604EB09E13E7745AE4768E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a cognitive or learning disability;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0FC892675BCF4294935BCD42B50EE5E5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a sensory disability;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H27C50688A8184929BD235B0AEF8AE282"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a physical or medical disability;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HEB7D5CA64AF540E7BB6F6DC4FA8B83A1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a mental health disability; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H71346B9F70F742B9BC84BF4F7E3847F8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>another disability; and </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H718EA94346AF41FF84E6433D855F838E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is registered as full time in six or more credits.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74A47CDEEFE74B7BB4C71BA65F441AB5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header> <clause id="H2C717570B6924364AEDA4619BD50854E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an applicant for assistance for a project under section 402E that desires to receive funds under this paragraph shall submit an application for such funds to the Secretary at the same time such applicant submits an application under section 402E (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>associated application</quote>).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC4D838152FB7497E9326A90C8E046A48"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application mid-cycle</header><text>An applicant that desires to receive funds under this paragraph that, at the time such applicant desires to apply for such funds, is receiving assistance for a project under section 402E may submit an application for such funds to the Secretary independent of an associated application.</text></clause> <clause id="HB95134A6B3C14A4D84BBE52E6727F3E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Content of application</header><text>An application for funds under this paragraph shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HD1C0BE7510A9470CBE4E38EA7DF823F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>describe identification, recruitment, and implementation strategies as well as programmatic elements specifically for eligible students; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8F94412ED7074F8DA2F2959DDE946953"><enum>(II)</enum><text>indicate whether this is a new project or will fund a project existing on the date of the application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FD3DB66246B4976B76FECC635A3D80F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Awarding of funds</header> 
<clause id="HA9F665C6EBD04122B241ED09C141B89A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award funds under this paragraph to an applicant in an amount that maximizes the number of eligible students served in a manner that meets such students' needs for successful programmatic outcomes.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1712D0FF58EC45BCAC4F1D0C22E857D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In awarding funds under this paragraph, the Secretary shall require an assurance that—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H4C3EB483739A48A5A52B8D6C8784FCD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than two-thirds of the eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be low-income individuals who are first-generation college students; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H40A1C5FCDE234C9796B7878B6F7C9947"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the remaining eligible students who are served with the funds under this paragraph be from a group that is underrepresented in graduate education, including—</text> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D56C66C04264977AF49BE4A45476B9B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Alaska Natives, as defined in section 6306 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></item> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90A70DF64A44402DA012A7CC393BF10C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Native Hawaiians, as defined in section 6207 of such Act; and</text></item> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE219B97D1B564D8C9312AC2BADC51548"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Native American Pacific Islanders, as defined in section 320.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD37F64E2A064E6BB388AC07E4DC27C6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Number of eligible students to be served</header> <clause commented="no" id="H4AF9C301A3E14DCEAB44ADB1888266EA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An applicant that receives funds under this paragraph shall use such funds to serve eligible students who are in addition to the students served through the associated program.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H3601AADEA2F64B6CA35B179E2FC131B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Number of students to be served</header><text>The number of eligible students to be served with funds under this paragraph shall be the number that maximizes the number of eligible students served in a manner that meets such students' needs for successful programmatic outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBA867EBF9054CF9869D363CA0F801A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds awarded under this subsection shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other funds available to carry out the activities described in this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F65E3C7DC034A6DB99749B1E3DC6D35"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HB65CAE9648BC40E5B4ABC9E30136C560"><enum>4.</enum><header>Staff development activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 1 of part D of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140a">20 U.S.C. 1140a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6549E1CC69EC4F7EB0021924B8D5BC62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 761, by striking <quote>model demonstration</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D7D1A41C11E4C60B5BF60BFF4F7933B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 762—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB0686A90F7A34B52890024C3AF13190F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <clause id="H3ED9517324BF43AE92269267288AD5D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and application</quote> after <quote>The development</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45C4D93FCF304DE4B7CF3C159B8B097F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and application</quote> after <quote>The development</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45857BEAF94448798F767CF1A3226744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5DD51D897BF4BE4910B3C0FC44468C1"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BA156D577A342D79091AD2C63073968"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H792F08312F39451E8773E82DBD99EBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Expanding Disability Access to Higher Education Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report on all projects awarded grants under this part for any of fiscal years 2024 through 2029, including a review of the activities and program performance of such projects based on existing information as of the date of the report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C4B90F2423B4CF4800936BDA9E057C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the first award of a grant under this subpart after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Expanding Disability Access to Higher Education Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD89D10DE91D1416DBD7B092F564F7E86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviews the activities and program performance of the projects authorized under this subpart; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H972FF68A845B42D5B3C3488B3DA786F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides guidance and recommendations on how effective projects can be replicated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC3CAE5E5D95B4280ADF126A6CEF872A7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Offices of training, technical assistance, and accommodations grant program</header> 
<subsection id="HBDD83F94EC3D457A948CCFDF3D7079D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grant program</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education to enable the institutions to establish an Office of Accessibility at the institution.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC787342249774FD49119F87DA710C703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration and amount</header><text>A grant under this section shall be 5 years in duration and in an amount equal to not less than $30,000 and not more than $80,000 for each year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB4EC462B9BE4B0C82DB9B39CC3BDFA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution of higher education that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including an explanation of how the institution will sustain the Office of Accessibility after the grant period ends.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA83A532807A41ED816FCB7D0F7D97FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awarding of grants</header> <paragraph id="HE8A482BB1CC64539AF4480BB6D9E8BBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H44CB23013B4E4E0F8C5290861DC3C71B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2-year institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8889F7DDCF244A3A9FF5257B35390219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) that intend to hire individuals with disabilities as staff at the Office of Accessibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDF5999E36004C5495CD5F2A68AF7DCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diversity</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure geographic, institutional, and urban or rural award distribution diversity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6A2D452C8D954FFDB2FDFF21F8FA1CF5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall establish an Office of Accessibility at the institution, which Office—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAEDE0377BE9F41C98891F3459A51C03B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE6CAD2ABA6F40C49625DB1E2D03BE94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as a site for confidential requests for accommodations for faculty members with disabilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAC6E623DBE14A95B96BBA20E35C41DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an accommodations officer who has demonstrated expertise in addressing the needs of individuals with disabilities and who is trained to serve, and provide outreach to, faculty members with disabilities, staff with disabilities, and students with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EB271FD48BD4FB3A5CDEA96CF32B777"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide training and technical assistance for faculty and staff on rights and accommodations for individuals with disabilities, including protecting the civil rights of individuals with disabilities on campus and in classrooms; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC83023CA0E0415FA65677120B05BCE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B89AE942AD047BD8B68215B3BF690CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop professional development activities for faculty and staff about rights and accommodations for individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FBDD2B8E6014C27BA76508072D83A9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create a website, that is accessible to individuals with disabilities, to serve as a clearinghouse of information for individuals with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A7ADA4B22DD4F79AA2D593C65ECF0D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carry out other activities that the institution determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29033C27333D48A1B75E78F590BFF02C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1249BCF454F046EAB498471354CE45FC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header> <subsection id="HADEAAF600FFC420087D61795667A6E8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header> <paragraph id="H27C0A422E0F04EC6ACE2BD69546BB883"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Outcome criteria</header><text>Section 402A(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1156A8CE60194CEB8629ED03CC072E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23CA82539B034A08B982B83B115A8226"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D2BB5E98D7040AC8DBE5E1D35D693FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaggregation of relevant data</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F67B83F641F4D0B88406C5D128529FA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the outcome criteria under this subsection shall be disaggregated by low-income students, first-generation college students, individuals with disabilities (including for each of the categories described in items (aa) through (dd) of subsection (i)(1)(A)(ii)(II)), gender, race and ethnicity, language status, and delayed enrollment in postsecondary education after high school, in the schools and institutions of higher education served by the program to be evaluated.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C88B5F3001F4DFF8ED58C49749F0450"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaggregation under subparagraph (A) shall not be required in a case in which the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF42C3C38FD648038868C49BB59A165D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="HE340B90D635A4652A4B59916DD12936D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(iii), by inserting <quote>(and, if the entity received funds under subsection (i), to a total number of eligible students as described in such subsection)</quote> after <quote>students,</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HF9DF314A74834F5E91971EBA7BC57CBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), by inserting <quote>(and, if the entity received funds under subsection (i), to a total number of eligible students as described in such subsection)</quote> after <quote>program,</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCFEA442B72B14B8FA1C84C85AB8CEA22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H716E28D6D14F406BB9D3F748DAB7CEA4"> <subparagraph id="HCB3ACAEDDF704506859FB3070E207501"><enum>(F)</enum><text>For—</text> 
<clause id="H13547C86D15D44FFB9073552761B8E5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>programs authorized under this chapter for which funds are awarded under subsection (i), the number of eligible students (as defined in subsection (i)(2)(A)(ii)) served with such funds; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC598A64D57E4EED9981D8BC053F39C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each of subparagraphs (A) through (E), the extent to which the programs described in each of such subparagraphs served individuals with disabilities (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H433E6DB6D6194A11BBE53BC173D636B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Section 402H of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-18">20 U.S.C. 1070a–18</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H78036D6BD38D4B62A6F35C8D0DDC8726"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H717F5CFDC46847D89E6523CFD6E0B2A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">to the authorizing committees</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H7A213E2453E0483B986FD31EF85D8B4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(E), by inserting <quote>(including for each of the categories of such students described in items (aa) through (dd) of section 402A(i)(1)(A)(ii)(II))</quote> after <quote>disabilities</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6204195AD7FB48B6AE7E375E54C8AF94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83A11C2351444233B1FD954F06818541"> <paragraph id="H80441A9977BB45C38A9174C9FC2C99C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <subparagraph id="H814025211A6543FE8C28346063DC0714"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each entity that receives a grant or contract under this chapter shall submit an annual report to the Secretary on activities assisted and students served under the program funded under this chapter, including information on—</text> 
<clause id="HA8C494CAE43740448D10759DF3C46E41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>student persistence in the program;</text></clause> <clause id="H2824DD21FA294907A568D7B1BD8DD345"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>student enrollment in challenging courses;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0A8050E0273D477299DA844604B06568"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>graduation rates;</text></clause> <clause id="HDD2DC283087F44839A59EDD555BC09F4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>postsecondary enrollment rates;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83298A8BB2524739BB8B37EA50291748"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the types of services and supports provided to enrolled students; and</text></clause> <clause id="H07C8DCD0311F4756BB0C25047A5C0038"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other information requested by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD99DE7CF02BC4FF4A50CB877FC938B59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header> 
<clause id="H53706764E7A74CEEB2DFD6384A756211"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the information provided under subparagraph (A) shall be disaggregated by low-income student status, first-generation college student status, disability status (including for each of the categories described in items (aa) through (dd) of section 402A(i)(1)(A)(ii)(II)), gender, race and ethnicity, language status, and delayed enrollment in postsecondary education after high school.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA65209600BC548EA97F8E53CFEE84EBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaggregation under clause (i) shall not be required in a case in which the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B60634038664EDB8C328462446574EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i), by striking <quote>and first-generation college students</quote> and inserting <quote>, first-generation college students, and students with disabilities</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CB6060343AD46D1B40760C141786308"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GEAR UP</header><text>Section 404G of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-27">20 U.S.C. 1070a–27</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19064055CB74488BB2E0673EB2F57CD8"> 
<subsection id="H676604DE895245C1B38BA99CC478DC43"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="H8E3DBFAD26BB4A04889AE4FA989E32BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this chapter shall submit an annual report to the Secretary on activities assisted and students served under the program funded under this chapter, including information on—</text> <subparagraph id="HF31D2F19C04C48C38C62B96E6507899D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>student persistence in the program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC78F32D80164C04BF9AB9469B77C89B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>student enrollment in challenging courses;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC80EB6BFCE144CB893D5EE41E557DBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>graduation rates;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2448E6E41CA34ED0BA810C9768D21823"><enum>(D)</enum><text>postsecondary enrollment rates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEED6F53966C14EE2B46B137A4C07CDEC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the types of services and supports provided to enrolled students; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H792436789F414132B99889661A8334DE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other information requested by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H718C257D5400441485A802CFE698452A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disaggregation and availability</header> <subparagraph id="H479A3A52AA2D4DD6B237A89A135CCFF1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Information contained in the annual report described in paragraph (1) shall be—</text> 
<clause id="H30E283304F6A4924BB9C25465B9B6151"><enum>(i)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), disaggregated by low-income student status, first-generation college student status, disability status (including for each of the categories described in items (aa) through (dd) of section 402A(i)(1)(A)(ii)(II)), gender, race and ethnicity, language status, and delayed enrollment in postsecondary education after high school;</text></clause> <clause id="HDBCE1C11F0064DBEB952393CFE60E50D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cross-tabulated; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD742586D878445C9043673A3135C232"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>made publicly available without personally identifiable information.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA5EE69F8C9D4A20BBCCFFD74F396FB5"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaggregation under subparagraph (A)(i) shall not be required in a case in which the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF46E64F130324CB3A0A585059FBE05EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make such report publicly available online.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD8A0CEC6EC04F4091F381ABD860A49A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header> <paragraph id="HB88C59B57B7A40ECA6DD2C82A0B159B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall begin a review that examines—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE0A9ACEF8204429883F6C8FAD3D6EB35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>what is known about the population of students with disabilities, including by subcategories of disability, who attend institutions of higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48437B6A986C46CBA82B7DFEA66D71CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how students with disabilities are identified and supported by the Department of Education and grantee agencies through all Federal TRIO programs under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>), including—</text> 
<clause id="HFC0595B3A6D94D35B9BBE617F2846134"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any information related to whether and how students disclose if they have a disability;</text></clause> <clause id="H6C6E309334D34853A00B103B40050DE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what, if any, transition services are provided to students with disabilities between high school and postsecondary education; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H86E4C8E551D04AA2A303945A9D2BE5D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how such Federal TRIO programs work with other campus and non-campus based services that support students with disabilities; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBD0B75AFDCD47608B8601EB9BEC0CEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what information is reported by the Department of Education about services for students with disabilities through such Federal TRIO programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6DB245B02EC41CFBEEF64CEFEA1375D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

