<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A6F6D3CE8F44B488C530E3BD45B370C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8780 IH: Expand eXpertise in China Education and Language Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8780</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220909">September 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve hiring authorities available to the Secretary of State with respect to expertise on China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF99872ECD6DB478B9786CB71E14196C2" style="OLC"><section id="HE5F393212863496EA0142ACBAC8FFC64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expand eXpertise in China Education and Language Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EXCEL Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB50DB345B39C42BEBD2A82F7ACE145DA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H2785FEC98FDE42BDAD167070547F08C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strategic competition with the Government of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) is the most significant geostrategic challenge the United States faces to security and prosperity in the 21st century;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5CEFB1AEABF4EEDB073D5FFF606E840"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Government needs to further invest in relevant linguistic, cultural, and regional expertise to effectively engage in strategic competition with the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1EB8BD16151441FA72DA11AFBBC3977"><enum>(3)</enum><text>existing hiring authorities across the Executive Branch are not being adequately utilized to bring in necessary expertise to win the strategic competition against the People’s Republic of China, and that agencies may benefit from additional flexibility to recruit, hire, and retain talent.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC2938074276F47F8A69C2EE41FA99118"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hiring additional expertise at the Department of State</header><subsection id="H670F6EFAE6484C1DB28851092F2E393B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct hire authority</header><paragraph id="HFE9301A6C94E45D39E38C352E964C647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not more than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall appoint, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title V, no fewer than 31 candidates with linguistic, cultural, or regional expertise relevant for strengthening United States understanding of and ability to compete with the People’s Republic of China directly to positions in the competitive service, as defined in section 2102 of that title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6EC958F88640709DA65CAE23292F2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority provided under subsection (a) shall terminate in 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69D7AF7F830249CAADC3A6614634A049"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Long-Term and short-Term contracts</header><paragraph id="HD52BFD0A52AD49CB917ACFE0301A4798"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall, to such extent or in such amounts as provided in appropriations Acts, train Foreign Service and Civil Service employees who hold positions relevant to advancing United States policies toward competition with the PRC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22C8F90797D64B748367670FD9EE3D06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Topics covered</header><text>The training shall cover the following topics:</text><subparagraph id="HC078FEB8BB72413FA5FC19DE94562A7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The domestic and foreign policy objectives of the PRC and the CCP, as demonstrated through publicly available speeches, and PRC and CCP documents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5665C330CAE2438DBFF98DC10A65B172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The tools the PRC and the CCP use to achieve those objectives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7A3502219554A75A2348FD9ED453786"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The role of ideology in shaping CCP policies and outlook.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB48D94A15AF4937BC8E415CCC64061D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Other topics deemed relevant by the China Strategic Advisory Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H300193BA85FF41B8BBC2A517E2E5B8F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracting or grants for training</header><text>The Secretary shall provide the training required in subsection (b) by obtaining assistance from knowledgeable persons and organizations through—</text><subparagraph id="H1F187D6DF0744BFD9E372CD1DB863306"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entering into short-term and long-term contracts, including contracts for the services of consultants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2635CA1B57E14825945AC756261B6FE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making grants available, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8018F4A350F14387A60248442353496F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other appropriate measures, as the Secretary deems necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFCBA107FBD97478189189653CA80ED77"><enum>4.</enum><header>Providing enduring strategic advice via the China Strategic Advisory Board</header><subsection id="HD09E80FD2C1E4337A6C790C6F7926275"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an advisory commission to be known as the <quote>China Strategic Advisory Board</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Board</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2388BC5A0794F5784F392C553E22EBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties and Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Board shall—</text><paragraph id="HC10E743B392F4CE9AA1F1531F78AFB70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide advice, expertise, and continuity in United States foreign policy matters pertaining to strategic competition with the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H393CCD25F17949059477964DF6D091BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review recruitment, training, and retention of Civil Service and Foreign Service members with the expertise and experience necessary to support United States policy toward the PRC; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC65E83EAFD214EF1AF3976F86A59F099"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review programs across regional and functional bureaus intended to respond to strategic competition with the PRC, including the Counter PRC Malign Influence Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BE2EEB7315048A4A3A7D5F6A53DE914"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H330B6D1402CA4A34A186C2DBD642D186"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The Advisory Board shall consist of between 12 and 24 members, and shall have at least 10 years of demonstratable record of substantial experience pertaining to issues related to United States strategic competition with China. No sitting officer or employee of the United States Government shall be appointed to the Advisory Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H133A9252DC674BBAAFC7C9B823FA7DA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointments by democratic party</header><text>The Democratic Party leaders in the House of Representatives and in the Senate shall jointly make the following appointments:</text><subparagraph id="H01E8601AA11442C2918836DDC5C3157B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C00F3FE5C004E6F9F5230492FA2277A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4072D3F20759445E91FB5EAA5339B622"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2028.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C4E830C6FE444728C8A6E527953BCBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appointments by republican party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Republican Party leaders in the House of Representatives and in the Senate shall jointly make the following appointments:</text><subparagraph id="HEF0FBA3B8ECF40849DA3055CFC1163BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H169F9F3223E34B12BF7CADC2F34E5ADF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEC83A6366CF423EB7F48297C2C2CFCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One appointment with a term that expires on December 30, 2028.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02EA6225989240CDBFC217B5A8783BAC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appointments by President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall make the following appointments, with at least 2 of the appointees shall be between the ages of 30 and 50 years of age at the time of appointment:</text><subparagraph id="HAEA26427C64943CD84E4595E96865601"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AA9D62781F84813A0B79116CBA92A36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC123B357D14E29983E6C9D1315CF37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2028.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB257AD6F3444DB85D686A09CD755BF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appointments by Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of State shall make the following appointments, totaling at least 6 appointments and no more than a maximum of 12 appointments:</text><subparagraph id="H3CA33C34AB914B70A8D875B572F462DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B6C6DBDA5BF44F29AFE325D5BBBD2E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C0D88742DA74DD58C1FCB2CAAC74553"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two appointments with a term that expires on December 30, 2028.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H154CEE38A4934C2BA60230EBA407C612"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The appointees shall meet the following criteria:</text><clause id="HE87EF892AF464683AC4CADFE4C6EA9DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>At least one of the appointees shall be between the ages of 30 and 50 years of age at the time of appointment.</text></clause><clause id="HB6DCFBB56B8F46A1A46824072FA4FC56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>At least one shall be able to credibly represent the views of the United States business community.</text></clause><clause id="H3E9C4CCF5F954942A60ACEE2FD442C25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>At least one shall have demonstrable experience as a United States diplomat.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A3B8ED501E34AF387A20F5AAA1E7EE9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Each appointing authority referred to in paragraphs (2) through (5) shall make appointments not later than January 1, 2023. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E75A27F45AC451CAD8694BA33BEB0D5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Replacement</header><text>Each appointing authority referred to in paragraphs (2) through (5) shall make appointments to replace the appointees that the authority appointed whose terms have expired. The appointing authority shall make replacement appointments not later than January 30th of the calendar year following the term expiration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39F9DFE82695465E9D9AA3CA1576389D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Term</header><paragraph id="HB5277985665A4DE6B49FA9534ECF92EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the initial appointments described in subsections (c)(2) through (c)(5), the term of each member shall be 6 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D18020B43F4E2CA30EF6F1E1094D5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional terms</header><text>Members may be reappointed for no more than one additional term of service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8945D6E64B6490FA6AF4F9F726EBA16"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rotating term expiration</header><text>Following 6 years of service for the first class of Advisory Board members, the terms of <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the body shall expire. Every two subsequent years following that date, the terms of <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the members shall expire on a rotational basis. Each appointing authority referred to in subsection (c)(2) through (4) shall have rotating permission to appoint new members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63CEC20A7428429E93AC219EBDDB83CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection of chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall select, from among its members, a chairperson and vice chairperson to each serve a term of one year. A chairperson or vice chairperson may be reelected upon expiration of his or her term.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4034473A40734A458578472E476C76D0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HCDAA671DF5974EA796C31DB5F1DD467D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quorum; frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A majority of the members of the Advisory Board shall constitute a quorum. The Advisory Board shall meet at least quarterly or as frequently as may be necessary to carry out its duties. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90F1289FFF9B439EBC97FAC8330CDE6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>The Advisory Board may be divided into subcommittees that meet separately from the whole Board. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE0711B42D0C4DA4B7B9537DE70702BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings with officials</header><text>The Advisory Board shall collectively meet with the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development no less than once per year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8443ECE091947A49B4EDF77414BF9ED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Board shall provide semi-annual briefings to the appropriate Congressional committees on findings and recommendations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H348DF6B75FD44917A928947D92036BA3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Security Clearances</header><paragraph id="H46684F36011D4BD5BC9D1F81898EDDFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All members of the Advisory Board shall be granted the necessary security clearances, subject to the standard procedures for granting such clearances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0515B20BC8744822951B86C53CF250C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Need to know</header><text>For purposes of any law or regulation governing access to classified records, a member of the Advisory Committee seeking access under this paragraph to a record shall be deemed to have a need to know.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E5A4818ED24482DA31F09F0BB240FDB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Advisory Board shall—</text><paragraph id="HD9A4911AC61B43909CA125638650F7D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each receive compensation at a rate of not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5, United States Code, for each day such member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Advisory Board; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09AA886D24314C189183A170B524825A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services of the Advisory Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DD1D45C4A374850B7869FA0C09E8B51"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $100,000 for each fiscal year to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36F0847F1484499AAC62E1353C4A136C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text>The Secretary of State shall ensure that the Advisory Board has access to all appropriate information to carry out its duties and responsibilities under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7F6840C96FE448A9B0DD87BE73871951"><enum>5.</enum><header>Identifying long-term solutions through the Government Accountability Office</header><subsection id="HA2970F09ABAE493EA462355A5B2D72E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the personnel capacity and capability at the Department of State and USAID to support United States strategic competition with the People’s Republic of China and on available mechanisms to address any identified gaps.</text></subsection><subsection id="H00FE0D2B646746888E4507AC70EC40EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall—</text><paragraph id="H7D95DB4444924FC086FBE0536401FFFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify the percentage of vacant foreign service positions and civil service positions in the Indo-Pacific vis-à-vis other regions globally;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54FC859D6770453EB983DE45840A2E84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult Directors and Deputy Directors the Comptroller at State and USAID that the Comptroller General deems relevant for informing United States policies on competition with the PRC to provide a qualitative assessment of the gaps in understanding of the PRC among the foreign service, civil service, and intelligence community and how this perceived gap hampers their work; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01A365DF10484B39A82F6838A2302EEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify actions across Congress, the White House, and the Department of State can take in the 1, 5, and 10 year period to address current gaps.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85BBB24FA3114B21B8152FAE6C3D5CAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing and report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Comptroller General shall provide the appropriate Congressional Committees an interim briefing on the progress of the study conducted under subsection (b), including any preliminary observations, interim findings, and barriers to completing the work.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C005A7E40884A5A9B646C9CD05197F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) may be submitted in classified or unclassified form, but must have an unclassified summary.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF4DE0F635EA449609CD9042CB2E27C60"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

