<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDA665C88EC424ED2850D10DF2FABFD35" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6965 RH: Visit America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 382</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6965</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–508, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 7, 2022</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote travel and tourism in the United States, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HIF00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H633DB0268964468F8C930EAC1FC92A8F"><section id="H9DAAE6C5603941CD94982D81FD05E714" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Visit America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H12D86CD29F7849E089242CDBE3EF05FC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Travel and Tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(d) of the Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1979 (93 Stat. 1382; 5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H00880AE2B9F14DD5ACF0E9FA9A4F634C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>There shall be in the Department two additional Assistant Secretaries</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) There shall be in the Department 3 additional Assistant Secretaries, including the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAA25DD4F36B4742BC1024B64A946B7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAB1BBB1E765B4D31A96965EE2D539E56" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H109378BCC6DA4D1BA19E49216CC5DDEF" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFCC2CD8A3DFA4915A95F05195877CDEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, subject to the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECAC65CB46D94FC39847C72C513A31E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report directly to the Under Secretary for International Trade.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HFAF30A0DEAF04ED4AFF46B383CCF0566"><enum>3.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism</header><subsection id="H7FF7E1B56DB04C88B25E9CCF2CA85EB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visitation goals</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Travel and Tourism (referred to in this section as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>), appointed pursuant to section 2(d) of the Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1979, as amended by section 2, shall—</text><paragraph id="H96EF9B67CCBA4B018DB4C9DDB552D903"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an annual visitation goal, consistent with the goals of the travel and tourism strategy developed pursuant to section 4(1), for—</text><subparagraph id="H46580FFA4626473186E1943C4D55786F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of international visitors to the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DB25D30D5544ED0B6C9EFCF1098859D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the value of travel and tourism commerce;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC77F79AAEEC4CE8AF6BB988ABFAE586"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations for achieving the annual goals established pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD883580048B4E0588B576DB98C464B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that travel and tourism policy is developed in consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="HE63D6ABBD3D842A19A0105A8C6D3AA9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Tourism Policy Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66946E219F744AB0B6311FBAB2334BEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE571ADAC0F74E4782E86765B5E2918E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Travel and Tourism Office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E1273469373451BA5C0516BAA787529"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Brand USA;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF5F20154AEA447F97CA97834F19EF35"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF951EAF2B3849C6827574EE80059D84"><enum>(F)</enum><text>travel industry partners, including public and private destination marketing organizations, travel and tourism suppliers, and labor representatives from these industries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20AAA30428854619999F6FC815857016"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish short-, medium-, and long-term timelines for implementing the recommendations developed pursuant to paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3DC58B92DC415E983C5E7B441B1F0D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct Federal agency needs assessments, in consultation with the Office of Management and Budget, to identify the resources, statutory or regulatory changes, and private sector engagement needed to achieve the annual visitation goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD430CC2D45644F47A4570DA4556978B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide assessments and recommendations to—</text><subparagraph id="H5A878F66A7F640F6A097A98EAAF7A6A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB26964F374CA47AD87035F97C9FD4949"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FAE233ECB0F464B8E4FE63998CA92EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public through a publicly accessible website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17ED8298463B486EB00E6B61B5A4E7FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Visa adjudication</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall—</text><paragraph id="H2D746636CBD2491C9CC79D660B0DD82C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>explore strategies for improving visitor visa processing with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H4A4FC5281C444A64BB1BDB65DE585251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum time for processing visas, by visitation type;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1455177A3EB4AB4BEBC0242B1BAA15F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regulatory and policy changes needed to meet the visa processing goals referred to in subparagraph (A), including changes regarding technology, processing centers, and training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5400707082174DDE9D37450214424B56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>streamlining visa applications and adjudications, including application design and data collection procedures; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EF06983A1864ED69E15BA706C16E3AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>explore opportunities to establish pilot programs to integrate technology into the visitor visa adjudication process, including video conferencing and biometrics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H738398C31E6A4B72AE74DF7293CEDB0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Domestic travel and tourism</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, to the extent feasible, shall—</text><paragraph id="HAED78463BF3A41B1A2935F1E9457396C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate, on an ongoing basis, domestic policy options for supporting competitiveness with respect to the strengths, weaknesses, and growth of the domestic travel industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5221B275C247CB8027EA5E1D1D40B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations and goals to support and enhance domestic tourism, separated by business and leisure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5305BF6CE5EF44498B9262A8734BB73C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engage public and private stakeholders to support domestic tourism.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89FB2797147D4F94A64C4383E370DA92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Workforce</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HF30CE4C11E674F0AB144AD8B8D971245"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary of Labor to develop strategies and best practices for improving the timeliness and reliability of travel and tourism workforce data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C63B87A7FC44EC7A4AC8E27F6EC4C0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work with the Secretary of Labor and the Bureau of Economic Analysis to improve travel and tourism industry data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H413360F474A94983A17A0C7BBBED9CE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide recommendations for policy enhancements and efficiencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D06704CE8754EDB9CD8ED7923318CDE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>International business travel facilitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, in coordination with relevant Federal agencies, shall work to increase and facilitate international business travel to the United States and ensure competitiveness by engaging in, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="H1E3C27D2753042809DEA4916DBF5490C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitating large meetings, incentives, conferences, and exhibitions to be hosted in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7010957C4B6B48679293D53EED15C71C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasizing rural and other destinations rich in cultural heritage or ecological tourism, among other uniquely American destinations, as locations for hosting international meetings, incentives, conferences, and exhibitions in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0B7CA3E1E74E928711AEE45EB264A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitating sports and recreation events and activities, which shall be hosted in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5DC4BFCAFDB4F059EA3D53926D05147"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recovery strategy</header><paragraph id="HDC47DF82F50742928AB71F4FADA13827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial recovery strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after amounts are appropriated to accomplish the purposes of this section, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with public and private stakeholders identified in subsection (a)(3) and public health officials, shall develop and implement a COVID–19 public health emergency recovery strategy to assist the United States travel and tourism industry to quickly recover from the pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD73592F081F74E568E478F4AD7E98453"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future recovery strategies</header><text>After assisting in the implementation of the strategy developed pursuant to paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with appropriate public and private stakeholders, shall develop additional recovery strategies for the travel and tourism industry in anticipation of other unforeseen catastrophic events that would significantly affect the travel and tourism industry, such as hurricanes, floods, tsunamis, tornadoes, terrorist attacks, and pandemics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H257EDB670A184DC7A8AB3D47B1FD48AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-benefit analysis</header><text>In developing the COVID–19 public health emergency recovery strategy under paragraph (1) and additional recovery strategies for the travel and tourism industry under paragraph (2), the Assistant Secretary shall conduct cost-benefit analyses that take into account the health and economic effects of public health mitigation measures on the travel and tourism industry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5DE06AB00FD4111A83001010A2E7B14"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="HCF68D351CDCD454CA0C10EA085FAB7B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall produce an annual forecasting report on the travel and tourism industry, to the extent feasible, which shall include current and anticipated—</text><subparagraph id="H21AE93D529DA4B188EC3F0DA77C10400"><enum>(A)</enum><text>domestic employment needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4985B8AFEE3B4711980DD8AA16ABCABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>international inbound volume and spending, taking into account the lasting effects of the COVID–19 public health emergency and the impact of the recovery strategy implemented pursuant to subsection (f)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC40BEDE8DC84DA8B68BA52AED15E5AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>domestic volume and spending, including Federal and State public land travel and tourism data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C93580F09B41D2A20469EFCBEE6094"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau of economic analysis</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis should annually update, to the extent feasible, the Travel and Tourism Satellite Accounts, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA3B2A822868442A48AD4124A51172A70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State level travel and tourism spending data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBC72FCF7685408ABFB78A418BDB1402"><enum>(B)</enum><text>travel and tourism workforce data for full-time and part-time employment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H606160311EED4AB2AD09E9B7EECC0984"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal and State public lands outdoor recreational activity and tourism spending data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA40CBD5FFBE4D8B82E7DD572DA9801C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National travel and tourism office</header><text>The Director of the National Travel and Tourism Office—</text><subparagraph id="HE6EA9CF2EA3043A88F365A558C261E8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in partnership with the Bureau of Economic Analysis, shall report international arrival and spending data on a regular monthly schedule, which shall be made available to the Travel and Tourism Advisory Board and to the public through a publicly available website; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501153A67F4942E9AB26DEDD71E26726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include questions in the Survey of International Air Travelers regarding wait-times, visits to public lands, and State data, to the extent applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC4D0EEC903464297B2D71247687B62ED"><enum>4.</enum><header>Travel and tourism strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board, the Tourism Policy Council, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall develop and submit to Congress a 10-year travel and tourism strategy, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HA0390E8B48F5467894A4EEE291680FAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment of goals with respect to the number of annual international visitors to the United States and the annual value of travel and tourism commerce in the United States during such 10-year period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE99DFF0EFE7C46369B7D0E05B144C808"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the resources needed to achieve the goals established pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B135B63CDF142FD875645E0BF5FD3EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for statutory or regulatory changes that would be necessary to achieve such goals.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H905821E802BF4D13B482CC355AD4D874"><enum>5.</enum><header>United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Act of July 19, 1940, entitled <quote>An Act to encourage travel in the United States, and for other purposes</quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1546">15 U.S.C. 1546</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H98692A06E887468A9FC5868408E3539C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">Sec. 3.</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>The Secretary of the Interior is authorized</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0689D704D02D4A74BB255ABD9040FBFF" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="H6660713221AF47DDB437BD11F224D604" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; Advisory committee</header><subsection id="H41430FBE66AA4EF29CA1C4C5537DAC7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board</header><paragraph id="H6A816717C4054F7F8EAE0AFA01A87E9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Board</quote>), the members of which shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce for 2-year terms from among companies and organizations in the travel and tourism industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34C1650FC0114AFEAE4092B8C4E20DCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Travel and Tourism shall serve as the Executive Director of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE12EA911654B4EB895194325DE9106"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive secretariat</header><text>The Director of the National Travel and Tourism Office of the International Trade Administration shall serve as the Executive Secretariat for the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF441E20C87418FB2AC949EB05177CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Board’s Charter shall specify that the Board will—</text><subparagraph id="H70AC056F3DE34AE2A190945C3BBC23CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as the advisory body to the Secretary of Commerce on matters relating to the travel and tourism industry in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CA78AB95B3B4290B76F5CC4F43C5B69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advise the Secretary of Commerce on Government policies and programs that affect the United States travel and tourism industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D15C3BBAD4E41DB9E07913DF9B275BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offer counsel on current and emerging issues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48ECE26AC92439BAFAE132CFE691408"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide a forum for discussing and proposing solutions to problems related to the travel and tourism industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H966A39F0D1ED457A864A0C3BC0876F41"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide advice regarding the domestic travel and tourism industry as an economic engine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AD3978B59A0420DB1AB8A9F0E1C5F63"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recovery strategy</header><text>The Board shall assist the Assistant Secretary in the development and implementation of the COVID–19 public health emergency recovery strategy required under section 3(f)(1) of the <short-title>Visit America Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H370AB3BC9E694F599E40E6A59DFDF8C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory committee for promotion of tourist travel</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce is authorized</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F73D6C7DCB74AADA76B314431076332"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the Secretary of the Interior to serve</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary of Commerce to serve</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDEB09E854D76489BA9D212B8AFF141F2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Data on domestic travel and tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall collect and make public aggregate data on domestic travel and tourism trends.</text></section><section id="H0B64B33B52AC4E48B98916EFDEF7E463"><enum>7.</enum><header>Completion of proceeding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the Secretary of Commerce has, before the date of the enactment of this Act, taken action that in whole or in part implements this Act or the amendments made by this Act, the Secretary is not required to revisit such action, but only to the extent such action is consistent with this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section><section id="H54E22862B4384511BB48A69870A6E36A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>COVID–19 public health emergency</quote>—</text><paragraph id="H20D8794E4C314F21BC6C4C95E35A31DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means the public health emergency first declared on January 31, 2020, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) with respect to COVID–19; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B3C5982AE3D4B79AD104E00A196B1CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes any renewal of such declaration pursuant to such section 319.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

