<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H050AB3FB19574588B75CF912E7621EE6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1492 RH: Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 491</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1492</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–672, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210302">March 2, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent methane waste and pollution from oil and gas operations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA4EA00C47A44AA2A26E6B819F0E6B16" style="OLC"><section id="H2D4248EFFD274B5FAE704B18B1C682D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7066D29645264C6BB71066ECB4952013"><enum>2.</enum><header>Controlling methane emissions from the oil and natural gas sector</header><subsection id="H2BC98B3BDFB940739AA5CD5375B9EF77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National goals</header><text>The goals of this section are to steadily reduce the quantity of United States methane emissions from the oil and natural gas sector such that—</text><paragraph id="HD13C12FF37FA4434B19DE3AF8078C4C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in calendar year 2025, the quantity of United States methane emissions from the oil and natural gas sector is at least 65 percent below calendar year 2012 emissions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC53AE777A1564ECE92A652245896FD22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in calendar year 2030, the quantity of United States methane emissions from the oil and natural gas sector is at least 90 percent below calendar year 2012 emissions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H155B842EEF6C4E0D8A909A5720A2456B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations To meet the national goals</header><paragraph id="H8E847FA794F6448D810CACB6A741FF0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall issue regulations pursuant to the existing authority of the Administrator under section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) to control methane emissions from the oil and natural gas sector to achieve the national goals described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF95FBB683C45C08BBF9793FCFDD30B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered sources</header><text>The regulations promulgated pursuant to this subsection shall apply to sources of methane from every segment of oil and natural gas systems, including oil and natural gas production, processing, transmission, distribution, and storage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2EB63AF672641ED9C8113AC56A1F1B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meeting the goal for 2025</header><subparagraph id="H09642D3A3C1C4D49B5CFD63BAC86B435"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline for issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2022, the Administrator shall finalize regulations pursuant to the existing authority of the Administrator under sections 111(b) and 111(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(b)</external-xref>, (d)) to achieve the national goal described in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AD75DE24B6D4713B2D26AE91EEE546B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The regulations required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="H72FDC4C763604478B71CED4430DB98D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations shall prescribe procedures for the establishment, implementation, and enforcement of standards of performance or design, equipment, work practice, or operational standards, or combination thereof, for existing sources and guidelines for States.</text></clause><clause id="HE209DF1EE71346A1B400B7E2438516CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The regulations shall require States to submit plans in accordance with section 111(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(d)</external-xref>) no later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause><clause id="HC7251770A7D940639007BBF8128D4CE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The regulations shall provide for the Administrator to prescribe, not later than 42 months after the date of enactment of this Act, a plan in accordance with such section 111(d)—</text><subclause id="H697FB2C95ED74A8399EDCCA3FCE410D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for a State that fails to submit a plan by the deadline specified in clause (ii); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE1C14463CADA4FAEB1624596B8C57062"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a State for which the Administrator disapproves the State plan.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98097C92C4794E2082EB1BA81EAE5F2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meeting the goal for 2030</header><subparagraph id="HA9E704BD78D34BCBB2112A2FF577B3D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2023, the Administrator shall finalize regulations pursuant to the existing authority of the Administrator under sections 111(b) and 111(d) to achieve the national goal described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC80F1836FB5A4D019FB82CB05714C612"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations required by subparagraph (A) shall provide for the establishment, implementation, and enforcement of standards of performance or design, equipment, work practice, or operational standards, or combination thereof, for new sources and existing sources, and guidelines for States, that include requirements for—</text><clause id="H5E6EEDEB919E44FCAE6D40AA6E99C270"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">new and existing natural gas transmission, gathering, and distribution pipelines to reduce methane emissions by application of the best system of emissions reduction pertaining to venting, flaring, and leakage reduction;</text></clause><clause id="H86CFCAD80E9140D7827CB314AE9DE93B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>new sources, and existing sources, with equipment that handles liquefied natural gas to reduce methane emissions from that equipment by application of the best system of emission reduction; </text></clause><clause id="HE41118C849884A00870E3FFFA8655923"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>new and existing offshore petroleum and natural gas production facilities to reduce methane emissions by application of the best system of emission reduction; and</text></clause><clause id="H166C3BE84B8B480D9797A1A65B703C36"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any source addressed under the regulations promulgated under paragraph (3) for which the Administrator determines that a more stringent standard is necessary to achieve the national goal under subsection (a)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15C28AFB48204698B90F9B54BE006A62"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distribution of hydrogen</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing this section, the Administrator shall ensure that any new distribution infrastructure is compatible with the distribution of hydrogen.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BC30ECABCB4466D9ACB67F3A73B6E31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H221409A55397432A9115E543D2D93A36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7B934123AF24BACBD20FF469BCEE186"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The phrase <quote>design, equipment, work practice, or operational standard, or combination thereof</quote> has the meaning given to such phrase for purposes of section 111(h) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(h)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H443D447C83014E988E5522483FEB445D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The terms <term>existing source</term>, <term>new source</term>, and <term>standard of performance</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3C2A7BD000A24EC2930E4DCD8AABFCA9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting</header><subsection id="H7C54AF47F7624851AA16BE6F5DFB8F5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1711">30 U.S.C. 1711 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H66909BAC29A542E3BFBC02BAB2444FB8" style="OLC"><section id="HA547693284B44F00BA3C3A93389E25B1"><enum>118.</enum><header>Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting</header><subsection id="HD615B57BFF1043118889A283015FD9EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations for preventing and reducing waste of gas via venting, flaring, and fugitive releases</header><paragraph id="H533EA4F2A7154A24AFB4DFE84F7DC211"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to issue regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue regulations pursuant to the Secretary’s authority under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the Indian Mineral Leasing Act of 1938, and other statutes authorizing the Secretary to regulate oil and gas activities on Federal land and Indian lands, that establish requirements for reducing and preventing the waste of gas, including by venting, flaring, and fugitive releases, from covered operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7CD47FFC88B4573A984F5FFEE7A97F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content of regulations</header><text>The regulations shall, with respect to covered operations—</text><subparagraph id="H6002266422C5411396AD679F9ABBC295"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that, beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title>, each operator captures at least 85 percent of all gas produced in each year from each onshore well that is subject to a mineral leasing law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DBB43046B99412B8D780FCD6789F515"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that, beginning not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title>, each operator captures at least 99 percent of all gas produced in each year from each onshore well that is subject to a mineral leasing law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EE412320A554176995895438D2966FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require flaring of gas, rather than venting, in all instances in which gas is not captured;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H553C485703AC4F9192792D4331877D04"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require that every application for a permit to drill a production well—</text><clause id="H0BD248AC69E14EC0AFD057ECE3BF7962"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrate sufficient infrastructure and capacity is in place to capture the expected quantity of produced gas from the well; and</text></clause><clause id="HBC9FB91FE2E64A8CB90A406C31227584"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be published with an opportunity for a public comment period of at least 30 days;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H626F5ACDF11B4FBB977B4D9C3BC9CE1E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title>, prohibit all new and refractured production wells from venting or flaring;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CDA72F06AAA4755BF3CFEAB5219AB70"><enum>(F)</enum><text>require the operator of any covered operation that routinely flares gas before the effective date of a regulation prohibiting flaring issued pursuant to subparagraph (E) to submit a gas capture plan to the Secretary not later than 180 days before such effective date that ensures that such operator will meet the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80A8D63A3D4344DF85EEDCBA5BF4E0E1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>set performance standards for newly installed equipment based on modern equipment that minimize gas loss from—</text><clause id="H34BB56706F1E4A7BAB7DE156F583E632"><enum>(i)</enum><text>storage tanks;</text></clause><clause id="HD3A8F131ACFE4C2B88DB802C6609992F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dehydrators;</text></clause><clause id="HC5AF2528FED94500B4C977808B680145"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compressors;</text></clause><clause id="HFDEB5D7F031741479FACFAFE4C162D82"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>open-ended valves or lines; and</text></clause><clause id="H37F5F48EB571405A9BB5BF2BFDD93940"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other equipment as the Secretary determines appropriate to reduce and prevent gas release;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F27144A44EE42B782C9EDAD52E52E90"><enum>(H)</enum><text>require that operators replace existing equipment within one year of the publication date of performance standards established under subsection (G);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H345FA6755AA8486FB5FBBE9C726629B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require the replacement of all gas-actuated pneumatic controllers and pumps with nonemitting equipment not later than 180 days after the date of issuance of the regulation enacted under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A13C78979074526B15E00A16A2F32E8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>set performance standards based on modern procedures and equipment that minimize gas loss from—</text><clause id="H35D810FD6DF74F38B1D42BF6482CD0C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>downhole maintenance;</text></clause><clause id="H8687D347CFB14034B95CC4F0616B5BE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>liquids unloading;</text></clause><clause id="H037BD333BCAF4158BFEC17C61ECCF749"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>well completion; and</text></clause><clause id="H9AAE1F6E3B3543658344F58D4CC23397"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other procedures as the Secretary determines appropriate to reduce and prevent gas release;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB246570AFC904DCB968758ED982BA610"><enum>(K)</enum><text>require all operators to have leak detection programs with monthly inspections that assess the entire covered operation using an infrared camera or other equipment with methods that provide overall at least equivalent sensitivity and effectiveness in detecting leaks on a timely basis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF29E603E77A4623B48526C029C829E5"><enum>(L)</enum><text>require any leaks found to be repaired promptly, and in any case not later than 4 weeks after the discovery of the leak, except where exceptional circumstances warrant an extension of not more than 8 additional weeks; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA525B02BDE5A42999CE561AC9C3939DE"><enum>(M)</enum><text>require recordkeeping for—</text><clause id="H79BF3A9F47354DE69728398B30D8C37B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>equipment maintenance;</text></clause><clause id="H70D0CEF32ABB4700BD9CEFEB64AAFFF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>leak detection and repair;</text></clause><clause id="H000766BF37604D998614ABEB195C7656"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>venting events;</text></clause><clause id="H8DEC16C524A54599827111051046004A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>flaring events; and</text></clause><clause id="HAFA9398F1CA24C1C972DFE064B02D8D8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other operations as the Secretary determines appropriate to reduce and prevent gas release.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB90DCCA310614580A56B8D343F10644E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gas measuring, reporting, and transparency requirements</header><paragraph id="H46B0D7E4E7954BD29FBE35CAB4805F81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than one year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Methane Waste Prevention Act of 2021</short-title>, issue regulations requiring each operator to measure and report, with respect to all gas subject to the mineral leasing laws, all such gas produced, consumed on site, or lost through venting, flaring, or fugitive releases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H657722026DB3475DAA0EDED471AC7360"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measuring and reporting requirements</header><text>To account for all gas referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall issue regulations requiring each operator to—</text><subparagraph id="H4836D3FC105344F9A730B1DF57F8606B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>install metering devices to measure all flared gas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF032CF8B988427CB535F482CD3FAD00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Secretary the volumes of gas measured pursuant to the requirements of this subsection, including—</text><clause id="H9D54208F6BAE4EFF827150065DB63689"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all new measured values for production and disposition, including vented and flared volumes; and</text></clause><clause id="HB15748139BFF440FB91156F29EB65D74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>values for fugitive releases based on guidelines for their calculation established by the Secretary in such regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90246760FCA44B62BBED004EDB73FFB3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall make all new data produced under the requirements established by the Secretary under this subsection, including calculated fugitive releases and volumes of gas lost to venting and flaring, publicly available through the internet—</text><subparagraph id="HE0F7C8E3DB9242CA9CB33BDCB9BC5DB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>without a fee or other access charge;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF75B237E60C4AEFBBA36210D1E46E95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a searchable, sortable, and down­load­able manner, to the extent technically possible; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F2B74A3E4754C48900350F34666FF97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as soon as technically practicable after the report by the operator is filed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C07CD4C1AA5409892C5742C9F16F57B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Except as otherwise specified in this section, the requirements established by the Secretary under this section shall apply to—</text><paragraph id="HD77043B35B54420EA8F3874C84676386"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the construction and operation of any covered operation initiated, including the refracturing of existing wells, on or after the date of the issuance of regulations under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9187D9E647B4C7CA197987CAC9E5E9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of the issuance of such regulations, any covered operation initiated before the date of the issuance of such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA814B5ECDA78452E818069D3B3A52BE4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement mechanisms</header><paragraph id="HF0542D14E24E42729F5EB61624E0A3F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the regulations issued under this section consistent enforcement mechanisms for covered operations that are not in compliance with the requirements established by the regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33E02924AFED468486AA6BDEA6AAF3B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the enforcement mechanisms described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HB4ACF9629D614934BF8C098FF0FF04D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>civil penalties for unauthorized venting and flaring, which shall—</text><clause id="HBD7D47D86632403FB80C00905ECEC86D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply in lieu of the penalties and related provisions under section 109; and</text></clause><clause id="H94C73DFBD33B41D5AA136811D8B67ED3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include production restrictions and civil monetary penalties equivalent to 15 times the market value of the vented gas and 3 times the value of the flared gas; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD4B236008B4486F9ACC517F3C22BD09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>civil penalties that apply to noncompliance with other new or existing procedures, which shall—</text><clause id="H171FDB06E23A40E8B3857E16A50AA54A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply in addition to or in lieu of the penalties and related provisions under section 109;</text></clause><clause id="H1D278A44C7B1475D9A4368A0CDEABCF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include production restrictions or monetary penalties, or both; and</text></clause><clause id="HCDD2AC0587CD4204A22CE4F170931FF3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of monetary penalties, be proportional to market conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6E59980513E4243B715A9E4B4A96150"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H65CC14B55AC744529284F57DA2609DB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capture</header><text>The term <term>capture</term> means the physical containment of natural gas for transportation to market or productive use of natural gas, and includes reinjection and royalty-free on-site uses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E29DF1A9344631B41C282A84EF77CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered operations</header><text>The term <term>covered operations</term> means all oil and gas operations that are subject to mineral leasing law or title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1761">30 U.S.C. 1761 et seq.</external-xref>), regardless of size, including production, storage, gathering, processing, and handling operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1AF1E4E2FCA4ED2ACECA3D1F87C553E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flare and flaring</header><text>The terms <term>flare</term> and <term>flaring</term> mean the intentional and controlled burning of gas that occurs in the course of oil and gas operations to limit release of gas to the atmosphere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8554C4BA8B8040D99AF2919D1A74763D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fugitive release</header><text>The term <term>fugitive release</term> means the unintentional and uncontrolled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H057DAAC5A6404B38BCF177B1B9042FB9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gas capture plan</header><text>The term <term>gas capture plan</term> means a plan that includes specific goals, including equipment and timelines, for capturing, gathering, and processing gas produced under an oil or gas lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3DC30FE41F643969DDA6DAF105A36B8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Gas release</header><text>The term <term>gas release</term> includes all gas that is discharged to the atmosphere via venting or fugitive release.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34F14BCADCE54AC99131386EE4DA78CE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Vent and venting</header><text>The terms <term>vent</term> and <term>venting</term> mean the intentional and controlled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas operations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9CC6C3544CA940E6A11EF6896AAB1490"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 117 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H843AB778028844C2BAE2FB06F12A85C7" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 118. Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB9F95C6541004F179AF1EC4952A9839B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall update the regulations required by the amendments made by this section when the Secretary determines appropriate, but no less frequently than once every five years, to reflect new information regarding gas waste, the impacts of that waste, and the availability of technologies and performance measures to reduce gas waste.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6E094CE01A445C69CAF74643DEAF72F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of prior rule</header><text>The final rule entitled <quote>Waste Prevention, Production Subject to Royalties, and Resource Conservation</quote>, as published in the Federal Register November 18, 2016 (81 Fed. Reg. 83008), is hereby reinstated, and each of its provisions shall apply unless and until the effective date of a subsequent final rule promulgated under the amendment made by subsection (a), or promulgated under another applicable authority, that replaces or repeals such provision.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1265BEE354D44DD4B419C7590047D993"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment of venting, flaring, and fugitive releases</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date the Secretary of the Interior first receives data submitted under the requirements established under subsection (b) of section 118 of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982, as amended by this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H34D55C87F5FE4547A32158280C660A3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit a report to Congress describing—</text><subparagraph id="H957CF492F1864014B8F593BC5AA32997"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the volume of fugitive releases, and gas consumed or lost by venting and flaring, from covered operations (as those terms are used in such section); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E6FE8DD22B24CCCAF898E9D1E61AD90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional regulations the Secretary considers would help further curtail venting, flaring, and fugitive releases, or the rational basis for not issuing such additional regulations if the Secretary considers additional regulations would not be appropriate to further curtail venting, flaring, and fugitive releases; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA69257D869F24333A2389F4BFD059948"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue regulations described in the report required by paragraph (1)(B) not later than 1 year after the date of the submission of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

