<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H515D70372DFF4E9D85E83C0F9AAC6805" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8064 IH: Advanced Manufacturing Jobs in America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish demonstration and pilot projects to facilitate education and training programs in the field of advanced manufacturing.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H510120E0FD244901BAFBA5AECAE365BE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB928B1DE88394378B855DE77A14DC9DB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Manufacturing Jobs in America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE15D3FC7DA674F5D8126DE1104DC176F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration and pilot projects to support advanced manufacturing workforce development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 169 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3224">29 U.S.C. 3224</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H5630AA97342B49A08B58185C578ABCBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA501BB4AB46940008C0AF57C31588863"> <subsection id="H4BD6EF207BCD4F10B8B8A9D187B5AB56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advanced manufacturing workforce development program</header> <paragraph id="HEC0019F49ACD4DD69DC1335C40A684F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under a plan published under subsection (b), the Secretary shall, through grants or contracts, carry out demonstration and pilot projects for the purpose of facilitating education and training programs in the field of advanced manufacturing, which projects shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H28B96A5A894347DC9233E660336074D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>target skills and competency development in communities with expected growth in advanced manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35C7694466314EFDA87498542DA7DFC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide education and training, for available jobs or job openings that are anticipated in advanced manufacturing, which result in a covered skill set and corresponding covered credential;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3D6AF0A8B0F94A7D8527FAC9DD3896A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educate individuals about opportunities for career advancement within advanced manufacturing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H93D64DEC143C45DD85843A43B3364C98"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be carried out in a way that gives priority to incumbent workers, dislocated workers, unemployed individuals, workers from rural areas, and underrepresented individuals (such as underrepresented racial and ethnic minorities). </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30002BEF577840F282192CADDC57A3A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
<subparagraph id="H679879B49F2041E7956AF7B7A55409CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant or contract under this subsection for a project under paragraph (1), an entity shall be one of the following entities in any of the several States or territories, in partnership with a manufacturer who employs individuals with advanced manufacturing skills (or a consortium of such partnerships):</text> <clause commented="no" id="H8AC4F9AF78AF4E48B4F06B2FB76380B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A technical college that offers a 2-year degree or program of study or an individual community college, such as a public or nonprofit community college, or a community college that is a tribally controlled college or university (as defined in section 2(a) of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1801">25 U.S.C. 1801(a)</external-xref>)).</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HA42007C3073B47ADBF8C18E845AA739E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A community college district system.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HDB6722C98FBC49D6953683553C73A8ED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A State community college system.</text></clause>
<clause id="HC55768C036334496874D85C37AC8BA57"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A local board, in partnership with one or more one-stop centers, that specifies one or more community colleges where education and training activities will occur.</text></clause> <clause id="HCB950FDB50594EFEA6B42B1B468214DA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A manufacturing extension center established under section 25(b) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278k">15 U.S.C. 278k</external-xref>).</text></clause>
<clause id="HB606C979A498450AA31D9F746B8E1EFB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A local educational agency.</text></clause> <clause id="H5595B4D692BE4ED980E0D31C86BF8E63"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Another entity, such as a public-private partnership, or the collection of entities and individuals carrying out an advanced manufacturing forum, that would serve educationally underrepresented individuals (such as underrepresented racial and ethnic minorities). </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB39959B50EA54CBF8B9591F763085CFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall give priority to any consortium of the partnerships described in subparagraph (A) that leverages substantial non-Federal funding for the project involved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC69F79EB489F40B1AD9963757B12010D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant or contract under this subsection, an entity shall submit an application at such time and in such form and manner as the Secretary shall determine, including the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H99364560C8D14A2CB463B67CD7755157"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the eligible entity, evidence of the eligible entity’s capacity to carry out activities in support of the strategic objectives described in the subparagraphs of paragraph (1), and a description of the expected participation and responsibilities of the eligible entity, or each partnership in the eligible entity in the case of a consortium.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H713A9E1D62E340AF881544D4ABC0BF9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of education and training activities to be provided that will—</text>
<clause id="HD0613AD41A664C54BA9AC48702F41D66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop skills and competencies demanded by advanced manufacturing businesses;</text></clause> <clause id="H2B4F4BF8BBA74C93882F286F3B622F69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead to a covered skill set and a corresponding covered credential; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3529A1E2341B411AB939EE64B05883A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>educate individuals about opportunities for career advancement and wage growth within advanced manufacturing.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD16F503D95684E138ED080A0C7C11182"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the economy where the entity is located would benefit, including—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HF0BC54DE9E904B1CBC48E69E33288ED8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evidence of the growth of advanced manufacturing in the State or locality involved;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H57E28833096943F1926D9AAFB61EAB99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information on the potential for additional job growth with investments in advanced manufacturing; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H74E115D792BB4F6387624C4250BF473E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information on how the activities will expose incumbent or dislocated workers, or unemployed individuals, to new advanced manufacturing technology skill sets.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2758F04926A04FEA8E297D441EC46F60"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity will employ evidence-based training models that integrate academic instruction with training, including on-the-job training in advanced manufacturing, to meet performance goals described in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D48675D6D25462DACE22D5E553B3A93"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity will coordinate activities with State boards or local boards, and State or local economic development officials.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC074D7EAC6954A74B0498CC8285FD639"><enum>(F)</enum><text>In the case of education and training activities that lead to a covered credential, a description of those activities leading to that credential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7714FAAB356D4F158DCB3D4427F45450"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Activities to be carried out under a project funded under paragraph (1) may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7F3EFE3758A43038A4F4D17F3784729"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classroom and onsite experiential learning;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC8294F84440A440582E5EB8AC7D1442C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on-the-job training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4AB9D42DE2274D858EA08108CC0345EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training which fits into an industry-recognized competency model for advanced manufacturing;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H728CB6F6D0954073A2614C8B9C8D4706"><enum>(D)</enum><text>development and implementation of registered apprenticeship and pre-apprenticeship programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91910DEECDE449C6A9B85143D825A9F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordination with local boards in order to implement and utilize existing (as of the first date of such coordination) articulation agreements with universities and other educational partners;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA5BB2906A93048F0A932A2BC8E3C1092"><enum>(F)</enum><text>distance learning; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE49A240776640B59660AC068308B992"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other activity the Secretary considers appropriate for providing education or training in advanced manufacturing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A200B5E16D0425DAE5B5627F6E0CB0A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Performance goals and measures</header>
<subparagraph id="HBA366CA721DD49A38E755FF1E4496E96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The performance goals for the activities provided through a project under this subsection shall be to—</text> <clause id="H17C2AD13BDB341C29F960121D2CF5A31"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance the skill sets of incumbent and dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals, who live in communities with expected growth in advanced manufacturing and enable such workers to obtain a covered skill set and a corresponding covered credential;</text></clause>
<clause id="H699FDCCD9BD4432A9787EEC17D3B9EB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop competencies of individuals with limited experience in advanced manufacturing;</text></clause> <clause id="H1C6B007341844A0FA3E864161FD41225"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strengthen community college partnerships with manufacturing extension centers described in paragraph (2)(A)(v) and advanced manufacturing businesses in an effort to meet the needs of the businesses for adaptability in training of incumbent and dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFEB0088016A74F25B804D1B68B0E7992"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>more fully utilize the capabilities of such manufacturing extension centers within the State involved;</text></clause> <clause id="HD6A1B474B3084C41935F467EB568F729"><enum>(v)</enum><text>strengthen partnerships of advanced manufacturing businesses with local boards and, if applicable, local educational agencies; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H8937CCF792ED4D0188ED2F21FD6333F0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>help incumbent and dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals, develop skills which lead to greater earnings.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08C79A07BEC246119877C2ACC90E0075"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall negotiate and reach agreement with each eligible entity that receives a grant or contract under this subsection, on performance measures that will be used to evaluate the performance of the eligible entity in carrying out the activities provided through a project under this subsection. Each performance measure shall be designed to enable the eligible entity to meet the performance goals described in subparagraph (A) and shall include an indicator of performance, which may include—</text>
<clause id="HC94A925A8B5B4559AB6EDF2D7A337BB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incumbent and dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals, receiving a covered credential for advanced manufacturing;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H60010F8813294123AD2D3602562CB187"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incumbent and dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals, attaining basic skills, as described in a covered skill set for advanced manufacturing;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HDCF252A23D43411EB85D46A3FE82EA3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incumbent workers whose education and training, provided through a project, enables them to meet the needs of their employers for skilled workers to enhance operations;</text></clause> <clause id="H433C502FF294427597DE3E74C0EC652D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the earnings growth of a manufacturer as a result of education and training provided through a project; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H5CD20EDADF824F9C8D2C351A2405CBF6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>another indicator the Secretary determines to be necessary to meet performance goals described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H276FC20883304FEABD875CBC9B8CE1B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the first disbursement of funds under this subsection, the Secretary shall provide for the continuing evaluation of the projects described in this subsection and funded under section 172, and shall transmit a report of the evaluation to Congress not later than 2 years after such date.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H51F0C809375D4B298B15F2158A841C1E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H96D00AF92E794A2399487109756CDE6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered credential</header><text>The term <term>covered credential</term> means—</text>
<clause id="H4943BC0E409D434696CA30C070098AF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential, such as an educational certificate or degree, an occupational license, an industry-sponsored certificate or certification, and a registered apprenticeship certificate or degree; or</text></clause> <clause id="H3F773F55AEFC4B29B94C0C8F54ECE352"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an employer-recognized credential.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7F8B3AC2DC59427081D1F9C6387C6B83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered skill set</header><text>The term <term>covered skill set</term> means an industry-recognized or employer-recognized skill set.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE04ADE9CBEC4ADC870AE9D9CC5B7617"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>The plan shall describe the projects described in subsection (d), to be carried out in accordance with that subsection.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H10BF264F7B4C403C8D4E278DDB390FB9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect as if enacted as part of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

