<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7EB76FDF1B4D41D5A92E147ED0F59011" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8990 IH: Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8990</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to restrict trading and ownership of covered investments by senior government officials, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H55218407585A4ADE89FDD26534D6BD41" style="OLC">
<section id="H62DA534D1DC04C23AC6B022A38F27E1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H10CBE90672424CA58A49D1521AB94FDE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restricting trading and ownership of covered investments by senior government officials</header> <subsection id="H299577BD7B8848A892FAED74ECF32BA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust amendments</header><text>Section 102(f)(3) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App 102(f)(3)) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HCF83D2248DDE40A9B10E438EE3E475D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C)(iii), by striking <quote>promptly notify</quote> and inserting <quote>promptly provide a written notice to</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D8125E73450492D8880FCBADD060BCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB389DA4E65584A61B1A5148E1775615F" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="H7052725DA464409586BAB784ACAE5152" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any asset described as a covered investment under title II that is placed in a trust after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> shall be divested not later than 18 months after such asset was so placed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66F6AE1B1163428C80B56655D6C80E06" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) through (G), a form of a trust approved by the Office of Government Ethics, Judicial Conference, House of Representatives, or Senate through rule making or by majority vote for its respective jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H609C73BFB5C74CCCAC6E05722A059190"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trade and ownership restrictions</header><text>The Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by inserting after title I the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB12BE6FF8C8C460EA0CD2F258693605F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <title id="H4FC0DA228AE6447383304E9100D5B1BC"><enum>II</enum><header>Restrictions on trade and ownership of covered investments by federal personnel</header> <section id="HAB1693E333084E46AEDBE47D1B90D398"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
<paragraph id="HAC20D791A0E6451AA000130CB69CB494"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commodity</header><text>The term <term>commodity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA25783A779484AA49A45EC34B420B2C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered investment</header><text>The term <term>covered investment</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2C171DA165BB4767B4E2019610F12502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an investment in a security, a commodity, a future, cryptocurrency or other digital asset, or any comparable economic interest acquired through synthetic means, such as the use of a derivative, including an option, warrant, or other similar means; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB756521EA6324F2B912E2601961CA3B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text>
<clause id="H48C1E18C18F04924AF6DF763F4A73217"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a widely held investment fund described in section 102(f)(8) that is diversified and publicly traded on a national or regional stock exchange;</text></clause> <clause id="HD408AEF856454A5E8556FE95A0A87232"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an asset held in a qualified blind trust;</text></clause>
<clause id="H687866B7A0DC42DC844C50991956D106"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an asset held in a qualified diversified trust;</text></clause> <clause id="H1202ECD841224123B739FC2CBC452660"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause>
<clause id="H92D2D4A3DB73471ABF90EDE5D43857DE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a diversified exchange-traded fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause> <clause id="H015A86D0566D49CAA33AF69BDCD8C8C4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a United States Treasury bill, note, or bond;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBFF01827C0EB4A668ECE8B9E2818F355"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a State or municipal government bill, note, or bond;</text></clause> <clause id="H64F05B28D137498E92642C47DEACE044"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Thrift Savings Plan (including any holdings in such plan);</text></clause>
<clause id="H63FA91CB3179422380413DF8B094907B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>any compensation received by the spouse or dependent child of a covered official from their primary employer;</text></clause> <clause id="HE9DE723BF8364C7AB9A40CB35886BB84"><enum>(x)</enum><text>any investment fund held in a Federal, State, or local government employee retirement plan; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H2FD8053DF29F4C6A8D5A38FA99D49F48" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>an interest in a small business concern or family-owned business that does not present a conflict of interest.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5A3147B7E2F49F285E5C772B0548E0E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H59C19BD61A894C769066646BE878E420" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Member of Congress as defined in section 109(12);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H135D4A76BF614DCAABB56AA44BCE5F58" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9B9DA782ADA44FD9A09CC8CFEB8179A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each officer or employee of the legislative branch (except any officer or employee of the Government Accountability Office) who, for at least 120 days, occupies a position for which the basic rate of pay is equal to or greater than 120 percent of the minimum rate of basic pay payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3869EAB41B348CF85EED1435B26F4A2" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the President;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H034883D7A42746FBAB46DE753F204907" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Vice President;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BD537DB283249CBAF3C3138D41E3DFB" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a political appointee who was appointed to such position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8CC2EDEC904F4D96B702DDA3A310260C" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a judicial officer as defined in section 109(10);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H106BF9094CC7459C9CA27E94CED93A3A" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H915E3277470549EEABFD4F02DF463CB8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a president or vice president of a Federal Reserve bank.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2142387264CD4E06AC15CACCFC0BB4D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cryptocurrency or other digital asset</header><text>The term <term>cryptocurrency or other digital asset</term> means an asset that is issued or transferred using distributed ledger or blockchain technology, including: virtual currencies, coins and tokens, or any other digital asset specified by regulations of a filer’s supervising ethics office.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H071FBF504E2E4C61B40C8A7B6804FA10"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dependent child</header><text>The term <term>dependent child</term> means an individual described in section 109(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6726FDEB3364C8BACB5F1B77758061D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <term>interested party</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(f)(3)(E).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F4FBCFDAAFA48DE9C7C346FF3571ED9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Future</header><text>The term <term>future</term> means a financial contract obligating the buyer to purchase an asset or the seller to sell an asset, such as a physical commodity or a financial investment, at a predetermined future date and price.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89511B8B0B2B467B8790D1E2F76799BB" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust</header><text>The term <term>qualified blind trust</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(f)(3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFB8240EEDCA34A56B4562C1DA82F6A25"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified diversified trust</header><text>The term <term>qualified diversified trust</term> means a trust described in section 102(f)(4)(B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48CB62A4F6D6478790AAABB6B7D5C496"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Security</header><text>The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8BB30EA32AB74DFEA46F46348A2C1BAC"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Small Business Concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1119BACF9A540BF9906646014E0B171"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Supervising ethics office</header><text>The term <term>supervising ethics office</term> has the meaning given the term in section 109(18).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HF77D253E51934473AF5A9D1718EBF163"><enum>202.</enum><header>Ownership of covered investments</header>
<subsection id="HEE72120E8444434490E1B55F29D39763"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conduct during federal service</header><text>Except as described in paragraph (2) of subsection (b) or subsections (c) through (h), no covered person may own or trade any covered investment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF2982A454284B809ADB4B1629331008"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>To comply with the requirements under paragraph (1)—</text>
<paragraph id="H719EA9E6748145249A87A8DB8CDD519D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a covered person shall not purchase any covered investment beginning 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> or the date on which an individual becomes a covered person, whichever is later; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C3D451607774B209C96D2100EB7D667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a covered person shall divest of any covered investment within 180 days of the effective date established in subsection (k)(2) or the date on which an individual becomes a covered person, whichever is later—</text>
<subparagraph id="H20B49DFDF6DD4854A5F7981A105D4366"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through gift or charitable donation of a covered investment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C3899BEB34F4398A6039A9C526E387C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by converting a covered investment to cash; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB7D9CA9088C4E6CBCE46D0DA9528F7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by placing a covered investment in a qualified blind trust in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCFA2D779FEBB43CF9CC5D8BBBA045634"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust</header> <paragraph id="HF7973C4F862C4168A29B64852165B9FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered persons as of date of enactment</header><text>An individual who is a covered person as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> may comply with subsection (b) by placing any covered investment owned by such person into a qualified blind trust not later than 180 days after the effective date established in subsection (k)(2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3D70423FE834B15830ED9DC26780D22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered persons after date of enactment</header><text>An individual who becomes a covered person after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> may comply with subsection (b) by placing any covered investment owned by such person into a qualified blind trust not later than 180 days after the effective date established in subsection (k)(2) or the date on which the individual becomes a covered person, whichever is later.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE37C0829906476D8B1B1198EC7FD00D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mingling of assets</header><text>A spouse or dependent child of a covered person may place a covered investment in a qualified blind trust established by a covered person.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFD01A131671C4F79AF1D589E716601C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public notification</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving any written notice under section 102(f)(3)(C)(iii), the supervising ethics office shall make such notices publicly available in the manner provided under section 105(a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H044B8678B5F845B6921E5E0B50E98E7C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to an individual who ceases to be a covered person within 180 days of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6B169EBD778442C7BD064F6CEFFF5AA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Complex financial arrangements</header>
<paragraph id="H30ED70407C8A42B9929CFA1C01389DBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Temporary exemptions</header><text>A supervising ethics office may grant a temporary exemption to a covered person regarding their compliance with the requirements of subsection (a) for investments held in trusts or other complex financial arrangements in which—</text> <subparagraph id="HC340A7F39DA54484A3E86D531658DC28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered person entered into, or was made a beneficiary of or to, a complex financial arrangement before the enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H28FC9E1426BA429C9A3E0D8434C35F59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered person is contractually prohibited from—</text> <clause id="H75A154533B8C42219793BCFDF8DCC7A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>having knowledge or control of the covered person’s investments; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H70F7F246830E4ED291D3E0CD701DDB66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>withdrawing the investment in certain circumstances.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC527F6EA19B0464C824DF2063E73C96F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>A supervising ethics office shall make publicly available in the manner provided under section 105(a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H990558EB38284EB486F5C7C94FDBF4D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any requests from a covered person for a temporary exemption within 30 days of receipt; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC4C3DEA485542218D478F156A28ADF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any decision by the supervising ethics office on the temporary exemption request of a covered person within 30 days of issuing it.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H02214E46E72D413A9081042F0C051AD7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Assets acquired in special circumstances</header>
<paragraph id="H4896C1D19F054A73A36D660A449A6B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Divestment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as described in paragraph (2), in the event that a covered person acquires a covered investment after the date of enactment of <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> other than by purchase (such as by marriage, inheritance, divorce settlement, or other circumstance), the covered person shall have 180 days of the effective date established in subsection (k)(2) to divest of such investment through any means provided under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DDC5E544A3844F78FFBE1C6A8254076"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>A supervising ethics office may grant a covered person an extension of time to comply with the deadline specified in paragraph (1) in accordance with subsection (h).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC64A74DF0BF14BC29D1A50D858004632"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>With respect to subsections (a) and (g), in response to a written request for an extension, a supervising ethics office may grant a covered person one or more extensions to comply with such subsections in the following manner:</text> <paragraph id="HA3EA7BC2EB414D849FB2E57A7DD39596"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An extension of up to 30 days may be granted but the total of all extensions for each covered person in a calendar year may not exceed 90 days.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCEA378832AA4A97AAD7027BFC5A9714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A copy of each extension granted by the supervising ethics office shall be made publicly available in the manner provided under section 105(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E216E623C554521945FB97C05E900D0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Certificates of divestiture</header> <paragraph id="H03174291CD114C0CAB4AC3B0D2A25EFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of certificate of divestiture program</header><text>For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1043">section 1043</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986—</text>
<subparagraph id="H430351DD0ABC4B43AFEF9FB17F134275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section shall be treated as a Federal conflict of interest statute;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CCE5A4E68564874A4568BBAD63D0FEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (C), any covered person shall be treated as an eligible person described in section 1043(b)(1)(A) of such Code;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE203D4BD3AD54ACB944859C04732F52E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any spouse or dependent described in section 201(3)(B) shall be treated as an eligible person described in section 1043(b)(1)(B) of such Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4B3C6F086AF47489B37374ED32B4DCE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a covered person described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 201(3), the requirement of section 1043(b)(2)(B) of such Code shall be treated as satisfied with respect to any written determination if such determination is issued by the supervising ethics office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H04C4717474C247FABA5A9CB38481CC8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issuance of certificate of divestiture</header>
<subparagraph id="H51D5F81C39814E548B339CDEF2F803E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall issue a certificate of divestiture to each covered person required to divest under this title.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79A58265ACAE457B986C54B25998BE36"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Such certificate shall include an identification of each specific property eligible for the application of the certificate of divestiture program as determined by the supervising ethics office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD516990117F24F7BA5567CFC538E3B17"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Assets upon separation</header><text>An individual who is a covered person under this section may not dissolve any qualified blind trust in which a covered investment has been placed pursuant to subsection (c), or otherwise control such an investment, until the date that is 180 days after the date such individual ceases to be a covered person.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5AEC0FE3265A43FCACBD2324CB8A317B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Administration and enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H02A6557499634C048B82306B221C703D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this section shall be administered by the supervising ethics office for each branch.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95B70277B5C746B1A269D4072A3BAFD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Within 180 days of enactment of <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title>, the supervising ethics office for each branch shall issue regulations implementing the provisions of this section and specifying an effective date for the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2628A477BA2048478E4E38BD4B95FDFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The supervising ethics office for each branch is authorized to issue guidance on any matter contained in this section for its respective jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC30A70C994164B0AAAEC5CD399D18830" commented="no"><enum>203.</enum><header>Penalties for violations of restrictions on trading and ownership of covered investments</header>
<subsection id="H7BDDD41E21A24A8EAED6C85768525634" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
<paragraph id="H632E6EF2CA3A4C8799389A4A9D891C93" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any covered person who violates the restrictions on trading or ownership of covered investments in section 202 shall, at the direction of the supervising ethics office, pay a fee of $1,000 after being notified by the supervising ethics office of such violation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H931B00F980B84C469ED67DBF8B7EC217" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of additional penalties</header><text>If the violation that is the subject of a notice under paragraph (1) continues for more than 30 days after the date of the notice (including a violation resulting from a covered person who continues to own a covered investment in violation of section 202) for each subsequent 30-day period after the date of the notice during which the violation is ongoing, such person shall be assessed an additional fee equal to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H89FED1423D4543FA81C3DC02E1D98679" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount in paragraph (1); plus</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FF26DD581D94660A10B1146852B5E20" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount equal to 10 percent of the value of the covered investment that is the subject of the violation at the beginning of the additional 30-day period of a continuing violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE76C71C318F9451DBEAA89BFF4A03A33" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual indexing of penalty for inflation</header><text>By January 31 of the calendar year following the enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> and in each year thereafter, the supervising ethics office shall adjust the amount of the penalty in paragraph (1) in the same manner that civil monetary penalties are annually adjusted for inflation pursuant to section 4 of the Federal Civil Penalties Inflation Adjustment Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/2461">28 U.S.C. 2461</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H298CF338F716421BA20941F4A8E02012" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of fees</header> <subparagraph id="H8CC2D3545F734F5AB608D074638ED03E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>All such fees collected under this section shall be deposited in the miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0413FE1A09074B038BF0E5A5C5E6EA9B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delegation of authority</header><text>The authority under this section to direct the payment of a fee may be delegated by the supervising ethics office in the executive branch to other agencies in the executive branch.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A223F22A9F5403B8CE8394721E2637A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver or reduction</header> <paragraph id="H4D198EF8DD37438FA365E7A242AC9D24" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The supervising ethics office may waive or reduce the amount of a fee under subsection (a) in extraordinary circumstances in response to a written request signed by the covered person to whom the fee would otherwise apply.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB10E7FF0B2B445C91D457676003DD57" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>In the event the supervising ethics office grants a request for a fee waiver or reduction, the response of the supervising office shall be made public in the same manner as under section 105(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H359DD94EEB694B51AC757AC568A8961D" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court in the same manner as authorized by section 104(a)(1) against any individual who—</text>
<paragraph id="H3D4B8A0276C14DB587B251E4431EF924" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully makes a transaction in a manner that is prohibited by section 202; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D3750D43AD144B9BB32E50F68495D76" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully holds a covered investment in a manner that is prohibited by section 202.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H4D06D8170FC04A478194EBF45B399BC4"><enum>204.</enum><header>Accountability and public disclosure of enforcement measures</header>
<subsection id="HA3A2FF45919B45F3998F21C9F1BF4802"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Referral to attorney general</header><text>The head of each agency, each Secretary concerned, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, each congressional ethics committee, or the Judicial Conference, shall refer to the Attorney General the name of any individual whom such official or committee has reasonable cause to believe has willfully violated the requirements under section 202.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB39C50058EFF42259E271007BCDA5AA3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial officers</header><text>Whenever the Judicial Conference refers a name to the Attorney General under this section, the Judicial Conference also shall notify the judicial council of the circuit in which the named individual serves of the referral.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0CC6D59462CE40F7BE7CE32C16FD8948"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
<paragraph id="HFE717A2687E14B9A9AE74156BBF9ED30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall annually submit to Congress a report on the criminal and civil actions brought against any individual under titles I or II.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB40EB6C4A7C147BAB721CD4CA14F694C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Such report shall be filed by January 31 of each year covering the prior calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5355A14F34B04300ABCCB0493AA670BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports by supervising ethics office</header>
<paragraph id="H4FFEB74B71004E4C80F1BDE72668F18D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall annually make a public report about compliance by individuals within its jurisdiction with the requirements of titles I or II.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H028C1734466F4E1680DF2DE141CA2C95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Such public report shall include the following information:</text>
<subparagraph id="H411F4CF882F4497E8F9E2BCE164D7916"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The overall compliance by such individuals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5941D75212644048A083DCC38837443B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The measures taken by the supervising ethics office to ensure compliance.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA3AD5F55A03A4670A109F8406DB9A4B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The efforts taken to enforce such requirements, including through the issuance of fees or other sanctions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74C830CBC713460D910B8192CB27CAE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The rate of compliance with the enforcement measures described under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA08A38255FE844F69E9A3D3770492332" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The issuance of waivers, reductions, temporary exemptions, and extensions for statutory requirements, rules, or enforcement measures described under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBAA99FF15A54F8EBDA9D02D71C17080"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Such public report shall be filed by January 31 of each year covering the prior calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H27BE3391F1BC41EB8C015A122138FB49"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reforms to financial disclosure requirements</header>
<subsection id="HA1427F7EBE1342469F95615F4A47B405"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updated income reporting requirements</header><text>Section 102(a)(1)(B) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/102">5 U.S.C. App. 102(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAD5B71BFD26D49C8AEDC0EDDF3AFFFB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by adding at the end <quote>or</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30F5F92975F94C3FB5681760B11DF3DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking <quote>greater than $1,000,000</quote> through <quote>not more than $5,000,000, or</quote> and inserting <quote>greater than $1,000,000, in which case the filer shall provide an indication of the value of such income rounded to the nearest one hundred thousand dollars.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H438224E11B9649F9A23567D843D554ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking clause (ix).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA0062525A004A5393C5438F9CC2E92B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increased transparency for interests in property, liabilities, transactions, and qualified blind trusts</header><text>Section 102(d)(1) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/102">5 U.S.C. App. 102(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD7127D8160D4462C8E16BAD13779E5CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by adding at the end <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB79C94126B0453683B9D53C454BC2E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (H), (I), and (J); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63E1F3C8D301426AB51AF9C05966D178"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (G) the following subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB2F5B60ED07746D08067358BEBCA76F5" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="HA5FA2707F5694E38946EE4B064AA4FB3" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">greater than $5,000,000, in which case the filer shall provide an indication of the value rounded to the nearest million dollars.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56A7C2555F7A4E3691A52129FDE38BB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ending disclosure loophole</header><text>Section 102(e)(1) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/102">5 U.S.C. App. 102(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H40EEF9209FFF4648B72C4B31DF81784B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Except as provided in the last sentence of this paragraph, each</quote> and insert <quote>Each</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F2A7433D8BA452C97334B0363ABE81F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8D5B393B2042485D877122CF91F6495F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Swifter disclosure of certain transactions</header><text>Section 103 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/103">5 U.S.C. App. 103</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H442F7D5A419C4580AF95D499A4072027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (l), by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (m), not later than</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BCEFB28CCE04DAFB515473CC2F31134"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="HC1B53C2FCC0240619531BCB62BE808DF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEC9B479E31C14E689591CDBCA26EF25D"><enum>(m)</enum><text>Not later than 14 days after receiving notification of any transaction required to be reported under section 102(a)(5)(B), where the value of the transaction is $15,000 or greater, but in no case later than 21 days after such transaction, the persons listed in subsection (l), if required to file a report under any subsection of section 101, subject to any waivers and exclusions, shall file a report of the transaction. In such case, the filer does not need to file an additional report of that transaction pursuant to subsection (l).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H515ED3032E28450784B821C9785C9EA8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Disclosure of cryptocurrency or other digital assets</header><text>Section 102(a) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/102">5 U.S.C. App. 102(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H015FE4740CBB476CB5033BBEFB5DC417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>For purposes of this paragraph, <quote>property</quote> includes cryptocurrency or other digital assets that are issued or transferred using distributed ledger or blockchain technology including: virtual currencies, coins and tokens or any other digital asset specified by regulations of a filer’s supervising ethics office.</quote> after <quote>similar financial institution.</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H307C3532A8724043907B2E181504B0E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(B), by striking <quote>other forms of securities.</quote> and inserting <quote>other forms of securities and in cryptocurrency or other digital assets that are issued or transferred using distributed ledger or blockchain technology including: virtual currencies, coins and tokens or any other digital asset specified by regulations of a filer’s supervising ethics office.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H78E3432E917F477C8D1AD3595DFECF3E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mandatory electronic filing</header><text>Section 103(a) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/103">5 U.S.C. App. 103(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or in which he will serve.</quote> and inserting <quote>or in which the individual will serve using the system for electronically filing reports implemented by that agency’s supervising ethics office.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9924A3B1A17F4938BE70D6CE32396EDC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Supervising ethics office</header>
<paragraph id="H5235867635F4416AA30F6A1244E5DDDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Added authorities</header><text>Section 111 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/111">5 U.S.C. App. 111</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3DFFF475AFFB4A50BABE7021417E634C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The provisions of this title</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC"></header-in-text>(a) The provisions of this title</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB2FDC0F751D46A3BB4A3A67E0F0B45B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Judicial Conference may delegate any authority it has under this title to an ethics committee established by the Judicial Conference.</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17565C63695A40109D73CA32E085AF10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking <quote>101(f).</quote> and inserting <quote>101(f). The Judicial Conference may delegate any authority it has under this title to an ethics committee established by the Judicial Conference.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11F0E80E881E49508ACEFE89FD80A19A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding after subsection (a), as redesignated by this subsection, the following subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0FED90BAD0274904AEF93876967252E5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H0B24FB8BE6C043DC9F0DF685C9307EEC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each supervising ethics office—</text>
<paragraph id="HC089FE76D594463B937BDC31EB763CAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall develop and make available forms for the reporting of information required by titles I or II, including modifications to the system for electronically filing reports implemented by that agency’s supervising ethics office, as necessary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D1DFC96B2604CCCA325CF0355F8D50D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may issue rules or regulations implementing titles I or II;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD230466B7D94C879469301B3F805D51" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may establish procedures and promulgate forms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8234887D9C8C4AAC919F348B8B1BEF21" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may render advisory opinions interpreting titles I or II in the same manner as authorized by section 106(b)(7);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H25D320EB1D85436CB9CE39B782F7FA8F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>may impose and collect fees as provided in sections 104 and 203;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53EC287489454D94A96F6A3991F4A343"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall notify any individual within its jurisdiction of the changes to disclosure requirements, including revisions to the forms and electronic filing system and any regulations issued by the supervising ethics office; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7FDD951CDA814EADBEACE84D0988155B" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>shall provide a written notice about the changes to titles I and II to any individual within its jurisdiction within 15 days of any such change.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD3A189AFFEB4B75A0AAE8B25959DF26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>For purposes of section 111(b)(1) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, as added by paragraph (1), the supervising ethics office shall develop the first iteration of the form required under such section within 90 days of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H33B3F86CE582434E91B632EDB27C64FF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any report due beginning 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, except that the amendments made by subsection (f) shall apply to any report due beginning 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB010C7D0A29F44F998501E7236AD2EAB"><enum>4.</enum><header>New and strengthened penalties for noncompliance</header> <subsection id="H3B6E4A4DA0E14F19A7A74E9540EB3A65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalties for failure To timely file reports; publication of fees assessed</header><text>Section 104(d) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/5/104">5 U.S.C. App. 104(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H24F2DDA082DE40199B3172DC496CDF52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>$200</quote> and inserting <quote>$500</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H168A09A6650A4E25B5FBD71761BC7DE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (5);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H32C111D5024641E48153452537BAEC5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF15CF656962E4B889A5AE345F7B7AA48" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H05450CAAF43840FD821A770B08ABECA1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each subsequent 30-day period during which the individual has not filed a report required to be filed under this title, the individual shall be assessed an additional filing fee equal to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB907074EAEBD416CB487DE49CCCCC935"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$500; plus</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B6585843FC843E7AABF365DEA2C1FC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the report is required under section 103(l), an amount equal to 10 percent of the actual value of the transactions that should have been disclosed on the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBF6D8668F65C418E8ACB57AA801B1327" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>By January 31 of the calendar year following the enactment of <short-title>Combatting Financial Conflicts of Interest in Government Act</short-title> and in each year thereafter, the supervising ethics office shall adjust the $500 figure in paragraphs (1) and (2) in the same manner that civil monetary penalties are annually adjusted for inflation pursuant to section 4 of the Federal Civil Penalties Inflation Adjustment Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/2461">28 U.S.C. 2461</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62C354D999BA49E9A14ADF601C65FE0D" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With respect to a filing fee required to be paid under this subsection, the supervising ethics office shall make available, on a publicly accessible website, the following information:</text>
<subparagraph id="H0C2924F453D04F27A0153B636D3FD587"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name and occupation of the individual required to pay such fee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92F279AD3DD44BC3A26C8B6CFBCF9BCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of each such fee that such individual is required to pay.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD47CE75E86F84DDFBB4056D450511831"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date on which the supervising ethics office assessed each such fee described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H637355A7DAFA46D2BDDE2703E75ACF4A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An indication as to whether such individual has paid each amount described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED82076114474112B7AB5CD829C70C24"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding after paragraph (5), as redesignated by this subsection, the following paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HF6FC10B1039D430BAB7EE592AA8D6A84" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA102F1C5B2CF4545993134C69BA6CA1C" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>With respect to a waiver granted under paragraph (5), the supervising ethics office shall make available the name and occupation of each recipient of such waiver on a publicly accessible website.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD1D61C3B34A4469BB5B4A45420EB69CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply for any report due beginning 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

