<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7367FF9540A342CC975F5B23B22FF831" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9290 IH: The Enrique Roman-Martinez Military Cold Case Justice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221110">November 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop and implement uniform standards for the treatment of cold cases by military criminal investigative organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5BD45DC113F94C108AEC6848272ED20B" style="OLC"><section id="HA050B503A6CD43CC91A1D9BB6C853A5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Enrique Roman-Martinez Military Cold Case Justice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HAE17B336565D40F1B2E9A79F70B7ED0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Standards and reports relating to cases overseen by military criminal investigative organizations</header><subsection id="H743D8082597B4678A01D224290FA6EE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standards required</header><paragraph id="HA7B7BAB571494202B83A26FD47937B3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall develop and implement uniform standards applicable to the military criminal investigative organizations of the Department of Defense that—</text><subparagraph id="H874658C24F3E47ECB3F9FAA72367A59C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish processes and procedures for the handling of cold cases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59CF48CF22B14C5B99E8463809E52C1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the circumstances under which a case overseen by such an organization shall be referred to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense for review; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9104805141D14240BD615104CE8B9B6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish procedures to ensure that, in the event an investigator transfers out of such an organization or otherwise ceases to be an investigator, the cases overseen by such investigator are transferred to a new investigator within the organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF585A457A7BF4A60A5195A3A59A063A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the standards developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7B313697E9841CB92117448DEE524C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Following the submittal of the report under paragraph (2), but not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall implement the standards developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9827ACE6EED45D1821137AD11BC107C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report establishment of cold case unit in the Army</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of establishing a cold case unit in the Army Criminal Investigation Division that is similar to the cold case units operating within the Naval Criminal Investigative Service and the Air Force Office of Special Investigations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

