<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H27F47E8272894D489589CE6B7FF74BB9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 6943 ENR: Public Safety Officer Support Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6943</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize public safety officer death benefits to officers suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder or acute stress disorder, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2470E4D445B34A96BCE3ACEB54A1262D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFAC6D4B3F9654478A320A0DEC04F5450" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Safety Officer Support Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFCB527DC84114944A9935C396D4C03B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB224BA02405544D5A80BC821183039AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Every day, public safety officers, including police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians, and others, work to maintain the safety, health, and well-being of the communities they serve.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE999752D3B094F0F9BED881B542CAA63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This means public safety officers are routinely called to respond to stressful and potentially traumatic situations, often putting their own lives in danger.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5B40A33D8544D3DA6FA0524E34CDC0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This work not only puts public safety officers at-risk for experiencing harm, serious injury, and cumulative and acute trauma, but also places them at up to 25.6 times higher risk for developing post-traumatic stress disorder when compared to individuals without such experiences.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BD778441FEE46F6B93D4C5BDE1CF7C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Psychological evidence indicates that law enforcement officers experience significant job-related stressors and exposures that may confer increased risk for mental health morbidities (such as post-traumatic stress disorder and suicidal thoughts, ideation, intents, and behaviors) and hastened mortality.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2021760833B45BC88014C622350D458"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Public safety officers often do not have the resources or support they need, leaving them at higher risk for long-term mental health consequences.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1395160066041DAB981E158EA079BCC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Whereas, although the Department of Defense already considers servicemember suicides to be line-of-duty deaths and provides Federal support to eligible surviving families, the Federal Government does not recognize public safety officer suicides as deaths in the line of duty.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA47A5918731F45E0948472ACD412F494"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2017, the Department of Justice approved 481 claims under the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program under subpart 1 of part L of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10281">34 U.S.C. 10281 et seq.</external-xref>), but not one of them for the more than 240 public safety officers who died by suicide that year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0872A105ECF841A492AB7F8CDE6D15DA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Public safety officers who have died or are disabled as a result of suicide or post-traumatic stress disorder do not qualify for the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program, despite the fact that public safety officers are more likely to die by suicide than from any other line-of-duty cause of death.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAE3F8D6BA0FF4FD89DAD61B5F668EBD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public safety officer death benefits for post-traumatic stress disorder, acute stress disorder, or trauma and stress related disorders</header> 
<subsection id="HB6E0342E0BED4B33B3CD22C231BDF5B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1201 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10281">34 U.S.C. 10281</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFE08C3AAAB0747D1BB14EFD1BBCAAA79" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HAC409ACA5CA24BE1AC754FBC8D46DC48"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Post-traumatic stress disorder, acute stress disorder, or trauma and stress related disorders</header> <paragraph id="HAE08CE018552433EA9AF6B6B3721133E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H737C6C5E0B4D4EF19B99B4F3912F9CED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mass casualty event</header><text>The term <term>mass casualty event</term> means an incident resulting in casualties to not fewer than 3 victims, including—</text> <clause id="H5B787C93D60849419A19773C1EFFA164"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an incident that exceeds the normal resources for emergency response available in the jurisdiction where the incident takes place; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBED91D6C50E64915980B5B024598861E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an incident that results in a sudden and timely surge of injured individuals necessitating emergency services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H394C6C9DD9564E1295A39318BF98850E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mass fatality event</header><text>The term <term>mass fatality event</term> means an incident resulting in the fatalities of not fewer than 3 individuals at 1 or more locations close to one another with a common cause.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF827DA7554A3442391199F549F9CD7D8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mass shooting</header><text>The term <term>mass shooting</term> means a multiple homicide incident in which not fewer than 3 victims are killed—</text> <clause id="H432E5166B800411597C1D0B93F43D5A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a firearm;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE729543360844171BEB1F9ED31E86C8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during one event; and</text></clause> <clause id="H586BEC8B77B7442082B12B3D9C5F1EF4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in one or more locations in close proximity.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9935D4D7EA64403B9B3340AB72D16D85"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exposed</header><text>The term <term>exposed</term> includes—</text> <clause id="H5B986F2D10794DDCA55AB604A9ED5563"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directly experiencing or witnessing an event; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB324A05963604353A05F4A5722F903B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>being subjected, in an intense way, to aversive consequences of the event (including a public safety officer collecting human remains).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAACD68797E34452BB9F561129A091DAC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Traumatic event</header><text>The term <term>traumatic event</term> means, in the case of a public safety officer exposed to an event, an event that is—</text> 
<clause id="H8B618ED4B06E4A05B07A37159F967038"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a homicide, suicide, or the violent or gruesome death of another individual (including such a death resulting from a mass casualty event, mass fatality event, or mass shooting);</text></clause> <clause id="HC685F29763B4455497F982C58D45AFDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a harrowing circumstance posing an extraordinary and significant danger or threat to the life of or of serious bodily harm to any individual (including such a circumstance as a mass casualty event, mass fatality event, or mass shooting); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE3E11E845FAE45AF9CD7187E2C40E9CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an act of criminal sexual violence committed against any individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB068639FE41D4895B4325A89F1911DA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal injury sustained in line of duty</header><text>As determined by the Bureau—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H95A4C8A35B194E1EBEB7FC670F3B1622"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post-traumatic stress disorder, acute stress disorder, or trauma and stress related disorders suffered by a public safety officer and diagnosed by a licensed medical or mental health professional, shall be presumed to constitute a personal injury within the meaning of subsection (a), sustained in the line of duty by the officer, if the officer was exposed, while on duty, to one or more traumatic events and such exposure was a substantial factor in the disorder;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCC6475072304D08AC5892986E18A31E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post-traumatic stress disorder, acute stress disorder, or trauma and stress related disorders, suffered by a public safety officer who has contacted or attempted to contact the employee assistance program of the agency or entity that the officer serves, a licensed medical or mental health professional, suicide prevention services, or another mental health assistance service in order to receive help, treatment, or diagnosis for post-traumatic stress disorder or acute stress disorder, shall be presumed to constitute a personal injury within the meaning of subsection (a), sustained in the line of duty by the officer, if the officer, was exposed, while on duty, to one or more traumatic events and such exposure was a substantial factor in the disorder; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H731EE38C74794398ABEBC5D611F22C07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>post-traumatic stress disorder, acute stress disorder, or trauma and stress related disorders, suffered by a public safety officer who was exposed, while on duty, to one or more traumatic events shall be presumed to constitute a personal injury within the meaning of subsection (a), sustained in the line of duty by the officer if such exposure was a substantial factor in the disorder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF57C9F991C604E65B679EE68B15DB0DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumption of death or total disability</header><text>A public safety officer shall be presumed to have died or become permanently and totally disabled (within the meaning of subsection (a) or (b)) as the direct and proximate result of a personal injury sustained in the line of duty, if (as determined by the Bureau) the officer either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H69855DB70C8248CCA97A652F80A6D7ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>took an action, which action was intended to bring about the officer’s death and directly and proximately resulted in such officer’s death or permanent and total disability and exposure, while on duty, to one or more traumatic events was a substantial factor in the action taken by the officer; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC57DD476654E47A1B6DC8BA774C46F4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">took an action within 45 days of the end of exposure, while on duty, to a traumatic event, which action was intended to bring about the officer’s death and directly and proximately resulted in such officer’s death or permanent and total disability, if such action was not inconsistent with a psychiatric disorder. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF47A378CC104A299BE57F3BE4C2FB7A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability of limitations on benefits</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF031BEB091B14BBA84582A74F6E3A564"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Intentional actions</header><text>Section 1202(a)(1) shall not apply to any claim for a benefit under this part that is payable in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C23B0CC7BF84DDAADD8EA7A8B990A50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substance use</header><text>Section 1202(a)(2) shall not preclude the payment of a benefit under this part if the benefit is otherwise payable in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H959EC37D3EB1455B8B8F0A15E0C3E627"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retroactive applicability</header> 
<paragraph id="HF13E1B75A0E84C759CE50FA097E3173D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HC04BBE8CA00348C0877A5AEBFF0E2456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take effect on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B6C82AB44524A87B681771F5BE3D7F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply to any matter pending, before the Bureau of Justice Assistance or otherwise, on the date of enactment of this Act, or filed (consistent with pre-existing effective dates) or accruing after that date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D86369BD6B246D99E3C0DD904D7677C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any action taken by a public safety officer described in paragraph (3) of section 1201(o) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (as added by this Act) that occurred on or after January 1, 2019.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD729A01ABB6D43288132735645B4B841"><enum>4.</enum><header>Technical fixes</header> 
<subsection id="H237863A72EAD45DFB6E2B3D347E105FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subpoena power; employment of hearing officers; authority to hold hearings</header><text>Section 806 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10225">34 U.S.C. 10225</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1EDA98BEF2AF417EB619C2A4F4045FC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5CDE2FEE512483DAC8D8C267C9DA638"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Assistance</quote> and inserting <quote>The Assistant Attorney General, the Bureau of Justice Assistance</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80B28C5A3A8243A38F43DEDD61B23B75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by the Attorney General</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D0D8C9EBE794E6B99FC2DC39F9BE0AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Code)</quote> and inserting <quote>Code (without regard to the days limitation prescribed therein), but shall, in no event, be understood to be (or to have the authority of) officers of the United States)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF59752D9B4704FB9BF7B834E5C0DF60E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such hearing examiners or administrative law judges</quote> and inserting <quote>or administrative law judges</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A009D9687624A328D1BDC00161374D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking <quote>necessary to carry out their respective powers and duties under this title</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>necessary or convenient to assist them in carrying out their respective powers and duties under any law administered by or under the Office</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H159C5CD0B58D4F75873592821135EE63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC8B268F096CE4EB1B20A7085EB31AC6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Assistance</quote> and inserting <quote>The Assistant Attorney General, the Bureau of Justice Assistance</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C26B24417A94B54A8D8484FB9D2ADBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or any</quote> and inserting <quote>, or (subject to such limitations as the appointing authority may, in its sole discretion, impose from time to time) any</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7152D7D44CB44DD8956094170495449"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting a comma after <quote>thereby</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA224CC3BCA8A4E63AA9F698A1B849907"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>examinations and</quote> and inserting <quote>examinations, and</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H483EE4F58ECF4E2D9620A0688CCA4CB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1204 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H428CFD433F6C4F499A9D6E299622779C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25A3C08DCED04FE699A511FBFE628455"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)(B), strike the period at the end and insert a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB70CF18E12884659A35835908572C931" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by redesignating the second subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5515FE9A80A647A0BAC57CEC883B35E0"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that details benefits issued pursuant to subsection (o) of section 1201 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10281">34 U.S.C. 10281</external-xref>), as added by section 3, and includes any recommendations to improve that subsection.</text></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

