<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF41F4436AC5646F99FD048C246A3002C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6762 IH: Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6762</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H22AF145E143347E0B388AC11E9727EF8" style="OLC"><section id="HBB4619E76A404B35B6BD447F7136A666" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3B333F86B4F0485F81E36491F043CCAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement</header><subsection id="HF623117BB0174D328AFCA93D663ABE6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established the Office of the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED97B597063749719BC60A690D840C49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment and removal</header><paragraph id="H066EED44EE74431F851FE500790C366A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Office of the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement is the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF301C0F35E04399BC6037815372F371"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The appointment of the Special Inspector General shall be made on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B3631475334DAAB3E27742E3F71CA1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nomination</header><text>The nomination of an individual as Special Inspector General shall be made within 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF63620BB5446D7A20B0B69BAA69B4B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Removal</header><subparagraph id="HF5F8DC467452483AB87B899EA484A7D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may remove the Special Inspector General only for any of the following grounds for removal: </text><clause id="HF6CF89CECCAD4C5BB60809C961736D8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Documented permanent incapacity.</text></clause><clause id="HD162F5DE6DF94F93A87DEA07C74F6BD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Documented neglect of duty.</text></clause><clause id="H4DC03273FF0243608418791D09C837BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Documented malfeasance.</text></clause><clause id="H4C6FF2B264A0477B9233902B64F5BE10"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Documented conviction of a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude.</text></clause><clause id="HC81939BFF43E451DBB4E81A16352E8BA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Documented knowing violation of a law or regulation.</text></clause><clause id="H041186A9C232410A87E45166D4079DD4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Documented gross mismanagement.</text></clause><clause id="H3081A2682D984AA6B8C7588F28B43D46"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Documented gross waste of funds.</text></clause><clause id="H34B1F5E5DC7F496E93F0B179569A32A5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Documented abuse of authority.</text></clause><clause id="HA68A8DABD9284386A3D37B4855F93734"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Documented inefficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF8630C22A1F4E10B3195C28F1A64902"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Committee notification of removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days before the date on which the President removes a Special Inspector General under subparagraph (A), the President shall notify the appropriate committees of any grounds for removal listed in such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABE0C086BC7B4A859D9DEC1DA05B6716"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability of certain provision</header><text>For purposes of section 7324 of title 5, United States Code, the Special Inspector General shall not be considered an employee who determines policies to be pursued by the United States in the nationwide administration of Federal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A4696A2719C4CD6B1A13297177629C9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pay rate</header><text>The annual rate of basic pay of the Special Inspector General shall be the annual rate of basic pay for an Inspector General under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /3">section 3(e)</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFEABCA7FADA84A17A12A718D9B024C9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Inspector General shall have the following duties: </text><paragraph id="H3EE48B4C04CA45ED9F85FC8F466745F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations of reported racial profiling, officer misconduct, use of force, use of deadly force, or pattern or practice of unconstitutional misconduct involving Federal law enforcement agencies or Federal law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADB169D1EB554D6AB4A52D9E5D4B3CFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations of the use of deadly force cases referred to the Special Inspector General by State and local law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0EB79A1FA5641A6A9EA04AC09E9A25A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establish, maintain, and oversee such systems, procedures, and controls as the Special Inspector General considers appropriate to discharge the duties described under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A5F1B666D0D433C89E054EAF7BBB5CC" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The duties and responsibilities of inspectors general under the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) as it relates to the duties described in paragraph (1) and (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9AA7883E104B3DA87E20D44C0990DA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Conduct, supervise, and coordinate an audit or investigation of any action taken under this section as the Special Inspector General determines appropriate under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7D5A1AFB91345268AE0AD5DA24B1A5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Powers and authorities</header><paragraph id="HFC23D18AE77142588D6214C5820EBE64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the duties specified in subsection (c), the Special Inspector General shall have the authorities provided in section 6 of the Inspector General Act of 1978.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2967DD99906D4EBBBC092EEDDD4A4E11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement to comply with Inspector General Act of 1978</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall carry out the duties specified in subsection (c) in accordance with subsections (b) through (e) of section 4 of the Inspector General Act of 1978.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6936D6FDEB59452396E6886665C68CA5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from initial determination of eligibility</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall be treated as an office included under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /6">section 6(f)(3)</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) relating to the exemption from the initial determination of eligibility by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34D5CD078F32479BA71115D54C66328D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disciplinary recommendations</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall have the authority to make disciplinary recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61719394093C4587B62A82AC51784025"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Personnel, facilities, and other resources</header><paragraph id="HC00DC9719C9B4CE9818A6FBD7575F63F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection and appointment of officers and employees</header><subparagraph id="HEDA31104C27248D79E3BC3C91632880C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Special Inspector General may select, appoint, and employ such officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out the duties of the Special Inspector General, subject to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ECBBA517DF74A2E816C88B544943B59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exercise of certain authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Inspector General may exercise the authorities of subsections (b) through (i) of section 3161 of title 5, United States Code (without regard to subsection (a) of that section). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43F226E6E065483FBB3AC34DD605B9E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Inspector General may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, at daily rates not to exceed the equivalent rate prescribed for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule by section 5332 of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56CB1C3CC978493E97B97B26E91C1FDB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><text>The Special Inspector General may enter into contracts and other arrangements for audits, studies, analyses, and other services with public agencies and with private persons, and make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Special Inspector General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7040F515F21D4D9A9CA4B98B0E85D49C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requests for information</header><subparagraph id="HE32B87E40B354936A50690019D04F96E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request of the Special Inspector General for information or assistance from any entity of the Federal Government, the head of such entity shall, insofar as is practicable and not in contravention of any existing law, furnish such information or assistance to the Special Inspector General, or an authorized designee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE59FB54827745D3A68CEAE133F3EFC8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report of noncompliance</header><text>Whenever information or assistance requested by the Special Inspector General is, in the judgment of the Special Inspector General, unreasonably refused or not provided, the Special Inspector General shall report the circumstances to the appropriate committees of Congress without delay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H465ADA045D724D88AABDD47D50DA969B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reemployment of annuitants</header><subparagraph id="HEE0D1DFF05F44CB285370B925A28A67C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under subparagraph (B), if an annuitant receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund becomes employed in a position within the Office of the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement, that annuity shall continue. An annuitant so reemployed shall not be considered an employee for purposes of chapter 83 or 84 of title 5, United States Code. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H319239E50A9044F4A04D4A577F7B5550"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply to not more than 25 employees at any time as designated by the Special Inspector General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92DF4B1B23C544CEA01006F928D2A398"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Corrective responses to audit problems</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a report, finding, or recommendation is published by the Special Inspector General relating to a Federal law enforcement agency, the head of that agency shall—</text><paragraph id="HD8BAECD6C0E5424BA70916C3578AE7A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take action to address each deficiency or recommendation identified by a report or investigation of the Special Inspector General; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B6F4B9D7384878A2FD4144FDFAFAF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>certify to appropriate committees of Congress that no action is necessary or appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FB57B307D314CE6AFF5CCC21268BC66"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cooperation and coordination with other entities</header><text>In carrying out the duties, responsibilities, and authorities of the Special Inspector General under this section, the Special Inspector General shall work with Inspectors General of any other entity as appropriate, with a view toward avoiding duplication of effort and ensuring comprehensive oversight of Federal law enforcement agencies and officers through effective cooperation and coordination.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9E1A32A0FC504835AB8186DBBA9A998B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Member of the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency</header><text>Section 11(b)(1) of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by inserting at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6EDBD5FBCB864D58B708CFAD9FC9D722" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAA96D39A7056403693DC8106676CD2C0"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8278C13FDB724ADF921FED141E63E9B8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HD472E8666F3B448EB4BC13D85E23E2CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the confirmation of the Special Inspector General, and not later than 30 days following the end of each fiscal quarter, the Special Inspector General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report summarizing the activities of the Special Inspector General during that fiscal quarter. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB7114E07C04E4295ABCABE355508B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Special Inspector General shall submit an annual report to the appropriate committees of Congress that includes the total number of use of deadly force cases, use of excessive force complaints, and findings of misconduct involving Federal law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC54832DB3CB4EC3BF8CC3B2917368E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the public disclosure of information that is—</text><subparagraph id="H6EBA277558FA4E3CA358BFC0ADC25CF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically prohibited from disclosure by any other provision of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1D08C3D13B14222A2A44AFE223E0EF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically required by Executive order to be protected from disclosure in the interest of national defense or national security or in the conduct of foreign affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F5CC22F59CF443BB109907EF32AD54C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a part of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF1DA9D30EA4CF49D7AFC40882AC21D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (3), all reports submitted under this subsection shall be available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H68886283975D422F90DA3AF399CD9C94"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants</header><subsection id="H2E36612C849246BE86D279DAA7CB8DDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enable referrals to the Special Inspector General requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in subsection (b) in which a State or unit of local government receives a grant under part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), the State or unit of local government shall have in effect a law establishing a process by which use of deadly force cases can be referred to the Special Inspector General for investigation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE8B752838B9468AA78FD9D2E7B858B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance and ineligibility</header><paragraph id="H487EF74E820C4EA6B247359EED97C1F7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the first full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act, each State or unit of local government referred to in subsection (a) receiving a grant shall comply with subsection (a), except that the Attorney General may grant an additional 180 days to a State or unit of local government that is making good faith efforts to comply with such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FF90898C6384DC895188970F3C2EECE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in paragraph (1), a State or unit of local government that fails to comply with subsection (a), shall be ineligible to receive any funds that would otherwise be allocated for that fiscal year to the State or unit of local government under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), whether characterized as the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0337537BD4A84BE3BF0A4B68D7E392E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts not allocated under a program referred to in subsection (b)(2) to a State or unit of local government for failure to fully comply with subsection (a) shall be reallocated under that program to States or units of local government that have not failed to comply with such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCA27A3AF2E3043A3A5BC5D2BA34BCC6F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>COPS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in subsection (b) in which a State or unit of local government receives a grant under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), the State or unit of local government shall have in effect a law establishing a process by which use of deadly force cases can be referred to the Special Inspector General for investigation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1EE7E024F934DA4B882DE9914388FB4" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Terms used in this section have the meanings given such terms in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section><section id="H62ED2F353A214D9982435EBB0A80A13A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Whistleblower</header><subsection id="H10BBF37102C54DE5B5EC48F5DBF44379"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right to disclosure</header><text>An individual may make a protected disclosure to the Special Inspector General.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1026FFC40F31416AA30B9BD519F803BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against discrimination</header><text>A Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency, or any prosecutor, officer, employee, or contractor of any such agency may not recommend, discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, or take or fail to take any other action that discriminates against any individual, including an employee, former employee, or applicant seeking employment because the employee, former employee, or applicant seeking employment because that individual—</text><paragraph id="H3C67B113B998451188E77656BD953C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>without violating a specific statutory prohibition, is perceived as making or about to make, or perceived as assisting or about to assist in making what the individual reasonably believes is a protected disclosure to the Special Inspector General; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3ABF8DCC60D4561ADBB7345B778D11E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refuses to obey an order that the individual believes would require the individual to violate this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D1EA675049B4765B2A06B27F02FFA51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appeal</header><paragraph id="H25633550C4EC43E8A8BCAEFA715D0AE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Law Enforcement Employees</header><subparagraph id="HF2DE4EE378B34AD6817BC5063C346632" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administrative remedy</header><text>Any individual who is a Federal, State, or local law enforcement applicant, employee, or former employee who believes that the individual has been subjected to discrimination prohibited under subsection (b) may, within 3 years after learning of the alleged discrimination, submit a complaint that alleges the discrimination to the Special Inspector General who shall investigate and submit to the relevant Federal, State, or local agency head and to the Attorney General findings and recommendations for any corrective action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE217734FA404C00B7625FF7900228D5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Judicial remedy</header><text>In the event that corrective action is not taken under subparagraph (A) within 210 days after the date on which the complaint was filed, any individual who is a Federal, State, or local law enforcement applicant, employee, or former employee who believes that the individual has been subjected to discrimination prohibited under subsection (b), who filed the complaint shall be deemed to have exhausted all administrative remedies with respect to the complaint, and may bring a de novo action at law or equity to seek compensatory damages and other relief available under this section in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over such an action without regard to the amount in controversy. Such an action shall, at the request of either party to the action, be tried by the court with a jury. An action under this subparagraph may not be brought more than two years after the date on which remedies are deemed to have been exhausted.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H462B31DA58114DD0AFCC4BF160105809"><enum>(C)</enum><header>General provisions</header><clause id="H122DEC1CAB2645DBB3F1035FF464FA33"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rights retained by employee</header><text>Nothing in this section shall diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any applicant, employee, former employee, or individual seeking employment under any Federal or State law.</text></clause><clause id="HFFF4127112FE411EA6462B039FD3A3F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual shall be immune from civil and criminal liability with respect to a disclosure by the individual if the individual would be protected from discrimination under subsection (b) for making the protected disclosure. The individual shall bear the burden of proving that the individual would be protected from discrimination under subsection (b) for making the disclosure.</text></clause><clause id="H85829333DA5D4BF0A2DEBE3819BE9E95"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><subclause id="H2B937FC88F824BCF80F15CAAC01256B6"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as required by law, when an applicant, employee, or former employee makes a protected disclosure to a person or body with authority to receive and address the information, any individual or entity to which the person or body provides the information, may not disclose the identity or identifying information of the individual providing the information without explicit written consent of the applicant, employee, or former employee.</text></subclause><subclause id="H63F7DE1D5E9C48FDA75E3AC9225EA42F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If disclosure of the identity or identifying information of an individual providing a protected disclosure is required by law, the recipient of the information shall provide timely notice to the individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4353F8381876482A980DB141E9D109A1" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Nonenforceability of waiver of rights and remedies</header><text>The rights and remedies provided for in this paragraph may not be waived by any public or private agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment, including by pre-dispute arbitration agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2DFA11CED644442B4EBEF2D15BCF379"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-law enforcement employee</header><subparagraph id="H95DC969F93484E0CB8A5A8F46AF651F0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Judicial remedy</header><text>Any individual who makes a protected disclosure to the Special Inspector General and believes that individual has suffered discrimination in violation of this section may file a complaint for relief pursuant to the procedures, burdens of proof, and remedies in paragraph (1)(B). The court may award punitive damages. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42900A034C9D4C0881EE96A8F55CD763"><enum>(B)</enum><header>General provisions</header><clause id="H0D7ABB2871314C7CB9912648DC1C1DD9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual shall be immune from civil and criminal liability with respect to a disclosure by the individual if the individual would be protected from discrimination or retaliation under subsection (b) for making the protected disclosure. The individual shall bear the burden of proving that the individual would be protected from discrimination or retaliation under subsection (b) for making the disclosure.</text></clause><clause id="HBCF0D3E6AB484738AF49EEF047FDF16A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><subclause id="HD2D5ECED8E61425AB9875A4A5D74FC81"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as required by law, when an applicant, employee, or former employee makes a protected disclosure to a person or body with authority to receive and address the information, any individual or entity to which the person or body provides the information, may not disclose the identity or identifying information of the individual providing the information without explicit written consent of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5285765EB2A04FB79CEC093CBECE4687"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If disclosure of the identity or identifying information of an individual providing a protected disclosure is required by law, the recipient shall provide timely notice to the individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H287A2627DE7746199EE31232A8B3A570" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Nonenforceability of waiver of rights and remedies</header><text>The rights and remedies provided for in this paragraph may not be waived by any public or private agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment, including by pre-dispute arbitration agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A36CA08D4B41C19AB36E7FBA82425A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Inspector General and any other authority enforcing this Act shall apply the legal burdens of proof specified in section 1221(e)(1) of title 5, United States Code, in determining whether discrimination or retaliation prohibited under subsection (b) has occurred in accordance with the rules and procedures under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3683DDBF889C45FF9EE69F60C4E9382C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement To post notice of rights and remedies</header><text>Any employer subject to the authority of this Act shall post notice of the rights and remedies provided under this section in all offices in a common place easily visible to all employees. Any law enforcement organization subject to this Act shall prominently provide notice to the public of rights available to citizens under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9CABDCB8B6D42E88DCA00F4899CC957"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="HA8EC9BD7166F49C5A735F9C04E55DB36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No implied authority to retaliate for non-protected disclosures</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the discharge of, demotion of, discrimination, or other reprisal against an employee, a former employee, or an individual seeking employment for a disclosure other than a protected disclosure or to modify or derogate from a right or remedy otherwise available to an employee, former employee, or individual seeking employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H069B2CE7BE1D4DDB99430AD488B5D3AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relationship to State laws</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preempt, preclude, or limit the protections provided for public or private employees under State whistleblower laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1020F69C1FE4DB190E000401FE1416C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header><text>A Federal, State, or other governmental entity shall not be immune under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution from an action in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction for a violation of this Act. In any action for a violation of this Act, remedies are available for such a violation to the same extent as such remedies are available for such a violation in an action against any defendant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77C518CC402E4029B070B4308BB1AF35" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Special Inspector General shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following;</text><paragraph id="H16E56046F02B4FCD8159672722AC9DF9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of any investigation of alleged discrimination or retaliation described under subsection (b) the Special Inspector General conducted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13A2766494664858ABB62923F8170DEC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The results of each investigation described under paragraph (1), including the number of cases dismissed on procedural grounds, the win-loss record for decisions on the merits, and accountability measures advised and taken against individuals or employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F2BBFEA56DE48848F29834FF20B11EB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The range for the length of time to complete investigations under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD73CAB50F944B0380180AEA930E50E7" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of discrimination or retaliation complaints filed under subsection (c) that result in a settlement agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B962ED8A8924F34931CDC81D187DD4E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Details of any remedy or relief that results from a complaint filed under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB151EE2C446D4914A17FC3AC56BAED10" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations for any legislative or administrative improvements.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA561A0646A8448699767E2726B7056B4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD094D945FA8C4C1BBCADF4AA847BFC07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadly force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deadly force</term> means that force which a reasonable person would consider likely to cause death or serious bodily harm, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7024709557EC48DD93B3BCB7B6007AED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the discharge of a firearm; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D02143F47224519B0FBE28663F90EBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a maneuver that restricts blood or oxygen flow to the brain, including chokeholds, strangleholds, neck restraints, neckholds, and carotid artery restraints; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2FB0C1AAD9B4AB3B3B764609612CDBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>multiple discharges of an electronic control weapon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BBF407080734EA6873ED42A8A4E76AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal law enforcement agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal law enforcement agency</term> means any agency authorized to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of Federal criminal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF831A30C75034D72AEA8C1BEE369DB02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given that term in section 115(c) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0869F2CABAD4ACF93EC369FF63899ED" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protected disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>protected disclosure</term> means any disclosure of information by an applicant, employee, or former employee that the applicant, employee, or former employee reasonably believes is related to the duties of the Special Inspector General described in section 2(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49CE9B0CE2624880B2BE4D4D79EEFE15"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Racial profiling</header><subparagraph id="H85795CDCCC914BF083B2720FE6087A60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>racial profiling</term> means the practice of a law enforcement agent or agency relying, to any degree, on actual or perceived race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, gender, gender identity, or sexual orientation in selecting which individual to subject to routine or spontaneous investigatory activities or in deciding upon the scope and substance of law enforcement activity following the initial investigatory procedure, except when there is trustworthy information, relevant to the locality and timeframe, that links a person with a particular characteristic described in this paragraph to an identified criminal incident or scheme.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB59ED994F7C24225B1359B468A653328"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a Tribal law enforcement officer exercising law enforcement authority within Indian country, as that term is defined in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code, is not considered to be racial profiling with respect to making key jurisdictional determinations that are necessarily tied to reliance on actual or perceived race, ethnicity, or Tribal affiliation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5BE0CBB3C674C97A381242E1F08122C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Special Inspector General</term> means the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement appointed pursuant to section 2(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21143510D1134CE4B3D36E79CF8BF519"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of force</header><text>The term <term>use of force</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HE865265ACDE544D0B158133CD26914F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of a firearm, electronic control weapon, explosive device, chemical agent (such as pepper spray), baton, impact projectile, blunt instrument, hand, fist, foot, canine, or vehicle against an individual; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H538EF37265B446729FA115BBA887A661"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of a weapon, including a personal body weapon, chemical agent, impact weapon, extended range impact weapon, sonic weapon, sensory weapon, conducted energy device, or firearm, against an individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H513BC6B9321A41D5910C7658394CD3AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any intentional pointing of a firearm at an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

