<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94824403CE244FA584F818B77DF575D6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7074 IH: Quality Education for Veterans Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7074</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop and implement a uniform application for use by any educational institution or training establishment seeking the approval of a course of education under the laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7E6719F08444EFF8BC75C11CF4CF532" style="OLC"><section id="HEB8401849F0242068556DB2C5B1A2055" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quality Education for Veterans Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF1A118D4020D40A887095E16B6F02AEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Uniform application for Department of Veterans Affairs approval of courses of education</header><subsection id="HD7F71A1E825B4A8AA671FB7AF3E08D8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3672">section 3672</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3346F3DA96014223A60C6B77D9173F25" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HB2B0E12ACB7842C78459601399601DAB"><enum>3672A.</enum><header>Uniform application</header><subsection id="H7642F56FC4F24ADB8092AD3837F6588D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H94927B72AAE04FFBB0E2F54873987C60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, in partnership with State approving agencies, educational institutions, and training establishments, shall require the use of a uniform application by any educational institution or training establishment seeking the approval of a new course of education under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7857D1805B3444BBC143A232AF44EE7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall maintain one uniform application for institutions of higher learning and one such application for other educational institutions and training establishments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BCA9C9E54BE43F2AD0583CF76A2D345" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of any State that uses approval criteria not covered by a uniform application under this section, the State approving agency for that State shall require the use of the uniform application and may require the submittal of additional information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73C77568F0D44360B147AAD4001C9C6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The uniform application required under subsection (a) shall meet the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H5C737869FCCD4292B55EB24A20028BF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that the appropriate executive of the educational institution or training establishment seeking the approval of a course of education attests on behalf of the educational institution or training establishment that the educational institution or training establishment—</text><subparagraph id="H1D1098CF77C14811ABDCE977C7A57ED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in compliance with all applicable laws and regulations relating to the approval of courses of education under this chapter; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03B37129CA724B8DA152C27E3DC7BB84"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the five-year period preceding the date of the application—</text><clause id="H8FB60D4D99AB4C7EB33B50D886433334"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has not been subject to, or been party to a contract with any individual or entity that has been subject to, any adverse administrative or judicial action that—</text><subclause id="H6DBABA4A8C284B5489A78758C7A448A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>related to the instruction or training, including with respect to the quality of education, provided by the institution or establishment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H540B4CA744CD40779FD5BF48633F90E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>resulted in a fine or penalty in an amount equal to or more than five percent of the amount of funding provided to the institution or establishment under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 for the fiscal year preceding the year in which the application is submitted; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD7FF15154E3447DE8C4F5BF2981C5ED6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not employed an individual, or been party to a contract with any individual or entity, that has been convicted of a Federal fraud charge related to the instruction or training provided by the institution or establishment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80458C1ACC644979A0C4308E47D6C811"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any educational institution or training establishment that is not participating in title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965, a requirement for the inclusion of—</text><subparagraph id="H82DB7DFD07274D23A7EE3EFCF3594E39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of—</text><clause id="H5F8BF5011ACB4F89AB7DE9944804EF93"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the articles of incorporation filed on behalf of the institution or establishment or proof of licensing to operate as an educational institution or training establishment in the State where the institution or establishment is located; and</text></clause><clause id="H6FC4BCE08F614F169518DB1CC78A5E42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the financial position of the institution or establishment, as prepared by an appropriate third-party entity; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20764751578F4E3D8CC96CFEADC92C5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other adequate evidence, as determined by the Secretary, that the institution or establishment is authorized to provide post-secondary education or training in the State where the institution or establishment is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9015D7AE07B647C0ADDF059486184C75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of any course of education that is offered by an educational institution or training establishment that has never offered a course of education that was approved under this chapter, a requirement for the inclusion of information about the course of education covered by the application, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2DEC26D00A36411997F756CF84EFB05D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of students who have entered and graduated from the course during the preceding two-year period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA78144786AA45A2A41D911B6B11F9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if available, the cohort default rate for funds provided to the institution or establishment under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5DE5D692DD24E2DBBF02CD6A47840C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the case of any educational institution or training establishment that is not an institution of higher learning, a requirement for the inclusion of—</text><subparagraph id="H8C158028959D4E0598DC81892B16D18A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of individuals who will serve as fully qualified instructors for the course of education, as of the date of the application, and an attestation that such individuals—</text><clause id="H6141DD4AD2AE4A469948EE633F9FE436"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a degree or other training, as appropriate, in the field of the course;</text></clause><clause id="H5B3972C4407F4E2493AA0C0E98494013"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>effectively teach the skills offered under the course; and</text></clause><clause id="H8060A4C95D7F472AA8156A8C2D2BDEB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have demonstrated relevant industry experience in the field of the course; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3FCEC09EF31418399AE3F89AF166E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of individuals who will serve as career services employees for students enrolled in the course and an attestation that such individuals are skilled at identifying professions in the relevant industry that are in need of new employees to hire, tailoring the course of education to meet market needs, and identifying the employers likely to hire graduates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B35014E93BF4B8E9031E87FB8528164"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for State approving agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the approval process with respect to a uniform application submitted by an educational institution or training establishment, a State approving agency, or the Secretary when acting in the role of a State approving agency, shall contact the Secretary of Education to determine whether the course of education subject to such approval process has withdrawn, or been denied or suspended, from receiving for benefits under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC07F9A7BC4C44DD3AE216BADAB8EAD52"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate executive</header><text>In this section, the appropriate executive of an educational institution or training establishment is a senior executive official, senior administrator, owner, or operator designated by the institution or establishment.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD5EE6C1E99704092B970433F6099A053"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3672 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0A5D9B003F124F98879071F6A6802DDD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">3672A. Uniform application.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2576A5E0D1244D58AD45A2BB7B1298EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The application required by section 3672A of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HA171CA1B3AFB4B1DA65C94D4D51C484D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be developed by not later than October 1, 2023; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA821B6B08A4F42CFACD4552654743428"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be required for the approval of any new course of education proposed on or after that day.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCD7275D6FA64419EA79E607DACE7C8F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice requirements for Department of Veterans Affairs education surveys</header><subsection id="H9DD21E0F5A0D426FBFC8DE1158FBC48D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Risk-Based survey</header><text>Section 3673A of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H063F808A9125480CA18D82E7C8BF8915" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8B45C59B85FA4EB7B47E9A89B2B32D97"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum amount feasible, the Secretary, or a State approving agency, as applicable, shall provide not more than one business day of notice to an educational institution before conducting a targeted risk-based survey of the institution under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8CFBD1593BB141B4A7EC1C36A1BEAADC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance surveys</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3693 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDC173D6A65894BABA0465907D8E4F56B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BEEA324A8F94871991F65943C092E0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H5A2F047FC42A4573B0905BE3DE35FB83" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H41729AD283364FB2AF3E05DBCCD4E1E2"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary, or a State approving agency, as applicable, shall provide not more than ten business days of notice to an educational institution or training establishment before conducting a compliance survey of the institution or establishment under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

