<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB8A8D2BA128A43B1B44B7DF44EA6213E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8643 IH: Student Loan Literacy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8643</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220802">August 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program for States to fund community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0AE8483B51A14230B1DB51FBA4AA59E4" style="OLC"><section id="HA097AB886E994FBA95215E4705824E8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Literacy Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H359CEED5C7F641C4A99C803C1565DF43"><enum>2.</enum><header>Student loan consumer information</header><subsection id="H2236068C662F4379807FEC74D56F1B7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Education shall award grants to States to enable such States to establish, expand, or provide support for community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2755F2525D8649FDBB7452670C64917E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Each State desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Education an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require. Such application shall identify the community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance organization or organizations that will participate in the program funded under this section, and shall include a description of the program activities the State and such organization or organizations will carry out.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB1F1847DE9F4001AF0B2F24091C85D8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>With funds provided by a State under this section, a community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance program—</text><paragraph id="H8530C15E3DDE4924BFF9A1D2FD9B2D6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall provide assistance to borrowers of Federal student loans, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6022617E28704391A3B13A051B9431BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receiving and responding to borrower inquiries and complaints concerning Federal student loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0A15A77B6E0470895906CEF5D889B17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assisting borrowers with the filing of complaints and appeals with relevant Federal and State entities and Federal student loan lenders, holders, servicers, and collectors, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA4DC0A0299C4C308658A12BF65015FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collecting, tracking, and quantifying problems and inquiries encountered by borrowers of Federal student loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD08AF6BFBCF04F08905368BEE3A80FDD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>educating borrowers about their rights and responsibilities with respect to Federal student loans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA84708058C854B339BB34B9F892A2075"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assisting borrowers with Federal student loan needs by providing information, referral, and assistance, including assistance resolving problems regarding Federal student loans; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB360390A86E040AD9598B2CB31A9A09D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consult with relevant Federal and State entities to facilitate borrowers with reporting, processing, and resolving issues and complaints related to Federal student loans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3AFF523DED248F99713E9EB6F6B25DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall collect data required to comply with the reporting requirements under <internal-xref idref="H4AA1AE9A6E424C679BCF60043042154F" legis-path="2.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7168F0D72CF84934890A2F1F8D4EBCAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may file complaints and appeals on behalf of borrowers of Federal student loans in accordance with any regulations established by the Secretary with respect to this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AA1AE9A6E424C679BCF60043042154F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header><paragraph id="H2526847A367346C6B02A786CE49BCB90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report to States</header><text>Each community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance program receiving funds under this section shall provide to the State providing such funds an annual report on the activities carried out by such program, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HDD2B66412DAC46E6AE01A8F7639CF927"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of borrowers served by the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F3FBEDC3B644960982EC7B82A22E1A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demographic data on the borrowers served by the program, including age, race, ethnicity, gender, and student or employment status, and if available, the income of such borrowers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17CDC3D119DA431E9F7696F723065AD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list and description of the types of issues and complaints presented by borrowers served by the program, including identification of the most common problems encountered by such borrowers with respect to Federal student loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2167183A73E64261B1ECFD97BA54AE5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the types of services provided to borrowers by the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B78B30D08134F3E9C9A6BB6D4F5D668"><enum>(E)</enum><text>data related to the issues and complaints presented by borrowers served by the program, including—</text><clause id="H0B33236F8F2842AE97F15C3A16FE4882"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of borrower issues or complaints the program referred to, or facilitated borrower contact with, a Federal or State entity or Federal student loan lender, holder, servicer, or collector;</text></clause><clause id="HE6A4D4D10FF14A1C90FD49E7094F950C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such issues or complaints the program filed, on behalf of a borrower, with a Federal or State entity or Federal student loan lender, holder, servicer, or collector; and</text></clause><clause id="H97A32653FDF840988F8DDC8A18C1DFD2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>data on the outcomes of such issues and complaints, including the number of such issues or complaints that have been resolved, and whether a borrower considers an issue or complaint to be resolved satisfactorily.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A10D9FADCD4357ACB6A7916BC5F8CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after receipt of an annual report described in <internal-xref idref="H2526847A367346C6B02A786CE49BCB90" legis-path="2.(d)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, a State receiving funds under this section for one or more community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs shall provide to the Secretary of Education a summary of the annual reports received from all such programs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CF6A232F19460D818F2571AD95BAE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report by the Secretary</header><text>Beginning 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Education shall provide an annual report on the grant program carried out under this section to the House Committee on Education and Labor and the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the entity in each State that is responsible for regulation of student loans, and any other Federal entity with responsibilities related to Federal student loans. Such report shall include areas of Federal student loan law, regulation, and administration that require increased enforcement or oversight, as identified by the Secretary using data reported by States in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HD4A10D9FADCD4357ACB6A7916BC5F8CF" legis-path="2.(d)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H211E06058ED548988F59A6D24B34FB4D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach</header><paragraph id="HC642FBCDBF9A400881685A9348CB4A8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Education shall establish, maintain, and make readily available to the public through the Department of Education’s website a list of the community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs receiving funds under this section to assist borrowers with locating and contacting such a program in their community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDDEEFA92C044A66B72595D0A1BEBB52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal student loan liaisons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that each holder, servicer, and collector of Federal student loans provides at least one individual representative of the holder, servicer, or collector, referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>Federal student loan liaison</quote>, who will—<italic></italic></text><subparagraph id="H760AB82AD8454A39B5626E8138C3E837"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs receiving funds under this section with respect to inquiries, issues, and complaints from borrowers, including the resolution of such inquiries, issues, and complaints; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612A97F48C04470191F8A7462921D170" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide community-based nonprofit student loan consumer assistance programs receiving funds under this section with a direct method of communication to the individual or department of the holder, servicer, or collector who is responsible for handling escalated issues or complaints.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1642C9A9CF6A47C59FA8BE0383707509"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3934C91062BB44B3965DAEA055C11158"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Borrower</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>borrower</term> means a borrower or potential borrower of a Federal student loan, including a parent who is a borrower of a loan made on behalf of a dependent student.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC42379F024468EAAE7F05F533BC1C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal student loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal student loan</term> means any Federal student loan made under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other Federal law to cover the cost of attendance of a student at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of such Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71ABAE82F344492C9535B92AC9BC952A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H000C2B90F13C43DCB91CF571373D59FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial funding</header><text>There is hereby appropriated to the Secretary of Education, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $80,000,000 for the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this section, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A73DDE7DDE448795B71D8CD6E641CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization for subsequent years</header><text>In addition to amounts appropriated under <internal-xref idref="H000C2B90F13C43DCB91CF571373D59FD" legis-path="2.(g)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Education, for each fiscal year following the fiscal year described in <internal-xref idref="H000C2B90F13C43DCB91CF571373D59FD" legis-path="2.(g)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

