<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HED3F76B78DF7484BA5A190A9C0E114A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8326 EH: Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>117th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 8326</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 13, United States Code, to improve the operations of the Bureau of the Census, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H286BB5265C194FD890BD35F4BAE11533" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5A847B978E214EDC95B66BFECD8A0A13" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H984EF69CA7A2489F9D682FB28FA545D6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of certain Bureau of the Census authorities</header> <subsection id="H138F2906C5774B8F94931837B70B20FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Budget requests</header> <paragraph id="H8AC22D5F3DDA4D8994101869C1BCE9D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/13/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 13, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/13/13">section 13</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H3A93CEB3D0B14B48A71590DC84D41B71" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H21EA952C8AC14C3E9DB42723597A44EB"><enum>14.</enum><header>Budget requests</header> 
<subsection id="HF253FA7B495549218E526D941CFAC6FC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the budget request of the Bureau for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter submitted to the President for inclusion in the annual budget submission under section 1105(a) of title 31, the Director shall include in such request to the Secretary the estimated costs of carrying out the duties of the Bureau during the five-year period beginning on the fiscal year covered by such request.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEB7CE752691E40C4BBE0628C7ADC7EF8"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that the estimate of costs is submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a), the Director shall submit such estimate to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C0A52A224CC4349BD3E560D32F39B26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such subchapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 13 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H0FD308DC1EFF42F99103E8F7E77444EF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">14. Budget requests.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H34571EC1A7AD4D578308D16F3E0A6D5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21(c) of title 13, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HBF52B3BCD37B4D99A71A85A4FD244A16" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H2595194EBD004ED3A22851E38F1BE779"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<paragraph id="HABF44B6CB3ED48B7A44CC82AD819AA6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall perform such duties as may be imposed upon the Director by law, regulations, or orders of the Secretary. The Director shall report directly to the Deputy Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H382539168728408F887257514466C3AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decennial census</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any operational, statistical, or technical decision for any decennial census of population may be made only by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3922ED76EE6449C49020C7782A059A5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory committees; Deputy Director</header> 
<paragraph id="H93E2288876A14A478AA130823DB192CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 21 of title 13, United States Code, as amended by subsection (b), is further amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB5AFE85ABC4485290F919905B15B4C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">duties</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Deputy Director; advisory committees</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9032B19A9F224C9FAF12ABB55E2A295A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H3AF11F16D83D4E36B17E0CF985B9168D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4F3AB56685284F939566E461788654A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deputy Director</header> <paragraph id="HD6A06271592D4F9B9EBE4B94116BBC57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Bureau a single Deputy Director of the Bureau, to be appointed by the Director. The position of Deputy Director shall be a career reserved position (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(8) of title 5). The Deputy Director shall be selected from among any career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(4) of such title) at any agency. The individual appointed to the position of Deputy Director shall be made from individuals who have a demonstrated ability in managing large organizations and experience in the collection, analysis, and use of statistical data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1BAED76F4AB4F5693EC09BE30C1575D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Deputy Director shall perform such functions as the Director shall designate. During any absence or disability of the Director, the Deputy Director shall act as Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A53745BEC044FF682C5046D3EBFB760"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event of a vacancy in the office of Director, or when the Director is absent or unable to serve, the Deputy Director shall act as Director until a Director is appointed. If no individual is serving as Deputy Director, the highest level career employee of the Bureau shall act as Director until a Deputy Director or Director is appointed. This paragraph shall serve as the exclusive means of designating an acting Director.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H51122BD227E74E858FFF782821183756"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Census equity official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deputy Director shall appoint an employee within the Bureau, who shall report directly to the Deputy Director, and who shall be responsible for optimizing racial and ethnic equity in the decennial census of population, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="HC20FA72DA7334D98A5CB7B07B6CCCA61"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing outreach to, and collaborating with, organizations and stakeholders that have demonstrated their influence with racial and ethnic communities that historically have had census participation rates that are lower than those of the overall population;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6FD4E4D33E4D42F7AE289355133431CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maximizing participation among racial and ethnic demographic cohorts that have historically had census participation rates that are lower than those of the overall population; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB452BE3753AC40DE93642A2DD77C2F82"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rectifying the undercount of cohorts of the population that have been undercounted in recent decennial census counts; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2CF364A54F734C9AAA149A9A560228CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other strategies, initiatives, activities, or operations that would optimize such equity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2682A8645F7D4DABA7897C6894E970D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Advisory committees</header> <paragraph id="H4C69BA5BCB81435EAF96E19DCD754F31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), and subject to paragraph (2), the Director may establish advisory committees to provide advice with respect to the mission of the Bureau. Members of any such committee, including a committee established under paragraph (2), shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to transportation expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence in accordance with section 5703 of title 5.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CFCFAC55CD24E09965D0CC77B54CDD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific advisory committees</header> 
<subparagraph id="H546B0252AC1B4A1FBB29E6245EFE14F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Bureau of the Census advisory committee on statistical quality standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall appoint a committee, to be known as the <quote>Advisory Committee on Statistical Quality Standards</quote>, composed of five members to review and provide recommendations on the statistical quality standards of the Bureau that guide the production and release of all Bureau decennial census products. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2E6301F72C84BBEA1698C6B7526BE84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby established the Bureau of the Census Scientific Advisory Committee and the Census Bureau National Advisory Committee on Racial, Ethnic, and Other Populations, as described in the charters for each such committee published on March 15, 2022, and March 23, 2022, respectively, or any subsequent charters. Such advisory committees shall operate under the terms and conditions set forth in the applicable charter.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22021A6ABFA94AF992A10E721582AF2D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>2030 Census Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall appoint an advisory committee, substantially similar to the 2010 Census Advisory Committee, consisting of up to 20 member organizations to address policy, research, and technical issues related to the design and implementation of the 2030 decennial census and the American Community Survey.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28DB4E38D5674AA5B518C68778E5C86C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter II of chapter 1 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 21 and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H608F5FC657904753BC42DCCC43DC6B86" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">21. Director of the Census; Deputy Director; advisory committees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97E27554459149ACACC59D9032036006"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Position requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 22 of title 13, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H771A2A34295747B8B7F1956904AF0F21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>All permanent</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">In general</header-in-text>.—All permanent</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1826508A0B3B4814BB214CD6CA9AA639"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HE7197851970D46C3909B8499769F7A8F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HBCE4F0E98460420596ED814E5E58505E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Positions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each position within the Bureau shall be a career position within the civil service, except for the position of the Director and not more than three other positions.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H237EDD0F92FC4BAB807D6A5D2EA9FEEF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations and requirements for the decennial census</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141 of title 13, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFB4271C1A6984A439C334C46086D5754"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (i); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85258933C72C46C795ADF534761AF163"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H896B6ED256BA4305A81A949BB5751407" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9EFEBEFB748E4A799B95E326AE9A2534"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitations and requirements</header> <paragraph id="H0697A35BB59842BA85282226462A93C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to Congress of subjects, types of information, and questions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2030 decennial census of population and each decennial census thereafter, the Secretary may not include any subject, type of information, or question that was not submitted to Congress in accordance with subsection (f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9012C959B7F5412AA80F00D85557A399"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biannual reports</header> 
<subparagraph id="H314745D0391D455F9DBDDBCDBFE215C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1 of the calendar year beginning after the date of enactment of the Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act and biannually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <clause id="HCA91A1E6CCF84AA6B72C36B34574C5AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes each component of the operational plan for the subsequent decennial census of population; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H10D13379CEF9484691D0B3A0BDF7920A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a detailed statement on the status of all research, testing, and operations that are part of the Bureau’s comprehensive plan for the decennial census, and including a detailed statement on the status of any initiatives, developments, and operations within the purview of the official appointed by the Deputy Director under section 21(d)(4).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C2DA076970C47159AB3F17F4C47AAF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Internet publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date on which the Secretary submits a report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall publish the report on the public internet website of the Bureau.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAECAA97810746C9918B7E8401316BBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary certification</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAE2353B2A0FE484C8DD7AEAFD55BCF1D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, upon the date of submission of the report required by subsection (f)(2), shall submit, to the committees of Congress having legislative jurisdiction over the census, a certification stating that any question that has not appeared on the previous two decennial censuses has been researched, studied, and tested according to established statistical policies and procedures.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E3B64DFED2741E58DCEB9E8F4871458"><enum>(B)</enum><header>GAO review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the Secretary submits a certification under paragraph (2), the Comptroller General of the United States shall review such certification and submit a report to Congress on whether the questions to be included in the census have been researched, studied, and tested according to established statistical policies and procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H822606D36C9D43FAB91BAE6BF410CCBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (i), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Definition.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>As used in</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB4A8557100A544F89ED725A44D6BEE29"><enum>4.</enum><header>Decennial census lifecycle cost estimates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141 of title 13, United States Code, as amended by section 3, is further amended by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H7FAA30EF43D641718DB669C58066DB67" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H77889C3820C34AAEBA7EB43285EDC0B4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Lifecycle costs</header> 
<paragraph id="H945C6D957F16458BA613F29BF6789BE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Estimate</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, and every ten years thereafter, the Director shall transmit to the chairs of the committees described in paragraph (3) a lifecycle cost estimate for the decennial census of population first occurring after the date of such transmittal. Such estimate shall include the following with respect to such lifecycle:</text> <subparagraph id="HF4DDB7842E8940919A37F85EBDA27718"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of costs by each fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EEC3D5B0CCF4ADB80B192A07E7158A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Estimates of capital versus operating expenses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF80B0993809A4B27AD197B03455D0F46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Staffing projections for each year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDAED91A936F4ABDB75BD8748B688564"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Assumptions about response rates, wages, and other economic variables.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC462105457144D57A3158913ACF96F77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date the President submits the annual budget under section 1105(a) of title 31 during any calendar year a decennial of census of population is taken under this section, and on the date such annual budget is submitted during the immediately preceding four calendar years, the Director shall transmit a report describing any changes to the applicable lifecycle estimate transmitted under paragraph (1). Such report shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DF6FA6CD3E041D1821CA46E091581E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The basis for any such changes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE511C696936F4325AC9087F0797D8943"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Projected impacts on response rates, staffing requirements, or costs throughout the lifecycle.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC77FDB57CE1C4BAE9BFFC85C51FCD07D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An explanation of any differences in budgetary resources between the amount requested in the President’s annual budget request and the lifecycle cost estimate, as updated by this paragraph. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BC5042A56114D9FBE88EE2200D9D053"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The committees described in this paragraph are the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HAE08F716E4FD48509F06C29581E4C552"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on local-level data and local field operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of the Census shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H199CA8C098764BFD959080A83B545A16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviews the Bureau’s current processes for consulting and engaging with jurisdictions and local partners in conducting the decennial census, including as it relates to preventing and addressing inaccuracies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA540E35F1F0A40D98CF6E7BA6E97F903"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides an update on the Bureau’s progress in implementing several of the Government Accountability Office’s recommendations as it relates to the collection and utilization of local-level data and coordination of local field operations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE9D948AF43B4805B7799DAEDCE7F583"><enum>(3)</enum><text>outlines additional resources needed to support and improve the Bureau’s capacity to conduct an accurate count of the Nation’s population.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220915" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 15, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


