<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H804782DE9F1342BD8DF9C84018BE57F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7701 RH: Wage Theft Prevention and Wage Recovery Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 388</calendar>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7701</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–540]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001204">Mr. San Nicolas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221007">October 7, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221007">October 7, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 10, 2022</action-instruction>
</action>
<action>
<action-desc><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 and the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 to prevent wage theft and assist in the recovery of stolen wages, to authorize the Secretary of Labor to administer grants to prevent wage and hour violations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H70084BCFA5944B2CBDC03A9B8AD0C62F">
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC36E8AEB12444B258F8C526ACA8ACBCA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wage Theft Prevention and Wage Recovery Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <title commented="no" id="H0D7ACD2C06D5401192EED96FA6245F83" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Amendments to the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header> <section id="H4B9EB765EB374E948B3BBA76D87D055B"><enum>101.</enum><header>Requirements to provide certain disclosures, regular paystubs, and final payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 is amended by inserting after section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/204">29 U.S.C. 204</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D580CA3C04B4AA7BD9C9586EF5031A1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00">
<section id="H967D8F092EDE49D3AA85E6264E5F07A9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirements to provide certain disclosures, regular paystubs, and final payments</header>
<subsection id="H1AA4776B33CE49E5A78890EFE0342B60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosures</header>
<paragraph id="H657BAB78485D4931848D61E8CD8D1F1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial disclosures</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date on which an employer hires an employee who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, the employer of such employee shall provide such employee with an initial disclosure containing the information described in paragraph (3). Such initial disclosure shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HA31BACC8BAA84084A3F435887E35D2B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provided as a written statement or, if the employee so chooses, as a digital document provided through electronic communication; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEFFC6F92C6074DCFB6AF324248784B2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made available in the employee’s primary language. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E2307EA54944E95B64463E29D0A2301"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification disclosures</header><text>Not later than the earlier of 5 days after the date on which any of the information described in paragraph (3) changes with respect to an employee described in paragraph (1) or the date of the next paystub following the date on which such information changes, the employer of such employee shall provide the employee with a modification disclosure containing all the information described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BED8D75D77C44DDA566508FCB3E0398"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The information described in this paragraph shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD993CF0BE9A446939F014E55906E6B5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of pay and whether the employee is paid by the hour, shift, day, week, or job, or by salary, piece rate, commission, or other form of compensation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D549B81B84F49ADBB45391D723BA018"><enum>(B)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB00CEE85EF324C0AB22D6A4AC46D0AE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an indication of whether the employee is being classified by the employer as an employee subject to the minimum wage requirements of section 6 or as an employee that is exempt from (or otherwise not subject to) such requirements as provided under section 3(m)(2), 6, 13, or 14, as well as the reason for the exemption; and</text></clause> <clause id="H51CA0D0FBA344A998C7847B98BD6D86D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case that such employee is not classified as being an employee subject to such minimum wage requirements, an identification of the section described in clause (i) providing for such classification; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H94AC957F384B4672BBABBE2465C54E1E"><enum>(C)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5D4317E0E2564AF59C994D24B3333BE0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an indication of whether the employee is being classified by the employer as an employee subject to the overtime compensation requirements of section 7 or as an employee exempt from such requirements as provided under section 7 or 13; and</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H26E48C3F9D9A47B0B4BD5C9617C3722E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case that such employee is not classified as being an employee subject to such overtime compensation requirements, an identification of the section described in clause (i) providing for such classification; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7D194A98E75474DA3FE8F5C75DDAE7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the name of the employer and any other name used by the employer to conduct business; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5E1ECEC6B824E3BA64BA58DB46D820D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the physical address of and telephone number for the employer’s main office or principal place of business, and a mailing address for such office or place of business if the mailing address is different than the physical address.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF2A28809CB12467B85D6A7AFC07A3413"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Paystubs</header>
<paragraph id="HCFA698D345F74AB3877E130E3F9BA5D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every employer shall provide each employee of such employer who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, a paystub that corresponds to work performed by the employee during the applicable pay period and contains the information required under paragraph (3) in any form provided under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43942DB9CB944C40A2480EFA8FE31A0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forms</header><text>A paystub required under this subsection shall be a written statement and may be provided in any of the following forms:</text>
<subparagraph id="H43192DADEF7547AF9104CF5584B5FC50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As a separate document accompanying any payment to an employee for work performed during the applicable pay period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F0F3A4BDD004BAB9E3DA6021506B396"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an employee who receives paychecks from the employer, as a detachable statement accompanying each paycheck.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC34CC1420B07442A853A444644A12B38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>As a digital document provided through electronic communication, subject to the employee affirmatively consenting to receive the paystubs in this form.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA06FBC5DAD6D43AA85EAD61769ED2631"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each paystub shall contain all of the following information:</text>
<subparagraph id="H186473AC60A14D37B1AFAD8F66809012"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the employee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2311973EDE974CA3B9C9CCCB81529DD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Except in the case of an employee who is exclusively paid a salary and is exempt from the overtime requirements of section 7, the total number of hours worked by the employee, including the number of hours worked per workweek, during the applicable pay period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEF1FCD82049049E6A3686C62855CFE87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total gross and net wages paid, and, except in the case of an employee who is exclusively paid a salary and is exempt from the overtime requirements of section 7, the rate of pay for each hour worked during the applicable pay period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H933A5527F1974AE9AE7ABC50701D1F0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case of an employee who is paid any salary, the amount of any salary paid during the applicable pay period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H844735CFFB8B4BE3B907F1DD730CAEFE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the case of an employee employed at piece rates, the number of piece rate units earned, the applicable piece rates, and the total amount paid to the employee per workweek for the applicable pay period in accordance with such piece rates.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5B5B96426B64505829F756A26AB2258"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The rate of pay per workweek of the employee during the applicable pay period and an explanation of the basis for such rate.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD8D77886F8B14299AC202AC3E99E28DF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The number of overtime hours per workweek worked by the employee during the applicable pay period and the compensation required under section 7 that is provided to the employee for such hours.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD299C78948084E72ACE08DA74F00F14B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any additional compensation provided to the employee during the applicable pay period, with an explanation of each type of compensation, including any allowances or reimbursements such as amounts related to meals, clothing, lodging, or any other item.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H943D3257F5B2468EA35232E10311B833"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Itemized deductions from the gross income of the employee during the applicable pay period, and an explanation for each deduction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79E155C8FA5C49699B447C5DF9EA0E10"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The date that is the beginning of the applicable pay period and the date that is the end of such applicable pay period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF085CA7C18BC42DF8508CD534D6479C9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The name of the employer and any other name used by the employer to conduct business.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95742477A59C40039FB9325C8C2CEF1F"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The name and phone number of a representative of the employer for contact purposes.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E3E9B85594F44788E0C8839E3278B44"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Any additional information that the Secretary reasonably requires to be included through notice and comment rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC27DA6E0B08B4402BDA6FCA746CA8E61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Model disclosures and pay stub</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe model disclosures and a model pay stub that may be used to satisfy the requirements of subsections (a) and (b), respectively. The Secretary shall make the model disclosures and the model pay stub publicly available to employers. </text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD26AA874BFCA4846810263D704D9D606"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Final payments</header>
<paragraph id="H5EB025D58D7D4E56827015D4482A706E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 14 days after an individual described in paragraph (4) terminates employment with an employer (by action of the employer or the individual), or on the date on which such employer pays other employees for the pay period during which the individual so terminates such employment, whichever date is earlier, the employer shall provide the individual with a final payment, which includes all compensation due to such individual for all time worked and benefits incurred (including retirement, health, leave, fringe, and other benefits) by the individual as an employee for the employer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCD9E27C2E4C43BAA8A920F0C30D4BE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuing wages</header><text>An employer who violates the requirement under paragraph (1) shall, for each day, not to exceed 30 days, of such violation provide the individual described in paragraph (4) with compensation at a rate that is equal to the regular rate of compensation, as determined under this Act, to which such individual was entitled when such individual was an employee of such employer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31587868259D4AC0A7AE00EC758573DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an individual described in paragraph (4) shall not be entitled to the compensation described under paragraph (2) if the employer successfully demonstrates that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9FD0F454B6B4118BA4AB7EEEA6677D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employer made a good-faith effort to provide the final payment described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1BC293ED1FD4A9D8614077CD51FB479"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual refused or otherwise intentionally avoided receiving such final payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2201F6C10D2241B1909165A0E4B77F87"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Individual</header><text>An individual described in this paragraph is an individual who was employed by the employer, and through such employment, in any workweek, was engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or was employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H61C12DB6F6814214BA0E6B7D102C2E15"><enum>102.</enum><header>Right to full compensation</header>
<subsection id="H5CDACF5F6A454C7286E368AB2859ECA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 is amended by inserting after section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/207">29 U.S.C. 207</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5B90A9FD2654B0DB389D828E86F6379" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"> <section id="H4A065CF137684894B35F76D39ABF3C39"><enum>8.</enum><header>Right to full compensation</header> <subsection id="H718E423556F949EBA8571FACF50AE572"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an employment contract or other employment agreement, including a collective bargaining agreement, that specifies that an employer shall compensate an employee (who is described in subsection (b)) at a rate that is higher than the rate otherwise required under this Act, the employer shall compensate such employee at the rate specified in such contract or other employment agreement.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7A896627F4E94DB1AB66D02173B92039"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee engaged in commerce</header><text>The requirement under subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any employee who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8EBAA064E47C40F1995610D944285D83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 is amended by repealing section 10 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/210">29 U.S.C. 210</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H3C557CD92FBC43209C62454D32F80421"><enum>103.</enum><header>Civil and criminal enforcement</header>
<subsection id="HE0772F466CB84362B7BC66CB618A912F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>Section 15(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFB11C04EDC814429B134C1001ED7C61E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 6 or section 7</quote> and inserting <quote>section 6, 7, or 8</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H51328BF102AD4EC8AFA65F6005563BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 6 or section 7</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5, 6, 7, or 8</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC16E4F73C9F04AD0B09BE61F1106501A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Damages</header><text>The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H1EA255CAA74E48CCBC79F4B993DC862F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 4(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/204">29 U.S.C. 204(f)</external-xref>), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>for unpaid minimum wages, or unpaid overtime compensation, and liquidated damages</quote> and inserting <quote>for unpaid wages, or unpaid overtime compensation, as well as interest and liquidated damages,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBC75CD39F3545BC89935184EAD66539"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 6(d)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(d)(3)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>minimum</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A2AC489112B4614965235222D97BAFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 16 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF840B6BCF184A6CA0B94EB35B6E4CB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
<clause id="H194A277EF6C04625A891F28F7BE0EFFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 6 or section 7</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 6, 7, or 8</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H185C030784B74EE490AE8E962286DF1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>minimum</quote> each place it appears;</text></clause>
<clause id="HD6023F694602453C85191E46C9D4BCD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>and in an additional equal amount as liquidated damages</quote> and inserting <quote>the amount of any interest on such unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation accrued at the prevailing rate, and an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to (subject to the second sentence of this subsection) 2 times such amount of unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H3DC80C08C0D1410993D63AD8CECEB106"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>wages lost and an additional equal amount as liquidated damages</quote> and inserting <quote>wages lost, including any unpaid wages or any unpaid overtime compensation, the amount of any interest on such wages lost accrued at the prevailing rate, and an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to 3 times the amount of such wages lost</quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="H147133C04C96437897D50E309F076857"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by striking the fifth sentence; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1A904141983E456A850AADD0DAA0FBF9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Arbitration Act</quote>), or any other law, the right to bring an action, including a joint, class, or collective claim, in court under this section cannot be waived by an employee as a condition of employment or in a pre-dispute arbitration agreement.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB5656D1151B84D10A9A6741323779842"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="HCA7A0782DF2D47E6A0DE1229BA673914"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>minimum</quote> each place the term appears;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBD434D5F4FF242C1812596C2CF59A8FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text> <subclause id="HDE0FEA22274A4127A262903DA95E9FE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 6 or 7</quote> and inserting <quote>section 6, 7, or 8</quote>; and </text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC71A9280410A4F8192410DF87138B2EF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and an additional equal amount as liquidated damages</quote> and inserting <quote>, any interest on such unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation accrued at the prevailing rate, and an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to (subject to the third sentence of this subsection) 2 times such amount of unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation</quote>; </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5669C1A113194380A3D41E1E0412FA85"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>and an equal amount as liquidated damages.</quote> and inserting <quote>, any interest on such unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation accrued at the prevailing rate, and an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to (subject to the third sentence of this subsection) 2 times such amount of unpaid wages or unpaid overtime compensation. In the event that the employer violates section 15(a)(3), the Secretary may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to recover the amount of any wages lost, including any unpaid wages or any unpaid overtime compensation, any interest on such wages lost accrued at the prevailing rate, an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to 3 times the amount of such wages lost, and any such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate.</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H96661D20695C4122ACAB49A8F788A651"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>sections 6 and 7</quote> and inserting <quote>section 6, 7, or 8</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38660971C459402FA669DF965979BE4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 17 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/217">29 U.S.C. 217</external-xref>), by striking <quote>minimum</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H00064BD1B1174B55B60FD8D3BADB9A5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil fines</header><text>Section 16(e) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H079F6A1762214A95935571161BC4E4F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H225FDA7D23FF4CC29073431897A3708C" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00">
<paragraph id="H62742E3D9AA74D1D91B28684C0D9EF45" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3B1107F829B2471C982A120E2FF1596A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), any person who violates section 6, 7, or 8, relating to wages, shall be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $22,030 per each employee affected for each initial violation of such section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D9103A7087142388934235511E833CA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any person who repeatedly or willfully violates section 6, 7, or 8, relating to wages, shall be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $110,150 per each employee affected for each such violation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0579276979A24551AC48DF6EDD29C1FB" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any person who violates section 3(m)(2)(B) shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $12,340 for each such violation, as the Secretary determines appropriate, in addition to being liable to the employee or employees affected for all tips unlawfully kept, any interest on wages lost accrued at the prevailing rate, and an additional amount as liquidated damages that is equal to 2 times the amount of wages lost, as described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64EAA5CF001C4E52BB2B56690AC41B53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H386FFCBD98204840877D3DE4D8155851"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF823B30E5FFB4515B108605F2C1E7308" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"> <paragraph id="HEDB603DB52FE4489BBD3A208D493FC63" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) or (b) of section 5 shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD8EDFC7140E64B25B571416318780E14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the initial violation of such subsection, be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $50 per each employee affected; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44B358BCCB8A412C9279B5DAFEF8CBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each repeated or willful violation of such subsection, be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $100 per each employee affected.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA87D089979E944A884CD92493F4ADED6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any person who violates section 11(c) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H824D17B069734D0A9363E7CF12CF8DA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the initial violation, be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $1,000 per each employee affected; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3EA7CBF8FE044D8CB21B8D52F3AD566F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each repeated or willful violation, be subject to a civil fine that is not to exceed $5,000 per each employee affected.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5127C81EBE145AB8B0BB7E3045CE182"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>Section 16(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HF18C9F7D9BBE47508B25D654F522ECE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Any person</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) Any person</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EB1FDE8A73E4A81AB5A38533E8BCD59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>$10,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$10,000 per each employee affected</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA84089802CE42E0B1460DEDEBBEF612"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>No person</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (2), no person</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC330138FC79F4576AFC8B69DFC1CF033"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H720CCFB60F9C4B37B962753F4F55A1E2" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00">
<paragraph id="HB5E5C6B275584E349919FFA1B8E73B98" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2AB261CFBB414C0FA6B43C254A6BEF4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall refer any case involving a covered offender described in subparagraph (B) to the Department of Justice for prosecution.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H380FDB9775DB4CC4885AB8B0AE8BF3F1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A covered offender described in this subparagraph is a person who willfully violates any of the following:</text>
<clause id="H9D8A2EBFDFDF4E4F8ED8D7918BE208D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Section 11(c) by falsifying any records described in such section.</text></clause> <clause id="H212964A6BC394F3D8AD510661D474C30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Section 6, 7, or 8, relating to wages.</text></clause>
<clause id="H0DC148272FD14B2A89B6A21C6A2C1FD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Section 15(a)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H37777BED74EC4EF68837EB655F31E847"><enum>104.</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header> <subsection id="H9AB908BCA19C49B8948C5F7E360AA383"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 11(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In the event that an employee requests an inspection of the records described in this subsection that pertain to such employee from the employer, orally or in writing, the employer shall provide the employee with a copy of the records for a period of up to 5 years prior to such request being made. Not later than 21 days after an employee requests such an inspection, the employer shall comply with the request.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2827ABF71B3D4FAD95C53C77A2888878"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption</header><text>Section 15 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09869675B7404746AB2BF32AD8D5EA79" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"> <subsection id="H5A062EF0638F4CA3B3DB9345531522B8"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In the event that an employer violates section 11(c) and any regulations issued pursuant to such section, resulting in a lack of a complete record of an employee’s hours worked or wages owed, the employee’s production of credible evidence and testimony regarding the amount or extent of the work for which the employee was not compensated in compliance with the requirements under this Act shall be sufficient to create a rebuttable presumption that the employee’s records are accurate. Such presumption shall be rebutted only if the employer produces evidence of the precise amount or extent of work performed or evidence to show that the inference drawn from the employee’s evidence is not reasonable.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title>
<title id="H4F0D0AAC0C4842338E56E6C53103F5F3" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Amendments to the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947</header>
<section id="HA469F09F63224309B2C4F816F8D6E650"><enum>201.</enum><header>Increasing and tolling statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/255">29 U.S.C. 255</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H30C72F165673438DBC57913CDB2BE749"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (a), by striking <quote>minimum</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC7777D920264CCD9E518A700CE9888B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8F641FC143D4EF2B819FF7C756E52B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>may be commenced within two years</quote> and inserting <quote>may be commenced within 4 years</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3EB6F42120FE4FF0B8495038A3AFF016"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>unless commenced within two years</quote> and inserting <quote>unless commenced within 4 years</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1E463236FBB4956B91456CAEF495337"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>may be commenced within three years</quote> and inserting <quote>may be commenced within 5 years</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD71D0CBDD4C4650B8F02E9A9A74D308"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (d), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E2A6F7FC7BE4F0CB2FC399E344D9AE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AEA2E07A0FE4ACE9D2BD5528818CB18" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00">
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37D98A977CA34F9486341D6B30C1E6B4" indent="down1"><enum>(e)</enum><text>with respect to the running of any statutory period of limitation described in this section, the running of such statutory period shall be deemed suspended during the period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Labor notifies an employer of an initiation of an investigation or enforcement action and ending on the date on which the Secretary notifies the employer that the matter has been officially resolved by the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H8E33CA25E96946078D611857E6A743B7" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Wage theft prevention and wage recovery grant program</header> <section id="HF1D88B57834A4A3C846B34CCDB5B01A7"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
<paragraph id="H4A6DFC91FDF44D86A9AA2117D1BA0F51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community partner</header><text>The term <term>community partner</term> means any stakeholder with a commitment to enforcing wage and hour laws and preventing abuses of such laws, including any—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E182740026A41D0A79E006CE003298A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State department of labor;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H890D992BCC3B4F3B9A270831EE914DE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>attorney general of a State, or other similar authorized official of a political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E2E7D348A3F4EBFA4614E13427A97B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>law enforcement agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8A7406476F184266A701A27BFD48C765"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consulate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DC4781954874E36A298905B3AC7BFE2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>employee or advocate of employees, including a labor organization, community-based organization, faith-based organization, business association, or nonprofit legal aid organization;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H269DE107226E48CE8ADD2FBE001E6D7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>academic institution that plans, coordinates, and implements programs and activities to prevent wage and hour violations and recover unpaid wages, damages, and penalties; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DF649FEC1E341A0A5AEB964B949C389"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any municipal agency responsible for the enforcement of local wage and hour laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9CD17017702145A89C505E73E0F3C567"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community partnership</header><text>The term <term>community partnership</term> means a partnership between—</text> <subparagraph id="H30F681C932714176A4F710B0A7A9D669"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a working group consisting of community partners; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD71127B394B4510963D8EA4FE22F1C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Labor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H833971CA38B34133A5F97D769B46E3E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity that is any of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H3F1476C5D403462D9F1F5924C5509C3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization, including such an organization that is a community-based organization, faith-based organization, or labor organization, that provides services and support to employees, including assisting such employees in recovering unpaid wages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AF856CA4C414A06A5BF4B4A5F34A5DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An employer.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0AF49EB4E594C4CA97BD439E36B7559"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A business association.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92BF2E76CD0946FB9A6B64B363B57D1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An institution of higher education, as defined by section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H362525CCB03D4226A7C0B9A828DF31B9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A partnership between any of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H590FB81AB3764E738A26F15CCCD6B4EE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employ; employee; employer</header><text>The terms <term>employ</term>, <term>employee</term>, and <term>employer</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59A52BE050A24782858222FF2C4C516E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E5BB73E1B3D4BE5849F27DB129EDBE9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Wage and hour law</header><text>The term <term>wage and hour law</term> means any Federal law enforced by the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor, including any provision of this Act enforced by such division.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF228EEDCE1FC4F7CB1562F1FFF1416AC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Wage and hour violation</header><text>The term <term>wage and hour violation</term> refers to any violation of a Federal law enforced by the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor, including any provision of this Act enforced by such division.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H383899F34F414D9DB128F05EB46359A2"><enum>302.</enum><header>Wage theft prevention and wage recovery grant program</header> <subsection id="H4DF2A551E4FA4DC3A5740A1FB75DFF13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide grants to eligible entities to assist amployees and employers.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7EC9DEFB1C5B4D3CA13DE7FCF58E326F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>A grant provided under this section shall be designed to—</text> <paragraph id="H9366FBE7AA0644F98D1DC359A257C584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support an eligible entity in establishing and supporting the activities described in subsection (c)(1); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB12C9BFDDCF74AE0A2E9D2AE8B2C79BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop community partnerships to expand and improve cooperative efforts to—</text> <subparagraph id="H5095F42E25D24708A244089A11715A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent and reduce wage and hour violations; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC3A475174EBC4F2A9DAB15E53A3EAE90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assist employees in recovering back pay for any such violations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06392C0C289F441BB56E589F6FB22565"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist employers in complying with wage and hour laws. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H96FE158DAD2F44588935923F4BC0A366"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The grants described in this section shall assist eligible entities in establishing and supporting activities that include—</text> <paragraph id="H5D70E834BB654122B23BA5AA4636C99F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disseminating information and conducting outreach and training to educate employees about their rights under wage and hour laws;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8F064C0C8444381B2BE2FF62BFC976C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conducting educational and compliance training for employers about their obligations under wage and hour laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F7870E32784434AB3771678AD229AB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing assistance to employees in filing claims of wage and hour violations; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE1857BCA19940ED8931580C3C20DA50"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other activities as the Secretary may reasonably prescribe through notice and comment rulemaking.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA7990B1041FC4E09974767248A9A578F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Term of grants</header><text>Each grant made under this section shall be available for expenditure for a period that is not to exceed 3 years.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC8759045BF574E3BA29E051ADE0E6CEB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header>
<paragraph id="H033532E5C61340BEBD0A95EFAD683589"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application for such grant to the Secretary in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9F77B37336E409F90BE9CA82C728178"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In the case of an eligible entity that is a partnership described in section 301(4)(E), the eligible entity may submit a joint application that designates a single entity as the lead entity for purposes of receiving and disbursing funds.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA91F724C785D4A54B83A720D57BB6DBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application under this subsection shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8476396A513F4CEFB5BE7A6C81B15697"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of a plan for the program that the eligible entity proposes to carry out with a grant under this section, including a long-term strategy and detailed implementation plan that reflects expected participation of, and partnership with, community partners;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA302BF831F4F438A8A435523CC1BADF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the prevalence of wage and hour violations in each community or State the eligible entity proposes to serve;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6825861A5344AA4826BEE8FE1721F8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on any industry or geographic area targeted by the plan for such program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6B58354F11A44CC3A915E213736E5B66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information on the type of outreach and relationship building that will be conducted under such program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB92917FB099C42AB97CB3E86AC868593"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information on the training and education that will be provided to employees and employers under such program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0FB0DEEDAE264B098D69E46522C39F4E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional information the Secretary deems relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF467DFD8FA9A4D1E96900CFE87B465D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Selection</header> <paragraph id="HA43B2CC90417441CB82D85BE61B2C05A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Competitive basis</header><text>In accordance with this subsection, the Secretary shall, on a competitive basis, select grant recipients from among eligible entities that have submitted an application under subsection (e).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H858F2A51EA8C4CE8BC3B6840991E2E80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting grant recipients under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7B1D5A9077A456B8939713B917EAEBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve employees or employers in any industry or geographic area that is most highly at risk for noncompliance with wage and hour violations, as identified by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD2E0602ED4049038BC06871313E9DF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate past and ongoing work to prevent wage and hour violations or to recover unpaid wages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8D03C402C94E4DC3B3032328533B31A3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header> <paragraph id="HB5787C79F482460581326D3B49303C3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving notification of selection for a grant under this section, the grant recipient shall negotiate and finalize with the Secretary a memorandum of understanding that sets forth specific goals, objectives, strategies, and activities that will be carried out under the grant by such recipient through a community partnership.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47108E333FEF488B9ACCA941DC4825B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Signatures</header><text>A representative of the grant recipient (or, in the case of a grant recipient that is an eligible entity described in section 301(4)(E), a representative of each entity that composes the grant recipient) and the Secretary shall sign the memorandum of understanding under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF93CB5A952EA4E8B8089492541A63A2A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>The memorandum of understanding under this subsection shall be reviewed and revised by the grant recipient and the Secretary each year for the duration of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8FE2E65258A84467966E19B498C956FE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Performance evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop guidelines for evaluating the activities of each program or project funded under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A0D7EB30E82470CB286B6DBCA0F780B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Revocation or suspension of funding</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a recipient of a grant under this section is not in compliance with the terms and requirements of the memorandum of understanding under subsection (g), the Secretary may revoke or suspend (in whole or in part) the funding of the grant.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA9CBC5EAF585465C93224299B0385BE3"><enum>303.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and for each subsequent fiscal year through fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended, to carry out the grant program under section 302.</text></section></title> <title id="HDA45CDA0417E47758041CE2250123741" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Relation to other laws, regulations, and effective date</header> <section id="HA06B0807FBC944AA849F7CFDDDEE308B"><enum>401.</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header> <subsection id="HD239253F3D014EAA94C31EABF9F1F7AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 18(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/218">29 U.S.C. 218(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The requirements of section 5 shall not preempt or supercede any requirement under State or local law that an employer disclose the rate, frequency, or classification of pay at any time during an individual’s employ, or that an employer provide regular paystubs or earnings statements to employees, so long as such requirement is at least as comprehensive as the requirements described under such section.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H78CFE50682F94434982C87381B3F223B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance to employers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall provide such assistance to employers operating in more than one State as may be necessary to ensure compliance with the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF52CD03E6C174BA59A06984ECAFCFE0D"><enum>402.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section>
<section id="H2B617BD3B4034623994BA2D63FD930DF"><enum>403.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by titles I and II shall take effect on the date that is the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="H3CF9189071854427896AA07F9CA08685"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 6 months after the date on which the final regulations are promulgated by the Secretary of Labor under section 401; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0EAC03D3F28F4F20B5C9B40ABD26B076"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></title> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20221007">October 7, 2022</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

