<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B11C7DFCF7147C38909B782CA3A112F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9412 IH: To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to permit issuers to submit draft registration statements to the Securities and Exchange Commission for confidential review for both initial public offers and follow-on offers, to set deadlines for when such statements shall be made public, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221202">December 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001156">Mr. McHenry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to permit issuers to submit draft registration statements to the Securities and Exchange Commission for confidential review for both initial public offers and follow-on offers, to set deadlines for when such statements shall be made public, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB2467EA473E04D21AB7BAF7496DBDC54" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H01CE833243BB43C1B290270A1F49B287" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Confidential review of draft registration statements and deadline for filing public registration statements</header> 
<subsection id="H2325B1271E164647BF74732FD514741D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Securities Act of 1933</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(e) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77f">15 U.S.C. 77f(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAF36B07649234693976866214058F970"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading of the subsection, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Emerging Growth Companies</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Confidential review of draft registration statements</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EAF7DA9ACC84679805866A504E5220D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A0A8334A5944513A21EF9D7E2A26411" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H04E68AD53D864DED80F1A8D113EE9B46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any issuer may, with respect to an initial public offering or follow-on offering, confidentially submit to the Commission a draft registration statement, for confidential nonpublic review by the staff of the Commission prior to public filing, provided that the initial confidential submission and all amendments thereto shall be publicly filed with the Commission not later than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF72B601451294CFD972A352DE37EA00C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an initial public offering, 10 days before the effective date of such registration statement; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC39E92599CC540DB87B1B8DB15EE9B89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a follow-on offering, 48 hours before the effective date of such registration statement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H658F51275CF744228C070D806C9D491A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8A4FFCDE8DDA4B7EB0E9171B5F162F4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H47B1401C7D4D4775B4659E3715DEABF2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Follow-on offering defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>follow-on offering</term> means an offering by an issuer during the 12-month period beginning on the effective date of the initial public offering of the issuer or the initial listing date of the issuer on a national securities exchange. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74EFF659DAAE4207B0E06102ABA0ADD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78l">15 U.S.C. 78l</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HED8643A25ACF4D3696680DD82F06F63A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H67A23ECE4FF14B1295CA7F20E079DDA0"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Confidential review of draft registration statements</header> <paragraph id="H6C45AFAFB7B146FF847440C6F2976EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any issuer may, with respect to a registration required under this section, confidentially submit to the Commission a draft registration statement, for confidential nonpublic review by the staff of the Commission prior to public filing, provided that the initial confidential submission and all amendments thereto shall be publicly filed with the Commission not later than 10 days before the effective date of such registration statement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BBE8E6F20B2443786DDCD93970268F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the Commission shall not be compelled to disclose any information provided to or obtained by the Commission pursuant to this subsection. For purposes of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, this subsection shall be considered a statute described in subsection (b)(3)(B) of such section 552. Information described in or obtained pursuant to this subsection shall be deemed to constitute confidential information for purposes of section 24(b)(2) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

