<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE320EBB5661245ABAC5DB8864CAD6903" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7501 IH: I–70 Detour Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7501</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Transportation to conduct a study on the significant improvements and potential alternatives necessary to offset extended closures associated with Interstate Route 70, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H2F2FD72FD3494244BA6AB54B90B4DD7B" style="OLC">
<section id="H5A7C3B32FBD64260B5F21031ADC4AEAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>I–70 Detour Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H06370A473BC14221978B287DD50EA3B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HB802301A6FF74CFFBA806035CC2B1FD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interstate Route 70 is the gateway to the Rocky Mountains and a major east-west interstate highway that runs through and connects 10 different states from Baltimore, Maryland, to Cove Fort, Utah.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92BF275C0F4A44F4A6C9B3ADA4DF10ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Because of natural hazards, Interstate Route 70 through Glenwood experiences significant closures that last greater than 1 week, three or four times a decade.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71EF9CEAD93E4A9D9900D4ECB63052F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Substantial improvements to existing roads and possible alternative routes should be studied and then funded in a timely manner to ensure the continuation of commerce as well as the safe movement of goods and people in the event that Interstate Route 70 is shut down again in the future.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20A75B52CD7C4F52B57FB54C63AEC957"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Closures of Interstate Route 70 are extremely costly, with an economic impact estimated at $1 million per hour.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6FAC94792254987A8AEA8B845EDFD27"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At this time, the local counties directly impacted by these closures and some of the alternatives proposed in this bill prefer for any county route or county road impacted by this bill to remain under county control and not become a state highway.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H388F6645177646F19C5F5B498C8BDF2A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Alternatives</header> <subsection id="H1BD9A5CD5AE147FFB96926AB9E6CDD3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H0FCBCD0954E04210850662159AE790B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress a report with recommendations for significant improvements and potential alternatives necessary to offset extended closures associated with Interstate Route 70, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1F344769CAFC418BB6D7A23424D6E911"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 alternative that includes the possibility of improving Catherine’s Store Road, as proposed by Garfield County, Colorado;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC55A36F716A94E37AB98428A64223B74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 alternative that includes the possibility of improving the 6 spot locations to existing roads, as proposed by Eagle County, Colorado; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCA3E3D167C984835AF9D1380A94FA3E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 alternative that includes the possibility of improving an existing road down Cottonwood Creek, as proposed by Eagle County stakeholders and the Colorado Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF0A640437C34087AB29E851EB23CD88"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 alternative that includes the possibility of improving Interstate Route 70 system resilience and reducing risks from nearby hazards; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF8084024A2A14321BC5BC081BC06A7E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other significant improvements and alternatives proposed by Garfield County, Colorado, Eagle County, Colorado, the Colorado Department of Transportation, or the Secretary before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78922BABEC034C3C9054563B9920E5F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include information regarding the cost and feasibility of each alternative or improvement described in such report. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2DB67869201A4A5FBCE0A60D47ED89F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legislation</header>
<paragraph id="H3967F174EE2947FDA3829BD60B6DFA3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the Secretary submits the report to Congress under subsection (a), the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate shall produce legislation based on the recommendations provided by the Secretary in such report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E3E1F93BD8A405CBA6556BD49B39C66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>The legislation produced under paragraph (1) shall include a provision to authorize appropriations to carry out any activities authorized in such legislation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED225124B79644CD8AB356DBD14E581F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Not later than 60 days after producing legislation under paragraph (1), the committees referred to in such paragraph shall move to consider such legislation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

