<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="H6C94679468F64A33BDF6D33DF2787EFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1" slc-id="S1-DUN22682-W4F-GT-KX3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3709 RS: Preliminary Damage Assessment Improvement Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 545</calendar><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3709</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 117–194]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20211115">November 15, 2021</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit to Congress a report on preliminary damage assessments and make necessary improvements to processes in the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEB45649F69F48D3BF068F5432B065E2" style="OLC"><section id="HD1CA29C93D634AE395A0A5091FCD93E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preliminary Damage Assessment Improvement Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2586D6BDB9D04DEEB7218003F3F67B49"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H097EAB7F7EDC496DA56A8681D1CE5324"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preliminary damage assessments play a critical role in assessing and validating the impact and magnitude of a disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H405DF7436401412EAD2AD1FBF9527E4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through the preliminary damage assessment process, representatives from the Federal Emergency Management Agency validate information gathered by State and local officials that serves as the basis for disaster assistance requests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C39BACD4804D189FB3FCA3274EEBC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Various factors can impact the duration of a preliminary damage assessment and the corresponding submission of a major disaster request, however, the average time between when a disaster occurs, and the submission of a corresponding disaster request has been found to be approximately twenty days longer for flooding disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7F031BAD4B24B1B93543E66AE2741F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With communities across the country facing increased instances of catastrophic flooding and other extreme weather events, accurate and efficient preliminary damage assessments have become critically important to the relief process for impacted States and municipalities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5296166451024D7382E5AB7D0AEEB63D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><subsection id="HADB76A6719C74F1FA4EA3FFFBA9A4FF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to Congress a report describing the preliminary damage assessment process, as supported by the Federal Emergency Management Agency in the 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE75CD6B60AF34182A18FD424EE227D07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall contain the following:</text><paragraph id="H45EDC7B27172439098DE4E85DA86CB60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The process of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for deploying personnel to support preliminary damage assessments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE850ADD00744C8A1FE85336BC125F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of Agency staff participating on disaster assessment teams.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14897C40E7244BDDBBAF69F29A779F98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The training and experience of such staff described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC251F2EEA39C4322BB1846E412323A1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A calculation of the average amount of time disaster assessment teams described in paragraph (1) are deployed to a disaster area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32B064CC5425471FBE8388A20C0B3E24"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efforts of the Agency to maintain a consistent liaison between the Agency and State, local, tribal, and territorial officials within a disaster area.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H86A964E320DA4F03B617EF3B602370BB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preliminary damage assessment</header><subsection id="H284903DEF9FC4943B083C55048F2080D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall convene an advisory panel consisting of emergency management personnel employed by State, local, territorial, or tribal authorities, and the representative organizations of such personnel to assist the Agency in improving critical components of the preliminary damage assessment process.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9730D90B7E3645DDA9EF36709CAB0863"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H8A6B957ACB3E4B02842143BA68D5A4FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This advisory panel shall consist of at least 2 representatives from national emergency management organizations and at least 1 representative from each of the 10 regions of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, selected from emergency management personnel employed by State, local, territorial, or tribal authorities within each region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67222B085BC2454CBD86F4A7AC5D01CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion on panel</header><text>To the furthest extent practicable, representation on the advisory panel shall include emergency management personnel from both rural and urban jurisdictions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE63C35FD5070442F9245515A3D50D95D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The advisory panel convened under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H5D8BFBDB259249369D17CF48CEDFE818"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider—</text><subparagraph id="HB8A967F947C34C048667449506A6F330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing a training regime to ensure preliminary damage assessments are conducted and reviewed under consistent guidelines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A0393B993AA4E61AAEEFC90BFEC9296"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilizing a common technological platform to integrate data collected by State and local governments with data collected by the Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H270F5A5B368B45B687CA7C65BC1F15DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessing instruction materials provided by the Agency for omissions of pertinent information or language that conflicts with other statutory requirements; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD05DE2561D44A3A89AC4C835625959"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify opportunities for streamlining the consideration of preliminary damage assessments by the Agency, including eliminating duplicative paperwork requirements and ensuring consistent communication and decision making among Agency staff.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE867058C79D64FAB988F2F3E077C0803"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report regarding the findings of the advisory panel, steps that will be undertaken by the Agency to implement the findings of the advisory panel, and additional legislation that may be necessary to implement the findings of the advisory panel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C1E2969179D4BE98A8D72A5D82384EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking and final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue such regulations as are necessary to implement the recommendations of the advisory panel and submit to Congress a report discussing—</text><paragraph id="H46897AB66AD44179947C29CD9854DC04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of recommendations from the advisory panel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB265AE1125E4996B66995D4EB16F71D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the identification of any additional challenges to the preliminary damage assessment process, including whether specific disasters result in longer preliminary damage assessments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F2AC83FE51E47F7A7833DD8C2AD789E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional legislative recommendations necessary to improve the preliminary damage assessment process. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

