<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3738D527EBE84E5E84C819FCC37AF4BC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8099 IH: Encouraging Private Investment for Better Broadband Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8099</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules applicable to using private activity bonds for broadband projects.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3B6302ACD42417691797A88E2919DF4" style="OLC"><section id="H173BD2F377F84A64A9440B86CD4469B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Encouraging Private Investment for Better Broadband Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDC5E511D5BFB4F5690E98082AA650867"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of rules for using private activity bonds for broadband projects</header><subsection id="H32E87AE727AC47758CCAC318AABEC326"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/142">Section 142(n)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBFE5E12BA19345C8B59894559DA8B090"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25 megabits</quote> and inserting <quote>100 megabits</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E8461EFD5F7480DA2EAEF47090129DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>3 megabits</quote> and inserting <quote>20 megabits</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0162E2B344A947A9A4DBB55985B6D22E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception from volume cap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 146(g) of such Code is amended—</text><paragraph id="H368765AE7B054206A7F1595E1D95119A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (15)</quote> in paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>(15), or (16)</quote>,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D73770497034B16A90C9B689195C8F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (4), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2C4E7AAD44149D3BF1E2B8CD178B262"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63758215655F41C3B939F76845DBCF85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to bonds issued after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H161B421750DE4C79B2A35E26BC191F6E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress and stakeholder input</header><subsection id="HFB3A42091FF54C7F8B239E7EAFA88470"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Federal Communications Commission shall jointly submit to Congress a written report which includes—</text><paragraph id="H771717767A254D838F51DD0DFDAED815"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of private activity bonds for qualified broadband projects issued by States and their political subdivisions,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06511EED3C2F4E53A7040A09F2AD6423"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of such projects that have been completed,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF6BD0BD69C1455BB2F25368EE9B3090"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of such projects that defaulted or were not completed,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC42B261F4C04C66963DD54A8ECF33CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the increase in the number of individuals with access to 100 megabits per second downstream and 20 megabits per second upstream after the date of the enactment of this Act,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA893954A55F84DA4A57226D7E3F46C42"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the total dollar amount of private activity bonds for qualified broadband projects issued after the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76B3DB7C03064530A33A543CD2AAFF75"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a report regarding the identification of matters described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99CEFC1FD73446C086CD187F88E9C26B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stakeholder input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of preparing the report described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury and the Federal Communications Commission shall solicit input from appointed representatives of the Governor of each State as well as representatives of the three largest private internet service providers in each State measured by annual reported revenue, including input related to the identification of any provision of Federal law, or lack thereof, which limits the volume of investment in private activity bonds for qualified broadband projects, including census mapping, right-of-way and easement issues, competition with existing grant programs, or any other matter which limits such investment. If the representatives appointed by any Governor under the preceding sentence do not include at least one representative of an internet service provider that primarily services rural communities and at least one representative of an internet service provider organized as a cooperative, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Federal Communications Commission shall solicit input from one or more of such representatives without regard to whether they have been appointed by such Governor. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that a State does not have at least one of the internet service providers described in such sentence.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

