<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7238E841C5D944ACB8103A16D8861132" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6954 IH: Direct Investigations on China, Take Action To Oppose Russia Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to provide to Congress a briefing and report on the support of the People’s Republic of China for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28E30DA1F6364784923BE87CFD2A93D7" style="OLC"><section id="H64258623A85A47BF97D6E6D9D652938B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Direct Investigations on China, Take Action To Oppose Russia Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DICTATOR Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6BD831D126FA46D4B4F00B4A9D2684A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H6DE90F5DE4874785850147032F7E3D63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China (in this section referred to as the <quote>PRC</quote>) and the Russian Federation have, in recent years, forged a closer relationship, based largely on their shared interest in challenging the rules-based international order, in an attempt to reshape that order into one that is more welcoming to their authoritarian systems of government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFC267DBC464D698ED654C6EE33BD57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On February 4, 2022, the PRC and Russian Federation issued a Joint Statement on the International Relations Entering a New Era and the Global Sustainable Development, which stated that <quote>friendship between the two States has no limits</quote> and that <quote>there are no forbidden areas of cooperation</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7E2E6C2E8A743F393DF8BAD842E4236"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In their Joint Statement, the PRC and the Russian Federation reaffirmed support for state sovereignty and territorial integrity and called on all countries to protect international law. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D9496362B164D17A6F5247E1C0F6E87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Per media reporting, leading up to Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, United States officials held multiple meetings with PRC officials presenting intelligence showing Russian troop buildup around Ukraine and requested Chinese assistance in urging the Russian Federation not to attack Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF43279F01FD46A293EB459F803F1B74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A March 2, 2022, New York Times article reported that senior Chinese officials told senior Russian officials in early February 2022 not to invade Ukraine before the end of the Winter Olympics in Beijing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04D7F64A6A834630B8B4D1E7441C0F95"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The New York Times reported that PRC officials later shared United States intelligence with Russia and stated that the United States <quote>was trying to sow discord and that China would not try to impede Russian plans and actions</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05DD8AA6343441B3A515A8B946C7B642"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On February 21, 2022, President Vladimir Putin of the Russian Federation declared unilateral recognition of the Donetsk and Luhansk separatist regions of Ukraine and ordered Russian troops to enter those regions in a further invasion of Ukraine to carry out <quote>peacekeeping functions</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDC3E3271464485294ABFBAFBD290241"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On February 24, 2022, Russian forces launched an unprovoked large-scale further invasion of Ukraine with the goal of taking over major cities, including the capital city of Kyiv, by military force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF83567D6DFB84136AEA6C765F7809037"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The PRC’s Foreign Ministry spokesperson refused to categorize Russia’s attacks as an <quote>invasion</quote> and referred repeatedly to the Russian Federation’s statements on Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H604C4D25D837485A9BEE3256A30A5AAD"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 24, 2022, the PRC announced it would lift restrictions on wheat imports from Russia to ease the impact of sanctions on Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H869F06AC7AAE4DA3957E0675C487CDFF"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Russian forces are reported to have targeted civilian population centers and launched attacks without regard for civilian casualties, some of which may constitute war crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BFF2394DCEB4BE49C670CB98485CC63"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 2, 2022, the Chief Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court announced an investigation into possible war crimes committed in Ukraine after a referral by 39 member states.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F7E3A76DBF40C8908DB0FD6A683DB3"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On March 2, 2022, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi recognized the conflict in Ukraine as a <quote>war</quote> and expressed that China was <quote>extremely concerned</quote> about the harm to civilians in Ukraine.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H73CE559DA3D34A09B6D61FEC1D2E4928"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HF114E9B97AB6488780D359029A9042CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government and entities associated with People’s Republic of China who assist the Russian Federation or Russian oligarchs in evading sanctions imposed following the Russian invasion of Ukraine are, in so doing, supporting the Russian Federation’s unprovoked attack on Ukraine and the Ukrainian people, including alleged war crimes committed by Russian Armed Forces against unarmed civilians; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF461081FC134DFD9BC4A27D6457813A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President should impose sanctions on those entities found to have aided the Russian Federation or Russian oligarchs in evading sanctions imposed by the United States and allied nations following the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0C774ACB7CBD44EC963C0F9EE0254AB0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on PRC support for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine</header><subsection id="HF972BEDBABEB40DBA5B39B8F65B89BF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on entities in the People’s Republic of China that have assisted, or continue to assist, the Russian Federation in evading sanctions imposed by the United States following the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5B0840108A64142A652C0B2D821F36A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H7E6B906155D94E4AB6BEAD340820A85E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the actions the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party may have taken to assist the Russian Federation in evading sanctions imposed by the United States following the further invasion of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED039782C5C472FB0D270DD082240B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the extent to which entities affiliated with the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party may have assisted the Russian Federation in evading sanctions imposed by the United States following the further invasion of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C90CB7FB3E4B0FAA807877E372B704"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A list of the entities referred to in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H437E3749EB4B49EBA31627BF70415E2A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the actions the Department of State and other relevant departments have taken to address the actions described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE585EAEE9743298734EDC693D88698"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An account of the changes and improvements the Secretary of State plans to make to the United States strategy to confront Russian aggression in Ukraine by economically isolating the Russian Federation from outside support and economic assistance from the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25C9D29D01DC495B8D8511465D6B3F58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7DB9D28B803F496F997D59703A483E42"><enum>5.</enum><header>Briefings to Congress on PRC support for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine</header><subsection id="H5BEE429A19BC4AFA950AA644D492CF70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, senior officials from the Department of State, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and other relevant Federal departments shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a briefing on efforts being taken by the United States to identify and sanction entities in the People’s Republic of China found to have assisted the Russian Federation in evading sanctions imposed by the United States following the Russian invasion of Ukraine. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA09ED32DCCB542DCA31174AAE0BCDBF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Post-Report briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the submission of the report required under section 4, senior officials from the Department of State, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and other relevant Federal departments shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a briefing on the contents of the report and steps being taken by the United States Government to pursue a strategy to confront Russian aggression in Ukraine by economically isolating the Russian Federation from outside support and economic assistance from the People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE6E95894E15F417F913A0B75D2A6B879"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of briefing</header><text>A briefing under subsection (a) or (b)—</text><paragraph id="H4AF7CD731B2C47B68CECB4B36AB894AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be provided in an unclassified setting; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F446A416D1744C8A10F261F2B351538"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be accompanied by a separate classified briefing, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

