<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0BFCD344523D4A59B6DCAB1107FB760F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7265 IH: Cerebral Palsy Research Program Authorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7265</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20220329">March 29, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a program of research related to cerebral palsy, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H54312B6DE3844E93924EC925BEDDDCC0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC37334AE88C94CE789DABE721660F7AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cerebral Palsy Research Program Authorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9E37AB2CDB404C43A6BC00AB1455FB2B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB859F1C713F042F593BB76F69FA5F875"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cerebral palsy is the most common motor disability in children, affecting more than 1,000,000 Americans, 1 in 345 children, and over 17,000,000 people worldwide.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40B7124846954AD69E2FE3CE4D439282"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the United States, more than 10,000 babies are diagnosed with cerebral palsy each year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED86E6D5B4BC4C9491DDC0D935EA8781"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cerebral palsy is a broad group of disorders disrupting a person’s ability to move, sit, stand, walk, talk, and use their hands.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1142818E64A7407CA87A9991E1D776B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In more than 80 percent of cases, the cause of cerebral palsy is unknown.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB1CC1B76701489C97CC0BB3CEE101DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Seventy-five percent of individuals with cerebral palsy also have 1 or more additional developmental disabilities including epilepsy, intellectual disabilities, communication problems, learning and attention disorders, chronic pain, autism, hearing disorders, and visual impairments or blindness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF89BEAEFE743462C9E44C61508DDB676"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Children with cerebral palsy are more likely to die from the flu and related viruses, including COVID–19, than children without neurologic disorders.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08A4038CF97F4F7FBD4F5A8639132F0F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>There is no consensus of best practices for a person with cerebral palsy at the time of diagnosis or through the lifespan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6061763697184EF8AFD60CA57639DC1B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is estimated that the lifetime care and medical costs for all people with cerebral palsy who were born in 2000 alone will total more than $13,500,000,000. The loss of productivity and lost wages of the individual with cerebral palsy and their family members is more than $35,000,000,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H183DAEF6A4DE417BB23F8CF7EA46693F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>There is no known cure for cerebral palsy, and in most cases, it is not preventable.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5AE316529FC14C5F82A602BBBC1B678A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cerebral palsy research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317C of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-4">42 U.S.C. 247b–4</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDEB225AED1EC45BF88445C58B71D70F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HF10361260D89454F887E64F7420F4403"><enum>317C–1.</enum><header>Cerebral palsy research</header> 
<subsection id="H4A432D9C228A4B57AEF71FFCB3138E2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and in consultation with other Federal agencies and partners, shall carry out (directly or through grants or contracts) a program of research related to cerebral palsy, including—</text> <paragraph id="H07F2F7396E8640DB9073A4C8DF0AD12E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H870593CBF7084E6897E1AA7B69423BD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the most promising avenues of cerebral palsy diagnosis and treatment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5616DB87D2D4C4FB5A62ED542618C31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>factors that may mitigate the prevalence of cerebral palsy; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB35D808132A48CB8C4D303D9EA80914"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the health care and societal costs of cerebral palsy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2AB4D3CB66A24F98B1550A1546126B5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>public health surveillance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5E3A2028DC145F2AC3B9D241FB72018"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other research that the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention determines to be appropriate to provide education and training for health professionals and the general public for purposes of diagnosing, treating, and explaining the causes, prevalence, and lifelong effects of cerebral palsy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H60A4392DE1944797985BEF923D777AAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may (directly or through grants or contracts) provide technical assistance to public and nonprofit private entities in furtherance of research under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF62A65855E44ABB90F3C0D53F78AE0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>The Secretary shall (directly or through grants or contracts) provide for the evaluation of activities under subsection (a) in order to determine the extent to which such activities have been effective, including evaluation of the effects of such activities on various demographic populations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE1540288B6B24D77ABD39033C7B03E87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H522DCEBA02CC42CEAB936864604951D0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Updating Strategic Plan for Cerebral Palsy Research</header> 
<subsection id="H164578F9583D49F7A264A40FC55A4979"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke and the Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development—</text> <paragraph id="H2A4E1B3FBA82458E818310F42CBAF967"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall conduct a strategic workshop with key stakeholders to provide updates on promising research performed to date with the goal of further refining the specific opportunities that were identified in the <quote>NINDS/NICHD Strategic Plan for Cerebral Palsy Research</quote> dated September 30, 2017 (or any successor strategic plan);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AD2C0E020374BC49F4091A8CF146E87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall update such strategic plan (or any successor strategic plan) to include—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E2402A8266E43299F1E5EC06443DFAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new research opportunities that are identified in the workshop under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57FA5412607D4FBBA0D24C48C9E20942"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a process and timeline for soliciting proposals for research on cerebral palsy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32D8FE59BA2941539C61715E4B39DA89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>implementation and clinical studies aimed at early detection and intervention, comparative effectiveness, and functional outcomes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H126AD897D0524FB8AFB972AEC565A099"><enum>(D)</enum><text>surveillance;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1935D17AF18F4B80BB6F65EA6DDCEDEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include in such updated strategic plan a focus on basic and translational discoveries, including with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7F3B82D392604C0A8D8DFE597C7D6A09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>neuroprotective medicine;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H063CDA8A59F44E6DBFBE3F7B0030AD32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regenerative medicine and mechanisms of neuroplasticity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4469B040F9C4B76B394C6BA1B81B0EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>genomics; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F3ED85ACA6B49F1A960925DF2D88269"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall publish the updated strategic plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H618C8C3A5CE14AA8804BC1AD69E34AF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 and 2024. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

