<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H5CE6EEDFF60C4E238EA594E6ADA55CBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 7335 ENR: MST Claims Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7335</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To improve coordination between the Veterans Health Administration and the Veterans Benefits Administration with respect to claims for compensation arising from military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0F3A3401467B4A14884BD6682BA29C29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H70E8924FD38C43778B4B4C811D270F6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>MST Claims Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H41BFDE212AFB41E88134CDD2F88FABA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Health Administration and Veterans Benefits Administration coordination for certain claims arising from military sexual trauma</header> <subsection id="H69474F6D14124C74AAD6DC5BFCF6E6D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordinated provision of materials</header> <paragraph id="H0E52C7444D78488A8141064565DDE00D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required materials</header><text>During or immediately after each covered event, and together with each covered document, in a claim for compensation arising from military sexual trauma experienced by a covered individual, the Under Secretary for Benefits of the Veterans Benefits Administration, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Health of the Veterans Health Administration, shall provide, to the covered individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3D78ACC4060F4097BCC36D048715C449"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outreach letters;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DA2069F990744C29C4590806897595E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the Veterans Crisis Line;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F469332F88F49F78C1A68F5DB873EB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on how to make an appointment with a mental health provider; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E53A18D2DC6463F9F98234840C6A7B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other information on available resources relating to military sexual trauma (including information on military sexual trauma coordinators of the Veterans Health Administration, mental health providers trained in military sexual trauma issues, and peer support specialists).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43D0EBF4C613471D8D84D5B92F7AC575"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format of materials</header><text>Materials described in paragraph (1) may be provided electronically.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD10634892D2464488010E6333C62679"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Automatic notification system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a claim for compensation arising from military sexual trauma experienced by a veteran, if the veteran is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, and consents to the notification system under this subsection, the Under Secretary for Benefits shall automatically notify the Under Secretary for Health shortly before the veteran—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB3C818768FD447C1840D77ACC3A88A2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participates in any covered event; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778DC7CDE9B04016B4DFC89C416F5981"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receives any covered document.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9B2523276E1E458C80491969A62C2151"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation deadline</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement this Act not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H69DA8AA382CA4F23A080305692E3FA23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H475449183A32494886455D07E2C23D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>compensation</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC86153673FE542BEA17DB1FAC3FE4ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered document</quote> means a determination (including a rating determination) that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs provides to the claimant in connection with a claim for compensation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE637483EF7F44C899B4659E5A79627F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered event</quote> includes, with respect to a claim for compensation—</text> <subparagraph id="H710CE1C33F9E48A486AF64297CED6CAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a medical examination under section 5103A of title 38, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF6420CD51D14E59A2DCFBA77F2533F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a hearing before the Board of Veterans’ Appeals under section 7107 of such title; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFADD16D54554C208B5231954E812E67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other event determined relevant by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H433B09DD22C24909A189A37AA55C3A0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means a former member of the Armed Forces (as that term is defined in section 1720D of title 38, United States Code) who elects to receive materials under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0DCB371A45541BD9B905A1AC1F9A6E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>military sexual trauma</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1166 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H588D9296FE08424CAB7F7590D1CCA3E9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Veterans Crisis Line</quote> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

