<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H448C4E063AF34000A3E6F34C87A57BAC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6836 IH: Robert Parris Moses Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6836</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To award posthumously a Congressional Gold Medal to Robert Parris Moses, in recognition of his achievements and contributions to advancing American education and civil rights.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEAA58EC2365749048F58A951FFBA1E87" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBE9CDB50E0C544E48312BC3FF9D6B576" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Robert Parris Moses Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H64263E28DEDD4505884564C49766509D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4EBFCBC437DF4180A34082E1E00942E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Robert Parris Moses was born in Harlem, New York City, on January 23, 1935.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38A9D6E11171474A8F236E587235E05B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Robert Parris Moses is regarded as an influential civil rights activist, peace activist, public education advocate, and math literacy educator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E2B9AFE2C5A4E4B9F47550D8D2ED5CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Moses grew up in Harlem River Houses and was one of only a handful of Black students at the time who was admitted to Stuyvesant High School.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BC3E77117044610B8FCF82F8FA97E63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Moses earned a scholarship to Hamilton College in Clinton, New York, and subsequently obtained a master’s degree in philosophy from Harvard University in 1957.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF283775A420F4914A7BF05A24C6D5C65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>His doctorate studies in mathematics were halted due to the death of his mother and the hospitalization of his father.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F751E9CE7DC40FE86B0A4228C189710"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1959, Moses helped with the second Youth March for Integrated Schools in Washington, DC.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E24B36C44C5478DA9B6DBB096986E45"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Moses visited Mississippi in the summer of 1960, and met with local National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) leaders who indicated the need to focus on voter registration. He returned to Mississippi after teaching the 1960–1961 school year in New York, where he organized and registered thousands of poor, illiterate, and rural Black residents to vote.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1E4481822E243CC81D3E9CB2F87E805"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As a leader of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, in 1964, Moses helped organize the Mississippi <quote>Freedom</quote> Summer Project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9340937BA337465E9BEEE544C7C86FF9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., called Moses’ <quote>contribution to the freedom struggle in America</quote> an <quote>inspiration</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD1DB6B5CF054B899B2887D662C13860"><enum>(10)</enum><text>After Moses married Janet, they started a family in Tanzania. He spent nearly a decade there teaching mathematics and working with the Ministry of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44886347B036487F9969D0D8ABF15513"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Moses returned to the United States in 1976, and continued his doctoral studies in Philosophy of Mathematics at Harvard. He received a MacArthur Fellowship in 1982, which he used to promote the Algebra Project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2930E433D09E438FB0693E2B1D9FB9A4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In founding the Algebra Project, Moses stated that K–12 math literacy, like voting literacy, is key to full citizenship for Americans from poor and minority communities as our society shifts from the Industrial Age to the Information Age.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H701CB739B28D42BFB1B96919FE9AD969"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Algebra Project is a non-profit dedicated to helping students from historically marginalized communities, including Black, Brown, and youth living in poverty, who often hail from low-income households. Students develop math literacy skills, which Bob Moses viewed as the path to permanently improving their life circumstances, as well as the social and economic conditions of their communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACEE565076DF4049BAFB534711BF565A"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Algebra Project uses mathematics literacy as an organizing tool to guarantee quality public-school education for all children in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6975E5A4C5CD4DEB88F439CEEDE8DF44"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Algebra Project is one of the few mathematics education initiatives to originate in the African-American community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDFA27474BC6414EB6EA7B752D21C0F9"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Since its inception in 1982, the Algebra Project has helped more than 40,000 students in hundreds of schools nationwide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CDE4A461BED4500B64C5E299A3F50F0"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In 1996, the Young People’s Project was launched by Algebra Project graduates from Cambridge, MA, and Algebra Project middle school students from Jackson, Mississippi. The Young People’s Project recruits and trains high school and college age <quote>Math Literacy Workers</quote> to facilitate enrichment workshops for younger students in mathematics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EA76E1BA3454CB08C71ECBDE38C80AC"><enum>(18)</enum><text>For his work, Bob Moses has been honored, including with an Honorary Doctor of Science from Harvard University and Ohio State University, an Honorary Doctor of Laws from Princeton University, the John Dewey Prize for Progressive Education, a Lifetime Achievement Award from the National Council of the Teachers of Mathematics, and was inducted to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02FB4FE8771B4B9D96C9210E8D9CAE30"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Moses wrote about his vision for education and experiences. He was co-author of Radical Equations–Civil Rights from Mississippi to the Algebra Project (2001), and co-editor of Quality Education as a Constitutional Right–Creating a Grassroots Movement to Transform America’s Schools (2010).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA361CF85A1649CF87BDCC234FB866F8"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Moses wrote in Radical Equations that <quote>the most urgent social issue affecting poor people and people of color, is economic access. In today’s world, economic access and full citizenship depend crucially on math and science literacy. I believe that the absence of math literacy in urban and rural communities throughout this country is an issue as urgent as the lack of registered Black voters in Mississippi was in 1961.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE31DCBF4226E4473932482DD6FA6465E"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Bob Moses passed away in Hollywood, Florida, on July 25, 2021.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H42F4E1D3E1CD4A1F92C6929225E2B6E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="HD2080B59CC7D4266AB0EC772478C44F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of Robert Parris Moses, in recognition of his achievements and contributions to American education and civil rights.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D16A71556B145FEB8336BF0FA7D6F38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA4175E84ED6466AA391637587A0E32C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized Recipient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), in honor of Moses, the gold medal shall be given to Maisha Moses, Robert Parris Moses’ daughter. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0740B4362F7430090B05DCC437E6D0C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National Museum of African American History and Culture</header> 
<paragraph id="HF0905746375F44C89770884994742786" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A bronze duplicate of the gold medal awarded under subsection (a) shall be given to the National Museum of African American History and Culture, where it shall be available for display as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A06DF9FEF124CB7916E0E495F44EFA1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the National Museum of African American History and Culture should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with Robert Parris Moses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5BA0E8A0C8844B22BCBEE1EB661D0DE4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3 under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="HC11FDCEF7EB146F1A5989F7B95C0073F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="H81375818DA564B8DB6678FFAEAC742FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67EF139DC288496595ED6DC5A4EB7956"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

