<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3A822E9559148E6A8B0B6C0B27B3A34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8503 IH: Securing Global Telecommunications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8503</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the development of a strategy to promote the use of secure telecommunications infrastructure worldwide, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC3B22F0A1524CDD81D2BF71A303817D" style="OLC"><section id="H9AFD1D6AE5F44373AABE23F1CE4FA4FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Global Telecommunications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6515C3CB30654483918D905916B6FB52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress as follows:</text><paragraph id="H3EC0AD882DFD495FB3A59C467FBA0010"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Government should promote and take steps to ensure American leadership in strategic technology industries, including telecommunications infrastructure and other information and communications technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F52EE4C588A4735B711C6EA5E8EF330"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expansive presence of companies linked to the Chinese Communist Party, such as Huawei, in global mobile networks and the national security implications thereof, such as the ability of the People’s Republic of China to exfiltrate the information flowing through those networks and shut off countries’ internet access, demonstrates the importance of the United States remaining at the technological frontier and the dire consequences of falling behind.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1959540AE02746858BB1BDFE85028729"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The significant cost of countering Huawei’s market leadership in telecommunications infrastructure around the world underscores the urgency of supporting the competitiveness of United States companies in next-generation information and communication technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28455E54AC4F404B8B24311D5EB9C41B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To remain a leader at the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) and preserve the ITU’s technical integrity, the United States must work with emerging economies and developing nations to bolster global telecommunications security and protect American national security interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H407A33CD4E47422AB5226C573FB67F7F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Multilateral cooperation with like-minded partners and allies is critical to carry out the significant effort of financing and promoting secure networks around the world and to achieve market leadership of trusted vendors in this sector.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAABC380BA8B04A9CB5ABF3648F584EBF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy for securing global telecommunications infrastructure</header><subsection id="HE456E705AEC74AAAA4681F4174616CEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a strategy, to be known as the <quote>Strategy to Secure Global Telecommunications Infrastructure</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Strategy</quote>), to promote the use of secure telecommunication infrastructure worldwide.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4AC28F19455D47CF871281C5996DF1BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall consult with the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Chief Executive Officer of the Development Finance Corporation, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Director of the Trade and Development Agency, the Chair of the Federal Communications Commission, and the Secretary of Commerce, in developing the Strategy, which shall consist of an approach led by the Department of State using the policy tools, and informed by the technical expertise, of the other Federal entities so consulted to achieve the goal described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H584F72FA7522416483E4C0F7C2C1F593"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Strategy shall also include sections on each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HD2D3E9E53CF04A719C6FBA167DDB315D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mobile networks, including a description of efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="H7243E5B6894E49B493E7F06F7D02E224"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote trusted Open RAN technologies while protecting against any security risks posed by untrusted vendors in Open RAN networks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB86051FCF7149B39E1B001184B2A4EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use financing mechanisms to assist <quote>rip-and-replace</quote> projects and to incentivize countries to choose trusted equipment vendors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9765C02AC40E49628B94A363B9D282F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>bolster multilateral cooperation, especially with developing countries and emerging economies, to promote the deployment of trusted wireless networks worldwide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EB45F8806034529AA7AF7F304B5CDB6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collaborate with trusted private sector companies to counter Chinese market leadership in the telecom equipment industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3458A37ADEF4AC58E0677BE9537969E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>review the feasibility of using low-Earth orbit satellites as a way to provide internet access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1069A17599764F4DA8EB1F2C74C39318"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data centers, including a description of efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="H9077FF2604E0492B8EAE706A417EB90E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collaborate with trusted private sector companies to counter the growing market share of untrusted Chinese companies and to maintain and promote United States market leadership in the cloud computing and data center businesses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE91F56150AB04DC29DC710B1FC218C36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilize financing mechanisms to incentivize countries to choose trusted data center providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35D0B66E2BB847D2873E0AFF3F4E349B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>bolster multilateral cooperation, especially with developing countries and emerging economies, to promote the deployment of trusted data centers worldwide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF20262089B4C5184BE398C574B2778"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Sixth (and future) generation technologies (6G), including a description of efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="HF1A28939070B4D8B8A64549C3167DD04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote United States leadership in 6G standards-setting processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1266535542AB45EA930752253FF65E4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deepen cooperation with like-minded countries to promote United States and allied market leadership in 6G networks and technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2AFB35D0E9F418DA5B4D666ED36BFC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increase buy-in from developing countries and emerging countries on United States and allied 6G standards and trusted technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H151712883B994796B5084B4484B69023"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Low-Earth orbit satellites, aerostats, and stratospheric balloons, including a description of efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="H1EF3CE22137D4EA58163032885FA990D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop the capabilities to rapidly deliver wireless internet anywhere on the planet; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB604C23D4A644C3909AAE52C9B2A68C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work with trusted private sector companies to retain the ability to quickly provide internet connection in response to emergency situations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD330E1C3BE874919AC4B3959209924DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>International digital economic and telecommunication advisory committee</header><subsection id="HE65ABDEDF8BE46829DDBAF6214FA1EB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Department of State an International Digital Economic and Telecommunication Advisory Committee (<quote>IDET</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H72820C8D5FB64EB1BD6E75775555C89B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The IDET shall seek to advise the Secretary of State on the formulation of United States strategies, policies, positions, and proposals on policy matters relevant to digital economy, digital connectivity, economic aspects of emerging digital technologies, telecommunications, and communications and information policy. Such advice shall include matters related to United States participation in the International Telecommunication Union (ITU), the Inter-American Telecommunication Commission of the Organization of American States, the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, the Telecommunications and Information Working Group of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Forum, the Group of Seven, the Digital Economy Task Force of the Goup of Twenty, and other relevant telecommunications standards-setting bodies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C097FC29A25487BB7E3EC09329AF496"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chair and membership</header><paragraph id="HFA6186F977D046699C665FC57B9751E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall designate an employee of the Department of State to serve as the Chair of the IDET.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19ED6826FE0B450BAB99BA5940238E42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Chair shall appoint not fewer than 20 members to the IDET who meet the qualifications listed in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BC2886FCE4465C87E5B8985A82415C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications for members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the IDET shall be appointed from among individuals who are citizens or legal permanent residents of the United States. To ensure diversity of advice, the IDET may not include more than one representative of any one particular United States organization during any period in which the IDET consists of 20 members or fewer. Together, the members should represent a balance of interests and diverse viewpoints and have substantial expertise addressing these policy issues, participating in United States preparatory activities for conferences and meetings of international organizations, and serving on United States delegations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE423D214FF43ECACEE825CA3ED5608"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Organizations represented</header><text>Members of the IDET shall include representatives of the following—</text><subparagraph id="H60C9619CB2A14B7FBBB1910EB3278FE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interested government agencies, whose representatives shall serve as ex officio members;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC865A8F2966140978781ACC947397080"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States organizations, including associations and scientific or industrial organizations that are engaged in the study of telecommunications or in the design or manufacture of equipment intended for telecommunications services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C412DC82B2E42BF8C0944230ABF0C78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>civil society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64C608AA17594DD08F3EBCAA1B99C475"><enum>(D)</enum><text>academia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00B7D66281F4433E84DD2639EA6C2CC3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>organizations, institutions, or entities with specific interest in digital economy, digital connectivity, economic aspects of digital technologies, and communications and information policy matters. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79EDB0B86E0444A383C9C71F51A8DDC5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Chair may remove any member for any reason.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC74A5B0FA4594AD4A5C5D7F4C2424F44"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><paragraph id="H17AF2274631C4EBEA100A647AA491F17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Private sector subcommittee</header><subparagraph id="HAB35E2AE3D5E4392A0242899405A0E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Chair shall establish a permanent private sector subcommittee to provide the perspective and expertise of private industry so that an understanding of market forces, technical realities, bidding environments, and industry equities informs the recommendations of the IDET.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAA2240B350744FD93CF6AFCD881BD4F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Chair shall appoint a chair of the permanent subcommittee from among the members of the IDET.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C9C81A922BF4540BD727BD546B629BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The subcommittee’s membership should represent the range of private sector entities in critical telecommunications infrastructure and technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H531D124511874926877FE009369029B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Chair may establish such other subcommittees as the Chair may determine appropriate to provide advice to the IDET on strategic planning and other communications and information policy issues. Such subcommittees shall provide advice only to the IDET and shall not provide advice directly to the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H264F74A689CE4ADB91B6F8E87C5C291B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Membership of subcommittees shall not be limited to a prescribed number and may include more than one member from one agency or organization designated for the subcommittee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40D444C0F5F34D1AB8F9192D7B4A7F1E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $250,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2D7FA52CED604F99BD97E9037B2B6FE7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on malign influence at the International Telecommunication Union</header><subsection id="HEE8D1066C6844931B30F1FD049AD0AA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on Russian and Chinese strategies and efforts—</text><paragraph id="HBE253FD860EF46BC8B4CE46DA9695398"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to expand the mandate of the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) to cover internet governance policy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0FDDCE6D7A348E09242E98D03A0DEE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to advance other actions favorable to authoritarian interests and/or hostile to fair, industry-led processes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E263BFEEF964033A19DACD58471735E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall also identify efforts by China and Russia—</text><paragraph id="HB80473FE5BBF41C69247122DF10FBCA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text> to increase the ITU’s jurisdiction over internet governance and to propose internet governance standards at the ITU;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7509CFB9342420EAB31C3FCEE48648A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to leverage their private sectors to advance their national interests through the ITU, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDAB29CA8C49A4ACAA9D0C2156EA9F986"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encouraging Chinese and Russian companies to leverage their market power to pressure other member countries to deliver favorable decisions on ITU elections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DFE53EFE06142E68005FF4CFD4D486B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>China’s efforts to leverage Huawei’s role as the primary telecommunications equipment and services provider for many developing countries to compel such countries to deliver favorable decisions on standards proposals, election victories, candidate selection, and other levers of power at the ITU; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A0650BBDB684BCDB2FCBB58055A406C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to use the influence of Chinese and Russian nationals serving in the ITU to advantage the companies, standards decisions, and candidates that advance the CCP and Kremlin’s interests.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H658F75DCC2C747329B127E9E271B3EDF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H84BA548CF175447A98C86972F4CA5C17"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on multilateral coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Administrator for the United States Agency on International Development, and the Chief Executive Officer of the Development Finance Corporation, shall develop and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that identifies opportunities for greater collaboration with allies and partners to promote secure information and communications technology infrastructure, including through—</text><paragraph id="H5F82F9805BCC4B1590850F57613CC493"><enum>(1)</enum><text>joint financing efforts to help trusted vendors win bids to build out information and communications technology (ICT) infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61A1E818C7DA462DBB7483ACD0C2F586"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporating ICT focuses into allies’ and partners’ international development finance initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEBB32EF73CB40728D134355EDBADBE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing working groups focused on promoting trusted ICT in international standard-setting bodies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA5373A73CB41B88DB05DA7B480604E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>diplomatic coordination to emphasize the importance of secure telecommunications infrastructure to countries using untrusted providers.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

