<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A5B97FC06574B45BF27C9FD3B939B69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7559 IH: Prescription Information Modernization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7559</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220421">April 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for digital communication of prescribing information for drugs (including biological products), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7F26EB0A92B44DCA9384826F8206C4E" style="OLC"><section id="H207B737C0F2646A98DF2B66DB1299E47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Information Modernization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD63BF23B8CD841BC94E280383C4FD2FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Digital communication of FDA-approved prescribing information for drugs (including biological products)</header><subsection id="HA1B4E6FDE5084A2DBA63401132574DF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(f) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Required prescribing information for drugs subject to section 503(b)(1) may be made available solely by electronic means provided that the labeling complies with all applicable requirements of law, that the manufacturer affords prescribers and dispensers the opportunity to elect to also continue to receive all such information in paper form, or to request paper labeling on an as-needed basis, and after such request, and that the manufacturer promptly provides the requested information without additional cost.</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE687D897E07A47AA8ECCF420AC473350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph id="H99325994F77345F1834691CFE25FCDB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final regulations to—</text><subparagraph id="H08D4E2BB1C8B4E468781CB848659C361"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement the amendment made by subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7717E6484DE34E3C81FD78604CA6DC4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide instructions on how health care professionals can receive paper copies of prescribing information directly from the manufacturer or distributor if desired.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64FFE7AA40242698A80797E7CDD9291"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Economic impacts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall design the regulations required by paragraph (1) so as to minimize the adverse economic impacts of such regulations on prescribers and dispensers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD55D2A17E42649F4A468535CF12BDF8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public workshop</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall hold a public workshop with relevant stakeholders to discuss how to continue to optimize the format, accessibility, and usability of prescribing information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4641090F167A408794AE3234ED24A821"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to drugs introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce on or after the sooner of—</text><paragraph id="H70B169680A7644FF817F7437FCAE8885"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5AC3D9E728E4D89AAA579C71E1F996E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effective date of the final regulations promulgated to implement such amendment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE823486A130E47D995CCF89BDEC7F9C1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>drug</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

