<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="H4C8AE3837DE6461A854224F4817FABE4" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 7108 PCS: Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 313</calendar><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 7108</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date>March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date>March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar </action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To suspend normal trade relations treatment for the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B7ACC87A6234E7C8613FB4204DA306C" style="OLC"><section id="H401590C26F164A74AB4012B7F061B817" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H0C9831895F5443459DAD1F9E32D0AA3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HCEC7800BC1E14F2F9E466A1811ADD356"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States is a founding member of the World Trade Organization (WTO) and is committed to ensuring that the WTO remains an effective forum for peaceful economic engagement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97E7B47D652F47FD8067DBE088D5FA09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ukraine is a sovereign nation-state that is entitled to enter into agreements with other sovereign states and to full respect of its territorial integrity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE393DF02934627840BE66F7CEA6720"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States will be unwavering in its support for a secure, democratic, and sovereign Ukraine, free to choose its own leaders and future.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E361C9F217945C5855F824D195611FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ukraine acceded to the Marrakesh Agreement Establishing the World Trade Organization (WTO Agreement) and has been a WTO member since 2008.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA23060D0884B02B0DBEC95B1A1F728"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ukraine’s participation in the WTO Agreement creates both rights and obligations vis-à-vis other WTO members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD8121651D24C91A1B0E46DC6458F24"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation acceded to the WTO on August 22, 2012, becoming the 156th WTO member, and the Republic of Belarus has applied to accede to the WTO.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H454F986DAD5B452389CF5F01F730735D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>From the date of its accession, the Russian Federation committed to apply fully all provisions of the WTO.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90790009289A4C75B7C9A7798724A223"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States Congress authorized permanent normal trade relations for the Russian Federation through the Russia and Moldova Jackson-Vanik Repeal and Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/208">Public Law 112–208</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A02BA6AD570409FBB1BC39D363D7390"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ukraine communicated to the WTO General Council on March 2, 2022, urging that all WTO members take action against the Russian Federation and <quote>consider further steps with the view to suspending the Russian Federation’s participation in the WTO for its violation of the purpose and principles of this Organization</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6891712F25BB46C6BB037386A75BB47E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Vladimir Putin, a ruthless dictator, has led the Russian Federation into a war of aggression against Ukraine, which—</text><subparagraph id="H468B18E099A84158A9C0AB9F01951ABA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>denies Ukraine and its people their collective rights to independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97B641E0151543199DB8A8FF63FEDD25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>constitutes an emergency in international relations, because it is a situation of armed conflict that threatens the peace and security of all countries, including the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD22E510F8144B5B33F0AF7A0A8481A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>denies Ukraine its rightful ability to participate in international organizations, including the WTO. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8B6069C92B6492282889E0898BC628E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Republic of Belarus, also led by a ruthless dictator, Aleksander Lukashenka, is providing important material support to the Russian Federation’s aggression.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB85A2E7B16482294FA7EF8C6C22DD7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Russian Federation’s exportation of goods in the energy sector is central to its ability to wage its war of aggression on Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7F3806D3F914AAD954813F7E88AEAAD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States, along with its allies and partners, has responded to recent aggression by the Russian Federation in Ukraine by imposing sweeping financial sanctions and stringent export controls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9F06F84B83C4AC59AF8EC1C1F2F489B"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The United States cannot allow the consequences of the Russian Federation’s actions to go unaddressed, and must lead fellow countries, in all fora, including the WTO, to impose appropriate consequences for the Russian Federation’s aggression.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEA67B667196D4CE79231F21B187AFAE8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Suspension of normal trade relations with the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus</header><subsection id="H31CB0F2432034EC489F8D8A1999CF53B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nondiscriminatory tariff treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning on the day after the date of the enactment of this Act, the rates of duty set forth in column 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States shall apply to all products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8ED0F2C254B44D38BFC5290F1BFAEF75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority to proclaim increased column 2 rates</header><paragraph id="H48EEEF9D16A544C4861158A7852754A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may proclaim increases in the rates of duty applicable to products of the Russian Federation or the Republic of Belarus, above the rates set forth in column 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16DA63D8D7DF43F698418669C67FE77C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior consultation</header><text>The President shall, not later than 5 calendar days before issuing any proclamation under paragraph (1), consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate regarding the basis for and anticipated impact of the proposed increases to rates of duty described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D488DF58414CF2BEB5D1C65D075AD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to issue proclamations under this subsection shall terminate on January 1, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H82D7F939F9D24E4589274C15360073E0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Resumption of application of HTS column 1 rates of duty and restoration of normal trade relations treatment for the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus</header><subsection id="H2243480696EA47E087956AE9F446D766" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary application of HTS column 1 rates of duty</header><paragraph id="H61E3E6A69BA34FC8B5527E4DD7D98079"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including the application of column 2 rates of duty under section 3), the President is authorized to temporarily resume, for one or more periods not to exceed 1 year each, the application of the rates of duty set forth in column 1 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to the products of the Russian Federation, the Republic of Belarus, or both, if the President submits to Congress with respect to either or both such countries a certification under subsection (c) for each such period. Such action shall take effect beginning on the date that is 90 calendar days after the date of submission of such certification for such period, unless there is enacted into law during such 90-day period a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H497A1479656A46B89596F9E023662BBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 45 calendar days before submitting a certification under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H057C139E67D74B8B8844963BF2173C72"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C867B0AD1904329AF349F4D948195CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to both such committees a report that explains the basis for the determination of the President contained in such certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7214B4D360964492A1A76CB36EF04B70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration of normal trade relations treatment</header><paragraph id="H58F69AA13ED3490C8E552239D0217B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized to resume the application of the rates of duty set forth in column 1 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to the products of the Russian Federation, the Republic of Belarus, or both, if the President submits to Congress with respect to either or both such countries a certification under subsection (c). Such action shall take effect beginning on the date that is 90 calendar days after the date of submission of such certification, unless there is enacted into law during such 90-day period a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF33D774750440E986F3D017DBE49B5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 45 calendar days before submitting a certification under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H2F71A4AF3B4D41DB8736D354CC5BB07F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EBF6F167CDA49AFA4BE10A2BC4CEA9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to both such committees a report that explains the basis for the determination of the President contained in such certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA6AE179787D41C99EC44D600795F3CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Products of the Russian Federation</header><text>If the President submits pursuant to paragraph (1) a certification under subsection (c) with respect to the Russian Federation and a joint resolution of disapproval is not enacted during the 90-day period described in that paragraph, the President may grant permanent nondiscriminatory tariff treatment (normal trade relations) to the products of the Russian Federation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2CA6F1CD2B54AA2B98FC49781EA18E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Products of the Republic of Belarus</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President submits pursuant to paragraph (1) a certification under subsection (c) with respect to the Republic of Belarus and a joint resolution of disapproval is not enacted during the 90-day period described in that paragraph, the President may, subject to the provisions of chapter 1 of title IV of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2431">19 U.S.C. 2431 et seq.</external-xref>), grant nondiscriminatory tariff treatment (normal trade relations) to the products of the Republic of Belarus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A2F186D2F54476FB0D85FAE0D668414" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A certification under this subsection is a certification in writing that—</text><paragraph id="HD33F3239C58E4D2880B22BC663E41C8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifies the action proposed to be taken pursuant to the certification and whether such action is pursuant to subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA69BB6DD8F4C1B8A4190678460D275" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains a determination of the President that the Russian Federation or the Republic of Belarus (or both)—</text><subparagraph id="H68EB38B6DA834DB7908F2E48CD9B4046"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has reached an agreement relating to the respective withdrawal of Russian or Belarusian forces (or both, if applicable) and cessation of military hostilities that is accepted by the free and independent government of Ukraine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30EEB23C10E0449FA8355A0572A54773" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">poses no immediate military threat of aggression to any North Atlantic Treaty Organization member; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A4F5B4F907546048F5582FC6A436670" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recognizes the right of the people of Ukraine to independently and freely choose their own government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H472F80CAA96D427B82407A81579A5CA7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph id="H3E6D6C02BE854F29A626AC1121984AD8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="HCB6CF9214A054FD0AEAD108951DD057E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C56B8412D4045E9A570888C12172216" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution disapproving the President’s certification under section 4(c) of the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89940772A6B741A5AE35ED3090E5B2A6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the certification of the President under section 4(c) of the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act, submitted to Congress on ___ </quote>, the blank space being filled in with the appropriate date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD31B9219404A43B83B6F1B02B9712B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction in the House of Representatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 legislative days beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (c) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the House of Representatives by the majority leader or the minority leader.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CBA9515598541C892C2E79214F9A2B2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Introduction in the Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 days on which the Senate is in session beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (c) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the Senate by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6709987583E547BAB417FBD65DF86E6A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration in the House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="HBD52B8A520A24615BC4B3EB275CAA558" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a committee of the House to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported such joint resolution within 10 legislative days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration thereof. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5581A397FDDC47BA9E660844AB67535A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after each committee to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred reports it to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on a joint resolution with regard to the same certification. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF77F6D20864F48D9B2C6A4BBC9C5553E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H218EADE029CC4DBC8EF7123231FF7783" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="H7EF0321701CB4CFC8268817B784641B5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BE6B3AAAFF047EC88A4815D07CE557D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Finance has not reported such joint resolution of disapproval within 10 days on which the Senate is in session after the date of referral of such joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of such joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888F9DD950A3490E8633E43FA90DD016" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Finance reports the joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from its consideration (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) shall be waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB4B97FC3AB34DD5949AA56CD2277C60" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>Debate on the joint resolution of disapproval, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. A motion to further limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution of disapproval is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F89286B6658402B8B8A8F7EA1C63EC2" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the joint resolution of disapproval and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate, if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF858E8B457714B779D4AE99544775BBE" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rules of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to the joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F859FB27AA3490AB47FF031089E4238" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to the joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with such joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC250A8C189AB4D82A607BABED9382748" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Procedures in the Senate</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the following procedures shall apply in the Senate to a joint resolution of disapproval to which this subsection applies:</text><subparagraph id="HF81BEC3E69334DFE92FDC4658F5C28EC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be referred to the Committee on Finance for consideration in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD3DC0FCE1D04347A832D3CB8CECFC46" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a joint resolution of disapproval to which this subsection applies was introduced in the Senate before receipt of a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives, the joint resolution from the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be placed on the calendar. If this subparagraph applies, the procedures in the Senate with respect to a joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate that contains the identical matter as the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives shall be the same as if no joint resolution of disapproval had been received from the House of Representatives, except that the vote on passage in the Senate shall be on the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D7BF91C6E42415EABB597EC7C289DB9" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of the House of Representatives and Senate</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="H214F7ABCB0AF46F9B49E8B06A417D262" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such are deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of legislation described in those sections, and supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3986924BCA644D92A30BAFAEC03B6BFE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H388FAF3E7B3F4827BB601E62F1F9A7B3" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cooperation and accountability at the World Trade Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative shall use the voice and influence of the United States at the WTO to—</text><paragraph id="H3F69E0A32E5F4BFE877B219EC262059B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemn the recent aggression in Ukraine; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H613A7B44C9E74B3EB73E5B460AACD761" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage other WTO members to suspend trade concessions to the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B00E4DA955F4DDA93A2CCDF817AD1A5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider further steps with the view to suspend the Russian Federation’s participation in the WTO; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BAE1F7CE176483A8E8DEBD03D6C380B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>seek to halt the accession process of the Republic of Belarus at the WTO and cease accession-related work.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4CCADBD4A5E547EEB551B98DB400A7FA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Modifications to and reauthorization of sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act with respect to human rights violations</header><subsection id="H3749BA6346604D1781D5DB4EE94FC51B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1262 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended by striking paragraph (2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DFE7B11D26D47AEA2ACED93346303A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><paragraph id="HD25B6BAC8A0741A4A42BA3287DEB6705" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after section 1262 (as amended by subsection (a)) the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H2C937131C6284111B438E3722194AEAD" style="OLC"><section id="H79C6F9B56DDE457098547B1D2D4735D1"><enum>1262A.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should establish and regularize information sharing and sanctions-related decisionmaking with like-minded governments possessing human rights and anti-corruption sanctions programs similar in nature to those authorized under this subtitle.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EBD9999EEEA427E9953BE501B583083" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) and in title XII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) are each amended by inserting after the items relating to section 1262 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H148CE1EC95D0469B9DA888923CF7BCEA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1262A. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C426AB3425745B8BA9BE8D29337322E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="H37AF4435226249A3B281F5FA716F47EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1263 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (Subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H4E41B5651D634837AD24129476521850" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE245C060CD9C47D99C01F59005A00F07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines, based on credible information—</text><paragraph id="HA1D2122F4C2641FE9D9353178CF027D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuse;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC50227B58F4C649351B09773A00D79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a current or former government official, or a person acting for or on behalf of such an official, who is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in—</text><subparagraph id="HA25643B5DFB0409EAD5B7B1F78E3A72C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>corruption, including—</text><clause id="H89345596B1AF406389CD398C918520CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the misappropriation of state assets;</text></clause><clause id="H65E577054AF247C99C1099A6E326D93C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expropriation of private assets for personal gain;</text></clause><clause id="HA5E0B4E004A94246BD79830E6A87D6E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>corruption related to government contracts or the extraction of natural resources; or</text></clause><clause id="HEC28472AD7FF43DB83EC4FC840C78864"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>bribery; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF91810F7723A478DA0AC2DE2F3D4A014"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transfer or facilitation of the transfer of the proceeds of corruption;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE96C80DA24354B3E9B6DAC977CEB1A06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is or has been a leader or official of—</text><subparagraph id="HCF0A048963264F499CC5E26BB988C6BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity, including a government entity, that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in paragraph (1) or (2) during the tenure of the leader or official; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13CF42106D0C482CB19F0F2FEFBA8954"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section as a result of activities during the tenure of the leader or official;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF64EA6BD21364D41AA7104CC6569ECCF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of—</text><subparagraph id="H403C00B6453A479EB8CF5508F0C5B144"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) that is conducted by a foreign person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF17983045B364EA483745AA756EF2DDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74981F3ACA34449A8A13EA7DFE583288"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity, including a government entity, that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) conducted by a foreign person; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CFB7DC31D0E481384DD8B5C8116C262"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by, or has acted or been purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H52318DB7AEDE4E7E809DCE8BF24473CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of certain information</header><text>Subsection (c)(2) of such section is amended by striking <quote>violations of human rights</quote> and inserting <quote>corruption and human rights abuses</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE2C93861C65481A9467F11A4B016999"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requests by congress</header><text>Subsection (d)(2) of such section is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H27D07FA8A0DD4A96A4B0D1E8028DDC85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HEA1E11F69FCA48698337C965C51E2CF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Human rights violations</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Serious human rights abuse</header-in-text></quote>; </text></clause><clause id="HE8CA65938D0846CCBDA99A8F7789274B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in subsection (a) relating to serious human rights abuse </quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA56C0ADE33374012BABE39F0DC39B938"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HC16579CA00324455A4919F94E2A74540"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>described in paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in subsection (a) relating to corruption or the transfer or facilitation of the transfer of the proceeds of corruption</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H248AB9691F88461280EFCE3850866644"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>ranking member of—</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D91217AF4934C069383C4A4ACC9F426"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Section 1264(a) of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD8DB1C1D2ACE467A8B29B40992CE36F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H671B93FBEA6B4D9B8E746257F5D3B1FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6606043ECE74CE2852AB58E705961AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H1327D69AAC4A4B8F9E6B91F774EAEC50" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5C629CF307574FF2B2A4AD0E1133521A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of additional steps taken by the President through diplomacy, international engagement, and assistance to foreign or security sectors to address persistent underlying causes of serious human rights abuse and corruption in each country in which foreign persons with respect to which sanctions have been imposed under section 1263 are located; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3D51A6CB3A47E68F3978D8E2CA87BB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of additional steps taken by the President to ensure the pursuit of judicial accountability in appropriate jurisdictions with respect to those foreign persons subject to sanctions under section 1263 for serious human rights abuse and corruption.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA4849587CD4455EBD689F5C8B7C56F4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of sunset</header><paragraph id="H36A9462F5B794239810165456D1A38DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1265 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE5FE5402B9D40F982EECC92E684192B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) and in title XII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) are each amended by striking the items relating to section 1265.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220317" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 17, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement display="yes"><action-date display="yes">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

