<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HAB395ECF2402446DA62F80D8FADB60E8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5502 RH: To require online marketplaces to verify certain information regarding high-volume third party sellers of consumer products on such online marketplaces and to disclose to consumers certain contact and other information regarding such high-volume third party sellers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 399</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5502</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–555]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211005">October 5, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000615">Mr. Pence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001135">Mrs. Steel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000376">Mr. Allred</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000377">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001312">Ms. Bourdeaux</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require online marketplaces to verify certain information regarding high-volume third party sellers of consumer products on such online marketplaces and to disclose to consumers certain contact and other information regarding such high-volume third party sellers.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D0113E174304696A13BF1141D004B04" style="OLC"><section id="H53080D0173564B71A6BE07E0400C1098" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Collection, verification, and disclosure of information by online marketplaces to inform consumers</header><subsection id="H55AEF23DDF0F4870ABA10350587EEAC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection and verification of information</header><paragraph id="H6FCC816CD9C14269B9C5F353F48300BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection</header><subparagraph id="H0679A86261C042D98AD89B0D1982C2EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An online marketplace shall require any high-volume third party seller on such online marketplace's platform to provide, not later than 10 days after qualifying as a high-volume third party seller on the platform, the following information to the online marketplace:</text><clause id="H3039B7A54592483AAEF9D5EC11EB4588"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Bank account</header><subclause id="HF8E728FE68304038BDCD8D0CB1C7845F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A bank account number, or, if such seller does not have a bank account, the name of the payee for payments issued by the online marketplace to such seller.</text></subclause><subclause id="H37BC12F9E16D4061A4E396C680610D78"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text>The bank account or payee information required under subclause (I) may be provided by the seller in the following ways:</text><item id="H6E0F0C5AA142472F86BAC10D0D6C876A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>To the online marketplace.</text></item><item id="H0B0AD29892C24CDFB9FB3478450C4CA8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>To a payment processor or other third party contracted by the online marketplace to maintain such information, provided that the online marketplace ensures that it can obtain such information on demand from such payment processor or other third party.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB1D099645B434521A6060D1494ED9294"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contact information</header><text>Contact information for such seller as follows:</text><subclause id="H26BF7F5433D84394951B92A5E02DD699"><enum>(I)</enum><text>With respect to a high-volume third party seller that is an individual, the individual's name.</text></subclause><subclause id="H98D8545C1864497086B0F59000FBDD1B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>With respect to a high-volume third party seller that is not an individual, one of the following forms of contact information:</text><item id="H72E7BD5BF4524282BE5D00219A2BAAE5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A copy of a valid government-issued identification for an individual acting on behalf of such seller that includes the individual's name.</text></item><item id="H7262D725F35C411FB2594268ADC77075"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A copy of a valid government-issued record or tax document that includes the business name and physical address of such seller.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HECDDADF298D54050A2A9DA49C25AC07F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Tax ID</header><text>A business tax identification number, or, if such seller does not have a business tax identification number, a taxpayer identification number.</text></clause><clause id="HF9A3031162BE4A31B128D8DF69989873"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Working email and phone number</header><text>A current working email address and phone number for such seller.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAA45671DE3C41BB8C503E0F6AE21AE4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification of change; annual certification</header><text>An online marketplace shall—</text><clause id="H59C186DC11A34DDBB8B93B4F2CBDF1FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>periodically, but not less than annually, notify any high-volume third party seller on such online marketplace's platform of the requirement to keep any information collected under subparagraph (A) current; and</text></clause><clause id="H3BFA1C1E04284FDC99E2BECBF7F000F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require any high-volume third party seller on such online marketplace's platform to, not later than 10 days after receiving the notice under clause (i), electronically certify that—</text><subclause id="H10ADFAD7BE8548108D6499BD825753B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the seller has provided any changes to such information to the online marketplace, if any such changes have occurred;</text></subclause><subclause id="H07077017C4624D54B08F16F18FA3B01E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>there have been no changes to such seller's information; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1840132764534C848AB2F4EBB1A14081"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such seller has provided any changes to such information to the online marketplace.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA12703809B64161BAA1C8D8EFA00397" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>In the event that a high-volume third party seller does not provide the information or certification required under this paragraph, the online marketplace shall, after providing the seller with written or electronic notice and an opportunity to provide such information or certification not later than 10 days after the issuance of such notice, suspend any future sales activity of such seller until such seller provides such information or certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F9673301EA742FF9D80D9781919BEB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification</header><subparagraph id="H3A3CB2B041BC4CE4B0CC03820C5A75DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An online marketplace shall—</text><clause id="H8A073B794351480BB9F981441551B424"><enum>(i)</enum><text>verify the information collected under paragraph (1)(A) not later than 10 days after such collection; and</text></clause><clause id="H5B491FFD846F46EEA0E5BB8D0F8647E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>verify any change to such information not later than 10 days after being notified of such change by a high-volume third party seller under paragraph (1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B1B5A3D00504A85855E5E7CABAC030D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Presumption of verification</header><text>In the case of a high-volume third party seller that provides a copy of a valid government-issued tax document, any information contained in such document shall be presumed to be verified as of the date of issuance of such document.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE33C29CE8E4F61A18931D27558B738"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data use limitation</header><text>Data collected solely to comply with the requirements of this section may not be used for any other purpose unless required by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2C20B5E4B0413FB90D094E77FC2A19"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data security requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An online marketplace shall implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices, including administrative, physical, and technical safeguards, appropriate to the nature of the data and the purposes for which the data will be used, to protect the data collected to comply with the requirements of this section from unauthorized use, disclosure, access, destruction, or modification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE39475F42F084C52AA61CCDF16C0B26C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure required</header><paragraph id="H29909FFDD2CC42C79E42A964E1B679AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><subparagraph id="HF7A61C1D6CC0471787164F8D76442B11"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An online marketplace shall—</text><clause id="HA70B2B00C191459FA405D2B2370A0FBA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>require any high-volume third party seller with an aggregate total of $20,000 or more in annual gross revenues on such online marketplace, and that uses such online marketplace’s platform, to provide the information described in subparagraph (B) to the online marketplace; and</text></clause><clause id="H68755E0EBCB34A10B7A357012A05BBFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disclose the information described in subparagraph (B) to consumers in a clear and conspicuous manner—</text><subclause id="H3BBBEF687490463683F129971DD78803"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the order confirmation message or other document or communication made to a consumer after a purchase is finalized; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H86B1B931E0A14879A13517C84280FCBB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the consumer’s account transaction history.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BEE1059C8FA4B25A13FB7304201594C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>The information described in this subparagraph is the following:</text><clause id="H062D74BF7D254FCA916AB6C34E443FEA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the identity of the high-volume third party seller, including—</text><subclause id="H13C9418DE82648C59A75EF8C77D262A1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the full name of the seller, which may include the seller name or seller’s company name, or the name by which the seller or company operates on the online marketplace;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCC2C3D36C0284E5698AC8671887F1B19" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the physical address of the seller; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7849D85584B1403A8A8B7CDF1BD9DD43" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>contact information for the seller, to allow for the direct, unhindered communication with high-volume third party sellers by users of the online marketplace, including—</text><item id="H6F971BE6761E4ABAA6F1BF31C1490941" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a current working phone number; </text></item><item id="H03B9159822DD47AAA378D96F6AEA8C54" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a current working email address; or</text></item><item id="H3024870B47AD40C99524EA2B9FD36A52" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>other means of direct electronic messaging (which may be provided to such seller by the online marketplace).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H8BD964CB11CC4F558C8C579AEA6D81A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Whether the high-volume third party seller used a different seller to supply the consumer product to the consumer upon purchase, and, upon the request of an authenticated purchaser, the information described in clause (i) relating to any such seller that supplied the consumer product to the purchaser, if such seller is different than the high-volume third party seller listed on the product listing prior to purchase.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5886EAA9C2C146CF97695060C4FA308A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><subparagraph id="H3F8DF5AA91614479AE0D16528A9B8952"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), upon the request of a high-volume third party seller, an online marketplace may provide for partial disclosure of the identity information required under paragraph (1)(B)(i) in the following situations:</text><clause id="HCB5514D45D60498A94592EA37901DF1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If such seller certifies to the online marketplace that the seller does not have a business address and only has a residential street address, or has a combined business and residential address, the online marketplace may—</text><subclause id="H7CD5F1FD3B4F445A82AD673AEE14CDFC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>disclose only the country and, if applicable, the State in which such seller resides; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF30E8659E25342A0BD3FA780E5CF3E51"><enum>(II)</enum><text>inform consumers that there is no business address available for the seller and that consumer inquiries should be submitted to the seller by phone, email, or other means of electronic messaging provided to such seller by the online marketplace.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA51CC211CFE54AE1853D29F5449CEE44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If such seller certifies to the online marketplace that the seller is a business that has a physical address for product returns, the online marketplace may disclose the seller’s physical address for product returns.</text></clause><clause id="HC92E9713BCD74C3BACBA9D00E22FD09F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If such seller certifies to the online marketplace that the seller does not have a phone number other than a personal phone number, the online marketplace shall inform consumers that there is no phone number available for the seller and that consumer inquiries should be submitted to the seller’s email address or other means of electronic messaging provided to such seller by the online marketplace.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB78C82620FF143FCB1B81A7FF23519B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on exception</header><text>If an online marketplace becomes aware that a high-volume third party seller has made a false representation to the online marketplace in order to justify the provision of a partial disclosure under subparagraph (A) or that a high-volume third party seller who has requested and received a provision for a partial disclosure under subparagraph (A) has not provided responsive answers within a reasonable time frame to consumer inquiries submitted to the seller by phone, email, or other means of electronic messaging provided to such seller by the online marketplace, the online marketplace shall, after providing the seller with written or electronic notice and an opportunity to respond not later than 10 days after the issuance of such notice, suspend any future sales activity of such seller unless such seller consents to the disclosure of the identity information required under paragraph (1)(B)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAFD3559CD1344069897D063376A025F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting mechanism</header><text>An online marketplace shall disclose to consumers in a clear and conspicuous manner on the product listing of any high-volume third party seller a reporting mechanism that allows for electronic and telephonic reporting of suspicious marketplace activity to the online marketplace. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0861E4428D44B3AC3A058F1A2922E7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>If a high-volume third party seller does not comply with the requirements to provide and disclose information under this subsection, the online marketplace shall, after providing the seller with written or electronic notice and an opportunity to provide or disclose such information not later than 10 days after the issuance of such notice, suspend any future sales activity of such seller until the seller complies with such requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7B7D85817114F2480E8D7782E8B9821"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="HA4D465F7462643D3B36E079337200DC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair and deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) or (b) by an online marketplace shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9A968141034E7CAFC0EEAB497350D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="H74F4E04C73AB4B9FAD4806B4FE6FF21D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce subsections (a) and (b) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3C7C193D41149E3BD4ACE407801DC31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person that violates subsection (a) or (b) shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52884B74A9474F76BE593825C34C3BE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission may promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the collection, verification, or disclosure of information under this section, provided that such regulations are limited to what is necessary to collect, verify, and disclose such information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H647C3F149C4043E79A1CE92360091BC8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10193BB011CA4193BA0C0B374A41E3FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by State attorneys general</header><paragraph id="H6C5697A47D0E4327BAFCAB12839E7A9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that any online marketplace has violated or is violating this section or a regulation promulgated under this section that affects one or more residents of that State, the attorney general of the State may bring a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States, to—</text><subparagraph id="H29FE5C11C78E441B9C451C3116421219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further such violation by the defendant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B11CBB82B4F441380F6EBEF7FA8D072"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforce compliance with this section or such regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13D49FEF231042749E35F1DB90B9D560"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties in the amount provided for under subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1250561A57404E2AAF70A661447B301A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain other remedies permitted under State law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B44E4D705AF48ABB81EDBB90EB1190B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC71C637A67084455A7013F26C12B7A6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The attorney general of a State shall provide prior written notice of any action under paragraph (1) to the Commission and provide the Commission with a copy of the complaint in the action, except in any case in which such prior notice is not feasible, in which case the attorney general shall serve such notice immediately upon instituting such action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB1F27FB64248E39C11AD5D1B3033FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intervention by the FTC</header><text>Upon receiving notice under paragraph (2), the Commission shall have the right—</text><subparagraph id="H688B2DCB852145F5B6E2E40A0600C347"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC36664996E94800B84B5C3E94029F6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2889D7DCAD845F3A270FB07FF7ED0BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60373B803E62474887032CFA2A684678"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission has instituted a civil action for violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section, no State attorney general, or official or agency of a State, may bring a separate action under paragraph (1) during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for any violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section that is alleged in the complaint. A State attorney general, or official or agency of a State, may join a civil action for a violation of this section or regulation promulgated under this section filed by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC592A51459A48A48D804B996DB6F639"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of bringing a civil action under paragraph (1), nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the chief law enforcement officer, or official or agency of a State, from exercising the powers conferred on such chief law enforcement officer, official or agency of a State, by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDC0C284A314252863505BDC12309FE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Actions by other State officials</header><subparagraph id="H4CAD0FCBEBBD4353BF12FEE79536E10D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to civil actions brought by attorneys general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so, except for any private person on behalf of the State attorney general, may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23A8C4A578FA4FFEADA2A56724BC17E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CB1B0D544424E9AB677981F393D8B93"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this section and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected by the invalidation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFBD62ADD586E4D798E8BE909A66FB687"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0C38370CE1C54F2CB1D100BC78C02141"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32D20A21E68744CEB460133D9A16DE9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer product</header><text>The term <term>consumer product</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Magnuson-Moss Warranty—Federal Trade Commission Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2301">15 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref>) and section 700.1 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D54487178854792B97FD544EFE24111"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-volume third party seller</header><subparagraph id="H8844297356CD4B5EA47DEDAAD036BB73"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>high-volume third party seller</term> means a participant on an online marketplace’s platform who is a third party seller and who, in any continuous 12-month period during the previous 24 months, has entered into 200 or more discrete sales or transactions of new or unused consumer products and an aggregate total of $5,000 or more in gross revenues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABB6989D8FF740F7916DAEAD2A8551C7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>For purposes of calculating the number of discrete sales or transactions or the aggregate gross revenues under subparagraph (A), an online marketplace shall only be required to count sales or transactions made through the online marketplace and for which payment was processed by the online marketplace, either directly or through its payment processor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C8D6CA35DE1435CA51FD6379299C5E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Online marketplace</header><text>The term <term>online marketplace</term> means any person or entity that operates a consumer-directed electronically based or accessed platform that—</text><subparagraph id="HB184C99058F541ACACB06B7C4EFFF9EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes features that allow for, facilitate, or enable third party sellers to engage in the sale, purchase, payment, storage, shipping, or delivery of a consumer product in the United States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C15BE5CC8454F9196D5D0EB9FCD5583"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is used by one or more third party sellers for such purposes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B90CEF44094B4D9218AC273BDFA93B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a contractual or similar relationship with consumers governing their use of the platform to purchase consumer products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60796DC96BB44D5B8482305A156B4942"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Seller</header><text>The term <term>seller</term> means a person who sells, offers to sell, or contracts to sell a consumer product through an online marketplace's platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBFEE507784C49B6BF90499131130FC5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Third party seller</header><subparagraph id="HFD5D48F8337B47D893728F25F0478323"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>third party seller</term> means any seller, independent of an online marketplace, who sells, offers to sell, or contracts to sell a consumer product in the United States through such online marketplace's platform. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49B49D67448E417294EC23302566595B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>third party seller</term> does not include, with respect to an online marketplace—</text><clause id="H60D9652155384DCEB70D4559321E34D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a seller who operates the online marketplace's platform; or</text></clause><clause id="H392EF6E8C114405C921E5F9735B3EC2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a business entity that has—</text><subclause id="H78AFC02FF89C43139301EC4A9418C849"><enum>(I)</enum><text>made available to the general public the entity’s name, business address, and working contact information;</text></subclause><subclause id="H438BCF6DB52143888DD691515A812BEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an ongoing contractual relationship with the online marketplace to provide the online marketplace with the manufacture, distribution, wholesaling, or fulfillment of shipments of consumer products; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEE1AA0FA4B19484DAD1E0C7CE497D99E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provided to the online marketplace identifying information, as described in subsection (a), that has been verified in accordance with that subsection. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFDD0CA40EE0493D9DD5D0F2F233CC82"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Verify</header><text>The term <term>verify</term> means to confirm information provided to an online marketplace pursuant to this section, which may include the use of one or more methods that enable the online marketplace to reliably determine that any information and documents provided are valid, corresponding to the seller or an individual acting on the seller’s behalf, not misappropriated, and not falsified.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB41CCC2408654FB9941869B0996DD727" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Relationship to State laws</header><text>No State or political subdivision of a State, or territory of the United States, may establish or continue in effect any law, regulation, rule, requirement, or standard that conflicts with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H573346FF42EB46B2B1E06DFF058DEE7F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc> Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

