<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF093B659AB144A2D92E97648C5625824" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9201 IH: Community Mental Wellness and Resilience Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9201</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221018">October 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to promote mental wellness and resilience and heal mental health, behavioral health, and psychosocial problems through age and culturally appropriate community programs, and award grants for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding community-based mental wellness and resilience programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7319E8712AC541FFA023414FA93DD870" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H578D57A8787C484B8304BEE24B42C67E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Mental Wellness and Resilience Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD4CB28573120448198D7CEC35F4B2F69"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for community mental wellness and resilience programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317U (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-23">42 U.S.C. 247b–23</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF56718DBED394C10A1427579FEE542C1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H81C9D8B1E7D34945AF05EFBE0B0D1FEE"><enum>317V.</enum><header>Grant program for community wellness and resilience programs</header> 
<subsection id="H6984E8E70D6146C9890EE10FFB2B3911"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<paragraph id="HABB9E6FB496F4A1FA5AEE92C225B2754"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="H652981272DA146C0B6D339CAD90CD7EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall carry out a program of awarding grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding community mental wellness and resilience programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H637C3DD2044D4A078FA3A1825E8CE089"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed $4,000,000. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF8997FC6EC24244BA80C8A292E05ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Planning grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAF0DE9570F054B1E8C5A602CE9415D13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants to entities—</text> <clause id="H5217EA1DA04B4F7FA66AFA0501E55C9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to organize a consortium that meets the requirements of subsection (c);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3DD5A2284354928A50AA74C7E35F379"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to perform assessments of need with respect to community mental wellness and resilience; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEFB7C5A2AD4343A9BF7D7CC1E07020FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to prepare an application for a grant under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5097621762BC480CA6A7304E973E4491"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a grant under subparagraph (A), with respect to any consortium to be organized for applying for a grant under paragraph (1), shall not exceed $15,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC14A26A0283C44178A59C178301B2594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>A community mental wellness and resilience program funded pursuant to a grant under subsection (a)(1) shall take a public health approach to mental health to strengthen the entire community’s psychological and emotional wellness and resilience, including by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H721247D0CD6A44429ABD3DA79E873B88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collecting and analyzing information from residents as well as quantitative data to identify—</text> <subparagraph id="H48830707424B464793A29F33D97D64E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protective factors that enhance and sustain the community’s capacity for mental wellness and resilience; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B0A8B6591924721B83D9E78E801A105"><enum>(B)</enum><text>risk factors that undermine such capacity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06589406DDD045C29A2DD6EFCDD7FFD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening such protective factors and addressing such risk factors;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04E8D1B7DDB74672943BEC0F43E5DFA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>building awareness, skills, tools, and leadership in the community to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F23FFB9C496484997E4555D10F4DF45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate using a public health approach to mental health; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A15DFB3F7FE48F1B7DA62110174D1E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>heal mental health and psychosocial problems among all adults and youth; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H441A4D5AEA394D6D9AF8278FDD5194D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>developing, implementing, and continually evaluating and improving a comprehensive strategic plan for carrying out the activities described in paragraphs (1), (2) and (3) that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6097A162F7624A95B5CFB407CF96A755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence-based or promising best practices for—</text> <clause id="HCE5D3B9C968E46C1B3F28AC87AABAD35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enhancing local economic and environmental conditions, including with respect to the built environment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H13503D41FCDB4688AEFA848052416EC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>becoming trauma-informed and learning simple self-administrable mental wellness and resilience skills;</text></clause> <clause id="H4B96CD122C2C47809012EBD5CDA1D850"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engaging in community activities that strengthen mental wellness and resilience;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54D3CAB0C182468DAD17C710F781AE62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partaking in nonclinical group and community-minded recovery and healing programs; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0FA14F67E6FE4978B70098588D8AD38C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other activities to promote mental wellness and resilience and heal individual and community traumas; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB17D315C874417CAE506B37FB76E9EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>age-appropriate and culturally appropriate methods to engage people in building social connections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8EC25FA4B770423E804AC68BDA5303BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header> <paragraph id="H32AC6C74476341E8944C0336F0AF92C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a)(1), an applicant shall be a consortium of entities including 1 or more representatives from at least 7 of the categories listed in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CA1F04E58C144AD80EF64D59D3607BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The categories listed in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H37FBE5ACC2584EE78218F53C18E13AAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Grassroots groups, neighborhood associations, and volunteer civic organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3A254176BD6439E9C1211E7F7EFE2B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Elementary and secondary schools, institutions of higher education including community colleges, job-training programs, and other education or training agencies or organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC9A4AC8453F4B7BA1383FDC5ADB584E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Youth after-school and summer programs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BFA2F33E7BC4ABBA39D7D90AEAF5DBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Family and early childhood education programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0494972844714E4B9F1F8997E0A25B16"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Faith and spirituality organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC13C9F62F3F64EFE8602CE6A87B97709"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Senior care organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A530B016C464D89BA751BA664B2F07F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Climate change mitigation and adaptation, and environmental conservation, groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9101C938DE7C4A1194C4D800C332B109"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Social and environmental justice groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69ACD5A59BDF4792B36F42B3CB1EA3FD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Disaster preparedness and response groups and organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71E3917755924D288BF901EA5166992D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Businesses and business associations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB4444D63B74407C98479F2D7FB5B764"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Police, fire, and other agencies and organizations involved with community safety, security, and the justice system.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H24CBF062C4EC4FF9AB265C296D6F63B3"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Social work, mental health, behavioral health, substance use, physical health, and public health professionals; public health agencies and institutions; and mental health, behavioral health, social work, and other professionals, groups, organizations, agencies, and institutions in the health and human services fields.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1DEDB9415D74D42A7E5F4D9D80B7C2F"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The general public, including individuals who have experienced mental health or psychosocial problems who can represent and engage with populations relevant to the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H666EB3B023604262806763CB1E2A3EE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding a grant under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants proposing to carry out a community mental wellness and resilience program that uses a public health approach to mental health to develop, implement, and continually evaluate and improve age and culturally appropriate education, skills training, and other services that use a strength-based approach to enhance the capacity for mental wellness and resilience for all types of toxic stresses and traumas among all adults and youth in the community.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H889832529E9942729FEEE7898AC35924"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H772C15FB4FDF40C5B8241AF9B1100A2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than the end of calendar year 2028, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the results of the grants under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A204242107548F78B46D7D7D21D6655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Such report shall include a summary of the best practices used by grantees in establishing, operating, or expanding community mental wellness and resilience programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H39B3E92C58DB48149D8B55CC444B0ED4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A97CFAC3B0545B5A8C554A802AB9493" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>public health approach to mental health</term> refers to methods that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD8C850B32D424477986B24ECF39A012D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take a population-level approach to promote mental wellness and resilience to prevent problems before they emerge and heal them when they do appear, not merely treating individuals one at a time after symptoms of pathology appear; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07B8816D61284887B4FCAACBDC26F546"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address mental health and psychosocial problems by—</text> <clause id="H697169AF71C045E1B0DDB3527EEF1D81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying and strengthening existing protective factors, and forming new ones, that buffer people from and enhance their capacity for psychological and emotional resilience; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1291E2EDD1C04C43917DE25D36D309B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>taking a holistic systems perspective that recognizes that most mental health and psychosocial problems result from numerous interrelated personal, family, social, economic, and environmental factors that require multipronged community-based interventions.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89A0832769F64ED2BD5984C75EDF7811"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>community</term> means people, groups, and organizations that reside in or work within a specific geographic area, such as a city, neighborhood, subdivision, urban, suburban, or rural locale.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA89D02AA9C146CD942B703870E1B9FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>community trauma</term> means a blow to the basic fabric of social life that damages the bonds attaching people together, impairs their prevailing sense of community, undermines their fundamental sense of safety, justice, equity, and security, and heightens individual and collective fears and feelings of vulnerability.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33346EE4F1284C789FD23CF9061C500A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>protective factors</term> means strengths, skills, resources, and characteristics that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DA12EA09D9F48A1A9848F6B0B33681B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are associated with a lower likelihood of negative outcomes of adversities; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75ED4E1D567B4AC584C7289037A25EF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the impact on people of toxic stresses or a traumatic experience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA4FFBA6D9024E4DBD56774EF8B12003" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>mental wellness</term> means a state of well-being in which an individual can—</text> <subparagraph id="H49C460D6FBDE497AB07D631E22DE5455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>realize their own potential;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7E6B5A4712C4711ABCD194F79803FE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>constructively cope with the stresses of life;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD881B0EDBFE84321B568F2470EEE709E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work productively and fruitfully; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22654FCB97674DC3AB3CE19AD2EFAC41"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make a contribution to their community.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC40A3CBBCCEF457DA3CEC22C22665A83"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>psychosocial problem</term> refers to how an individual’s mental health or behavioral health problem disturbs others such as children, families, communities, or society.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H681AC5E80B2B45F0ABD4C7667283B5EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>resilience</term> means that people develop cognitive, psychological, emotional capabilities and social connections that enable them to calm their body, mind, emotions, and behaviors during toxic stresses or traumatic experiences in ways that enable them to—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A851D9025F243CBA06D592DF6BC0804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>respond without negative consequences for themselves or others; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H621545431DB44E7993168C301EA9843F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use the experiences as catalysts to develop a constructive new sense of meaning, purpose, and hope.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2854C690FADF4443BC8C4F582828DFBF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>toxic stress</term> means exposure to a persistent overwhelming traumatic and stressful situations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H602A849B2AF941F1809F7BFB28D740C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2024 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

