<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H861568E01B7C4601866C6532FA77E052" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8304 IH: Rapid Financing for Critical Condo Repairs Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to insure loans made to condominium associations to finance repair or replacement of common areas, systems, and features, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D1ADBE700B84208986391E746E5FDDE" style="OLC"><section id="H7AD7B9FE0F5644618D4825A0153AE646" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rapid Financing for Critical Condo Repairs Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8449A9CE2B9B43D287BF8BBD52D35A7A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Insurance of mortgages to finance repair and replacement of common facilities of condominium projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 234 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715y">12 U.S.C. 1715y</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5F4EB8E3135245599BC04040B076D55E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>and preserving</quote> after <quote>increasing</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE76002FB92438AA69FFC57317CE2D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (b), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and except that the term <quote>mortgage</quote>, for the purposes of subsection (l), includes a loan financing the costs of a rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving a condominium project and that is secured by future lien-based mandatory unit owner payments required pursuant to State statute, a recorded declaration of covenants, or lawful rule, by-law, or guideline adopted by the governing body of the condominium project, real property, or a combination thereof</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD9A154AC8F6416B91A132F9CC9F9741"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E636470FA974DC598C2C6E619DA6EC7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8B35F105852345F5BFE986B719B768A4"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Insurance of mortgages To finance repairs and replacements of common facilities</header><paragraph id="H7BA655D4A0C34DA2A090818141F638D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to mortgages insured under the other provisions of this section, the Secretary may insure, in the discretion of the Secretary and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, a mortgage—</text><subparagraph id="H12A6D50CDDF44C8A8994B5CA8898FF21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that finances, in the case of condominium projects, the costs of a rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D72829A77D64648A059499ECB2FE630"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the mortgagor is the governing body of the condominium project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD009DDA0889491EB05249AA144902C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loan limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for insurance under this subsection, a mortgage may not involve a principal obligation in an amount exceeding 90 percent of the cost of the proposed rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement project.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id1B5CC763AA4144E8BF3EEC01D530E277"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by inserting <quote>or (l)</quote> after <quote>subsection (d)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

