<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE901EEBA22F447849B6B58EBBB0878E7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6374 IH: Strengthening Supply Chains for Servicemembers and Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6374</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense with respect to mitigation of foreign suppliers in the pharmaceutical supply chain of the Department of Defense.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26F0F1D536CE4328A9AE821082A70BB5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7250C17131974E308774123D4DE4E641" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Supply Chains for Servicemembers and Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H1BE0993E21C94630920A7583F6D7A701"><enum>2.</enum><header>Risk management for Department of Defense supply chains</header> <subsection id="HCC7A58B8510E4AE4A0CAAB690C0A9011"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Risk management for all Department of Defense supply chains</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HC68D65CF2DFF4A0D993B688FD543F66A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and issue implementing guidance for risk management for Department of Defense supply chains for materiel for the Department, including pharmaceuticals; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81961C1C587845598DD9D692435F0E49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify, in coordination with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, supply chain information gaps regarding reliance on foreign suppliers of drugs, including active pharmaceutical ingredients and final drug products; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81022E53F2F847B7BB437BF077E64F5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="HAF97B2EAE36541168BE713A289C45C33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing information streams, if any, that may be used to assess the reliance by the Department of Defense on high-risk foreign suppliers of drugs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBA56C92326E64C94B2F1BAD54C1CF504" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vulnerabilities in the drug supply chains of the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2DCCDB7BCF3415D997DB89C022B1608"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations to address—</text>
<clause id="HCCAE1F5EA3C4468D97368C16B5A05495"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information gaps identified under paragraph (2); and </text></clause> <clause id="HF629916AD32A4E6D9071E2A89A59C9EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any risks related to such reliance on foreign suppliers. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCDAA04D3385C4E07A3E948AF1FF5E5C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Risk management for Department of Defense pharmaceutical supply chain</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Defense Health Agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2B056B7DF6464FBCA16AA3876B2F41AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than one year after the issuance of the guidance required by subsection (a)(1), develop and publish implementing guidance for risk management for the Department of Defense supply chain for pharmaceuticals; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF1BE0B7EDBB943429B0EBFFC94C3EAD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a working group—</text> <subparagraph id="H7385756F8CAD488785D08D1E659E5308"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assess risks to the pharmaceutical supply chain; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H299428A0249649E0A8CC2A5FA01D79B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify the pharmaceuticals most critical to beneficiary care at military treatment facilities; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAC1D82EFA6C4901A4DF526F535D9F69"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish policies for allocating scarce pharmaceutical resources in case of a supply disruption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7BE75173916946BAB52A95DA0F822DA6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsiveness testing of Defense Logistics Agency pharmaceutical contracts</header><text>The Director of the Defense Logistics Agency shall modify Defense Logistics Agency Instructions 5025.03 and 3110.01—</text> <paragraph id="H482517C699DC49039A652AAEB3A44A18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require Defense Logistics Agency Troop Support to coordinate annually with customers in the military departments to conduct responsiveness testing of the Defense Logistics Agency’s contingency contracts for pharmaceuticals; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3BA091997277487893D290BD9FDABE65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to include the results of that testing, as reported by customers in the military departments, in the annual reports of the Warstopper Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

