<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5953F7B8729445BABCA9548066D292D9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8445 IH: LGBTQI+ and Women’s History Education Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8445</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220720">July 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Director of the National Museum of American History of the Smithsonian Institution to support LGBTQI+ history and women’s history education programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDBA0A5CE0714974AD26D39ABC0DF8EE" style="OLC"><section id="HBA69726BB3624D939964885AFD827221" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>LGBTQI+ and Women’s History Education Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEE13D58E0B164A9994FE4335FC8A74E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H44A1E5D9A6F24F34BA848BDF61F44B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the New-York Historical Society Museum &amp; Library, only 13 percent of named historical figures in textbooks across the United States are women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F027B4C28D4CBC8CC1592EE7EF0AC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2017, the National Women’s History Museum analyzed elementary and secondary education standards in social studies for all 50 States and the District of Columbia and found that approximately 1 woman was mentioned for every 3 men in these standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77BA332E1308432F869CB3640836B26D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Museum also found that 53 percent of the mentions of women’s history were included within the context of domestic roles, as opposed to the 20 percent that were included within the context of voting rights and suffrage and 2 percent that were included within the context of being in the workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B5E859D4C8D44859C4D6CC9A165EB8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Countless studies show that when youth feel seen and affirmed in their curricula, they experience improved academic engagement and achievement. In research the National Women’s Law Center conducted in partnership with Latina girls in 2019, the girls reported that when they feel represented in their curricula, they feel a powerful sense of belonging and an emphasized identity of resilience.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H299A85594EB64131A24B2B1CB25894CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the National Women’s History Alliance, only 3 States (Illinois, Florida, and Louisiana) have mandated that women’s history be taught in elementary, middle, and high schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF61EEA8676D842DCBA99B444EBA11AE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to GLSEN, only 7 States (California, Colorado, Connecticut, Illinois, Nevada, New Jersey, and Oregon) have passed legislation in support of an LGBTQI+ inclusive curriculum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56D9604FF1404A03A6DD3AC1345E7CCE"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Museum of disABILITY History, as of 2014, 24 States had established disability awareness curriculum for public schools or were in the process of passing legislation to do so. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA97939A31E148C888CA6812480A9D47"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In March 2022, Governor Ron DeSantis of Florida signed HB 1557 into law. Commonly known as the <quote>Don’t Say Gay or Trans</quote> legislation, this law prevents teachers from administering instruction on sexual orientation and gender identity in kindergarten through third grade.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD7891323BA4E4A836CF849C93C006D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>GLSEN reports that 9 other States in addition to Florida (Alabama, Arizona, Idaho, Iowa, Mississippi, Oklahoma, New Hampshire, Tennessee, and Texas) have recently passed curriculum censorship laws that prohibit honest teaching about race, gender, or LGBTQI+ communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1C856E217C54B3594D58041E2408416"><enum>(10)</enum><text>According to the African American Policy Forum, at least 16 States have passed racial and gender equity curriculum prohibitions, and 15 other States are considering them.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6BA8AF4941742DFAF36C1B25045A670"><enum>(11)</enum><text>According to Education Week, at least 15 States are considering nearly 30 bills that would affect discussions or interactions with LGBTQI+ youth in schools during the 2021–22 legislative session.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF654B933E95C4CBF9B290830738E05AD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to GLSEN, 4 States (Louisiana, Mississippi, Oklahoma, and Texas) have <quote>no promo homo</quote> laws in place that prevent positive and affirming representations of LGBTQI+ identities in schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B166911A77C4F15AD0B267625B46241"><enum>(13)</enum><text>LGBTQI+ youth already experience high rates of mistreatment in schools:</text><subparagraph id="HFC7DCC5F7AE74FC7920ADF42AD23E9AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>According to GLSEN’s 2019 National School Climate Survey, over 80 percent of LGBTQI+ students ages 13 to 21 report being verbally harassed during any given school year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33EAD88FD6014B09A0A1497943D84BD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>According to the National Center for Transgender Equality’s 2015 U.S. Transgender Survey, 77 percent of transgender K–12 students experienced anti-transgender mistreatment, including verbal harassment, and physical or sexual assault.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF81AB9F9A6A4F1CBB6582EB7D45D647"><enum>(C)</enum><text>According to a 2021 survey, 45 percent of intersex students reported experiencing gender-based harassment or discrimination from teachers or faculty during the 2021 school year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H510C6686FEAD44B69EDDAB25812EE0DF"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Nationally, only 19.4 percent of respondents to GLSEN’s 2019 National School Climate Survey said they had been taught any positive representations of LGBTQI+ people, history, or events in their schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50BC94DCFCD2434A8B770B26F8C2FDB3"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Results from GLSEN’s 2019 National School Climate Survey also indicate that, compared to students in schools without an LGBTQI+-inclusive curriculum, LGBTQI+ students in schools with an LGBTQI+-inclusive curriculum were less likely to—</text><subparagraph id="H2388E865070142F2990A5CADF7A19C2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hear homophobic slurs or negative remarks about transgender people often or frequently;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0A5B0EEDD30443BA6EC5F2CEA26EDC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>feel unsafe because of their sexuality or gender identity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF5F1E398494CF69EA07B189FFB63CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>miss school because they felt unsafe or uncomfortable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00F77F16A7454BA280C936D18AC11B78"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Women and LGBTQI+ people—including those of color and those with disabilities—have been and continue to be powerful agents of change in United States history. For example:</text><subparagraph id="HD816A84D3DE14186B4773CE20DA11984"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Black and brown transgender women, including Marsha P. Johnson, Miss Major Griffin-Gracy, Sylvia Rivera, and Stormé DeLarverie were prominent leaders and participants of the 1969 protests against unjust police raids of the New York City gay bar, the Stonewall Inn, that ignited the national movement for LGBTQI+ justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1524466795A4581A30F97E520A185E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Dr. Margaret Chung, a queer Chinese American woman, advocated for Chinese Americans’ and women’s right to vote at a time when women, particularly women of color, were denied that right.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E8D13E476944D729933D92D6D7450D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Judith Ellen <quote>Judy</quote> Heumann is an internationally recognized disability rights advocate who played a leading role in the development and implementation of major legislation, including the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Americans with Disabilities Act, and the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADE42301DE9A4E3D92E646D661D88534"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Alice Wong is a queer disabled activist and the founder and director of the Disability Visibility Project who served on the National Council on Disability.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC07D152A457A4D7A80415C6EC05E5DC7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Ruby Bridges, a Black civil rights activist, pioneered the school desegregation movement and was among the first Black students to integrate schools in the South at the age of six. Ruby’s story, particularly as it was memorialized in her children’s book, Ruby Bridges Goes to School: My True Story, continues to inspire girls across the country but was also one of the histories specifically targeted for censorship in States prohibiting honest teachings about race.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H506820E68ECC42EF8764ACAACE42C799"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discrimination on the basis of sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity) compounds with discrimination on the basis of other identities, such as race, national identity, religious background, or disability. Within marginalized groups, compounding layers of discrimination across intersectional identities often results in the most marginalized members of a group being silenced or left out of historical narratives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D21FCD16C0748E7BD857429CBBB317C"><enum>(18)</enum><text>All women, LGBTQI+ people, and those living at the intersection of those identities, deserve to be represented in classrooms across the country in an accurate, unbiased, intersectional, and inclusive manner.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H836BAA19740E471F83DA801786AE6596"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H1B84BEE076684648AE5ECAFAAE65F916"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00C71910C55F4986B06C7133BB98AA51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusive educational approach</header><text>The term <term>inclusive educational approach</term> means a teaching approach that acknowledges, includes, and affirms experiences of people who are Black, Indigenous, and people of color (<quote>BIPOC</quote>), people with disabilities, LGBTQI+ people, and all marginalized communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD86089DE06914694AD3EAEC0FA162167"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intersectional educational approach</header><text>The term <term>intersectional educational approach</term> means a teaching approach that acknowledges, includes, and affirms the unique and compounded forms of discrimination experienced by those who live at the intersection of two or more oppressed identities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34A23CFD319A428AB0F0828D86762552"><enum>(4)</enum><header>LGBTQI+</header><text>The term <term>LGBTQI+</term> means sexual and gender minority populations, as defined by the Sexual and Gender Minority Research Office of the National Institutes of Health, including individuals who are lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, nonbinary, Two-Spirit, and intersex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E06B9C9336648AABB76D8F3EF494914"><enum>(5)</enum><header>LGBTQI+ history education</header><text>The term <term>LGBTQI+ history education</term> means culturally relevant (to the extent practicable), unbiased, non-discriminatory, and accurate education about the roles and contributions of LGBTQI+ individuals in order to promote representation and visibility and combat prejudice, inclusive of multiple identities within LGBTQI+ populations, including transgender, nonbinary, gender non-conforming, Two-Spirit, and intersex individuals, which have historically been marginalized within the larger LGBTQI+ population.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC60EFC66C6844E109CE4CAEA0BD0BB26"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Women’s history education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>women’s history education</term> means culturally relevant (to the extent practicable), unbiased, non-discriminatory, and accurate education about the roles and contributions of women, with a specific focus on non-domestic roles, in order to promote representation and visibility and combat prejudice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C54E670AF14C5E881CE7BF4FA2436F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Culturally relevant</header><text>The term <term>culturally relevant</term> means, with respect to education, education that is—</text><subparagraph id="HA1083EE8FDAB44E8A69F93BB10B53BD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>available in multiple languages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09CCACE11E3441EFB70F61FEC015EB33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consistent with census data and demographics of the area in which the education will be provided.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDDC856066F945AD8E8197CDD2E28B91"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Museum of American History of the Smithsonian Institution.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9F1FDAB4489247D7B60B3DA16BAE0BE2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Program authorized</header><subsection id="HB9F6D1FA5B184BBE9C8938906B567D81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H65A128F08C174D7FAD76A916D68E899C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in accordance with any program of the National Museum of American History of the Smithsonian Institution established before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act, shall use funds appropriated under <internal-xref idref="HB9F6D1FA5B184BBE9C8938906B567D81" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to carry out the following activities: </text><paragraph id="H508F225928AE424A8ED06C24A3179CB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and national dissemination of accurate, relevant, and accessible national resources for classrooms to administer LGBTQI+ and women’s history education in an inclusive and intersectional approach, which shall include digital resources and may include other types of resources, such as print resources and traveling exhibitions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4D1CD8268242629279E5ED95E8FA10"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development, national dissemination, and implementation of principles of sound pedagogy for administering LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB79C005E235A479FBF3A5DC284D68D04"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of professional development services to administer LGBTQI+ and women’s history education, such as through—</text><subparagraph id="H0609CE59052D4D919449AFCDB8D11656"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local, regional, and national workshops;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2C80C0354FF428091C5F966D11B7135"><enum>(B)</enum><text>teacher trainings or engagement in conjunction with LGBTQI+ and women’s history education centers and other appropriate partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3164316735FE4A4B94ED9A81378F5BAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engagement with— </text><clause id="H4BF177E24EB7443687F4465F1D0F0932"><enum>(i)</enum><text>local educational agencies;</text></clause><clause id="HAA3B031F77E54F13B0FE2B56F5AE9428"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State education agencies; </text></clause><clause id="H1705EA79A6634725B565FA0EB97A1679"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>schools that are independent of any local educational agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HD928FA22013244AA9EF0731D82A0E751"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>school-based extracurricular meetings or organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7807CF0140B44FEAEF07C36CDC83AA3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>development, operation, and expansion of a teacher fellowship program to cultivate and support leaders in LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64578E33A33B4327912F78F6B61C5246"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engagement with State and local education leaders to encourage the adoption of resources supported under this Act into curricula across diverse disciplines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FAED8441C4F4180AB41C3C6E124FED4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through an intersectional and inclusive approach, convening experts, providing opportunities for discourse, and engaging with the public through programming, educational resources, and social media with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF48F630478CF4108B8F4BA4C083D10DD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through an intersectional and inclusive approach, increasing resource capacity, technical support, and content creation to engage various audiences in person and via online platforms with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6650F673DE384466BC6A0FA838B9BA16"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Creating, expanding, and disseminating scholarly work through research, curricula, in-house and traveling exhibitions, publications, and programming with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H839F672F912146C08890E62031F767DC"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing language translation of the work of the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of American History, including scholarly work, research, traveling exhibitions, publications, programming, pamphlets, and other information distributed about activities funded under this Act with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E16C775B7742B48996D1E9856F04B8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expanding the collection acquisition and collection access processes, including staffing, conservation, processing, and digitization with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C00B5ECDD64E0FB626A8663E4A9F23"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Creating, developing, implementing, replicating, or taking to scale entrepreneurial, evidence-based, field-initiated innovations for museum improvement with respect to LGBTQI+ and women’s history education, and evaluating rigorously such innovations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5799E4147A104E01885B57F5C9C874A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Online LGBTQI+ and women’s history education resources</header><paragraph id="HFAE79F752F764E48A63633A4866DA91B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the activities described under <internal-xref idref="H65A128F08C174D7FAD76A916D68E899C" legis-path="4.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, the Director shall use the funds appropriated under <internal-xref idref="HB9F6D1FA5B184BBE9C8938906B567D81" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to develop and maintain on the website of the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of American History content designated for educators, students, and families to improve their awareness and understanding of LGBTQI+ and women’s history education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98B5887BA83848C4BCFAD28F1D911E8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall use such funds to distribute information about the activities funded under this Act through the website of the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of American History, and shall respond to inquiries for supplementary information concerning such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H404AD99E77AA45C8A098D584A8EB213F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Continuation of activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of American History is engaged in an activity described in <internal-xref idref="H65A128F08C174D7FAD76A916D68E899C" legis-path="4.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> or this subsection on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall use the funds appropriated under <internal-xref idref="HB9F6D1FA5B184BBE9C8938906B567D81" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to continue that activity. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE14120F261BC4950948B210BE532A354"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual report</header><subsection id="H21D5C8E814C94230904FC69A073AA4C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 1 of each year, the Director shall submit to the Congress and make available to the public a report describing how the funds made available under this Act have been used—</text><paragraph id="HE26F258CE569448194DD61BD94526C2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create and promote educational activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37E12AE72FAE4F9298D2CC48172CB258"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to otherwise carry out this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69A558253B2441608286CB3BDA25B7A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date on which funding is first distributed under this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director or the Director’s designee shall brief the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate on the programs and activities carried out under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H92E5414C72FC47F7804DF534C7C7AE89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) shall cease to be effective on September 30, 2027.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

