<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H59F08E40C04D41AD83159C1C6B8E4CCC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>112 HR 6447 IH: Financial Accountability for Uniquely Compensated Individuals Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6447</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001054">Mr. Carl</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the STOCK Act to require the public availability of financial disclosure forms of certain special consultants and information relating to certain confidential filers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Accountability for Uniquely Compensated Individuals Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAUCI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id228312F4C7344EDF9A4D474B485805E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public availability of financial disclosure forms of certain special consultants and information relating to certain confidential filers</header><subsection id="id1B391AB701C7483C87D14F7A111EA270"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11(b)(1) of the STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/105">Public Law 112–105</external-xref>; 5 U.S.C. App. 105 note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idc8199ecfd1994484801b125e9d50b928"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, through databases maintained on the official website of the Office of Government Ethics</quote> after <quote>enable</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73ed77fca50544758e25ace58cdcabe8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the undesignated matter following subparagraph (B); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78c6afa3db24496295e96ffa4e8a7275"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)— </text><subparagraph id="id4AA730A15413459CB7B2040AB543274F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in each of clauses (i) and (iii), by striking the comma at the end of the clause and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6230C91B722648B9AEDF60BC96F89298" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by inserting <quote>any officer or employee in the executive branch (including a special Government employee (as defined in section 202 of title 18, United States Code) and any special consultant appointed under section 207(f) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/209">42 U.S.C. 209(f)</external-xref>)) whose annual rate of pay is equal to or greater than the annual rate of pay for a Member of Congress under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>),</quote> before <quote>and any officer</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36091CCB3F8A42B7B485DAD121A53649"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>, and</quote> at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7E4CB80C43594F6DB15CA05068B80711"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9A2939CBC7BD41BDA5F005AF3F26AF21"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ED975A102CA4B97B44F08BB25046012"><clause id="idFA4A52302262430A88F8FED69324FA41"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a list of the name, position, and salary of each individual whose annual rate of pay is equal to or greater than the annual rate of pay for a Member of Congress under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) that filed a confidential financial disclosure report under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /107">section 107(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.), including a description of the specific type of information included in the financial disclosure report filed by the individual.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21B186A452614C11A0A49829B69E519F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable deadlines</header><text>The Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall publish on the public website of the Office of Government Ethics any information with respect to which public access is required by an amendment made by subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="id826b35203d35480b8cda395591da0c3f"><enum>(1)</enum><text> not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of information required for calendar year 2020;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9A312E09A02341BE8CF37A5F54AD4742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of information required for each of calendar years 2017 through 2019; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3F34FCE0009B4743B63240E5BE699770"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of information required for each of calendar years 2014 through 2016; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEDD5B9AEC69D40E5BFD00F32E765B4C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not later than May 15, 2022, in the case of information required for calendar year 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9812FAD5A1624951BC2F207353AA05A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the financial disclosure is filed, in the case of information required by an amendment made by subsection (a)(3)(B) for calendar year 2022 and each calendar year thereafter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id661F91B5D90D48BFAD666F72362D42D5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>not later than May 15 of the subsequent calendar year, in the case of information required by an amendment made by subsection (a)(3)(E) for calendar year 2022 and each calendar year thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

