<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H02A048DB0E4D429F93B5910FDECE7F18" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6827 RH: Securing the Checkpoint Property Screening System (S-CPSS) Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 254</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6827</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–337]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize appropriations to accelerate the procurement and deployment of computed tomography equipment to enhance detection capabilities for carry-on baggage, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8E5244C85464FA98EE7D18BB6F41CFF" style="OLC"><section id="HA3980D20DF3E4057B4C1B7E96774049E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing the Checkpoint Property Screening System (S-CPSS) Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H67517B00AEA146BEA140AA6C0C949BB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procurement and deployment efforts of computed tomography equipment at airport checkpoints</header><subsection id="H9E3A46BB673D47E89F565FED18D89AB9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>TSA briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Administrator shall brief the appropriate congressional committees regarding planned procurement and deployment efforts of computed tomography equipment at airport checkpoints through the Checkpoint Property Screening System program to enhance detection capabilities for carry-on baggage. Such briefing shall include information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H207C4DF85CFA492682EF7C039F3FC1BB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount of computed tomography equipment TSA could procure under the authorization of appropriations in each of fiscal years 2022, 2023, 2024, 2025, and 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7801857B2C3748FAA988C5DB5251E91A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of computed tomography equipment TSA could deploy in each of such fiscal years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9561FEDD1CD4401EB58CD1AFE09F2395" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A procurement and deployment plan, together with a funding and execution plan, to complete the deployment of computed tomography equipment, disaggregated by all base, mid, and full sized units of such equipment, at airport checkpoints by not later than September 30, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03CB5427B5BF42F4850CB89212B173C1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether additional funding will be necessary in fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H010BE0CD72DD40A497FCD045DD47B3A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan for maximizing competition and innovation within the Checkpoint Property Screening System program, including by supporting the participation of small businesses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91DF207DB5244AFEB4AB599BBE9DAC83"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to set aside funds for small businesses within the Checkpoint Property Screening System program, to the extent practicable, as determined by the Administrator, or if not practicable a description of challenges in doing so.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5D27951A94419B9937359691873E6F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of how each award made under the Checkpoint Property Screening System program within the immediately preceding year satisfies Department of Homeland Security and TSA operational requirements, including requirements for detection, safety, cybersecurity, interoperability, availability, and throughput, as well as other relevant standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51076E14AC974DEE91813428D2CB670A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A description of how each award made under the Checkpoint Property Screening System program within the immediately preceding year satisfies Department of Homeland Security and TSA requirements for testing and evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5635C9B3511F428EB014F8FE21144EA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award-Specific briefings</header><text>If TSA intends to make an award to a system that does not satisfy the Checkpoint Property Screening System program key performance parameters, the Administrator shall brief the appropriate congressional committees at least two weeks prior to any such award regarding why such award is necessary and in the best interest of national security and good government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED3AA2AD23AB4F0F94C0D98E0AC3EFA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HCDBD01182F4A46B58F24DE3AC4F3C730" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,641,400,000 to TSA for procurement and deployment of computed tomography equipment at airport checkpoints through the Checkpoint Property Screening System program to enhance detection capabilities for carry-on baggage as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HEF5AD9BD4E4847A3896E991623ED6270" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$257,000,000 for fiscal year 2022.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4B25B2540594363ADF047314C1ED333" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$336,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DDADBB42BD44810A51A1854CFDE1854" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$343,000,000 for fiscal year 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H818D8CDADA1B4E318F0638A7B44124A6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$350,000,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H173AF923E2B44D1F9C19E8CB55B51A96" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$355,400,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H181E71C8D83E4F2FB04179B6854E115D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small business research and development</header><subparagraph id="HD66F396B3DF842DFB53C73ABD807E73D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to funds authorized to be appropriated in accordance with paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated $82,077,000 to TSA to provide to small businesses in support of research and development of technologies under consideration for the Checkpoint Property Screening System program, as follows:</text><clause id="HE5258FEA28C4497A806BF29A7E8C3DD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$12,850,000 for fiscal year 2022.</text></clause><clause id="H305CD91B28284CD289CD89ACEF3C71C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$16,800,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></clause><clause id="H6F7A43EB9BF64FCC8C414E73FACD1AC6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$17,150,000 for fiscal year 2024.</text></clause><clause id="H7D0BFC6F5086473593EAE6A34490784D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>$17,500,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></clause><clause id="H4F2C4F6A69114D048E0AB3CD92285A35"><enum>(v)</enum><text>$17,777,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63EFE045FC6F410E9164816E5199A873"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive funding under subparagraph (A), a small business referred to in such subparagraph shall demonstrate an ability to produce technologies supporting the advancement of checkpoint security screening, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H387BD7680F8744D080399EF581A54CB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA911F76DC32406BA8A08162ABAFBDD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB00A6CC624A24D798023E086758979B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32094D937D3A49EAB3F7CF5CF0ABC2CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4E975327DC114B33A7D715680A0F4A52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DAB79FE63164101815AE6A3B3B371F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE90D48F2F379435FA1CCB11C36552641"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H376DB3ECFD6741579C77CDE949173613"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77FEC1388A004DE4B655151BD762B711"><enum>(3)</enum><header>TSA</header><text>The term <quote>TSA</quote> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

