<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDAADA7F17904C56AFFCCADA5AA44FEB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6773 IH: Protecting Federal Funds from Human Trafficking and Smuggling Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6773</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000479">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001084">Ms. Herrell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to require the disclosure of violations of Federal law with respect to human trafficking or alien smuggling, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA05731F8B5948798631512D2840BFFA" style="OLC"><section id="HBFC6C21138D94578848BA556B75EC06B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Federal Funds from Human Trafficking and Smuggling Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H62765A9941B04B82A19A67CEAFA7F9FE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory disclosures of human trafficking and alien smuggling</header><subsection id="HCC81A1BBCC2A4BCC811BECEBCEB4D025"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on award of Federal funds</header><paragraph id="H248A9D4A466940C1A0DA9EBB895AE68D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Future recipients</header><text>Beginning not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may be awarded to a non-profit entity unless such entity submits to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a certification that the entity is in compliance with Federal law with respect to human trafficking, alien smuggling, fraud, bribery, or gratuity and has not been convicted of an offense under section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A804123A4044FBD80E388F917789809"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current and prior recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, each non-profit entity that is in receipt of awarded Federal funds as of the date of the enactment of this Act, or was awarded Federal funds prior to January 1, 2021, shall submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a certification that the entity is in compliance with Federal law with respect to human trafficking, alien smuggling, fraud, bribery, or gratuity and has not been convicted of an offense under section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>). If the entity does not submit the certification, or is determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to have violated section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>), the entity shall repay any such funds awarded.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F5B62627BFE4EF4B534202A2B7C5210"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of tax exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/503">Section 503</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H280D7F29BDEC482782477851C074D048" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HC6D75F6262C84D65982B5281C090FE15"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Denial of exemption for not meeting certain certification requirement</header><paragraph id="HB5D370419C984B41A5B5EBA04882E938"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An organization described in section 501(c) shall not be exempt from taxation under section 501(a) if such organization does not submit the certification required pursuant to section 2(a) of the <quote><short-title>Protecting Federal Funds from Human Trafficking and Smuggling Act of 2022</short-title></quote>, or is determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to have violated section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ABF4452E2684BF69B392036E02DCF25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Re-application for exemption</header><text>Not sooner than one year after the date on which an organization described in section 501(c) is not exempt pursuant to paragraph (1), such organization may reapply to be exempt from taxation under section 501(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCB1274337CC3481495AC48E9F0355D4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text><paragraph id="HF79CC576C4CE4DF7A9D0681446F71564"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a written strategy and best practices guide for non-profit entities to ensure they are in compliance with Federal law, including how to detect, deter, and report human trafficking and alien smuggling; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA2B687EF1043C28732A8F8F4CE9A43"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish on the internet website of the Department of Homeland Security information on violations of any non-profit entity as it pertains to compliance with State and Federal laws with respect to human trafficking, and alien smuggling; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CC7CFF011A146CD9CBE937D7F754264"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a written strategy to improve cooperation with non-profit entities, State, and Federal law enforcement agencies with respect to improving cooperation on deterring, detecting, reporting, and removing aliens.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H792D4E0020664AC483D95AD914A3CED7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report by Comptroller General</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to Congress on each violation by a non-profit entity to certify under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H874476A92B144628A40FCBE980F0F6DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subsection (a) shall apply to any non-profit entity awarded Federal funding, including a non-profit entity who has an agreement, contract, award, or relationship with the Federal Government on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

