<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2242F17FB3140318067C462778AE16D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6667 IH: Fresh Start Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permit expungement of records of certain nonviolent criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H072D519F8B114EBE9CD2AE95E77144F7" style="OLC"><section id="H2B5122EB3E394EF2A36075D403FC9DC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fresh Start Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8DD649D59D704DBA8A233B31E12F2E60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expungement of criminal records for certain nonviolent offenders</header><subsection id="H483E081F075C49BEA525A0A644641E26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/229">Chapter 229</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after subchapter D the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block id="HBC5F800D28564FAE87803591CC937F5D" style="USC"><subchapter id="H75A520D29BA54584B556A9C3B5F49912"><enum>E</enum><header>Expungement</header><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HBC5F800D28564FAE87803591CC937F5D" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEF636CD75424435CB1DD78798469C68A" level="section">3641. Expungement of certain criminal records in limited circumstances. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2BC0EDB265E3401F81489A6A21C13089" level="section">3642. Requirements for expungement. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE36D434EFDB2444AB70CEBC59FED20D6" level="section">3643. Procedure for expungement. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H963C5694D7324317A22DFD652C11A219" level="section">3644. Effect of expungement. </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H923C2E1C37454676BF2170A2F5F6EF4E" level="section">3645. Disclosure of expunged records. </toc-entry></toc><section id="HEF636CD75424435CB1DD78798469C68A"><enum>3641.</enum><header>Expungement of certain criminal records in limited circumstances</header><subsection id="H1D9FF132D8BE4A809BCCAA62BAA161B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any eligible individual convicted of a nonviolent offense may file a petition under this subchapter for expungement with regard to that nonviolent offense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A265CEA5D5C490BA9223D0BC8F61A8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of nonviolent offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subchapter, the term <term>nonviolent offense</term> means any offense under this title or under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/801">8 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>) that is not a crime of violence.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9FCCA5D2BAE84E60AFBB2289ABDB398A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of crime of violence</header><text>In this subchapter, the term <quote>crime of violence</quote> means an offense, punishable by one year or more in the prison, that—</text><paragraph id="H8075E2C5A26840328F05B0C55D71CB1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against the person or property of another; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD91474A82988410AA13DB33F63C86EC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involves the unlawful possession, sale, transfer, or use of a firearm, explosive, or other deadly weapon, or the attempt thereof; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H432C1FA5A3544A3BA3AD7E695A22757E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">causes the petitioner to be required to register under the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20901">34 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2BC0EDB265E3401F81489A6A21C13089"><enum>3642.</enum><header>Requirements for expungement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An individual is eligible for expungement under this subchapter if that individual—</text><paragraph id="H3068758EB05542B288F6EEB2B14975E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the time of filing, had never been convicted of any criminal offense other than nonviolent offenses committed in a single criminal episode that includes the offense for which expungement is sought; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FD2C6BF12744A8190462552334BD750"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has fulfilled the requirements of the sentence of the court in which the individual was convicted of that nonviolent offense, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCBBE208E7B01405F91B5EC79B6886256"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paying, or consistently fulfilling obligations of a payment plan for, all applicable fines, restitutions, or assessments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82041746BDAB4AB3ACB3122FE588BE48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>completion of any term of imprisonment or period of probation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8730E5E1FABD42B09681C1AA65BCA206"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meeting all conditions of supervised release; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE507CA45066A40BE9488FA97CA665250"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if so required by the terms of the sentence, remaining free from dependency on or abuse of alcohol or a controlled substance for a period of not less than 1 year.</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">If extenuating circumstances prevent an individual from fulfilling the requirements of the sentence, as required under paragraph (2), the court, in its discretion, may waive a portion of such requirement. </continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HE36D434EFDB2444AB70CEBC59FED20D6"><enum>3643.</enum><header>Procedure for expungement</header><subsection id="HBBF16A2E25FC4925942D7AA86AE74FB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A petition for expungement may be filed only in the court in which the petitioner was convicted of the nonviolent offense for which expungement is sought. The clerk of the court shall serve that petition on the United States Attorney for that district. Except as provided under subsection (e), not later than 60 days after service of such petition, the United States Attorney may submit recommendations to the court and provide a copy of those recommendations to the petitioner.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5242335CC0F04FF1AE618BFEC4CE3F55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of counsel</header><text>The court shall appoint counsel upon the request of an indigent petitioner to represent the petitioner in proceedings under this subchapter, including the preparation of a petition or subsequent petition under this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H078E0ADCC7AE4BBF8FEA283549751DB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of evidence</header><text>The petitioner and the Government may file with the court evidence relating to the petition.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF224ED3FC99F432D8892B0B836C67FDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Basis for decision</header><text>In making a decision on the petition, the court shall consider all evidence and weigh the interests of the petitioner, the best interests of justice, and public safety.</text></subsection><subsection id="H71EB3BC0848A477290C0618BE66EC267"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subsequent petition</header><text>If the court denies the petition, the petitioner may not file another such petition until the date that is 2 years after the date of such denial.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9B7CE49D314E40DFA80647C80A61CD8F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mandatory grant of petition</header><paragraph id="H156BDB77720B47B89C06C6022691A926"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the court shall grant the petition of an eligible petitioner who files the petition on a date that is not earlier than the date that is 7 years after the date on which the petitioner has fulfilled the requirements of the sentence, as described in section 3642(2). The United States Attorney may not submit recommendations under subsection (a) with regard to that petition.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H690B5AFF7B574835934E536F54374CB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall not grant under this subsection the petition of a petitioner who has committed any offense under this title that caused a victim or victims to sustain a loss of $25,000 or more.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9BA7C1C148F48D6BDAE44147F236518"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Discretionary grant of petition</header><paragraph id="H67A367CDBEA9441D8FBD97AAAF5E553A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the court shall grant the petition of an eligible petitioner who files the petition on a date that is not earlier than the date that is 1 year after the date on which the petitioner has fulfilled the requirements of the sentence, as described in section 3642(2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84D94A708D73495583530175D2F3CAEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The court shall not grant under this subsection the petition of a petitioner who has committed any offense under this title that caused a victim or victims to sustain a loss of $250,000 or more. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6531111EF8514A82A1021DE59AAB44AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification of expungement</header><text>Not later than 7 days after granting an expungement petition, in order to facilitate the timely update of relevant records, the court shall send a copy of the petition and final order to—</text><subparagraph id="H9D8F3C2FA2BE4330B296CAE97D0BAF11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Attorney General of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC379545881B44066911E8E1B869CCCC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the chief law enforcement officer of the State in which the crime was committed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9A8E1B610245D19434163F37CDA7EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the chief law enforcement officer of the State in which the petitioner resides; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D244E8F51D64B81A74518E869EEA485"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any local law enforcement agency that serves the jurisdiction in which the crime was committed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2841954627AA4168A3BBEDE24B05BBBE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any local law enforcement agency that serves the jurisdiction in which petitioner resides.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H963C5694D7324317A22DFD652C11A219"><enum>3644.</enum><header>Effect of expungement</header><subsection id="HA72767CC036440C7AE44FFBEA13EB868"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An order granting expungement under this subchapter shall restore the individual concerned, in the contemplation of the law, to the status such individual occupied before the arrest or institution of criminal proceedings for the nonviolent offense that was the subject of the expungement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F63FB993F47443594BC8E945EDEB5A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sentencing</header><text>In determining an appropriate sentence for unrelated subsequent criminal conduct, a court of the United States shall not consider an expunged criminal conviction for the purposes of determining the appropriate sentencing range pursuant to the United States Sentencing Guidelines, or to sentence a person outside of that sentencing range.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2209D69C732F4A61B9C4B995AE9395E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No disqualification; statements</header><text>An individual whose petition under this subchapter is granted shall not be required to divulge information pertaining to the nonviolent offense with regard to which expungement was granted, nor shall such individual be held under any provision of law guilty of perjury, false answering, or making a false statement by reason of the failure of the individual to recite or acknowledge such arrest or institution of criminal proceedings, or results thereof, in response to an inquiry made of the individual for any purpose. The fact that such individual has been convicted of the nonviolent offense concerned shall not operate as a disqualification of such individual to pursue or engage in any lawful activity, occupation, or profession.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA10C31823A0C4D2EA5331E7C042DB215"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Records expunged</header><text>Except as provided under section 3645, on the grant of a petition under this subchapter, the following shall be expunged:</text><paragraph id="H7DE3D5576EA346E7A1C93F43D77F3F59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any official record relating to the arrest of the petitioner, the institution of criminal proceedings against the petitioner, or the results thereof (including conviction) for the nonviolent offense with regard to which expungement is sought.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F9379FC945F474DB09FFA83565D5EDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any official record to the arrest of the petitioner, the institution of criminal proceedings against the petitioner, or the results thereof (including conviction) for the nonviolent offense with regard to which expungement is sought.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22C0EBD7A67F4DEAA2E7CB6799B1DE21"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The Attorney General may make rules providing for exceptions to subsection (d) as the Attorney General determines necessary to serve the interests of justice and public safety.</text></subsection></section><section id="H923C2E1C37454676BF2170A2F5F6EF4E"><enum>3645.</enum><header>Disclosure of expunged records</header><subsection id="H696F4B9EB5DE4115840023CF7B706CE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Justice Records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall retain an unaltered nonpublic copy of—</text><paragraph id="H9F4EE7D7720640B3BE043CF647B1FB3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any record that is expunged; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F6B6594C1F4E56832AF689D538C3B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any record containing a reference that is expunged.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE39C9C90FBEB48CABB474C3EC2D545F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Law enforcement purposes</header><text>The Attorney General shall maintain a nonpublic index of the records described under subsection (a) containing, for each such record, only the name of, and alphanumeric identifiers that relate to, the individual who is the subject of such record, the word <term>expunged</term>, and the name of the person, agency, office, or department that has custody of the expunged record, and shall not name the offense committed. The index shall be made available only to an entity to which records may be made available under subsection (d) or to any Federal or State law enforcement agency that has custody of such records.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C98464C2D5C41C7AF5CC8BBC821303A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Court records</header><text>The court shall retain an unaltered nonpublic copy of—</text><paragraph id="H0AE6DAA259B44D50A574F9B94A726DA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any record that is expunged; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E3DB57131CC4C398BE48E7CB407ACFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any record containing a reference that is expunged.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AB13F9AC6634C06A81610D6BD0261BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorized disclosures</header><paragraph id="HA937F4B4847C46B2B39FA1B4C7CB32A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), any record described in subsection (a) pertaining to an individual may be made available only—</text><subparagraph id="HD38A24C2877B45BFBB9FDA4336732319"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the petitioner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44CC161FD5C94381B5F582D06D28A795"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to a Federal or State court or Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency, in the case of a criminal investigation or prosecution of an individual or in conducting a background check on an individual who has applied for employment by such court or agency; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35937C495C914AC59C41EF744E5285A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a Federal or State court or Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency for the exclusive purpose of maintaining accurate official records.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF9632A1D08480A82D42137AC260212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized disclosure to individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On application of the petitioner, the record may be available to an individual identified in the petitioner’s application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5867E38D88594968989DA537695E3ECC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Punishment for improper disclosure</header><text>Whoever intentionally makes or attempts to make a disclosure, other than a disclosure authorized under subsection (d), of any record or reference that is expunged under this subchapter, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6FC336A529E64DCA811E90BFF816D659" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/229">chapter 229</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41384D11BCF44F359EC9717C596BD98A" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="section"><toc-enum>E.</toc-enum><level-header bold="on" level="section">Expungement</level-header><target>3641</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8878071360FF4525BA6064BFF8224A8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to individuals convicted of an offense before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

