<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC7C1F910C2FF4AC5A6A41464F0F17842" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9270 IH: No Budget, No Fundraising Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221103">November 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit certain campaign fundraising with respect to Members of Congress, a national congressional campaign committee of a political party, or any affiliated committee of a national congressional campaign committee of a political party during a fiscal year until there is in effect a budget resolution providing for a balanced budget over a 10-year window and each of the regular appropriations bills for the fiscal year has been enacted into law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF6A7ED1B247C4B9687E1B89966EB3E7F" style="OLC"><section id="H193C4721674B4A3D9ED884A99CB2F7F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Budget, No Fundraising Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDDC68588BC194492BA881AE7DA728AA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting certain campaign fundraising until balanced budget resolution is in effect and appropriations bill are enacted</header><subsection id="H5E3C24B5450F4E2D91F60415B9C8B839"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 323 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30125">52 U.S.C. 30125</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBDD05235C8394D7AA1900A12BD23FB14" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEF85B88D10ED4BD9AAF863CE35FCEAEA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibiting certain fundraising until balanced budget resolution is in effect and appropriations bills are enacted</header><paragraph id="H577945FE631147628A4A392CE4682055"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a fiscal year, a Member of Congress (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress), a national congressional campaign committee of a political party, or an affiliated committee of a national congressional campaign committee of a political party may not solicit funds in connection with an election for Federal office until each of the following applies:</text><subparagraph id="H1DAFED3F42224C90ADA0E4D7B35723D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in effect for such fiscal year a concurrent resolution on the budget under which, notwithstanding the exclusion of off-budget items, the excess of total budget authority (including all on- and off-budget authority and net interest costs) over total receipts declines gradually from the fiscal year and each of the 9 succeeding fiscal years such that the total receipts exceed total budget authority not later than the ninth succeeding fiscal year, and in no case later than the last day of fiscal year 2033 (as certified by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39C71D994BB04CBDA9E1CE6ED74DFBE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each of the regular appropriations bills for such fiscal year has been enacted into law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B743E7DEF64B998AB3024D6507ACB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each of the regular appropriations bills for such fiscal year, as enacted, is consistent with the concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBF990EB95249EFAFAB73D6D53C98B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regular appropriation bill defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>regular appropriation bill</term> means any annual appropriation bill which, with respect to the Congress involved, is under the jurisdiction of a single subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives (pursuant to the Rules of the House of Representatives for that Congress) and a single subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate (pursuant to the Standing Rules of the Senate).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6E8946B07FAA4464A90316EA84AAB6B7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by <internal-xref idref="H5E3C24B5450F4E2D91F60415B9C8B839" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2024 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

