<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H376A087942284A3197A1474F4387258E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7426 IH: 21st Century Courts Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220406">April 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for the establishment of a code of conduct for the justices of the Supreme Court of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H965F54E4A4924E589FBBE2893A928F3E" style="OLC"><section id="H0CA69B6A9AEA4B189E8CFC6BB86B3EF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Courts Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H825C5834B1BA4B80A99E636604C3013F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Code of conduct for the Supreme Court of the United States</header><subsection id="H8F732ABA13A14FF688DB4DE46D593C7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">Chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5ECFA26EE67A447EB932D2589A114F45"><section id="H003FEAFD3DAE4B0EB86F43F6D9AF29E2"><enum>365.</enum><header>Codes of conduct</header><subsection id="HE7132CDBD8F94588A59F05996E1361D8"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section—</text><paragraph id="HFBBACFF7FD854A38A213DC55CFF02F36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Supreme Court of the United States shall, after appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment, issue a code of conduct for the justices of the Supreme Court; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA487186CF48B4C7C96CC387D3060A07B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Judicial Conference of the United States shall issue a code of conduct for the judges of the courts of appeals, the district courts (including bankruptcy judges and magistrate judges), and the Court of International Trade.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EC10F62DE8F4E6A8CFB3ECCC12AC74F"><enum>(b)</enum><text>If the Supreme Court of the United States fails to comply with subsection (a), the code of conduct for justices of the Supreme Court shall consist of the Code of Conduct for United States Judges, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2EC1FBEB9ACE46B5B6ABBC1DB8DF4EB5"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference may modify the applicable codes of conduct under this section after giving appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB9196F7BF7CD4633ABB1ECAB17ACC21F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0E2FBF595D9949E7BE10C1E75964F7A3"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H003FEAFD3DAE4B0EB86F43F6D9AF29E2">365. Codes of conduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HA152D184207D4D2CAD960BB8A6C6C385"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disqualification of Federal judges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H97E40E8E8A464FEBB5A9F3976DF2584B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>bankruptcy judge,</quote> after <quote>judge,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E57DA126A44759BDADB174F636F86D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1161897153C349508B1A584D8A16D634"><paragraph id="H52DDB0D9A1B7443F91AA1FECAB0FD72C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Where the justice, judge bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States received, during the 6-year period ending on the date on which the judge was assigned to the proceeding, income, a gift, or reimbursement required to be reported under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /102">section 102</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) from a party to the proceeding, a lawyer in the proceeding, an individual employed in a supervisory capacity by a party or law firm in the proceeding, or an affiliate of a party or law firm in the proceeding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H703CF207A0CF4EE18F0381FA837B7B51"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Where a party to the proceeding, a lawyer in the proceeding, an individual employed in a supervisory capacity by a party or law firm in the proceeding, or an affiliate of a party or law firm in the proceeding made any lobbying contact or spent substantial funds in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB4F01EF1D0546A29A767101E39D4F95"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Where the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States, their spouse, child, or spouse of their child has, during the 6-year period ending on the date on which the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States was assigned to the proceeding—</text><subparagraph id="H6A58CE5A552B49C2AE86E49BF8430B40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received income, a gift, or reimbursement required to be reported under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /102">section 102</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) from, or been employed or volunteered for more than 6 consecutive months in an official supervisory or advisory capacity for a party to the proceeding, a lawyer in the proceeding, or an affiliate of a party or law firm in the proceeding; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEEC36380F1642B782D2BCC4960EC7A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>been employed or volunteered for more than 6 consecutive months in an official supervisory or advisory capacity alongside a lawyer in the proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6521976C7C142859FB3B8EFE742DB15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4A074D0BE6941D0A5ED3F08E0F120D7"><subsection id="H361CD4510B2848F48507A4F633988638"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States shall be informed about—</text><paragraph id="H41C182E47CDC4E718F1C27044561FDD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the personal and fiduciary financial interests of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D2DC4C0C44744B8AE2C9A5AC45C3EB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the personal financial interests of the spouse and minor children residing in the household of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46869C57E3134A6DA7701650F9BE8BDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any interest that could be substantially affected by the outcome of the proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H197AA17CF9674DD58F1C45F19B297B36"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="HD996721270F949AD994A0C8E2A6773F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="H60AE1AC55D1A42F490215E55D247D097"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by inserting <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="H82DB4E4C32A34861AA926EC0BCB6665E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H702C41915ED44637BF4BAB5AB9BE16C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H905CF4777A294D909321EE1699BDFF2C"><paragraph id="HCD05C27C25734CBDB559DAB71457E9F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text><quote>official supervisory or advisory capacity</quote> includes acting as a director, officer, trustee, or any other equivalent position;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF57F90544DC44574A277A76F46A7FD52"><enum>(6)</enum><text><quote>affiliate</quote> means an entity that effectively controls or is controlled by another entity or is associated with another entity under common ownership or control, regardless of tax status or corporate form. Whether an entity is an affiliate of another shall be determined under the totality of the circumstances, including—</text><subparagraph id="H65EDE32666F24FEA9B1EECF8CF2C7F73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the entities share employees, board members, or officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H260ACB0D8FD842818BB03F6253A47E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the entities share facilities or mailing addresses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F064C88D0FB4408B21C971FBD7344FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the entities are related organizations, as defined by the Internal Revenue Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B534ABCFF7443DB91288B589A760E6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any indicia that the 2 entities are alter egos or otherwise effectively the same organization regardless of tax status or corporate form;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AD63F32B0CD44C89351F808EA3DDA55"><enum>(7)</enum><text><quote>substantial funds</quote> means an amount of money that a reasonable person would consider to be significant based on the totality of circumstances, including—</text><subparagraph id="HAEAA788840414243AFAC4EB81F1E158D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proportion of funds spent relative to the revenues or expenditures of the individual or entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF4B81A730A64EF5AAD898BAEB0DAE38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proportion of funds spent relative to other known spending in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50219CFD31B9422DBCB0BD6E89E161D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other objective indicia of the significance of the financial support of the individual or entity for the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF449AD06F91D4622BB12A80036ED4EA7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H260E506B5D664CA691715884EBECFECF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by adding <quote>bankruptcy judge,</quote> after <quote>judge,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD77CC4900C494F6E87F924A78E26A552"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, unless the ground for disqualification arises under paragraph (7) of that subsection</quote> before the period at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7726969E93F04AD9B8E275619637FA80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after the second sentence, by adding <quote>Where the ground for disqualification arises only under subsection (b)(7), waiver may be accepted only if offered by all parties to the proceeding.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B60E7C3BFD4987A15788696B685136"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by inserting <quote>under subsection (b)(4)</quote> after <quote>disqualified</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFE79FC31EAA463790187F42A736532D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0250CA45214141D8880C70D6AABC2F1B"><subsection id="H7ED20986E3864C08BAFFE05FF14553E2"><enum>(g)</enum><text>If a justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge learns that a condition requiring disqualification under this section is present, the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge shall—</text><paragraph id="H22947A06DA0C469A9BBE36BB1B873745"><enum>(1)</enum><text>immediately notify all parties to the proceeding; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H004112E34D884227B31C19B474D7B62B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include the notification required under paragraph (1) in the official record of the proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FDAA62201AB41A4ACD360DD29EAC029"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCD89F52C74B245E5A627A1512C7AC718"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge shall grant or certify to a reviewing panel a timely motion filed by a party to the proceeding that is accompanied by a certificate of good faith and an affidavit alleging facts sufficient to show that disqualification of the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge is required under this section or any other Federal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H8EBC34C2339B44FA887AD9D3A870C412"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A reviewing panel described in paragraph (1) shall be selected at random from judges of the United States who do not sit on the same court as the judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge who is the subject of the motion or as the other members of the reviewing panel. No more than 1 member of the reviewing panel may be a judge of the same judicial circuit as the judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge who is the subject of the motion.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H5AE2294308FC4C5AB9CB6B9315E9C2C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Supreme Court of the United States shall be the reviewing panel for a motion seeking to disqualify a justice.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CB802D1FE7046E481079CB3F7FD3CFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The clerk of the applicable court shall publish timely notice on the website of the court of—</text><paragraph id="HADDD691B9CDE4BC3B217B079A4F68650"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any matter in which a justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States disqualifies is disqualified under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD134AB7C10554029B670CB842B8F5DCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any matter in which the reviewing panel under subsection (h) rules on a motion to disqualify; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BDF3973CA141D783C7E8FCA367C155"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of each reason for the disqualification or ruling, which shall include a specific identification of each circumstance that resulted in disqualification.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H6475E738D83C42D0B0EA641EA2787CF9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conflicts related to amici curiae</header><subsection id="HF1C141BC620342E9BFFB8DB53E0DE8A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception as provided in subsection (b), the Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 of title 28, United States Code, for prohibiting the filing of or striking an amicus brief that would result in the disqualification of a justice, judge, or magistrate judge.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C555FC799EE4F3CBD59E7D464081994"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Supreme Court of the United States shall transmit to Congress—</text><paragraph id="H40531F08E363478EA95B0EBA1758B835"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proposed rules required under subsection (a) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA205F323DB5429DB66AB91DD1152E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any rules in addition to those transmitted under paragraph (1) pursuant to section 2074 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H033EE02A3D5547D3B7AF5F1DB615781D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Amicus disclosure</header><subsection id="H4332B882518D4DE68062300A880C8224"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22AEACFD2EDF4387AF1A5BFDE5DD0C99"><section id="H456B9950C8FD4B89971654815FEE5A42" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1660.</enum><header>Disclosures related to amicus activities</header><subsection id="H23B82450AC154A31B7360614832E4EC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered amicus</term> means any person, including any affiliate of the person, that files an amicus brief in a calendar year in the Supreme Court of the United States or a court of appeals of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7980466A5ECB4AD180C606FBF9F4D3F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><paragraph id="HBB9B66AF21E341A4B6D4F289CECAD896"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any covered amicus that files an amicus brief in the Supreme Court of the United States or a court of appeals of the United States shall list in the amicus brief the name of any person who—</text><subparagraph id="H0D03A014F7BB411584EE45627F34C423"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contributed to the preparation or submission of the amicus brief;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAB284668827432299E46C99E5409668"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contributed not less than 3 percent of the gross annual revenue of the covered amicus for the previous calendar year if the covered amicus is not an individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A3996DBBF654299AC11C54DA3C644B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contributed more than $100,000 to the covered amicus in the previous calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED1E62EFB426401487FCCFF609EC160D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to amounts received by a covered amicus described in paragraph (1) in commercial transactions in the ordinary course of any trade or business conducted by the covered amicus or in the form of investments (other than investments by the principal shareholder in a limited liability corporation) in an organization if the amounts are unrelated to the amicus filing activities of the covered amicus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BBC730B0A9643FCA50CD4D1B06063A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an annual audit to ensure compliance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC758BAFE556D41FBBFA638AD8B8156E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of gifts or travel by covered amici to judges and justices</header><paragraph id="H7BF745D10C524F43AD6EA8AE55A68EA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no covered amicus may make a gift or provide travel to a judge of a court of appeals of the United States, the Chief Justice of the United States, or an associate justice of the Supreme Court of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8ADA98F37284FF09185E31543126BF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement for travel for appearances at accredited law schools</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to reimbursement for travel for an appearance at an accredited law school.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED8CAD32AB5545FFA45B5E6237367605"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Civil fines</header><text>Whoever knowingly fails to comply with any provision of this section shall, upon proof of such knowing violation by a preponderance of the evidence, be subject to a civil fine of not more than $200,000, depending on the extent and gravity of the violation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF29FAB396A8341E79F56E922DD931452"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="H6DB45F3A09734CA382072A3A250AC8D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Constitutional rights</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit or interfere with—</text><subparagraph id="H9F5EE60D3C1744AB9F5E0151EB0FD84B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right to petition the Government for the redress of grievances;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F27FE78574742D8B356DC6279F07E3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right to express a personal opinion; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC188BF401376402F986A1A957F128992"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right of association, protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFDAA0242511490F9F87DDB3179F2032"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of activities</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit, or to authorize any court to prohibit, amicus activities by any person or entity, regardless of whether such person or entity is in compliance with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H079DEEDEBA6B4086A5A60E67FCDE596C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application thereof, is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this section and the application of such provision to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC1FE094EE4734F18A5AEC303B326CB78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE107CF9A65CF46D4BB3A6A5EB1055E43"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H456B9950C8FD4B89971654815FEE5A42">1660. Disclosures related to amicus activities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HDA57ABDC0171467885404A8EF9AEB9B2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Judicial travel</header><subsection id="H2CEBE5A7CE9442298E668068B08F374E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosures regarding travel-Related reimbursements</header><paragraph id="H1B9B30B3F11144388B7516939B78CBB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 102(a)(2)(B) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H8BB87B873CEC4467BB6096A5D47FF576"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>source and a brief</quote> and inserting <quote>source, and a brief</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78AEBAB4B27F4A5EB15C60395BE8B573"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including the value,</quote> before <quote>of reimbursements</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8E63647E07647A2A4681CC3B38010A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>greater and received</quote> and inserting <quote>greater, received</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF94922888FA34F9BB8B0EC72E738CE5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text>Section 103 of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C91C67B940D4FF38D98F695131FBAE1"><subsection id="H097E9939C14E4393A121EC875D74E277"><enum>(m)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE0B6BB75D7904505BA87E754C271D043"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after completing travel in connection with which a judicial officer receives, or will receive, a reimbursement required to be reported under section 102(a)(2)(B), the judicial officer shall file a report regarding the reimbursement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE097D2FDA1F448E82E5A57B05BCFFEB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall publish on a website of the Federal judiciary each report filed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2397DE40320843C297F93303DD7F5F26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of personal hospitality of an individual</header><paragraph id="H6C1ED40EB64749E29F0C2B33AE13583E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 109(14) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA2FAF402E1A74AAD8345CCAE34FECF96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any individual’ means</quote> and inserting the following: “an individual’—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A2890F6344144C5BE07C4A03071ABAD"><subparagraph id="H59EB812452A64DDB9E49BA31A1952EBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E8678B0700C4B0AA2CEF31ACFC67F35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) (as so designated)—</text><clause id="H2DA360E192ED44E3885D994CA58E57EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his family</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the family of the individual</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HE1E47B17F8274F6D869BEBB53D7CE095"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DD047D003A440598FDBD35EEAF21F9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCFA0F834F3045C68C317B0CD097563C"><subparagraph id="H0704F5A013AC448CADCD54DBF40BEA34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a judicial officer, does not include—</text><clause id="HD2F7065A132C4C878B738638B45D2259"><enum>(i)</enum><text>private travel on a boat or airplane owned by an individual if that travel is substituting for commercial transportation;</text></clause><clause id="H65CD42C688F1442397FEA9485FC2DFD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any food, lodging, or entertainment provided by an individual who has (or owns or controls an entity that has) a matter pending before the court on which the judicial officer serves or before a court the decisions of which may be appealed to the court on which the judicial officer serves;</text></clause><clause id="HE7B536B98974414986B9EBF7E27DF723"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>lodging at a residence or other property that is rented to others by the individual providing the hospitality;</text></clause><clause id="HC6D5C2E629E44392A95EEC62EB876619"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>hospitality provided by an individual at—</text><subclause id="H4EBF869C1D0A49F4A50BD74414047C18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a restaurant, nightclub, resort, hotel, or other commercial establishment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H264324638C0140F88875B33D37A86781"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a private club of which the individual is a paying member;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H613D2C51027D436DB78F6B08BDF8CB4F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>hospitality extended by an individual, the cost of which is paid for by a corporation or organization, including a corporation or organization that is not less than 10-percent owned by the individual; or</text></clause><clause id="H6DD4EA652A7D4698ACBE85470E94620F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>hospitality extended by an individual, the cost of which is reimbursed to the individual by any third party.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CC9CD96604747EAB89752B9D7063AE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification regarding lack of reimbursement</header><text>Section 102(a)(2) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H6AFCEFB5A8F946D3BDD050B6B4029ABF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>The identity</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), the identity</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFA63D05830C4E0A9C9885FB5B340FA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E5C13FAF0BF48ABACB9D68C76E9179E"><subparagraph id="H1B32258101684793904E69B476B21F49"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A judicial officer who receives food, lodging, or entertainment that is exempted under subparagraph (A) from being reported as being food, lodging, or entertainment received as personal hospitality of an individual shall include in the report covering the period during which the food, lodging, or entertainment was received a certification that the cost of the food, lodging, or entertainment was not reimbursed by any third party.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA462C86D593447CAA1A2F3E2E9F3A70F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Financial conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>Government employee,</quote>, <quote>or an officer or employee of the judicial branch of the United States Government,</quote>.</text></section><section id="HD73EB33062014E809A83C2097EB79F05"><enum>8.</enum><header>Video recording of court proceedings</header><subsection id="H7C9C919BA29F458F804B10C90DA77BC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Courts of appeals</header><paragraph id="H347F764D0DEE4E76A24879762C176C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE0074754DB94F1B91225E8CB359F629"><section id="H37638333EBBC4A648C074BE1842C76C5"><enum>50.</enum><header>Internet publication of certain video recordings</header><subsection id="H297B9EAAB4EE46B1AC549FC63CFE1BA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The open proceedings of each hearing of a court of appeals shall be made available by video for public transmission over the internet—</text><paragraph id="H1D132897FCBA41A481913EA9C3F35FEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, in real time during such hearing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2AEEC656D84396AD2D498683C45D1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for not fewer than 5 years after the date on which the hearing concludes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C78249BD107471B862B9B4976F28EE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Copyright protection not available</header><text>An audio or video recording created pursuant to the requirement under this section shall be considered a work of the United States Government for purposes of section 105 of title 17.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6606FF78DE214F52826B26FA5667D538"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H62C22C0CA563435091DE46DD80591880"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H37638333EBBC4A648C074BE1842C76C5">50. Internet publication of certain video recordings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC59399FEC38247F09F4DB42219B2C5C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supreme Court of the United States</header><paragraph id="H70949AF9A2D54320B2BFF4480C28B311"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H976EA75E65AB4CEC969595FA75B5F948"><section id="HAD023F46AE9A4867B56D95FB93971B94"><enum>7.</enum><header>Internet publication of certain video recordings</header><subsection id="HCFB908D948CA4652978C664DE43DB003"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each oral argument and reading of an opinion before the Supreme Court of the United States shall be made available by video for public transmission over the internet—</text><paragraph id="H333125DA5F5D4D218FF357271E0EC99D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the day of such oral argument and reading; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A8EFB189B44C1887B350AFC84D7A14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in real time during such oral argument and opinion reading.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF54639233D6C43529DD37ABB8332C300"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Copyright protection not available</header><text>An recording created pursuant to the requirement under this section shall be considered a work of the United States Government for purposes of section 105 of title 17.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD43361ACD81482EAE797BF34FD152C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H13450FA3C09542E0863188CC31488D68"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HAD023F46AE9A4867B56D95FB93971B94">7. Internet publication of certain video recordings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2E3624C7B33446FC9F925AAE2CA19D39"><enum>9.</enum><header>Restrictions on sealed court filings</header><subsection id="H7ED002B0063F4FEAA980E01918A54023"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73B6E988A03D4FB29D9D144E0A8502B6"><section id="HEEA0FED95149445983C6139B42C7404C"><enum>1661.</enum><header>Restrictions on sealing judicial records</header><subsection id="H8107FA83D21B4113BF14364E6896A891"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Unless otherwise provided by law, no court may seal any judicial record or any part of a judicial record unless—</text><paragraph id="HE3A7DB92D52D4548B0B84B897C963BF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the court finds that a compelling interest justifies abridging the right of public access to the judicial record or the part of the judicial record;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6DDBF0897F640288032CB2224355264"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the court are specific to each judicial record or each part of a judicial record;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36541F6F07443D2BAF0319515273628"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the seal is narrowly tailored and lasts no longer than necessary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H165879EFEBEC4CB7908D6FE73A63AECB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the public has been given notice and opportunity to challenge the seal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59C0CC6D4ACB48EE9432256D6DDE1978"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules</header><paragraph id="HF32E5D07704A48EE8B52CCD13D52C9D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 to ensure that disinterested members of the public have a simplified and inexpensive process to contest a motion to seal a judicial record, to appeal an order sealing a judicial record, and to request that a judicial record be unsealed. No local rule of procedure may be less protective of the right of public access to judicial records than the rules prescribed under this subsection. Such rules shall be prescribed and submitted to the Congress pursuant to sections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H730F239565A04F11AE5157837CFFBD01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Supreme Court of the United States shall transmit to Congress—</text><subparagraph id="H0D7347D810F443B6B6525BF299ABB5A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proposed rules required under paragraph (1) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76272AC621DE438A823951682B854813" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any rules in addition to those transmitted under paragraph (1) pursuant to section 2074 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H724906B8C8E6477EBCA4EC7D50581A01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H17B721E784214361A15482E47719418D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abolish, diminish, or infringe upon any right, responsibility, or remedy provided by the Constitution of the United States or any other law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F17D8D052B486B87C22552D7F88E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relieve a court of any part of the independent duty of the court to enforce the right of public access to judicial records;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72C510C6E8CD4C4B8AB63E93473AE7BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>abrogate any rule of law that is more or additionally protective of the right of public access to judicial records.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H36DEA7D612B2436B8C7169547E3AE6BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H15FDF204E5914B55A737A6DF67450C9B"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HEEA0FED95149445983C6139B42C7404C">1661. Restrictions on sealing judicial records.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H6CDFA3078E2C4BF6B4489880A460AC60"><enum>10.</enum><header>Studies by the Federal Judicial Center</header><subsection id="HE6D5C7A658A04ADBB1698DF0D321A710"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2022, and every other year thereafter, the Federal Judicial Center shall conduct a study of the extent of compliance or noncompliance with the requirements of sections 144 and 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 3 of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H747D2A520B3845CCBD2CE57364153FE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than April 1 of each year following the completion of the study required under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HD0C8A68D49A246A8BC25FA1818372131"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Judicial Center—</text><subparagraph id="HEEDB545F10A140298073E5270AC879E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B84236931B241F4966235A5E45540AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may submit to Congress recommendations to improve the compliance by the Federal judiciary with the requirements of sections 144 and 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 3 of this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4E531DC3BF4AE8A802716883519EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing an evaluation of the methodology and findings of the study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF31F2398E6A5447E932AFEF93AAB72DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facilitation of studies</header><text>In order to facilitate the studies required under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H6DEFB5A6C9B64A6DB291DDE4F3A01D35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Judicial Conference of the United States shall maintain a record of each instance in which a justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge was not assigned to a case due to potential or actual conflicts indicated on a conflicts sheet; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAC2713CADC44DEB8844AB53E0D12624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the clerk of each court shall maintain and include in the relevant case docket a record of each instance in which a justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge disqualifies after a case assignment is made. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

