<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA8D6406AB4354C1689D9DBE69AD2F622" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6411 IH: Support The Resiliency of Our Nation’s Great Veterans Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6411</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220118">January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the mental health care provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H751DB6E6DA3E42548DED1ADFA9512C6C" style="OLC"><section id="H6842A51E44D941D18949513F76D2E916" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H027150BB55A2411EAAC3E566FC16824F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support The Resiliency of Our Nation’s Great Veterans Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRONG Veterans Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC516FA31ABC04FD68FE0BFBA95DFF7EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H6842A51E44D941D18949513F76D2E916" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2098B42BB77E4A8793B1E613DF14E566" level="title">Title I—Training to Support Veterans’ Mental Health</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE0DCB1580048445AB02B2E46E0819DDB" level="section">Sec. 101. Mental health and suicide prevention outreach to minority veterans and American Indian and Alaska Native veterans.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBA6D23598B884EC0AF9DD36AD114729A" level="section">Sec. 102. Expansion of Vet Center workforce.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H360D0C9D97E94069895058F0B5780AD7" level="section">Sec. 103. Expansion of mental health training for Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H338DCC6E2DD0478EBF65F2758D1E0C4E" level="section">Sec. 104. Expansion of scholarships and loan repayment programs for mental health providers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9AD73174D15244CDA63F37C1E3BDDC60" level="title">Title II—Veterans Crisis Line</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5BE6BDF1690A4BD5B9FB00DF2B340A26" level="section">Sec. 201. Veterans Crisis Line.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H90C885A2142F4223828EA6EB9E514AEB" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Veterans Crisis Line Training and Quality Management</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H955257011C8A40F5B518E6724294B3D7" level="section">Sec. 211. Staff training.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H48BF2885277948E1AB1AACFD1676C4A6" level="section">Sec. 212. Quality review and management.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5DF17A9B7136400ABCD66D117FB3C883" level="section">Sec. 213. Guidance for high-risk callers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H344C7FB4C16E446F9BABF26CDA0CDCE2" level="section">Sec. 214. Oversight of training of social service assistants and clarification of job responsibilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6548CF0A9B014A1CA238A232F35FBEE4" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Pilot Programs and Research on Veterans Crisis Line</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0C01FFE0BAB348E5BB4AA68DB9B2DACE" level="section">Sec. 221. Pilot programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA595279685D147F0BEA1D13E0BFC44C0" level="section">Sec. 222. Authorization of appropriations for research on effectiveness and opportunities for improvement of Veterans Crisis Line.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H74247E9995A848438FCDFB672F3D1786" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Transition of Crisis Line Number</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2B28BD69881242C3881C3B4B692C91DF" level="section">Sec. 231. Feedback on transition of crisis line number.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB02DB431A02D4CA9BC8A35A4357CFCDE" level="title">Title III—Outreach to Veterans</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H05EFC019795B457B9F11F21E0E3895B1" level="section">Sec. 301. Solid Start program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9D19204126BB41F0B7B77C01D3063526" level="section">Sec. 302. Designation of Buddy Check Week by Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF71658EDDCB54106BC02D89C3E8390AE" level="section">Sec. 303. Improvements to Veterans Justice Outreach Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H88F96A3DC6F540BB97B3F338AC2A366C" level="section">Sec. 304. Department of Veterans Affairs Governors Challenge Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H45FA95A5AB284B3990EA3ADD37DFC113" level="title">Title IV—Mental Health Care Delivery</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA2D944DAE7244E4B9EABDACAD2949910" level="section">Sec. 401. Expansion of peer specialist support program of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H295DD8F8D946459B8BA6C67FE6E080F7" level="section">Sec. 402. Expansion of Vet Center services.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC81D4BE509F845A2B214F8EA25EFC1BE" level="section">Sec. 403. Eligibility for mental health services.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC54A0E6C267D4F43864126DBFF94D8CB" level="section">Sec. 404. Mental health consultations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFB8E41A4C0E64E9BB0AB7913ECEB6E22" level="title">Title V—Research</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4D3988E111C64D3AAE9B0BF758057B5F" level="section">Sec. 501. Veterans integration to academic leadership program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF5BAB65BD56441189B6957E519F4608E" level="section">Sec. 502. Improvement of sleep disorder care furnished by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H359A3A8DFF554737B3BC3DA4F0A93091" level="section">Sec. 503. Study on inpatient mental health and substance use care from Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEA256FFFA76D4987BC3EE9A040AE4593" level="section">Sec. 504. Study on treatment from Department of Veterans Affairs for co-occurring mental health and substance use disorders.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD0FDE77B618A4BECB71E8BF3DB028D3A" level="section">Sec. 505. Study on workload of suicide prevention teams of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC39B81C5134347A7B9164F4ECA85565B" level="section">Sec. 506. Expansion of suicide prevention and mental health research.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9E01A5F7F2F4411EAB6053D6C0CBAA05" level="section">Sec. 507. Study on mental health and suicide prevention support for military families.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6AABA977153044408CC829B12D7BE346" level="section">Sec. 508. Research on brain health.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCF942056A84C4D9EA24B5311F505BC10" level="section">Sec. 509. Study on efficacy of clinical and at-home resources for post-traumatic stress disorder.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="H2098B42BB77E4A8793B1E613DF14E566"><enum>I</enum><header>Training to Support Veterans’ Mental Health</header><section id="HE0DCB1580048445AB02B2E46E0819DDB" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mental health and suicide prevention outreach to minority veterans and American Indian and Alaska Native veterans</header><subsection id="H5A7A48BFC0374C3498019F1D20D227B7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Staffing requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs has no fewer than one full-time employee whose responsibility is serving as a minority veteran coordinator.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1830C38E3214B989C6F97F86B038DC4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Indian Health Service and the Director of the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall ensure that all minority veteran coordinators receive training in delivery of culturally appropriate mental health and suicide prevention services to American Indian and Alaska Native veterans, especially with respect to the identified populations and tribes within the coordinators’ catchment areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF36E8861842E4041956814F6EE259271" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with suicide prevention coordinators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention, shall ensure that the suicide prevention coordinator and minority veteran coordinator of each medical center of the Department have developed and disseminated to the director of the medical center a written plan for conducting mental health and suicide prevention outreach to all tribes and urban Indian health organizations within the catchment area of the medical center. Each such plan shall include for each tribe covered by the plan—</text><paragraph id="H33B8342F32A146A9BE2CE99C2AA9E5F3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contact information for tribal leadership and the tribal health facility or Indian Health Service facility serving that tribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97F33005DD9A4A0C9DF17FC1E7D76064" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a schedule for and list of outreach plans (including addressing any barriers to accessing Department mental health care);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA48695D5D7494B9592B71CC6AD342651" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>documentation of any conversation with tribal leaders that may guide culturally appropriate delivery of mental health care to American Indian or Alaska Native veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H510147639F9D49EE95020B7D5799A64A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documentation of any progress in incorporating traditional healing practices into mental health and suicide prevention protocols and options available for veterans who are members of such tribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68E9703903E340BA9B241105C4DB876F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>documentation of any coordination among the Department, the Indian Health Service, urban Indian health organizations, and the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration for the purpose of improving suicide prevention efforts tailored to veterans who are members of such tribe and the provision of culturally competent mental health care to such veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62AB327EB0624FBF8766BC427289EDAD" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on outreach efforts to minority veterans and American Indian and Alaska Native veterans. Such report shall include each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H46D3FC0B0C5C4186858C16724E6A3AEB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of minority veteran coordinators within the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B3F6E2610A43758710A9B9B247582D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of minority veteran coordinators who are women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0148B411EBC040B6AE6227D6B73D0BEF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number and percentage of minority veteran coordinators who are persons of color.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0058BCB0B084C198370BCBC0022AF79" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number and percentage of Department medical centers with minority veteran coordinators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC26623C74AA4A09931D3E4C23F07162" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of Department mental health providers who are enrolled members of a federally recognized Indian tribe or self-identify as Native American.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9725B2287D24E2B86A3A1C1296A05BA" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number and percentage of Department mental health providers who speak a second language.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F5324137D6E435F8EE0D7823879F616" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A review of the outreach plans developed and submitted to all Department medical centers for outreach to American Indian and Alaska Native veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0D2BD75BFF463CAB78B354923C8713" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A review of mental health care provided annually by the Department to American Indian and Alaska Native veterans for the past three years, including number of appointments, and an assessment of any barriers to providing this care.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBA6D23598B884EC0AF9DD36AD114729A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Expansion of Vet Center workforce</header><subsection id="H6829B796E30945B98FBCB728F12406D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall hire an additional 100 full-time equivalent employees for Vet Centers to bolster the workforce of Vet Centers and to provide expanded mental health care to veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and their families through outreach, community access points, outstations, and Vet Centers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98914EDD700E446F96A33A9C2BA6F189"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vet center defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="H360D0C9D97E94069895058F0B5780AD7"><enum>103.</enum><header>Expansion of mental health training for Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="HF8F20A6759804E4B9B2D1E40F4930088"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention and the Office of Academic Affiliations, shall add an additional 500 paid trainee slots in covered mental health disciplines to the workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3876EE848644419983847FDDEF704F04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered mental health disciplines defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered mental health disciplines</term> means psychiatry, psychology, advanced practice nursing (with a focus on mental health or substance use disorder), social work, licensed professional mental health counseling, and marriage and family therapy.</text></subsection></section><section id="H338DCC6E2DD0478EBF65F2758D1E0C4E"><enum>104.</enum><header>Expansion of scholarships and loan repayment programs for mental health providers</header><subsection id="H5B5C36A4EAEB44B4A19E6F53B66AA655"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of Health Professional Scholarship Program</header><text>Beginning in academic year 2022, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include not fewer than an additional (as compared to academic year 2021) 50 awards per academic year under the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professional Scholarship Program under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for applicants otherwise eligible for such program who are pursuing degrees or training in mental health disciplines, including advanced practice nursing (with a focus on mental health or substance use disorder), psychology, and social work.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE753F066B9594485866BC82A86898111"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of Education Debt Reduction Program</header><paragraph id="HE9608FC708A241D9808D7F0284B7B4D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2022, the Secretary shall provide not fewer than an additional (as compared to fiscal year 2021) 200 debt reduction awards per year under the Department of Veterans Affairs Education Debt Reduction Program under subchapter VII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to be used to recruit mental health professionals to the Department of Veterans Affairs in disciplines that include psychiatry, psychology, advanced practice nursing (with a focus on mental health or substance use disorder), and social work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E839AC68B94FC0887215FBA0D27E20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $8,000,000 per year to carry out the additional awards under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D01C99C92E9463AB928202494F34DF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach</header><paragraph id="H1DB4C840BC1944B48DC5071D5F61B15F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop a public awareness campaign to encourage veterans and mental health professionals to choose the Department for their mental health career.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A572BF400A4DCFA86FCE4433AD8F0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The campaign required under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HF7A9C152898E40E3B7E14C0BF100FE09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall advertise the paid trainee, scholarship, and loan repayment opportunities offered by the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA90045DCA594397B11A2703C287B70A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may highlight the new graduate medical education residencies available at the Department for medical students entering residency. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H9AD73174D15244CDA63F37C1E3BDDC60"><enum>II</enum><header>Veterans Crisis Line</header><section id="H5BE6BDF1690A4BD5B9FB00DF2B340A26"><enum>201.</enum><header>Veterans Crisis Line</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <quote>Veterans Crisis Line</quote> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text></section><subtitle style="OLC" id="H90C885A2142F4223828EA6EB9E514AEB"><enum>A</enum><header>Veterans Crisis Line Training and Quality Management</header><section id="H955257011C8A40F5B518E6724294B3D7"><enum>211.</enum><header>Staff training</header><subsection id="H9DAF9C9D10F24EABB3FB2D60803D0F18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review of training for Veterans Crisis Line call responders</header><paragraph id="H86C0234303FA45B583FEF7F4D1D9450A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall enter into an agreement with an organization outside the Department of Veterans Affairs to review the training for Veterans Crisis Line call responders on assisting callers in crisis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ADAA45BD6344B8FAF807B66C11AE7BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Completion of review</header><text>The review conducted under paragraph (1) shall be completed not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD75EC0CC2449CA82373B44BE4379DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The review conducted under paragraph (1) shall consist of a review of the training provided by the Department on subjects including risk assessment, lethal means assessment, substance use and overdose risk assessment, safety planning, referrals to care, supervisory consultation, and emergency dispatch.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43065224F18A42B3BACD3296AB4879DE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Update of training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any deficiencies in the training for Veterans Crisis Line call responders are found pursuant to the review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall update such training and associated standards of practice to correct those deficiencies not later than one year after the completion of the review. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C59F1470A5D4F9799A539C63534B72F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retraining guidelines for Veterans Crisis Line call responders</header><paragraph id="H67C77403C7754719968F1EF9C37DCFBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop guidelines on retraining and quality management for when a Veterans Crisis Line call responder has an adverse event or when a quality review check by a supervisor of such a call responder denotes that the call responder needs improvement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AFE7709F74A4A0EABD8F4D1F8F69724"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines developed under paragraph (1) shall specify the subjects and quantity of retraining recommended and how supervisors should implement increased use of silent monitoring or other performance review mechanisms.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H48BF2885277948E1AB1AACFD1676C4A6"><enum>212.</enum><header>Quality review and management</header><subsection id="H7DC62817A85340179384AF16AD42E2A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Monitoring of calls on Veterans Crisis Line</header><paragraph id="HA099122A449B437C8BF1333445D250D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall require that not fewer than two calls per month for each Veterans Crisis Line call responder be subject to supervisory silent monitoring, which is used to monitor the quality of conduct by such call responder during the call.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD382D019E7EE4AD09E0C96931F1EFD33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benchmarks</header><text>The Secretary shall establish benchmarks for requirements and performance of Veterans Crisis Line call responders on supervisory silent monitored calls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF342AD7C71743B59AAE73216C1CA225"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text>Not less frequently than quarterly, the Secretary shall submit to the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs a report on occurrence and outcomes of supervisory silent monitoring of calls on the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90C08A1A720E4E788979D76ACA1F1C1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quality management processes for Veterans Crisis Line</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the leadership for the Veterans Crisis Line, in partnership with the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department and the National Center for Patient Safety of the Department, shall establish quality management processes and expectations for staff of the Veterans Crisis Line, including with respect to reporting of adverse events and close calls.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE855950831244143BC69EE50AE6613ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual common cause analysis for callers to Veterans Crisis Line who die by suicide</header><paragraph id="HD4E7A103D0D24FBB8EFF72039BCFA650"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall perform a common cause analysis for all identified callers to the Veterans Crisis Line that died by suicide during the one-year period preceding the conduct of the analysis before the caller received contact with emergency services and in which the Veterans Crisis Line was the last point of contact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C26FD506C4B46228659A349D1DA52F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal of results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department the results of each analysis conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8392B75A2E744A0A6ADE849954D36A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of themes or lessons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall apply any themes or lessons learned under an analysis under paragraph (1) to updating training and standards of practice for staff of the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5DF17A9B7136400ABCD66D117FB3C883"><enum>213.</enum><header>Guidance for high-risk callers</header><subsection id="H4ACA4D7C7B444BD1A511872420D2E901"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of enhanced guidance and procedures for response to calls related to substance use and overdose risk</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with national experts within the Department of Veterans Affairs on substance use disorder and overdose, shall—</text><paragraph id="HF454E5BD2ACC484CA7A1630291B8BF32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop enhanced guidance and procedures to respond to calls to the Veterans Crisis Line related to substance use and overdose risk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H282232B70B484528B09BFEAC29BDD25F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update training materials for staff of the Veterans Crisis Line in response to such enhanced guidance and procedures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7F6D5F1BA074B009A7A072227628198"><enum>(3)</enum><text>update criteria for monitoring compliance with such enhanced guidance and procedures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA05A868620C8443BAB2F71A5B8822550"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and improvement of standards for emergency dispatch</header><paragraph id="HFCE4DFB4213443DE88F84003B7C4E996"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5A6472F2F3FE49388BD81BD25B1572DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the current emergency dispatch standard operating procedure of the Veterans Crisis Line to identify any additions to such procedure to strengthen communication regarding—</text><clause id="HC0EE68B0AFC34ABC8057A0C4840590D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>emergency dispatch for disconnected callers; and</text></clause><clause id="HEA9ED1501CFC4AF5996B2F3FE0DA1905"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the role of social service assistants in requesting emergency dispatch and recording such dispatches; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98F482D07A6C467E91C2DD931EDAC0A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>update such procedure to include the additions identified under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59A9E3BEAC9948399DD0581AA557CDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all staff of the Veterans Crisis Line are trained on all updates made under paragraph (1)(B) to the emergency dispatch standard operating procedure of the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H344C7FB4C16E446F9BABF26CDA0CDCE2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>214.</enum><header>Oversight of training of social service assistants and clarification of job responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="H05C16A219BAC47A4A80381FDB4384C07"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish oversight mechanisms to ensure that social service assistants and supervisory social service assistants working with the Veterans Crisis Line are appropriately trained and implementing guidance of the Department regarding the Veterans Crisis Line; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FC8274436CD4937B559556049D1B2A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refine standard operating procedures to delineate roles and responsibilities for all levels of supervisory social service assistants working with the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle style="OLC" id="H6548CF0A9B014A1CA238A232F35FBEE4"><enum>B</enum><header>Pilot Programs and Research on Veterans Crisis Line</header><section id="H0C01FFE0BAB348E5BB4AA68DB9B2DACE"><enum>221.</enum><header>Pilot programs</header><subsection id="HC2A538EE640843A2816C9B15B2DFBCC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extended safety planning pilot program for Veterans Crisis Line</header><paragraph id="HA402C00E454E4BBA94F7BDDD19FD4384"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Commencing not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to determine whether a lengthier, templated safety plan used in clinical settings could be applied in call centers for the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5225CE9D2FD543359C1730C173C33931"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide to Congress a briefing on the findings of the Secretary under the pilot program conducted under paragraph (1), which shall include any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the continuation or discontinuation of the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B0CC3A5EE0E4E0AB69BFACE034ACE53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Crisis line facilitation pilot program</header><paragraph id="H864F080959F248448C0671BF91E551C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Commencing not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a pilot program on the use of crisis line facilitation to increase use of the Veterans Crisis Line among high-risk veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A7D53DE0BCB4F579CF18FC5290BA65D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide to Congress a briefing on the findings of the Secretary under the pilot program under paragraph (1), including any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the continuation or discontinuation of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65B8343CE5D749AA90049B78F13E2F72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H7E2C64A83B254AA08F2F4B14ED32E20F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>crisis line facilitation</term>, with respect to a high-risk veteran, means the presentation by a therapist of psychoeducational information about the Veterans Crisis Line and a discussion of the perceived barriers and facilitators to future use of the Veterans Crisis Line for the veteran, which culminates in the veteran calling the Veterans Crisis Line with the therapist to provide firsthand experiences that may counter negative impressions of the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5BB48E0BD3945E4BE5495E82E9D8F51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>high-risk veteran</term> means a veteran receiving inpatient mental health care following a suicidal crisis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA595279685D147F0BEA1D13E0BFC44C0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>222.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for research on effectiveness and opportunities for improvement of Veterans Crisis Line</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, a total of $5,000,000 for the Mental Illness Research, Education, and Clinical Centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs to conduct research on the effectiveness of the Veterans Crisis Line and areas for improvement for the Veterans Crisis Line. Amounts made available pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under this section shall remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></section></subtitle><subtitle style="OLC" id="H74247E9995A848438FCDFB672F3D1786"><enum>C</enum><header>Transition of Crisis Line Number</header><section id="H2B28BD69881242C3881C3B4B692C91DF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>231.</enum><header>Feedback on transition of crisis line number</header><subsection id="H5C34CB1F01534D589DE7DDA8E5803528"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall solicit feedback from veterans service organizations on how to conduct outreach to members of the Armed Forces, veterans, their family members, and other members of the military and veterans community on the move to 988 as the new, national three-digit suicide and mental health crisis hotline, which is expected to be implemented by July 2022, to minimize confusion and ensure veterans are aware of their options for reaching the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD50EB65CEAA4648ADFF16F32299C97D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonapplication of FACA</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to any feedback solicited under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9B85149DBF948588BDCA4C89EEF5A6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></subtitle></title><title id="HB02DB431A02D4CA9BC8A35A4357CFCDE"><enum>III</enum><header>Outreach to Veterans</header><section id="H05EFC019795B457B9F11F21E0E3895B1"><enum>301.</enum><header>Solid Start program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H6B25673C0F8845B89365D214ED4BA0F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/63">Chapter 63</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter: </text><quoted-block id="H400209FDD7A44BE193B53040C3F563F1" style="USC" act-name=""><subchapter id="H0C89FFD48194427789BE80B9CB0A1EA8" style="USC"><enum>II</enum><header>Other outreach programs and activities</header><section id="H56FBA41F9AB94A59A34E54D09D550A3C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6320.</enum><header>Solid Start program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H050C9E1E90BA4C6A812FB78E0897C4E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program, to be known as the <quote>Solid Start program</quote>, under which the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H285494FBCA0046B0A53A04BC4EDF8139"><enum>(1)</enum><text>build the capacity of the Department to efficiently and effectively respond to the queries and needs of veterans who have recently separated from the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0964446EDA55484A89D524CCAE289BA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>systemically integrate and coordinate efforts to assist veterans, including efforts—</text><subparagraph id="H30978B0BB46445E7B7B6C2CC68CE56CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to proactively reach out to newly separated veterans to inform them of their eligibility for programs of and benefits provided by the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ABC504107CD4F57A216E0BE5D322C50" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to connect veterans in crisis to resources that address their immediate needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC633EDAAD5F4C77A4C4C1EB37D24BC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities of the Solid Start program</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEE8B0BF9DC9B4327A6DF93FC5DF32977"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall carry out the Solid Start program of the Department by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE7DB6608C9A4C939C3F02F967219056" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collecting up-to-date contact information during transition classes or separation counseling for all members of the Armed Forces who are separating from the Armed Forces, while explaining the existence and purpose of the Solid Start program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H7965EE0A9B4C4AF2B84E2818BBC2C7BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>calling each veteran, regardless of separation type or characterization of service, three times within the first year after separation of the veteran from the Armed Forces; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HEB2498451B8B4EF1955B2E50E1FB3290"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing information about the Solid Start program on the website of the Department and in materials of the Department, especially transition booklets and other resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H5DFD0A6923164A8B90999719F2E454DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensuring calls are truly tailored to the needs of each veteran’s unique situation by conducting quality assurance tests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H40A93115A07840B486AB4DA7E7CD36B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>prioritizing outreach to veterans who have accessed mental health resources prior to separation from the Armed Forces; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HE8D144A13F264C64B522996113CE1DE6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing women veterans with information that is tailored to their specific health care and benefit needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H61E9394FBC0F4E88A8D28A9F6E9D9525"><enum>(G)</enum><text>as feasible, providing information on access to State and local resources, including Vet Centers and veterans service organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H57C388C01E0D422791D632CA62B99D3A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>gathering and analyzing data assessing the effectiveness of the Solid Start program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" indent="up1" id="H986E3884493E41A2BEE0239AF6F183EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may carry out the Solid Start program by—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H625AB37EEF8E4789B56E5AC3F0560183"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encouraging members of the Armed Forces who are transitioning to civilian life to authorize alternate points of contact who can be reached should the member be unavailable during the first year following the separation of the member from the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H971295FF13DC4A58B73FD1616DFD37B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>following up missed phone calls with tailored mailings to ensure the veteran still receives similar information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H36FAB571EF3D486AB355E2F5F5402EA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>striving to reach out to veterans who separated prior to the initiation of the Solid Start program to provide similar services to those veterans, as feasible. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" indent="up1" id="H20A2AD99ED8B417DBB0ACA01944DB98B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection: </text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H85A271A903A047F5BB918C14D0404F24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>Vet Center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1712A(h) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H2A38DF2FC6F64C9E8B53C4538CD0A25A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A74C1D032D8431C900158CF5E7DA1EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obligations of amounts</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may not, in a fiscal year, obligate an amount to carry out the Solid Start program that is less than the total amount obligated in the previous fiscal year to carry out the program, unless the Secretary determines that increased efficiencies of the program warrant the obligation of a lesser amount.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFE93789842AF471899A1B55723F84CED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Chapter 63 of such title, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H1396E5CBAE834895A7FA536AFE1A61AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting before section 6301 the following: </text><quoted-block id="H694960FB1F534922AA8B7D8F8C97FA44" style="USC" act-name=""><subchapter id="H8F7D786A3B5848AC97C6495E0A4A5078" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Outreach services program</header></subchapter><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7ABD3AF727043EB820FD13225D22108"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in sections 6301, 6303, 6304, 6305, 6306, and 6307, by striking <quote>this chapter</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>this subchapter</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87F50A22F28542F3969AA98A5AD1C2DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 63 of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB88E1E6E142E42B9A87BCA63E53C66D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting before the item relating to section 6301 the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13445F0839DA4BCB9AB57AC1B9758D52"><toc><toc-entry level="subchapter" bold="off">Subchapter I—Outreach services program </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF8DF098F69B4D6D8AF5B15F2D87E365"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new items: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64217EDD8E884D779C49ABB08D34F434"><toc><toc-entry level="subchapter" bold="off">Subchapter II—Other outreach programs and activities 
 </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">6320. Solid Start program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H9D19204126BB41F0B7B77C01D3063526"><enum>302.</enum><header>Designation of Buddy Check Week by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H12E8A5CBA00E49A98757D7A9D0FF94F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall designate one week each year to organize outreach events and educate veterans on how to conduct peer wellness checks, which shall be known as <quote>Buddy Check Week</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2C15608C1051457F883E69F5774B7350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Educational opportunities</header><paragraph id="HC0C1875AC11043819B5E435FCD00AFBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During Buddy Check Week, the Secretary, in consultation with organizations that represent veterans, nonprofits that serve veterans, mental health experts, members of the Armed Forces, and such other entities and individuals as the Secretary considers appropriate, shall collaborate with organizations that represent veterans to provide educational opportunities for veterans to learn how to conduct peer wellness checks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB9F002CC1124D4AAE1D7F0D08345700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training matters</header><text>As part of the educational opportunities provided under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBBFC22ACFE1B4F5E885EE3AD77A435E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A script for veterans to use to conduct peer wellness checks that includes information on appropriate referrals to resources veterans might need.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF82C030A1BDD443DB5105EEFA11B5D05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Online and in-person training, as appropriate, on how to conduct a peer wellness check.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BE5B478938D4BC6AB8F1591E2E35483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Opportunities for members of organizations that represent veterans to learn how to train individuals to conduct peer wellness checks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33416C90F8E7486A963BA083F7A82493"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Training for veterans participating in Buddy Check Week on how to transfer a phone call directly to the Veterans Crisis Line.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD56548CA3BC540BBA9088C2E86A86C25"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Resiliency training for veterans participating in Buddy Check Week on handling a veteran in crisis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32FEF62C265641539D3904B73E9006DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Online materials</header><text>All training materials provided under the educational opportunities under paragraph (1) shall be made publicly available on a website of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69B1C9833144474281963DBE78464DE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with organizations that represent veterans, may conduct outreach regarding educational opportunities under subsection (b) at—</text><paragraph id="HE359FFA240CF4014B1DDF5107B783624"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public events where many veterans are expected to congregate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2563ACDD0BB4E549DBA6843B69E4B25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>meetings of organizations that represent veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26ACE70BC06547999199ACE0D399D3FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilities of the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76DB03D22111482CAA4D3CB5C1376A94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other locations as the Secretary, in collaboration with organizations that represent veterans, considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0177801E18A2411AA141EDAF3DB26552"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Veterans Crisis Line plan</header><paragraph id="H5EFB0F9ECA18417FA7C2EBBC89170413"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a plan exists for handling the potential increase in the number of calls into the Veterans Crisis Line that may occur during Buddy Check Week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC25C7BB0FBC4FB2B74A285155F4262F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal of plan</header><text>The head of the Veterans Crisis Line shall submit to the Secretary a plan for how to handle excess calls during Buddy Check Week, which may include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB65580579E7C4729A38CAF4536CE6C04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Additional hours for staff.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H156A0617726344E480E9A56B936E502B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The use of a backup call center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB5E9CBB1E0443FBBF4865DB624FE383"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other plan to ensure that calls from veterans in crisis are being answered in a timely manner by an individual trained at the same level as a Veterans Crisis Line responder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D1D41D1519E4F8581CE3920E1ABDBA1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="H2C77C5AA9E9C40AF880932ED8099E710"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>organization that represents veterans</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DE8A1A89CB741D787D514177F8DC0CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BB94A7C47544C1995A1D9D8632C2E1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans provided by the Secretary under section 1720F(h) of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF71658EDDCB54106BC02D89C3E8390AE"><enum>303.</enum><header>Improvements to Veterans Justice Outreach Program</header><subsection id="HDA8F3C43E22D4C62A9614F38D22F305B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct outreach regarding the Veterans Justice Outreach Program to justice-involved veterans, military and veterans service organizations, and relevant stakeholders in the criminal justice community, including officials from local law enforcement, court, and jail systems and others as determined appropriate by the Secretary. Such outreach—</text><paragraph id="H3CD85F55BF9F4AFB96A3485157BAE736"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be designed—</text><subparagraph id="H2115E3F3868D42BCBE216BCE2EA08052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to spread awareness and understanding of the Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D0C3D33071C45738AB92632573F0371"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to spread awareness and understanding of veteran eligibility for the Program, including the eligibility of veterans who were discharged from service in the Armed Forces under conditions other than honorable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD17B54D6855E47C0812AE26E2009A2B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to improve the identification of justice-involved veterans; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF87A6A9A112A4D3FBC321B6B1A4D7DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be conducted in person, virtually, or through other means, including by the dissemination of informational materials and contact information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36F3A717BDF149A59E2D51C1E7C12499"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop a strategic plan for the Veterans Justice Outreach Program. In developing such plan, the Secretary shall conduct—</text><paragraph id="HB72001E3AC0444F896291623CB1C6439"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of barriers to working with justice-involved veterans in rural, remote, and underserved areas, including potential steps to address such barriers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H846989B79EAA443DBDD1ECC58806123D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a workforce gap analysis for the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H479231EC6E1E46D4AB82877DFC8764E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increase in number of VJO specialists</header><paragraph id="H03FCE72B71754ACA9BAB130821A0D24F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall increase the number of Veterans Justice Outreach specialists responsible for supporting justice-involved veterans in rural, remote, or underserved areas, including areas located far from Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers, as determined by the Secretary, through—</text><subparagraph id="H8D229814BB204452BE26AE5FC872AE28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the hiring of additional Veterans Justice Outreach specialists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49B6E048D34448D988B77CFEAA7D57A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reallocation of existing Veterans Justice Outreach specialists; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B87BE65EAFB4EA6820091C324915995"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other means as may be determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDFDFE411A164D548F010C74A646EDA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine the number of Veterans Justice Outreach specialists required, and the locations of such specialists, under paragraph (1) by taking into account—</text><subparagraph id="H2245C0A0F6654D8AAEFA8A3985393592"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such number and locations needed to achieve the mission and strategic goals of the Veterans Justice Outreach Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0EE9146ACAB42FBBB9E2246D6143822"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any gaps in the workforce of the Program, including such gaps identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89AC569F19E641D495040D50C3959849"><enum>(C)</enum><text>strategies to address such gaps.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFD23FFEFEAF47BB8CF2FDFC44DF7595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the use of virtual technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC815CD831F1467A8780361D91D8916F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance goals and implementation plans</header><paragraph id="H1A3D52087A974762BADAB7F5F7F3CB91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish performance goals and implementation plans for—</text><subparagraph id="HF94601A53EC84E67B2FC04216BD4FE44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Veterans Justice Outreach Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCA2C30FD96C4E71818095F8FF19B8EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CD98307FB7745D091B244C195F26ABF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing support for research regarding justice-involved veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H518A340580D44BEA9E3E1DB5C5713420"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consistency with strategic plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the performance goals and implementation plans under paragraph (1) are consistent with the strategic plan under subsection (b) and include—</text><subparagraph id="H641FCEABA1D44204A90604BC9A0B1E6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualitative and quantitative milestones, measures, and metrics, and associated timelines for completion of the plans under paragraph (1) and barriers to such completion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83B7D6A10024456CBB48D3315999440F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of relevant staff; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85742858C9F14E8B91E45D184F07FB45"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of resource needs and sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D068C7278854A8CA61E8D89D86FA178"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Performance data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a process to regularly collect and analyze performance data to assess the efficiency and effectiveness of implementing the plans under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE31762256AF448189C7F33F88D28371A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists receive training not less frequently than annually on—</text><paragraph id="H534897D0FCB6482F91BC8FF50E240FB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>best practices for identifying and conducting outreach to justice-involved veterans and relevant stakeholders in the criminal justice community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H972082F3799C400C8D98BC8E21B3D821"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">veteran eligibility for the Veterans Justice Outreach Program, including with respect to consistently communicating changes regarding eligibility (including through the use of a script or other reference materials). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83E4B3281C9A4E708A928227FAA9B933" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports on implementation</header><paragraph id="H206172AF875247369992D21AB44661FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the following:</text><subparagraph id="H797B0DB904F84569BF8298C6BA7E0910" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of implementing subsection (c), including—</text><clause id="HA69A933D2504477BAA361E65B81C2F91" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies to increase Veterans Justice Outreach specialists responsible for supporting justice-involved veterans in rural, remote, or underserved areas; and</text></clause><clause id="HAB7B1A48483B4A158C488DF48E02E744" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress of the Secretary in addressing gaps in the workforce of the Veterans Justice Outreach Program identified pursuant to paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3945FC0FE8B54FFAAB28DEF0337FC356" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The performance goals and implementation plans established under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6111792E6F734F208FDB8FE042075EC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date on which the first report is submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in meeting the performance goals and carrying out activities under the implementation plans established under subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28A3783C16B64F1E808988D6DA9AC431"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report on veterans treatment courts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall submit to Congress a report on the engagement of the Department of Veterans Affairs with veterans treatment courts, including—</text><paragraph id="H260704D1B2EA417FB6ACCD6A2D661930"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability and efficacy of veterans treatment courts in meeting the needs of justice-involved veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58A184E0F99C45ACBB01379C3F616695"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices for Department of Veterans Affairs staff and justice-involved veterans in working with veterans treatment courts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H235C453F90484EDDAE1F23088EE2810C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the ability of justice-involved veterans to access veterans treatment courts, including any barriers that exist to increasing such access.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75E0FD3B9C0B4ED28B28B33B62932E54"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0ED76266BC4248D89DEAD8B1EF3DB9D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>justice-involved veteran</quote> means a veteran with active, ongoing, or recent contact with some component of a local criminal justice system. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D051A3E97E44ADEBAD4209D04BC35A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Veterans Justice Outreach Program</quote> means the program through which the Department of Veterans Affairs identifies justice-involved veterans and provides such veterans with access to Department services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD084B8623764AD980AC9F0C7DF8C4A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>Veterans Justice Outreach Specialist</quote> means an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who serves as a liaison between the Department and the local criminal justice system on behalf of a justice-involved veteran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E1721A573E4A95B14209B4E094532B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veterans treatment court</quote> means a State or local court that is participating in the veterans treatment court program (as defined in section 2991(i)(1) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa(i)(1)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H88F96A3DC6F540BB97B3F338AC2A366C" commented="no"><enum>304.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs Governors Challenge Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may enter into agreements with States, territories, and American Indian and Alaska Native tribes for the development and implementation of veteran suicide prevention proposals through the Governors Challenge Program.</text></section></title><title id="H45FA95A5AB284B3990EA3ADD37DFC113"><enum>IV</enum><header>Mental Health Care Delivery</header><section id="HA2D944DAE7244E4B9EABDACAD2949910" commented="no"><enum>401.</enum><header>Expansion of peer specialist support program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H7196326BA8FB4BD589C35024895E5894" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 506 of the VA MISSION Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6246C40059EE43D4B0577F111F9C27DF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (d) through (f) as subsections (e) through (g);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H534E452CBBE64613940E2CDC1205CC2B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Each such peer specialist shall be a full-time employee whose primary function is to serve as a peer specialist and shall be in addition to all other employees of such medical center.</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC889390F7BFE4DBF8296E5C714941E00" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading of subsection (b), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Timeframe</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Initial timeframe</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9890B573CEAF4AC7B4DD5C10A42B6655" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H30F04D6DC7E545B3A0B7E84D7B554118" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Selection</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Initial selection</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7DD8881D0824A5EADE2921BD64A837B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary shall</quote> and inserting <quote>In establishing the program at initial locations, the Secretary shall</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35B5DEEEE44F40908F8AEE5EF0CCBE4D" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H172F763E3A0548C8BC0B17DD9CD0865D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HD611E8B2CC4C47CDA8900F9B60508C9F" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timeframe for expansion of program; selection of additional locations</header><paragraph id="HF108ED27CB6C4618A2B1649D0BA55366" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timeframe for expansion</header><text>The Secretary shall make permanent and expand the program to additional medical centers of the Department as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HE557F57B825E46FB92402DA47609AB41" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As of the date of the enactment of the STRONG Veterans Act of 2021, the Secretary shall make such program permanent at each medical center participating in the program on the day before such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02A17E4DD4F64A2A98454DEC2BEBF566" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>During the seven-year period following such date of enactment, the Secretary shall expand the program to an additional 25 medical centers per year until the program is carried out at each medical center of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63497852E8B49609EB96BA6DF3E256D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of additional locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting medical centers for the expansion of the program under paragraph (1)(B), until such time as each medical center of the Department is participating in the program by establishing not fewer than two peer specialists at the medical center, the Secretary shall prioritize medical centers in the following areas:</text><subparagraph id="H2EAFFCC784044ECB9CE169E244C0C2A8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Rural areas and other areas that are underserved by the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAEEDD5DC6A749129259DBDD98828E30" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Areas that are not in close proximity to an active duty military installation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31ED50FBCE234B53B3785633D3477344" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Areas representing different geographic locations, such as census tracts established by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F6AA230B8BD49A18B76D83EA0FC60C2" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as redesignated by paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H4BCA6184C3854090BC03552A98FCA6B0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Gender-specific services</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Considerations for hiring peer specialists</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09CF9DD9F13745FCB6D27612CCB576A0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>location selected under subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>medical center</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6507E021857241C9AC2788A8676E6699" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF7AB9493C5D4FEDA047EE60AF0F8519" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following new paragraphs: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H58EAF46564C74221BE2B542B1F2DAB23" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H9E8AFBAB278C44B5A7D73876D031BBA0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">female peer specialists are hired and made available to support female veterans who are treated at each medical center; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12FEB21CB8F54909AD4B577AD9CA74FA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practical, peer specialists are hired in demographic percentages that reflect the racial and ethnic demographic percentages of the overall veterans population.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCDC7C013C2F43E4BF5C620239F08957" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subsection (g), as redesignated by paragraph (1), to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H294BFB8B49A7403596CF315A0F47557A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1E5FAE2B11354AF1A301B42F573454C6" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H1C5992697F7A4967A2292DAC9E50F531" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><subparagraph id="H6A33AA29207E4A85A8C49135CA5F8029" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the STRONG Veterans Act of 2021, and annually thereafter for five years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the program, including the expansion of the program under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H956B625CDBDC49B788B0D4D184999B52" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report under subparagraph (A) shall include, with respect to the one-year period preceding the submission of the report, the following:</text><clause id="H1AE3D4C006D248D09167A754C735877A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The findings and conclusions of the Secretary with respect to the program.</text></clause><clause id="HB42BB6BD7EF643D7A2E1A6958FB1C1D9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An assessment of the benefits of the program to veterans and family members of veterans.</text></clause><clause id="HB3ABBBEBE133411295C9011B562435D4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of peer specialists in engaging under subsection (f) with health care providers in the community and veterans served by such providers.</text></clause><clause id="HFA11ACA95B524E7DB6C83941E3CC0E49" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The name and location of each medical center where new peer specialists were hired.</text></clause><clause id="H6AAE8A4D58ED4B008D1D6415ADCE4955" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The number of new peer specialists hired at each medical center pursuant to this section and the total number of peer specialists within the Department hired pursuant to this section.</text></clause><clause id="H392D55FCB1D64C60AE36D3A913693E77" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An assessment of any barriers confronting the recruitment, training, or retention of peer specialists.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB046291905F049998C2E21E278DAF40D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the Secretary determines that the program is being carried out at each medical center of the Department, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report notifying such committees of such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H554CCCBFEA0844D88C23313C998FE90A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs to implement section 506 of the VA MISSION Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsection (a), the following amounts:</text><paragraph id="HA5BABA451CDF404AA0D71E44759D6414" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,600,000 for fiscal year 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC097EFD4A4A34880AF3640CFD95B1CE5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$7,200,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6AAE88713F47BCB2F625E8D089EFCD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$10,800,000 for fiscal year 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8255C30E8CFB474AA7EDEC95A1689A78" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$14,400,000 for fiscal year 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8EF3CBCF5F646DAAC105CA189EEEDBF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$18,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1CF0A5F35F14211989C5EE41D70118D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$21,600,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD52D3C3686184FA89C2BEC1578D2A1E2" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$25,000,000 for fiscal year 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H295DD8F8D946459B8BA6C67FE6E080F7"><enum>402.</enum><header>Expansion of Vet Center services</header><subsection id="HADED40C0F0704F4BA9614A04AD2D4E15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Veterans and members using educational assistance benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1712A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8C8B50615301454AA6D9784A97E31C4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>clauses (i) through (vi)</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>clauses (i) through (vii)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01E356B125C144C88B111F3A25D9770A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in clause (vii)</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>in clause (viii)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D888C63B4F84EC59F24B4CC12FFD711"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(C)—</text><subparagraph id="H52175EDB89F048299D8D530B98CB2325"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (vii) as clause (viii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB328D512C52E47A99FF1CC8D2290786F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (vi) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F816A56FB2146AD849DC916A90B45BD" style="USC"><clause id="HB3AF0FD7F4F74A1CA0F37DF7FA825D3D" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any veteran or member of the Armed Forces pursuing a course of education using covered educational assistance benefits.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82BF706DF8E34F6DB3F3D5E4F50ED6CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD57F4FDD66E642198DA066B05D2C77E4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0853FBDE68B14CBA878FDF9CF61E00C8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered educational assistance benefits</term> means educational assistance benefits provided pursuant to—</text><subparagraph id="H2E68E1C5D5EE43DE8E8FD79C4835161D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chapter 30, 31, 32, or 33 of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AA01ECCC8C9439B8D30A10619410100"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59C900687EE045C1B7F47AD6D73E4839"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 116 of the Harry W. Colmery Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/48">Public Law 115–48</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3001">38 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA63ECCDBB833441ABAA7A326698D7A32"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 8006 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3001">38 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note prec.).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19F6DF091E4C424BAF03F76340682F17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report assessing—</text><paragraph id="H6560D10CAC8C46C88E60BFC62B558567"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mental health needs of veterans pursuing a course of education using covered educational assistance benefits (as defined in section 1712A(h)(6) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E5D550C82C4FEC918B3E0F174E15D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efforts of the Department of Veterans Affairs to address such mental health needs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC81D4BE509F845A2B214F8EA25EFC1BE"><enum>403.</enum><header>Eligibility for mental health services</header><subsection id="HEB24BBABF0B449B2BF63FEC7198CA0F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1712A(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 402, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HB929D932462F41AA921DE1A16769572A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text><subparagraph id="HE085C8C74BA7490D986541E089E16837"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C557D5C95034A29B9BF6301031FA71B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA83D157F3B84372AC3E42F07493ECE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD2C07DD00E5D4392993E03858E6518DE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H0D0A9574BB824EAC94C5C53C61D3D8A3" indent="up2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a veteran or member who died by suicide, to the degree that counseling furnished to such individual is found to aid in coping with the effects of such suicide.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52B1AD2CFC5646FDBF43432E2BB13BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)(II)—</text><subparagraph id="H1C25B9EB39444B4FB7D001C9511DA347"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in item (aa), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69A46CF58B5D4CDB8427E2340C0724F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in item (bb), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEDA820159DD48A4B86CD11307C71A6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following;</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2E8BD9F4ABD34041B240EEC99D604B01" display-inline="no-display-inline"><item id="H90615237C0EB4CFE8A203EA959EC6E97" indent="up2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coping with the effects of a suicide described in subclause (III) of such clause.</text></item><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB7C7FB058D04F32BD584DFA1A9E8F02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(vii)—</text><subparagraph id="H9CCF302128F14A0C823FF5C63E2A8CDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65A8B94FE15F4CF59B24D6391AD52201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7444490797494D4FB5AA81B08D6C04BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEFFA5B1C5D1043FA856A859B03A859D4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="HFC231CCA70824DF6994FB9B28F0D90D5" indent="up2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">veteran or member of the Armed Forces who died by suicide.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90B2D398EC80453AB8E58C572151FE9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to family members of a member or veteran who died by suicide before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC54A0E6C267D4F43864126DBFF94D8CB"><enum>404.</enum><header>Mental health consultations</header><subsection id="H4D76E9DDEF2D43CB8796AC5A2BFCCC23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mental health consultations for veterans filing for compensation</header><paragraph id="H3D78D503268C407885B3E6B859F7E75A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VI of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H64223BE6A2E249BD9D3AED90C6AF7629" style="USC" act-name=""><section id="H0746D97E15E642D98A7D86C76C0F9635"><enum>1167.</enum><header>Mental health consultations</header><subsection id="HD7058508790C4367BEADA6C6A8EAB9C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which a veteran submits to the Secretary a claim for compensation under this chapter for a service-connected disability relating to a mental health diagnosis, the Secretary shall offer the veteran a mental health consultation to assess the mental health needs of, and care options for, the veteran. </text></subsection><subsection id="H45802C8E619F430E9E6F61CE865D186C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H2B7EDCE20FAD448C92201F82E724A08D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>offer a veteran a consultation under subsection (a) without regard to any previous denial or approval of a claim of that veteran for a service-connected disability relating to a mental health diagnosis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78344AB3D2F5427AAED5A2819D7B33E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that a veteran offered a mental health consultation under subsection (a) may elect to receive such consultation during the one-year period beginning on the date on which the consultation is offered or during such longer period beginning on such date as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DD950FBF1DD420AB14F08F1861DD114"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consultation provided to a veteran under this section shall not be construed as a determination that any disability of such veteran is service-connected for the purposes of any benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H084A68C74B464BC690FA2491C7AC1BF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 11 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57CA4F4D538C42588A7BA724852D06EC"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">1167. Mental health consultations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF610F088CA7D4A7D8D70985301DF357B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mental health consultations for veterans entering Homeless Programs Office programs</header><paragraph id="HC3C2074709D8414283EB2DF20F3F3825"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section: </text><quoted-block id="H21AA7866C7444132978A82B530A13209" style="USC" act-name=""><section id="H8F2DE0BEC3034225898543AA6974016E"><enum>2068.</enum><header>Mental health consultations</header><subsection id="HBB14AB1C3C1C4489A750CEB8DFAB4F93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two weeks after the date on which a veteran described in subsection (b) enters into a program administered by the Homeless Programs Office of the Department, the Secretary shall offer the veteran a mental health consultation to assess the health needs of, and care options for, the veteran. </text></subsection><subsection id="H73348F0CECAB4645B2C9DB78607F5234"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veteran described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A veteran described in this subsection is a veteran to whom a mental health consultation is not offered or provided through the case management services of the program of the Homeless Programs Office into which the veteran enters.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE8442692344994AFEAC15D483BD6EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F7624CFF6E544ABB51D2A0F83AA7C1E"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">2068. Mental health consultations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HFB8E41A4C0E64E9BB0AB7913ECEB6E22"><enum>V</enum><header>Research</header><section id="H4D3988E111C64D3AAE9B0BF758057B5F"><enum>501.</enum><header>Veterans integration to academic leadership program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H9B85CF0A53D441E6BAF692698AB6FF5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the Veterans Integration to Academic Leadership program of the Department of Veterans Affairs. The report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H95C8541056984EB7A952A58232356E6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of medical centers of the Department, institutions of higher learning, non-college degree programs, and student veterans supported by the program, and relevant trends since the program began.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB4246B91CF3449DA51CA3055C7BA6E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The staff and resources allocated to the program, and relevant trends since the program began.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4922B26FA25C4470B3F4062318A46A6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the outcomes and effectiveness of the program in—</text><subparagraph id="H08FB4FF3E2294BE18E923FA0ACE0A223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting student veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54B8D6716BE547178322EF1518DED2B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>connecting student veterans to needed services of the Department or services provided by non-Department entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA6521B986E432189DD3B93B3A095B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>addressing the mental health needs of student veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF22E2C1FB8794E03A1B7D66098D5CA42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lowering the suicide risk of student veterans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF915745F4664EB891172FDB72D7AF70"><enum>(E)</enum><text>helping student veterans achieve educational goals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19CD527D195545929DAA6EBB13AEDB76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of barriers to expanding the program and how the Secretary intends to address such barriers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB81610433C174E0891F1EB70B093B2DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the program should be expanded outside of the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention to support students veterans with needs unrelated to mental health or suicide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72689D88C9BE4D10AD96058BFA193632"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uniform best practices, goals, and measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish best practices, goals, and measures for the Veterans Integration to Academic Leadership program of the Department that are uniform among the medical centers of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C7BCE62E1244FFAB1ADEDCC56C75206"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach among the Armed Forces, veterans service organizations, institutions of higher learning, and non-college degree programs with respect to the Veterans Integration to Academic Leadership program of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1B4620E337248F8B026B308A5676E79"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall assess the feasibility and advisability of including the suicide rate for student veterans in the National Veteran Suicide Prevention Annual Report of the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="H74210306E378409E97CD5A7DCAB9A7E4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAF9CC6840EEE45699F6FA0F91A127EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>institution of higher learning</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3452 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0981792E687E4320BFFE911F39BACE5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>student veteran</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0ADDFC27638D49FB9F493DD0CCAAD77A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A veteran or member of the Armed Forces using educational assistance under any of the following provisions of law:</text><clause id="HEE15719D8ACA429BB064A867F79EF260"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 30, 31, 32, or 33 of title 38, United States Code, or chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H20CAD6BF9E6F47A6A03F73C82009B0FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 116 of the Harry W. Colmery Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/48">Public Law 115–48</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3001">38 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note).</text></clause><clause id="H01E0932B08E24DC99BF7F3C03B10A8E5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8006 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3001">38 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note prec.).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3F0BD40B21347DE9FD8543731BC3513"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A veteran who is enrolled in an institution of higher learning or other training program, without regard to whether the veteran is using educational assistance specified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF5BAB65BD56441189B6957E519F4608E"><enum>502.</enum><header>Improvement of sleep disorder care furnished by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H8FE3902940114A3284D1B964A1D2E73C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to the analysis conducted under subsection (b), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall take such action as the Secretary considers appropriate to improve the assessment and treatment of veterans with sleep disorders, including by conducting in-home sleep studies for veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6FCADE3E8B054432A54F8A46851446AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct an analysis of the ability of the Department of Veterans Affairs to treat sleep disorders among veterans, including—</text><paragraph id="HA53F44B1800C440EABFDA7DB601507AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessment and treatment options for such disorders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5844443536DD4E95BE67663E4AD642B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers to care for such disorders, such as wait time, travel time, and lack of staffing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D24FB22CF874E58AA65C467706FF326"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the efficacy of the clinical practice guidelines of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense for such disorders; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B12242E58DA4F409519FAD50563CAFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of and efficacy of the use by the Department of Veterans Affairs of cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B11B97968F743278D90B00B7EC45DFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on—</text><paragraph id="H4CBDB12993A14885864A94706736DD27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings from the analysis conducted under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72542042C9BB490CA7896D373A3FEF17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any actions taken under subsection (a) to improve the assessment and treatment of veterans with sleep disorders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H260C4564C99C43569A6557EB1253B779"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for in-Home sleep studies</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $5,000,000 to be used to conduct in-home sleep studies for veterans, as part of sleep disorder assessment and treatment conducted by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection></section><section id="H359A3A8DFF554737B3BC3DA4F0A93091"><enum>503.</enum><header>Study on inpatient mental health and substance use care from Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H1317FFFC101140CEA32A7B290BCF9C8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall complete the conduct of a study on access of veterans to care under the residential rehabilitation treatment programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs to determine—</text><paragraph id="H17276FC8045D4B00B6E6A10DE63EBD51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if there are sufficient geographic offerings of inpatient mental health care, especially for veterans in rural and remote communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7876574D3ACA4A42910B6AEE0313FD3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if there are sufficient bed spaces at each location, based on demand and drive time from the homes of veterans; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C91F911D0CF41F18516CAE84BAB9C2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if there are any workforce-related capacity limitations at each location, including if beds are unable to be used because there are not enough providers to care for additional patients;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB94BE4FAD0374779A2C425F245FC9CBB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if there are diagnosis-specific or sex-specific barriers to accessing care under such programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5180730A3A0743D18964800D8E5880AC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the average wait time for a bed in such a program, broken out by—</text><subparagraph id="H21A86FCEDDDD41D8A8A70A519F5A28D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF73FC053FF54E4A899EDA5A92552E79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rural or urban area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEB1A49CD0D846E1976A92B803E55829"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sex; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECFE7867139E499DAC6A25C338EA94C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>specialty (general program, substance use disorder program, military sexual trauma program, etc.). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H506A1D5115E64A9BA3E6FD70FA46FCD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations for modifications to treatment programs</header><text>Using the results from the study conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make recommendations for—</text><paragraph id="HEF323C8051DE4F70AA6E03D710F1C3CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>new locations for opening facilities to participate in the residential rehabilitation treatment programs of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H680D0E38FF4040188776180E5F685C79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilities under such programs at which new beds can be added; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69F76393C80A4AA589D2B06A3F019A38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional specialty tracks to be added to such programs, such as substance use disorder or military sexual trauma, in order to meet veteran need and demand.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66ECCAAAF0BD423E893B98FE9695D739" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after completion of the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a) and the recommendations made by the Secretary under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HEA256FFFA76D4987BC3EE9A040AE4593"><enum>504.</enum><header>Study on treatment from Department of Veterans Affairs for co-occurring mental health and substance use disorders</header><subsection id="HB6D581C10ABB441BB286A20B305C32E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study examining—</text><paragraph id="H3B5450A6E2004658A64DBCC3A1B39B77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the availability of treatment programs for veterans with co-occurring mental health and substance use disorders (including both inpatient and outpatient care);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1BC06A36E9470B9AEFD0E8905ED707"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any geographic disparities in access to such programs, such as for rural and remote veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA15E1FDD554ABFA90CB4777DFA6B4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the average wait times for care under such programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3708FCB847B246C38AEEAEB7FD91EB24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HBF4CA3BCA9E34A25BAA081848F8E2A03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74F56CA8F3274F398AD433236517D2E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H7AD3264B9B7449148E3A730816A245C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any recommendations resulting from the study conducted under subsection (a) with respect to improving timeliness and quality of care and meeting treatment preferences for veterans with co-occurring mental health and substance use disorders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F7344E02324CB6BE1A06D1874BBB2F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any actions taken by the Secretary to improve care for such veterans. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD0FDE77B618A4BECB71E8BF3DB028D3A"><enum>505.</enum><header>Study on workload of suicide prevention teams of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H8B012A3A7AA04B2BA725F4D647756D49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Under Secretary for Health and the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention, shall conduct a study evaluating the workload of local suicide prevention teams of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8211F51059DC44CB8357904F0FE92B95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HBCF23C7339234A7893E71170F6DBC9E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify the effects of the growth of the suicide prevention program of the Department on the workload of suicide prevention teams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H809BF62D2F2746DD96AF72EE0E0C8B61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate key practices for staffing model design in determining suicide prevention staffing needs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD97CB8343947919F2097B78C01012B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determine which facilities of the Department need increased suicide prevention coordinator staffing to meet the needs of veterans, with an emphasis placed on facilities with high patient volume and facilities located in States with high rates of veteran suicide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F040856BB1649948481E07896C3F129" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10EC0975008B45329C1ABD98B1F73712"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HF954B56AD3424BEE8E7715F13C3BCC22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>indicating any changes made to the staffing of suicide prevention teams of the Department resulting from the determinations made under subsection (b)(3), including a list of facilities of the Department where staffing was adjusted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC39B81C5134347A7B9164F4ECA85565B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>506.</enum><header>Expansion of suicide prevention and mental health research</header><subsection id="HF1DD742311F84ACF9867191C33CF55B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research on moral injury</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Research and Development of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct suicide prevention and mental health care improvement research on how moral injury relates to the mental health needs of veterans who served in the Armed Forces after September 11, 2001, and best practices for mental health treatment for such veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB7044DACCD94E6BA08FD04F5BC7EE9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs an additional $10,000,000 to be used by the Center of Excellence for Suicide Prevention of the Department and the Rocky Mountain Mental Illness Research Education and Clinical Center for purposes of conducting research on the factors impacting veteran suicide and best practices for early intervention and support.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9E01A5F7F2F4411EAB6053D6C0CBAA05"><enum>507.</enum><header>Study on mental health and suicide prevention support for military families</header><subsection id="H7F20CEC338E9430EA027F1D9477E4288"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Secretary of Defense, shall conduct a study on secondary post-traumatic stress disorder and depression and its impact on spouses, children, and caregivers of members of the Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6873B11B93D4D52920C7EB000F6AADC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H25854E0C49734091882B448632A2FE12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to Congress, veterans service organizations, and military support organizations a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67CB08BAC06543C9B592FD07AC5C1DF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H7D746566AE3B4D749EEFFF4E3682BC0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>military support organization</term> has the meaning given that term by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H986CC29C83614D939D7FA1D467F60C86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6AABA977153044408CC829B12D7BE346"><enum>508.</enum><header>Research on brain health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs an additional $5,000,000 for ongoing and future research at the Translational Research Center of the Department of Veterans Affairs for traumatic brain injury and stress disorders to provide better understanding of, and improved treatment options for, veterans who served in the Armed Forces after September 11, 2001, and who have traumatic brain injury or post-traumatic stress disorder.</text></section><section id="HCF942056A84C4D9EA24B5311F505BC10"><enum>509.</enum><header>Study on efficacy of clinical and at-home resources for post-traumatic stress disorder</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Research and Development of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct a study on—</text><paragraph id="HB9C4FC7B350744E6B7E2B0AEC2912397"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the efficacy of clinical and at-home resources, such as mobile applications like COVID Coach, for providers, veterans, caregivers, and family members to use for dealing with stressors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79DC79D239FC419ABBF9A553DED99778"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the feasibility and advisability of developing more such resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62EC044620DE462DB5E912F0D3F09CA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies for improving mental health care and outcomes for veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C023DCFBA504B30A465E3C69321B965"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices for helping family members of veterans deal with secondary post-traumatic stress disorder or mental health concerns.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

