<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42E149CE11C64D52AF95E2C4B6F8C8F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7999 IH: No Transferring GITMO Terrorists to America Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220609">June 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the transfer or release of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and the construction or modification of facilities in the United States to house detainees transferred from United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BD5883F5F68414C888CEC8B16D98DCC" style="OLC"><section id="H7B4C6A69A7AB4BB2AF4B15930D5EA543" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Transferring GITMO Terrorists to America Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8364B3352FE44DDA938464FBFD8DAE15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for transfer or release of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for the Department of Defense for any fiscal year may be used to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer of or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions any individual detained at Guantanamo.</text></section><section id="HC9EF72519CB64CECB673C138B1F99FF4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds to construct or modify facilities in the United States to house detainees transferred from United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba</header><subsection id="H8512810536FF447A99B7D576842A619D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for the Department of Defense for any fiscal year may be used to construct or modify any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual detained at Guantanamo for the purposes of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under the control of the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H58E2CCC8DCC749F98B101E45D3D31293"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to any modification of facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9E1E370858A24394BC385AADD1F2BFF7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Individual detained at Guantanamo defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>individual detained at Guantanamo</quote> means any individual located at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, as of October 1, 2009, who—</text><paragraph id="H925E027A592A42099A2864FC66C95921"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not a citizen of the United States or a member of the Armed Forces of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D12E8DC0B874230B7BB6A25C7598EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is—</text><subparagraph id="H12C7F34458A5497CB970B21772329D67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the custody or under the control of the Department of Defense; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H606212B2766849A68B49935A6768FA51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise under detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

