<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1FB391A2E29C49A18C0E3D0CCDCA85C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7198 IH: Chattahoochee River Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7198</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001312">Ms. Bourdeaux</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a program to provide environmental assistance in the Chattahoochee River Basin, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1344D8B3D4824EBBA371923C812820EB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H653BF4818CE64A64A79CA5D02EC633AB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chattahoochee River Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1EE5AFEA7BB843638DE5EFC25C0C6ADE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chattahoochee River program</header> <subsection id="H90C583D098ED4B0098C3687FC1BCCD42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCCF50E25FC914BD0A00208A2DAAD2D15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal interest</header><text>The term <term>non-Federal interest</term> has the meaning given the term in section 221(b) of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b(b)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65406D7398AC49818F2AC90A7C444E39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C5401FAE9C44F51A5AF4CA534399C96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HC7E1ADD252FF4FB1809051B7D8AB3498"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to provide environmental assistance to non-Federal interests in the Chattahoochee River Basin.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E487129B0EE472CB576DA8173AD00BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The assistance under paragraph (1) shall be in the form of design and construction assistance for water-related resource protection and restoration projects affecting the Chattahoochee River Basin, based on the comprehensive plan under subsection (c), including projects for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF556A8EEF02E4E4EBA8A7A193C808DFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sediment and erosion control;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34DD7231960C4560ABE50A8441F47955"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection of eroding shorelines;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECDB4FE2F6984DB1ADCB5C8D89B39DF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ecosystem restoration, including restoration of submerged aquatic vegetation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H518ECB012DCF4F16B6552C731932126F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>protection of essential public works;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D126CBE94D74FDD87FC802952418A40"><enum>(E)</enum><text>beneficial uses of dredged material; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A5CF59A951D414285C6FDBEFF6B1E5D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other related projects that may enhance the living resources of the Chattahoochee River Basin.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18FC2424EE874D0E8BDB77E23157EDB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H4E53DEFCB6B64C089055B5C92E193D97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in cooperation with State and local governmental officials and affected stakeholders, shall develop a comprehensive Chattahoochee River Basin restoration plan to guide the implementation of projects under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9D4FCD7186B40A493E48053EF7853DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The restoration plan described in paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, consider and avoid duplication of any ongoing or planned actions of other Federal, State, and local agencies and nongovernmental organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD965EF7E8694137977E7EC2C21A997E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>The restoration plan described in paragraph (1) shall give priority to projects eligible under subsection (b)(2) that will also improve water quality or quantity or use natural hydrological features and systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H395863470CCE4679AA6A46EEAC5F478E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreement</header> <paragraph id="H5D108840566E4124AE4CB1335029D4C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before providing assistance under this section, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with a non-Federal interest for the design and construction of a project carried out pursuant to the comprehensive Chattahoochee River Basin restoration plan described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7E625CFE4FA40B9AC525A69ED0FF06F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each agreement entered into under this subsection shall provide for—</text> <subparagraph id="H83E292DFED3649A9BB5EBF08516DF80C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development by the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal, State, and local officials, of a resource protection and restoration plan, including appropriate engineering plans and specifications and an estimate of expected resource benefits; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53BE164ECD7645CEA887B734BCEA13CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of such legal and institutional structures as are necessary to ensure the effective long-term operation and maintenance of the project by the non-Federal interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H837FEDA930D74A0A810213FCB9B7B541"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header> <paragraph id="H5FFA46721BD045BAB535AD229E5176F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), the Federal share of the total project costs of each agreement entered into under this section shall be 80 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA3EE008A4774A46864DE687D632EA70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-federal share</header> 
<subparagraph id="H93106ED89E0E43CC853F601F764727DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Value of land, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations</header><text>In determining the non-Federal contribution toward carrying out an agreement entered into under this section, the Secretary shall provide credit to a non-Federal interest for the value of land, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations provided by the non-Federal interest, except that the amount of credit provided for a project under this paragraph may not exceed 20 percent of the total project costs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F6C64771134430EAE384D00D35BDBDD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance costs</header><text>The non-Federal share of the costs of operation and maintenance of activities carried out under an agreement under this section shall be 100 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9009C9D46DCE455683FEBFBF7061A9B4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall cooperate with—</text> <paragraph id="HE8EB400224FE4D32AEE892B12A5ED926"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22F96C1E649442E98EC807C069BC5177"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A706B5CAFF9445295A986D936FD71B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H247808289CA748D9BCE12503DF3D3773"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7A39114EBE249A9BBD1798B9289C7B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the heads of such other Federal agencies as the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD386D3139981448780F5BE7F1BC0DEC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agencies of a State or political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAB98717F987845AB88392EED9770B0C2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Protection of resources</header><text>A project established under this section shall be carried out using such measures as are necessary to protect environmental, historic, and cultural resources.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1886600B2CE54C478E3D9519A52516E0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Project cap</header><text>The total cost of a project carried out under this section may not exceed $15,000,000.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60297FE9C3BE4E1BBAB8196515D042EC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $90,000,000. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

