<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E69136FC3F94A0CB75A73A0DF0B3D90" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8677 IH: Infrastructure Modernization Project Related to the OVerall Enhancement of Nursing Homes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8677</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with State health departments, to establish a grant program to award grants to nursing facilities to replace traditional nursing facilities with small-house nursing facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74C70B74EDAC4C82870E6CAB43A253FD" style="OLC"><section id="H7378226175B24D66A08FBDCBB95D2141" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Infrastructure Modernization Project Related to the OVerall Enhancement of Nursing Homes Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IMPROVE Nursing Homes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFA277D151268436EA1446DB3A7169A06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to develop small-house nursing facilities</header><subsection id="H5ED32106227349B893D570C9AE49805A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and in coordination with State health departments, shall establish a grant program to award grants to nursing facilities to convert traditional nursing facilities to small-house nursing facilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFCF6572A14724DE7932E9C153ED983DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the grant program under subsection (a) shall be to replace beds used for long-term care in nursing facilities with beds used for long-term care in small-house nursing facilities, including by—</text><paragraph id="H64E4213EC51F43CD817ACEAC13A9C6D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing the total number of such beds available in small-house nursing facilities as of the date of enactment of this Act by 250,000 by January 1, 2028; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3475B7D2441A4CABBCB2DC4E623ADFDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each State in which a nursing facility that receives a grant under this Act is located, increasing the number of—</text><subparagraph id="H7BA6C146E2304C80BA97A94FCC2AB4A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small-house nursing facilities in operation in the State by not fewer than five sites; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB2CB3604D0345F0A0DEC2AE420CEEB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beds available at such nursing facilities in the State by not fewer than 250.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC11B7B156BFD4D5B9FB9828964950C6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nursing facility receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant—</text><paragraph id="HFBA1763FA8C74C93951CF03088F56B88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exclusively for converting traditional nursing facilities to small-house nursing facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDD9E99C7F614D50867870479A663457"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not for operation of the converted facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA66718CF7FE04086B9AE802C882C0E16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, a nursing facility shall agree to each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H5448A888CF46425ABAE4382EE884EC5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation in planning and design process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nursing facility will consult with residents, families, a long-term care ombudsman, direct care nursing home workers, and a certified medical director from the American Board of Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine as part of—</text><subparagraph id="HE9A86569A7B84646853C55151E3460DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the planning and design process for converting traditional nursing facilities to small-house nursing facilities pursuant to the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68F0A19E1CF648BB852D419B418F7EDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>obtaining any necessary regulatory approvals for such facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H770126D0D1014B099C374400E014F1AB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Person-centered care</header><subparagraph id="H86EF34F7399043CABA95069B6C92E6C9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Sites that receive funding shall agree to demonstrate person-centered care upon completion of construction. Person-centered care should be measured prior to starting construction, 3 months following move-in at the new small-house nursing facilities, and annually thereafter for 5 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3F6F1198452423BABC06C38BF5C3683" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Measurement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The measurement described in subparagraph (A) shall be done through a partnership established between each site awarded the funding, a quality improvement organization, the Department of Health and Human Services Office of the Inspector General, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development. The quality improvement organization may be a Quality Innovation Network/Quality Improvement Organization (QIN/QIO). Quality improvement organizations should provide technical assistance for nursing home sites and advise sites in their continuous quality improvement efforts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H004B6B801B014A05805377A628FC6D81" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Practices</header><text>Person-centered care shall be measured via at least the following practices: food and drink are available 24/7; residents are able to choose when to go to bed and when to wake up; residents are able to easily and regularly access outdoor spaces; residents have opportunities to engage in activities promoting relationship building that include different ages and abilities; person-centered care training is required as part of on-boarding for new staff and is required as part of continuing education for all staff; residents have opportunities for spontaneous and meaningful enjoyment of simple daily pleasures; there is consistent assignment of staff to residents; and staff learn about residents’ interests, memberships, and relationships, and provide opportunities to continue these. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC434D07EEC2B4D39B7DBE149727E0196" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>If person-centered care improvement is not demonstrated within 2 years upon completion of construction, nursing facilities that received project funding will not be eligible for the next round of these Federal grant funds. If person-centered quality falls more than 10 percent from year 2 to year 5, nursing facilities that received project funding will not be eligible for the next round of these Federal grant funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H013100B0D92847608C42F681ABF299D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum of 20 years of operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nursing facility will provide for operation of the small-house nursing facilities funded pursuant to the grant for a period of not less than 20 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B981B40BC1A4057ADE067DF241530D4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><paragraph id="HCC644B12E35B460F80499DFA5F9B2B25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to a nursing facility based on a demonstration of financial need.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0F8BBD495AD4C078E9E458CD244095D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In assessing the financial need of a nursing facility or purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="H196967D0D4084050B74D563515BA96D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of the parent company of the nursing facility to provide resources for converting traditional nursing facilities to small-house nursing facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8117C085E9BA416F86484E67858587C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage of such facility’s residents who are receiving medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) for care provided at such facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D2CBA9BC11E4D27B6D07F0C70E53F97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the track record of the nursing facility and its parent company in providing high-quality care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5D49F13EE6A4C28A694C4E99D539248"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To seek a grant under this section, a nursing facility shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including funding available for construction.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF1ED5CA66894DB783AFF3CF0994D2FB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H356EE53B349E4033BFDF6E73F6D6422E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant recipient report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, a nursing facility shall agree to submit to the Secretary an annual report on the activities conducted through the grant, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB03D4262FC7048CFA3079BCB76F8007C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a breakdown of how and when the grant funds were used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4EB4810701647198E16C4097EC132DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each resident at such facility, any difference in—</text><clause id="H7E77BDBDB7A54A73ABC8592AE2F84F89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>quality of care; and </text></clause><clause id="H533E35E6B77A45D29B16873AF46C3568"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>quality of life.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36F44D34183D4DA8965CC634F3D4B8CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1, 2028, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the grant program under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6F84E46BCC3E4B3A8154AC78E31FFBE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the reports under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52B4374791294F0A8FEB88FB64327C8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary comparing the quality of care and quality of life among residents who are in a small-house nursing facility to residents in traditional nursing facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE8EC32FBF164D13A63EE39E2DF5BA87"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Davis-Bacon Compliance</header><paragraph id="H3A550B774E2E4CE7A869A01135A67298"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors to perform construction, alteration, or repair on projects funded in whole or in part by this Act shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a character similar in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC89347F75378408D83A060CC3864BFC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>With respect to the labor standards specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A346EBAC7F749BC9DBF709A157A06C1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H46AAB3629FAD4B6BB78E087A3E51BE20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Small-house nursing facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small-house nursing facility</term> means a nursing facility that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0659EAA3A30C425F8E0546659AEDE4A1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provides each resident—</text><clause id="H2697EFCCC63F460F99A8E5C32D1427AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a single-occupancy room with a private bathroom; or</text></clause><clause id="H07A20011A3F44D31ADD8F9DE8267BB25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the request of the resident, a room with a private bathroom to be shared with the resident’s spouse, partner, or preferred roommate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6673D62B70742B89388C633085FA288"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Serves not more than 12 residents—</text><clause id="H6925B24A0B9A43E5AB4F57DE5EE51842"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a separate building for a nursing facility located in a rural area; or</text></clause><clause id="H5FA42E3130DE4D55B023FC682D243517"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a separate building, a separate floor, or a separate wing for a nursing facility located in an urban area.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71BC2C4FC17F4D429C2F72099FFC55CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Uses appropriately skilled staff to provide all personal care for residents, including cooking, light housekeeping, and laundry service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92B2B06EAF6742B0B3F8C19B5B002ABF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assigns each nursing assistant for each work shift to not more than one nursing facility segment described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5339D271F7024F5DBCBA81ACC549B4C9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provides resident-centered care that allows maximum level of resident independence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE771231CC94A4E4DB459181DEE23F1F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nursing facility</header><text>The term <term>nursing facility</term> has the meaning given such term under section 1919 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF8A1D77AD544579AF72C296BC6E1D53" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rural area</term> means an area other than an urban area or an area contiguous and adjacent to an urban area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62377D67051C42DA931EAC0394614830"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Urban area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>urban area</term> means a town or city that has a population of greater than 50,000 residents, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFECC1368683D406182571EB16F21DCE4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><paragraph id="HCDD52004C8944AD99341F3C7DA4C54B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2024 through 2027.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD40C4D988F64324864A69A14EF9C61A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum amounts</header><text>Of the amounts available under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall award—</text><subparagraph id="H2AF11A7F985643388F3956DD4C9F6D93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 30 percent to urban nursing facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E786AE240BB4E05952F9B1D1AE8A899"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 10 percent to rural nursing facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51A3A802881D4666B124374C3367DC31"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 50 percent to nursing facilities that have 85 percent or more residents who receive benefits under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

