<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H92EF84684D6E46DDB3639C5E445DA8F2" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8888 : Food Security for All Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 8888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221011">October 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs an Office of Food Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9C0A7A72BCE14440B2A5AB7F985E4850" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HE83E194EBF154E4FB9067C37E676E66A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Food Security for All Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H00CF7CBEFC024B24822C13FDB5678370"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Department of Veterans Affairs Office of Food Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7C732F58A8F343F9A3B5797F51AE6CCC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H0C80173EE6E541DAA5124F9CB3038B6B"><enum>325.</enum><header>Office of Food Security</header><subsection id="HE36E9B9D281F41B7885D8078D860F17E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department an office to be known as the <quote>Office of Food Security</quote>. There is at the head of the Office a Director, which shall be a career position.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF6F69BD48964F879F119D9EE66261F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0FCBB1971D34485A80D3C7770255F03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Food Security shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text><subparagraph id="H836960FDCC35413CACF16F35011ECA76" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide information to veterans concerning the availability of, and eligibility requirements for Federal nutrition assistance programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FD07D79442945FFB5727487C1420BFC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To collaborate with other program offices of the Department, including the Homeless Programs Office and the Office of Tribal Government Relations, to develop and implement policies and procedures to identify and treat veterans at-risk or experiencing food insecurity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31FC2BF292DA4A6DBEA91AA4FB298F6F" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To collaborate with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Defense on food insecurity among veterans, including by collaborating with the Secretaries to develop materials related to food insecurity for the Transition Assistance Program curriculum and other transition-related resources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D1CE2260E8D4769B26201EBBEEBF7EB" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop and provide training, including training that may count towards continuing education or licensure requirements, for social workers, dietitians, chaplains, and other clinicians on how to assist veterans with enrollment in Federal nutrition assistance programs, including the supplemental nutrition assistance program and the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H313C5DE46E844309BC9DC1920EAF7B8B" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To issue guidance to Department medical centers on how to collaborate with their State and local offices administering the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3606AAB178294F1E8C07CBAF40759F80" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the responsibilities under paragraph (1), the Director shall consult with and provide technical assistance to the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, including the Department of Agriculture, Department of Defense, Department of Interior, and Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09A157D7BE264C9CBF03D8C1010FF769"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report on food insecurity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives an annual report on veteran food insecurity. Each such report shall include data on the following:</text><paragraph id="H2FA64574E4BE44508D6ED29556620683"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The socioeconomic, ethnic, and racial characteristics of veterans experiencing food insecurity, disaggregated by State in which the veteran is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H094E24F3062A48FCA1E7DB844211C1FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Native American veterans experiencing food insecurity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39F8114B86C43788CD4D090F996667F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specific interventions for veterans who screen positive for food insecurity. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE4AC0838DCF45B296DF9DA73D105DDB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility screenings for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program completed by personnel of the Department of Veterans Affairs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F9A284A85F542AC9552D8294442E069"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of applications for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program completed with assistance from personnel of the Department. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51995BB7D6E54C169B849981BDAC3C0D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Changes, as a result of participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program, in the number of food insecure veteran households.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0626065D68B149F8812EF140BF0AC44C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordination efforts between State agencies and Department facilities located in that State regarding outreach to veterans to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57EC09E5CCC64996B25477781C9F2154"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H15D853BBF1FD4DCC9757A1CE1BC507B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <quote>Native American</quote> and <quote>Native American veteran</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3765 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A13B7436B4B4CAFAC3F291ACEF78D5C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>State agency</quote> and <quote>supplemental nutrition assistance program</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA14EB5C9A4514961833CB113041DEF6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220929" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 29, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

