<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27344B37AB3B4EA29E1E3D5D80879B52" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6872 IH: Election Worker and Polling Place Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6872</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220228">February 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001312">Ms. Bourdeaux</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect election workers and polling places.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBAA26C3B6C9C41B8939BB014DA801861" style="OLC"><section id="HBFEA2F9ECEC04ACDA89E89BBF633514D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Election Worker and Polling Place Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="HFE22929DDD8247E4AC25BA5B8FD26D11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Election worker and polling place protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10307">52 U.S.C. 10307</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H943E380A424F4D73A3715882D4E8BE1F" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="H4548B00129974186A3827220D4D75785" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFC4526F2BEB94D5BB76B424D4344B092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whoever, whether or not acting under color of law, by force or threat of force, or violence, or threat of harm to any person or property, willfully intimidates or interferes with, or attempts to intimidate or interfere with, the ability of any person or any class of persons to vote or qualify to vote, or to qualify or act as a poll watcher, or any legally authorized election official, in any primary, special, or general election, or any person who is, or is employed by, an agent, contractor, or vendor of a legally authorized election official assisting in the administration of any primary, special, or general election, shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and if bodily injury results from the acts committed in violation of this paragraph or if such acts include the use, attempted use, or threatened use of a dangerous weapon, explosives, or fire, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="HC81B95820CF94FE0B4506894C169AE88" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whoever, whether or not acting under color of law, willfully physically damages or threatens to physically damage any physical property being used as a polling place or tabulation center or other election infrastructure, with the intent to interfere with the administration of an election or the tabulation or certification of votes, shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both; and if bodily injury results from the acts committed in violation of this paragraph or if such acts include the use, attempted use, or threatened use of a dangerous weapon, explosives, or fire, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="HA2C1F2C258BD416F9201EA8EE11F0547" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, de minimus damage or threats of de minimus damage to physical property shall not be considered a violation of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H4D9F3499A8D1454983824DAEEE82119C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>election infrastructure</term> means any office of an election official, staff, worker, or volunteer or any physical, mechanical, or electrical device, structure, or tangible item used in the process of creating, distributing, voting, returning, counting, tabulating, auditing, storing, or other handling of voter registration or ballot information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H215052FC870C4979ADBB99E729C7C348" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><text>No prosecution of any offense described in this subsection may be undertaken by the United States, except under the certification in writing of the Attorney General, or a designee, that—</text><paragraph id="H1B7CFDFA2F5B4FA69864FAD713748AD3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State does not have jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C717CA3F20422DA78BC2E6BA065314" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State has requested that the Federal Government assume jurisdiction; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31C34EF95ECB4D27B7513564A1EA7181" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a prosecution by the United States is in the public interest and necessary to secure substantial justice.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

