<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HC837824288714D33B350C5F839484D7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6878 RH: Pregnant Women in Custody Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 361</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6878</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–465, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 1, 2022</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the health needs of incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H59012928F1494A6A84EE0CF6D769B2EB"><section id="HBD57B0C6731B415DAC2C8769F6F69BF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pregnant Women in Custody Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H726D3CAECC214ED4AB82CEA0E7DC8130"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7732B6859EC14988BBF605BF287511EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In custody</header><text>The term <quote>in custody</quote>, with respect to an individual, means that the individual is under the supervision of a Federal, State, Tribal, or local correctional facility, including a pretrial, juvenile, medical, or mental health facility and a facility operated under a contract with the Federal Government or a State, Tribal, or local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63353A7E829D4C46BBE6ACCD68D1085B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other pregnancy outcome</header><text>The term <quote>other pregnancy outcome</quote> means a pregnancy that ends in stillbirth, miscarriage, or ectopic pregnancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F10019C16AB4BDCB4B66382366E2EEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postpartum recovery</header><text>The term <quote>postpartum recovery</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 4051(c) of title 18, United States Code, as added by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64703BC4B2424807BDF203E44C60CF5E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restraints</header><text>The term <quote>restraints</quote> means any physical or mechanical device used to control the movement of an incarcerated pregnant woman’s body, limbs, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7BCA5361DF74915B44035E2DF781305"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>The term <quote>restrictive housing</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 4322 of title 18, United States Code, as added by this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAEFF7637CD01413E82C38CF43DAFF4E7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Data collection</header><subsection id="H4DD087296364422B9F9D3402A8A6A1C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, pursuant to the authority under section 302 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10132">34 U.S.C. 10132</external-xref>), the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics shall include in the National Prisoner Statistics Program and Annual Survey of Jails statistics relating to the health needs of incarcerated pregnant women in the criminal justice system at the Federal, State, Tribal, and local levels, including—</text><paragraph id="H0D3B25EBE9FB4A2AB0A31813F97682B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demographic and other information about incarcerated women who are pregnant, in labor, or in postpartum recovery, including the race, ethnicity, and age of the woman;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D66209AA754FA89711995EE5979DD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provision of pregnancy care and services provided for such women, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF14B9E5667484658A58E5D4DBCBD49F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether prenatal, delivery, and post-delivery check-up visits were scheduled and provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C4F9FC2679C489FB14F3768BCE73A8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether a social worker, psychologist, doula or other support person was offered and provided during pregnancy and delivery and post-delivery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C0325C5FE446D09817EC6CD8111CFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether a pregnancy or parenting program was offered and provided during pregnancy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D9E454B4D3C462DB360176E81AA3C2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether a nursery or residential program to keep mothers and infants together post-delivery was offered and whether such a nursery or residential program was provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE53CE85C86EF44C3BFFA100255006AED"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of days the mother stayed in the hospital post-delivery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1947340D9F964DDCA2C55ACF4A3194A3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of days the infant remained with the mother post-delivery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ED647FF83A84835AD614815FF5D4B09"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of days the infant remained in the hospital after the mother was discharged;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86F26115F0FE414B94FAE446F8F5DDB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the location of the nearest hospital with a licensed obstetrician-gynecologist in proximity to where the incarcerated pregnant woman is housed and the length of travel required to transport the woman;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B5E000E4A94E47B3BC758ED4FCBF6E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether a written policy or protocol is in place—</text><subparagraph id="H0342BA1CD23D4461A4036DEA53698B19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to respond to unexpected childbirth, labor, deliveries, or medical complications related to the pregnancies of incarcerated pregnant women; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BF21110169E4B61B252ED395FD6333A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for incarcerated pregnant women experiencing labor or medical complications related to pregnancy outside of a hospital;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05CC6F5777AF4A0B8F9E8233880A018D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of incarcerated women who are determined by a health care professional to have a high-risk pregnancy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48E0C5CAE51F40E08CBC93BFEDDEB984"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the total number of incarcerated pregnant women and the number of incarcerated women who became pregnant while incarcerated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A449E9AB91941329AB1BC31D06B6D50"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of incidents in which an incarcerated woman who is pregnant, in labor, or in postpartum recovery is placed in restrictive housing, the reason for such restriction or placement, and the circumstances under which each incident occurred, including the duration of time in restrictive housing, during—</text><subparagraph id="HD8917655B9014D139A4FD3476F33DF26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pregnancy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5EC2B373984E8BA628BE0DBB85EE55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9AB7C6EBC6F4A90B31D0303D06E6286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delivery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B39D43709D642C2824ACA4842ED4AD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>postpartum recovery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC823754D67498BA095D9CEFC1D9491"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the 6-month period after delivery; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAED8A34E2B84AFDA03F30BBBDA83A03"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the disposition of the custody of the infant post-delivery.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D6994A0E82B4D0BAD3DC14438866C51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>Data collected under this section may not contain any personally identifiable information of any incarcerated pregnant woman or woman in postpartum recovery.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA9E84E0C433F4C94831CFEB150CAD471"><enum>4.</enum><header>Care for federally incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth</header><subsection id="HC0E80D4A56B244CFB2113366D37753D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that appropriate services and programs, as described in subsection (b), are provided to women in custody, to address the health and safety needs of such women related to pregnancy and childbirth. The warden of each Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women shall ensure that these services and programs are implemented for women in custody at that facility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BFD81B46C6749EA91B34F7725901710"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services and programs provided</header><text>The services and programs described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H161FFBD0C03C4A8FB1337E7C5B66CFB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access to complete appropriate health services for the life cycle of women</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons—</text><subparagraph id="HB4A0FFCDF3F7468F8E9BE92874559833"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall provide to each woman in custody—</text><clause id="HD24CD858124E4F19A2F6E9A22C9C6748"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pregnancy testing and testing for sexually transmitted diseases; and</text></clause><clause id="H357D31FE37864077AC6ED491D91A71DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the option to decline such testing; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56E2EC147F164C1987B7E736EE7D7881"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at an inmate’s request, shall provide contraception.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC786B3098A84084BEF11A1561D36755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with protocols relating to health of a pregnant woman</header><text>On confirmation of the pregnancy of a woman in custody by clinical diagnostics and assessment, the chief health care professional of the Bureau of Prisons facility in which the woman is housed shall ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H4335280183D947D1BBF22CBBF1DADC95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of all appropriate protocols directly pertaining to the safety and well-being of the woman are provided to the woman;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7730EB1C3A5145B68C31EDF25313728C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such protocols are complied with; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE27CFFC1E7470988F02FAB2FBDC953"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such protocols include an assessment of undue safety risks and necessary changes to accommodate the woman where and when appropriate, as it relates to—</text><clause id="HAEFF7822AB984094A48A0F292F708296"><enum>(i)</enum><text>housing or transfer to a lower bunk for safety reasons;</text></clause><clause id="H12B15EDF50DC49E1914EEE62DDE0B040"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appropriate bedding or clothing to respond to the woman’s changing physical requirements and the temperature in housing units;</text></clause><clause id="H8CE1CFC9D1C5462A950B2AE4F1996179"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>regular access to water and bathrooms;</text></clause><clause id="HE6A5B26D16914E1A89C0B1E3DF6AB9E4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a diet that—</text><subclause id="H29B68A0F977F4C3E858ACC77B29D726E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complies with the nutritional standards established by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services in the Dietary Guidelines for Americans report published pursuant to section 301(a)(3) of the National Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5341">7 U.S.C. 5341(a)(3)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H63D266E7A1614C5D90527221ADB65409"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes—</text><item id="H4E2554D87CAB49EBA8BDB81A0C7477EE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any appropriate dietary supplement, including prenatal vitamins;</text></item><item id="HA07BF6F573C6478BA486EA9847957674"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>timely and regular nutritious meals;</text></item><item id="H49850D30D74B40B781736D27C1E0547A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>additional caloric content in meals provided;</text></item><item id="HAA96EB1B174641A582913C5AA6D14CBB"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a prohibition on withholding food from the woman or serving any food that is used as a punishment, including nutraloaf or any food similar to nutraloaf that is not considered a nutritious meal; and</text></item><item id="H519E91E9B8B14EE4BCCE628D78C7464C"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>such other modifications to the diet of the woman as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons determines to be necessary after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and consideration of such recommendations as the Secretary may provide;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H00D28A294D3E4DA38C7FD9775ABDFE39"><enum>(v)</enum><text>modified recreation and transportation, in accordance with standards within the obstetrical and gynecological care community, to prevent overexertion or prolonged periods of inactivity; and</text></clause><clause id="H0AC6C92265CE4D71AE7AE1EFE6285499"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such other changes to living conditions as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons may require after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and consideration of such recommendations as the Secretary may provide.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H032FFE2652A440A392362CBD593FEB33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Education and support services</header><subparagraph id="H64822140878A4CF88FD706E2A96262F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Pregnancy in custody</header><text>A woman who is pregnant at intake or who becomes pregnant while in custody shall, not later than 14 days after the pregnant woman notifies a Bureau of Prisons official of the pregnancy, receive prenatal education, counseling, and birth support services provided by a provider trained to provide such services, including—</text><clause id="H2B6C997C5BBB4368BA517A45F90FBA0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information about the parental rights of the woman, including the right to place the child in kinship care, and notice of the rights of the child;</text></clause><clause id="H2CACC9B2744440B1A290B8A2B64E0C50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information about family preservation support services that are available to the woman;</text></clause><clause id="H69283CC4A33B4BAABB36DE6AC062F5FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information about the nutritional standards referred to in paragraph (2)(C)(iv);</text></clause><clause id="H60820CB303D64C35BC7767014CE59D15"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information pertaining to the health and safety risks of pregnancy, childbirth, and parenting, including postpartum depression;</text></clause><clause id="H94F0610BA775434C8A463C961D3C5B13"><enum>(v)</enum><text>information on breast-feeding, lactation, and breast health;</text></clause><clause id="H5D2C2F2B6F1043ACA763DDF8087F03CF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>appropriate educational materials, resources, and services related to pregnancy, childbirth, and parenting;</text></clause><clause id="H68B2C6E5CF4C4BD582A7EA795FE764F4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information and notification services for incarcerated parents regarding the risk of debt repayment obligations associated with their child’s participation in social welfare programs, including assistance under any State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) or benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, as defined in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012</external-xref>), or any State program carried out under that Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HF4D78E6766674BF58D20BFD6C4E19B99"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>information from the Office of Child Support Enforcement of the Department of Health and Human Services regarding seeking or modifying child support while incarcerated, including how to participate in the Bureau of Prison’s Inmate Financial Responsibility Program under subpart B of part 545 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor program).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F476A4230EE41CD8261255E20AFFAFB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Birth while in custody or prior to custody</header><text>A woman who, while in custody or during the 6-month period immediately preceding intake, gave birth or experienced any other pregnancy outcome shall receive counseling provided by a licensed or certified provider trained to provide such services, including—</text><clause id="HD1E564A157104EFBA239CB7CC5DA7A1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information about the parental rights of the woman, including the right to place the child in kinship care, and notice of the rights of the child; and</text></clause><clause id="H932AF19542264AFABAE5BD8A24F8C7D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information about family preservation support services that are available to the woman.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA954A4013F404E63B48CE2DC43C89BA1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><subparagraph id="HE21FCE6572034D71A0DA54527457E921"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each woman in custody who is pregnant or whose pregnancy results in a birth or any other pregnancy outcome during the 6-month period immediately preceding intake or any time in custody thereafter shall be evaluated as soon as practicable after intake or confirmation of pregnancy through evidence-based screening and assessment for substance use disorders or mental health conditions, including postpartum depression or depression related to pregnancy, birth, or any other pregnancy outcome or early child care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EB6DA6436504440BB1660948D6E0B25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Risk factors</header><text>Screening under subparagraph (A) shall include identification of any of the following risk factors:</text><clause id="HCCF1CED62C3843D59A0E528537624E69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An existing mental or physical health condition or substance use disorder.</text></clause><clause id="H2C07519BB0364E7BA4098019E4943709"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Being underweight or overweight.</text></clause><clause id="H46D289D3010F4E0783D144DEDFC937B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Multiple births or a previous still birth.</text></clause><clause id="HBF4DD9BF81164F04AD382C0CAF38B8A0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A history of preeclampsia.</text></clause><clause id="H313AB28573024A5FA9E6D978AB76A73D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A previous Caesarean section.</text></clause><clause id="H0577036B02054A8B82BFA5DDE825EBC6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A previous miscarriage.</text></clause><clause id="HA77FBA1E7F694CA6962BE19623BA8948"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Being older than 35 or younger than 15.</text></clause><clause id="HF711B29F61EB4C009D34268B256E1AAE"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Being diagnosed with the human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis, diabetes, or hypertension.</text></clause><clause id="H339BA7A90972492E8113A0BA390A649A"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Such other risk factors as the chief health care professional of the Bureau of Prisons facility that house the woman may determine to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H223819CA803745ABB6945B9CB3721127"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unexpected births rulemaking</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide services to respond to unexpected childbirth deliveries, labor complications, and medical complications related to pregnancy if a woman in custody is unable to access a hospital in a timely manner in accordance with rules promulgated by the Attorney General, which shall be promulgated not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2976CDB2FA4D407F8E509D16ED69965B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall use best efforts to provide a woman in custody who is pregnant and diagnosed with having a substance use disorder or a mental health disorder with appropriate evidence-based treatment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H573CFC70E3D04F5C80B462D40AD4E00D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of restrictive housing on incarcerated pregnant women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited</header><subsection id="HB0CCBFAF9F464B6997E42EFBB43794F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4322 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HEF9018B712934B868960981EFA4FCC29" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><section id="H6213A83F5B404187B5964092775C7FC7"><enum>4322.</enum><header>Use of restrictive housing on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited</header><subsection id="H2F2954F7C25341DD977E98E479534B96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), during the period beginning on the date on which pregnancy is confirmed by a health care professional and ending not earlier than 12 weeks after delivery, an incarcerated woman in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, or in the custody of the United States Marshals Service pursuant to section 4086, shall not be held in restrictive housing.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC66B2951027F4F868A362CBAEE1B260E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HB08582D92EFF482A9CCC4F95B5FD13BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), the prohibition under subsection (a) relating to restrictive housing shall not apply if the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or a senior Bureau of Prisons official overseeing women’s health and services, in consultation with senior officials in health services, makes an individualized determination that restrictive housing is required as a temporary response to behavior that poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DC00FA18E0E4F9E89779B61A7F91680"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The official who makes a determination under subparagraph (A) shall review such determination daily for the purpose of removing an incarcerated woman as quickly as feasible from restrictive housing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9113089736F8477F80676D7FD00D6A05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restrictive housing plan</header><text>The official who makes a determination under subparagraph (A) shall develop an individualized plan to move an incarcerated woman to less restrictive housing within a reasonable amount of time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F77F8878B344C99B4E6FB5C2E42A665"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on solitary confinement</header><text>An incarcerated woman who is placed in restrictive housing under this subsection may not be placed in solitary confinement if the incarcerated woman is in her third trimester.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A0E6038689F4C83A538AF506FF2176E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H9B967D6E9A5B40EA9F73E00CDECA632F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to directors and health care professional after placement in restrictive housing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which an incarcerated woman is placed in restrictive housing under subsection (b), the applicable official identified in subsection (b)(1), correctional officer, or United States Marshal shall submit to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or the Director of the United States Marshals Service, as applicable, and to the health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the woman, a written report which describes the facts and circumstances surrounding the restrictive housing placement, and includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC6C56498CD31401DB4D4EC1160F00B55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The reasoning upon which the determination for the placement was made.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H211F774DC14747BBBF7894D72C75160C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The details of the placement, including length of time of placement and how frequently and how many times the determination was made subsequent to the initial determination to continue the restrictive housing placement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9465ED37872541EA9754C57AB1942302"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of all attempts to use alternative interventions and sanctions before the restrictive housing was used.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7D2049E4AB48D684711AB68710B9FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any resulting physical effects on the woman observed by or reported by the health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the woman.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF14E10ABE64685B187CEB1ED82CF22"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Strategies the facility is putting in place to identify more appropriate alternative interventions should a similar situation arise again.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0B1B28851304A739A254EFBB012F8AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Pregnant Women in Custody Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period of 10 years, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the placement of incarcerated women in restrictive housing under subsection (b), which shall include the information described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFF1242636794C5BA807A0D50EC7A7F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after the confirmation of the pregnancy of an incarcerated woman by a health care professional, that woman shall be notified, orally and in writing, by an appropriate health care professional, correctional officer, or United States Marshal, as applicable—</text><paragraph id="HF53E9984C41F4D638A01A64BBD20BBA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of the restrictions on the use of restrictive housing placements under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H339143BAEA514885982D1037D75884BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>of the right of the incarcerated woman to make a confidential report of a violation of restrictions on the use of restrictive housing placement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4847D206F91D4F6189742A2DBA133A15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the facility staff have been advised of all rights of the incarcerated woman under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H754157F190804F95BB63A907427D6531"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Violation reporting process</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Pregnant Women in Custody Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the United States Marshals Service shall establish processes through which an incarcerated person may report a violation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H369FDADC5E1C4E3B939C0E73743379CD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification of rights</header><text>The warden of the Bureau of Prisons facility where a pregnant woman is in custody shall notify necessary facility staff of the pregnancy and of the rights of the incarcerated pregnant woman under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H576BAA71C55841E19446CDCB8E3F56CA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Retaliation</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any Bureau of Prisons or United States Marshals Service employee to retaliate against an incarcerated person for reporting under the processes established under subsection (e) a violation of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H78A577D84ECC4E8AA18590705480558E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Education</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the Pregnant Women in Custody Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the United States Marshals Service shall each—</text><paragraph id="H61B5C2C40A7345AC88745A63E40F812C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop education guidelines regarding the physical and mental health needs of incarcerated pregnant women, and the use of restrictive housing placements on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H522C1CFAE2A3469E9DA901A3C1CCD35F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate such guidelines into appropriate education programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2822975E08F54F45B1C0DD121A4141AE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>restrictive housing</quote> means any type of detention that involves—</text><paragraph id="HF87A2A1E39DA450BB58C607CD1B9684C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>removal from the general inmate population, whether voluntary or involuntary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC184678CA9AA4309BB61DA91F1F43D56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>placement in a locked room or cell, whether alone or with another inmate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3608F994C124776A499B6B3DC7F7DC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inability to leave the room or cell for the vast majority of the day.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H82D3708C419E44DAA1FF7002F4B32812"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/317">chapter 317</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 4322 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H80FAB8033779468089C1E2841BF34A2E" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc-entry level="section">4322. Use of restrictive housing on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H30D2C72EC24B4961B57AF132BA2BF446"><enum>6.</enum><header>Treatment of women with high-risk pregnancies</header><subsection id="HAF49477879EC44FC83FC157C88D23CCC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/303">Chapter 303</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H46BC1830290A477896BC356C74F94761" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><section id="H301BF940F10B4F3E96ADE821F4003AF0"><enum>4052.</enum><header>Treatment of incarcerated pregnant women</header><subsection id="H106129F96F2F4C7FAEB0B87A244E3100"><enum>(a)</enum><header>High-Risk pregnancy health care</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that each incarcerated pregnant woman receives an evaluation to determine if the pregnancy is high-risk and, if so, receives healthcare appropriate for a high-risk pregnancy, including obstetrical and gynecological care, during pregnancy and postpartum recovery.</text></subsection><subsection id="HECED2450693C42ACA389F45D00DC6199"><enum>(b)</enum><header>High-Risk pregnancies</header><paragraph id="HC16F87A7D0534B6D874A141873B9F59F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall transfer to a Residential Reentry Center with adequate health care during her pregnancy and postpartum recovery any incarcerated woman who—</text><subparagraph id="HF98CA34738014E13A3C5302D504FBDE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is determined by a health care professional to have a high-risk pregnancy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA2C531310544FD4A5872E549807113D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agrees to be transferred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0164F571F4D0405C9374EEDAF8B38771"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Residential Reentry Center to which an incarcerated pregnant woman is transferred under paragraph (1) shall, to the extent practicable, be in a geographical location that is close to the family members of the incarcerated pregnant woman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE7951112EC439984899C762609D0BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transportation</header><text>To transport an incarcerated pregnant woman to a Residential Reentry Center, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide to the woman a mode of transportation that a healthcare professional has determined to be safe for transporting the pregnant woman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BB0F8C7E2614CB493E1C3E4496C7B64"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service of sentence</header><text>Any time accrued at a Residential Reentry Center or alternative housing as a result of a transfer made under this section shall be credited toward service of the incarcerated pregnant woman’s sentence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H045FD140C6664D6FB266A63D9126B982"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0A139091F8234E119006E18E9CF9CD1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health care professional</header><text>The term <quote>health care professional</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H82265DB4FEE5431387C1D5B68CFA49B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a doctor of medicine or osteopathy who is authorized to diagnose and treat physical or mental health conditions under the laws of the State in which the doctor practices and where the facility is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H784E0EEF8A644E6FB86AAB58557D62BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any physician’s assistant or nurse practitioner who is supervised by a doctor of medicine or osteopathy described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17899F8B2ADF496D9765B8E144914000"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other person determined by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to be capable of providing health care services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F9974E9792B42088E957AB062E7849A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High-risk pregnancy</header><text>The term <quote>high-risk pregnancy</quote> means, with respect to an incarcerated woman, that the pregnancy threatens the health or life of the woman or pregnancy, as determined by a health care professional.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB50B605FD544FD5BF27D6687C783813"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postpartum recovery</header><text>The term <quote>postpartum recovery</quote> means the 3-month period beginning on the date on which an incarcerated pregnant woman gives birth, or longer as determined by a health care professional following delivery, and shall include the entire period that the incarcerated pregnant woman is in the hospital or infirmary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD98467EDE46E4BDCB3BD3A8A069391A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Residential reentry center</header><text>The term <quote>Residential Reentry Center</quote> means a Bureau of Prisons contracted residential reentry center.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEEC96717664349199B9F4079CCA38B06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/303">chapter 303</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDCAB5F08CCCB4349B6C771287395E1A2" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc-entry level="section">4052. Treatment of incarcerated pregnant women.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H16BC76FD64654E90960A7326EE1E5470"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting requirement regarding claims filed by pregnant inmates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons shall make publicly available on the website of the Federal Bureau of Prisons on an annual basis the following information:</text><paragraph id="H4075889A73E7432E82B28DF5A36C8FFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of Administrative Remedy appeals related to pregnant inmates that were filed during the previous year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1347103914D425D867AA91B3ACB5F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of institution-level Requests for Administrative Remedy related to pregnant inmates that were filed during the previous year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3990336EC2264C659F951413E0DD6F3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The total number of informal requests for administrative remedy related to pregnant inmates that were filed during the previous year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA43345B865B14726ABDFC949971A0CAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The total number of requests or appeals related to pregnant inmates during the previous year that were not resolved before the inmate gave birth or that were mooted because the inmate’s pregnancy ended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H992FC84556DC4E76A55D291D5B29D4D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The average amount of time that each category of request or appeal took to resolve during the previous year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD05455B9C642E2BBF2876DDA3CE288"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The shortest and longest amounts of time that a request or appeal in each category that was resolved in the last year took to resolve.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8F2E9261B4BA48F29C469DED1AD6BEDE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Education and technical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Corrections shall provide education and technical assistance, in conjunction with the appropriate public agencies, at State and local correctional facilities that house women and facilities in which incarcerated women go into labor and give birth, in order to educate the employees of such facilities, including health personnel, on the dangers and potential mental health consequences associated with the use of restrictive housing and restraints on incarcerated women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery, and on alternatives to the use of restraints and restrictive housing placement.</text></section><section id="HF08DB97FDFF849C7902542693CE5C6FB"><enum>9.</enum><header>Bureau of prisons staff and united states marshals training</header><subsection id="H864011269FFE495791CCCF7869C0D264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bureau of prisons training</header><paragraph id="HB45E76445AE547EAB0AD978D7D4DCFFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H148BB7A642DC4527B9EDEE1E262CF5CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial training</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide training to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act to each correctional officer at any Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women who is employed on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9239DAFBBC549039A83D4D972C7E49C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent training</header><text>After the initial training provided under subparagraph (A), the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide training to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act twice each year to each correctional officer at any Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H252334B874C34D4E830A35BCCF606FD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New hires</header><subparagraph id="HE854833070904326A90438A76D47B573"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>covered new correctional officer</quote> means an individual appointed to a position as a correctional officer at a Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA19A9BD2EB074921B4B0CC7F15C4F37B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall train each covered new correctional officer to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act not later than 30 days after the date on which the covered new correctional officer is appointed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F523F8B568C421FB8975091EBF53DD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United states marshals training</header><paragraph id="HFD6D2F2EFDAF47798D7100ADA764D014"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Marshals Service shall ensure that each Deputy United States Marshal has received trained pursuant to the guidelines described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF3C155262EE4A9390184C0237476D1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New hires</header><subparagraph id="H84ED250F8A0C424790BD273F1BAE1F84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>new Deputy United States Marshal</quote> means an individual appointed to a position as a Deputy United States Marshal after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDADB9D488244EA58ABD6F18DC320A34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a new Deputy United States Marshal is appointed, the new Deputy United States Marshal shall receive training pursuant to the guidelines described in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E6A6AFA0BA34D939961BA33DC61390C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><paragraph id="H359987C8902D4E4FAB167E59F5868A28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the United States Marshals Service shall each develop guidelines on the treatment of incarcerated women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery and incorporate such guidelines in the training required under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65D6468988904700ADB2317073FE23F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidelines developed under paragraph (1) shall include guidance on—</text><subparagraph id="H88D95ACBE49442C7BDFE2CD14898D331"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the transportation of incarcerated pregnant women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15A4161B99BE4E0FADC800FD2B5BAC1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>housing of incarcerated pregnant women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E2402B65DC54C6F9BE2EFAE5DAB41A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nutritional requirements for incarcerated pregnant women; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE44E9C960444B985ECDFEAB4BB63BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right of a health care professional to request that restraints not be used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9440A1BFAAD5438FA408D81A8F2B9F25"><enum>10.</enum><header>GAO study on State and local correctional facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of services and protections provided for pregnant incarcerated women in local and State correctional settings, including—</text><paragraph id="H0ED9AEC14519444F95ED0B2A6D381C9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>policies on—</text><subparagraph id="HB45ED51716AD470AB95D23FB73E44C0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obstetrical and gynecological care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E5CC066D280494D830496B7F526AF45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>education on nutritional issues and health and safety risks associated with pregnancy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50162E0309C840BF8C915EFDE6964B94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mental health and substance use treatment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7694087631F74150B7BFE977BBE75F0F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access to prenatal and post-delivery support services and programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB964802C977F4CA49E0901D5DA8A2583"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the use of restraints and restrictive housing placement; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H160D58036663443C892C98E2AFC5F59B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which the intent of such policies is fulfilled.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5338F8A8F0864FA29B487ACC6563C9DF"><enum>11.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go-Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

