<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B3257D3848F49309032E3000297A747" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7781 IH: Urgently Feeding America’s Babies Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7781</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220516">May 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate baby formula as a scarce and critical material under the Defense Production Act of 1950, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H42B29282F5E04755B56C6C3A1F0772C9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C666C0E9E804BD0BDAF94022BB4E3EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Urgently Feeding America’s Babies Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6C0BD4A6ACFC4B9A89063FB8378C2CA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of infant formula as critical material</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Immediately upon the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall determine under subsection (b) of section 101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4511">50 U.S.C. 4511</external-xref>) that— </text>
<paragraph id="H965EEC9D2D5240EA8B4D4A70A0EE75BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>infant formula is scarce and a critical material essential to the national defense; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D2399E6939A46EB960A3B7718664A5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the requirements of the national defense for infant formula cannot be met without exercising the authority provided by subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H747192787FDB48F0AAE290942561411E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Waiver by Food and Drug Administration</header>
<subsection id="H933E2C74219E46A4B014934AA7256C86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall implement a process under which the Secretary may issue waivers, with respect to an infant formula that is available for commercial use in the European Union, of the requirements of sections 412 and 415 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/350a">21 U.S.C. 350a</external-xref>; 350d), and other applicable requirements of such Act, as appropriate, in order to allow for the introduction into interstate commerce of such infant formula in the United States. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H720F1472004242D69D633F271D20D151" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish safety guidelines for each infant formula for which a waiver is issued under this section. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

