<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H1A55E719A0554B79916C7FEF7F98AD42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 4599 RH: Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 161</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4599</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–227]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210721">July 21, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220118">January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220118">January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 21, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen and enhance the competitiveness of American manufacturing through the research and development of advanced technologies to reduce steelmaking emissions, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H452C1077CF044934BAC76BE2023A6BF7"><section id="HDFF26546C09647A4B3B0ADE051D17D60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUPER Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H29C3054F360A4CCE8B2F9BB9DD2F72DA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low-emissions steel manufacturing research program</header><subsection id="H52C41BC68EDD4ACCA32396CF132B1178"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text>Subtitle D of title IV of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17111">42 U.S.C. 17111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 454 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6AD67B5AA8454C35A2AD1440668DE101" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><section id="H0DDAAB09FE7D443F8C2F1E516A606205"><enum>454A.</enum><header>Low-emissions steel manufacturing research program</header><subsection id="HD573489CE91148CEB9A220516EA6D40D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to encourage the research and development of innovative technologies aimed at—</text><paragraph id="HDFD0433611ED4CD3B3DB591C19482972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing the technological and economic competitiveness of industry and manufacturing in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42BCCC6178EE4B2ABEE9D77E7ADE4881"><enum>(2)</enum><text>achieving significant net nonwater greenhouse emissions reductions in the production processes for iron, steel, and steel mill products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B38A94334544014B051CDAD06D75395"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE8076A7F87D24ECD985F736AD46AE821"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercially available steelmaking</header><text>The term <quote>commercially available steelmaking</quote> means the current production method of iron, steel, and steel mill products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D1B4FB6E96D423B8DCD1A0E7D6D318E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical material</header><text>The term <quote>critical material</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 7002 of division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC6E486E5124EB29AFB5F3169223E93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <quote>critical mineral</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 7002 of division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H582DD2747BA34E42BAE35CD20A4B7696"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2234AA0840B7402EBA47AE971F38FE0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A609FC3A69B40D8B609FEF1340FF3F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an appropriate State or Federal entity, including a federally funded research and development center of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD13EA477861442DFAE328AF3823E691A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit research institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB554BE8813C64EE18C2BF8083031F1CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a private entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D574E17D22F41F7A2DF321446692CE1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other relevant entity the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3769459C0FC84E6B9744744568AEB032"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a partnership or consortium of two or more entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F94830D23FB420DA98CED93623AA8B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Low-emissions steel manufacturing</header><text>The term <quote>low-emissions steel manufacturing</quote> means advanced or commercially available steelmaking with the reduction, to the maximum extent practicable, of net nonwater greenhouse gas emissions to the atmosphere from the production of iron, steel, and steel mill products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD33C925F8F14B15A560294EF5C54E95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of advanced tools, technologies, and methods for low-emissions steel manufacturing.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAC72527837F543F7A68E6C56D4F9280B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H3255D66195F144848C4784CC621581EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate this program with the programs and activities authorized in title VI of division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57CAACE5F0F148BABE8F2A3964CAB3EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate across all relevant program offices of the Department, including the Office of Science, Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, the Office of Fossil Energy, and the Office of Nuclear Energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6499A046B3E249228C4D2AB55FDFFAC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leverage, to the extent practicable, the research infrastructure of the Department, including scientific computing user facilities, x-ray light sources, neutron scattering facilities, and nanoscale science research centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BE3AF5E397C4BA5B74F3FB83D6F2C22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct research, development, and demonstration of low-emissions steel manufacturing technologies that have the potential to increase domestic production and employment in advanced and commercially available steelmaking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B30C2BC4FC94EE6BAC54FC4147F9FB8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><paragraph id="HBD4DCD70A0E4457FB8F3ED869FA49057"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall develop a 5-year strategic plan identifying research, development, demonstration, and commercial application goals for the program established in subsection (c). The Secretary shall submit this plan to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCF8C14B8D414802877973904FC71ED2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategic plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1C32D176A8634955893767C4C613894C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify programs at the Department related to low-emissions steel manufacturing that support the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities described in this section, and the demonstration projects under subsection (h);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8905B8ABD2AC43378FF35A622DBAEEC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish technological and programmatic goals to achieve the requirements of subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76BD8F64A12040EEBFF4965FEFBD8EBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include timelines for the accomplishment of goals developed under the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6380380AC3374F5785DD46FD6FCE89A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to plan</header><text>Not less than once every two years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an updated version of the plan under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B58869759C447A2A1A60110653F57EC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Focus areas</header><text>In carrying out the program established in subsection (c), the Secretary shall focus on—</text><paragraph id="H2FD3CFCD061A4232A709FB3AB5D28305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>medium- and high-temperature heat generation technologies used for low-emissions steel manufacturing, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HDB9B59B6A8FF4B428F89CF3A9ED5D5D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>alternative fuels, including hydrogen and biomass;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFDBE82E0CFE4512832D6A7E1298283F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alternative reducing agents, including hydrogen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEE3FC17D1694FABB71A2E28E32000AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>renewable heat generation technology, including solar and geothermal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6D4A1067C9E480584B3F252112812D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>electrification of heating processes, including through electrolysis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D6963CB7E51487DA09EC1AD6F37C5C8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other heat generation sources;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1EE53057970451FB414748FF682A479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carbon capture technologies for advanced and commercially available steelmaking processes, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HD3A6918BD63E4EC4BFAD0B20613999CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>combustion and chemical looping technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AEECCFBF2B34B1E920FCE23727E05BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use of slag to reduce carbon dioxide emissions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D73D81812D4A6383065FBDE9906FF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pre-combustion technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD332BB1D9BE447D8AF2D080668CA3682"><enum>(D)</enum><text>post-combustion technologies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EE454D5779E4A8CBF081D9DCA1FB361"><enum>(3)</enum><text>smart manufacturing technologies and principles, digital manufacturing technologies, and advanced data analytics to develop advanced technologies and practices in information, automation, monitoring, computation, sensing, modeling, and networking to—</text><subparagraph id="H4FB542E0AE404F0285797D84B92E5162"><enum>(A)</enum><text>model and simulate manufacturing production lines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29780C5964904BC883EB8E5C8CA81F37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor and communicate production line status; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92D771A4C22D4B05A2BECD036E4AF19B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>model, simulate, and optimize the energy efficiency of manufacturing processes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB68AAE5ED352423C83E49CFCAB354CF8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>technologies and practices that minimize energy and natural resource consumption, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H70C40B5F92EB4E16B03CA4471BC54184"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designing products that enable reuse, refurbishment, remanufacturing, and recycling;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE960002757D495BAE8C423D109496FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimizing waste from advanced and commercially available steelmaking processes, including through the reuse of waste as resources in other industrial processes for mutual benefit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1AD82D7EBE84EC89981A81C3E3A30A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increasing resource efficiency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35ECC85E47540F7A5763506256847F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing the energy efficiency of advanced and commercially available steelmaking processes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H145FF5D613C245C192B59183E2EAEDD9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>alternative materials and technologies that produce fewer emissions during production and result in fewer emissions during use, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H74176A63CB374445A709043F5814B547"><enum>(A)</enum><text>innovative raw materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD193BE3F414D47268178D795EE4DF0CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>high-performance lightweight materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2233B60195CA459FBD73049B3F4B3804"><enum>(C)</enum><text>substitutions for critical materials and critical minerals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D92A0088DE94C56B71E8AA890DC9910"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other technologies that achieve significant carbon emission reductions in low-emissions steel manufacturing, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC6608D106CC4AB990A5EE4E76DEDEE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>high-performance computing to develop advanced materials and manufacturing processes contributing to the focus areas described in paragraphs (1) through (5), including—</text><subparagraph id="HAD1E3EDE8EE448B6A496070D0772BFDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modeling, simulation, and optimization of the design of energy efficient and sustainable products; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB64C4213A71A47F2A2672F7C67B7D7D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of digital prototyping and additive manufacturing to enhance product design.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFF1E66DF782462590F074A72E2114BB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Testing and validation</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall support the development of standardized testing and technical validation of advanced and commercially available steelmaking and low-emissions steel manufacturing through collaboration with one or more National Laboratories, and one or more eligible entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H39C564ECB9F647EE94744E4DE894152C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Demonstration</header><paragraph id="H50EF5C8F2A8C43398620FC7C137CC47F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act, the Secretary, in carrying out the program established in subsection (c), and in collaboration with industry partners, institutions of higher education, and the National Laboratories, shall support an initiative for the demonstration of low-emissions steel manufacturing, as identified by the Secretary, that uses either—</text><subparagraph id="H0894B6DDF41842B9AB09EED7F48638AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a single technology; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B16B8332D784F449C73D50DC397599D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a combination of multiple technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5E6396525F64AADB1BC67324427E342"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the initiative established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall select eligible entities to carry out demonstration projects and to the maximum extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="H1297FB9F291D4221BC46BCA6D172DCB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage regional diversity among eligible entities, including participation by rural States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H820AD0B9CF5940DB9627D99478066680"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage technological diversity among eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6625B77C99E4437AA1487466118B14F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that specific projects selected—</text><clause id="H46B8C94B9DA145A99111AB5EEA7A54DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expand on the existing technology demonstration programs of the Department; and</text></clause><clause id="HB1FEB852F51A422581A21FF8F6188221"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prioritize projects that leverage matching funds from non-Federal sources.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA645A49673F44F7BB2556F77AAD2767F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate—</text><subparagraph id="H12EE079FB5EF41A8B54B7E1B87E676FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every two years for the duration of the demonstration initiative under this subsection, a report describing the performance of the initiative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC299167AFBD64ADB8E4278A549FBAD93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the initiative established under this subsection is terminated, an assessment of the success of, and education provided by, the measures carried out by recipients of financial assistance under the initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5444E0E3FB44F4D8607942FBCD0065D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Additional coordination</header><paragraph id="H6174C930CA554A00BFF3B8D4E89826B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturing U.S.A.</header><text>In carrying out this section the Secretary shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="HD125652A76D4473D816AE0BA673F18A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leveraging the resources of relevant existing Manufacturing USA Institutes described in section 34(d) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s(d)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7474C75796744E3FAAF0CBDBEAF6DFD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrating program activities into a relevant existing Manufacturing USA Institute; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB94A03A1EE44CCDBE5344E259ECCD57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing a new institute focused on low-emissions steel manufacturing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7464C1D005A423F844A36BCFD204073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other Federal agencies</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with other Federal agencies that are carrying out research and development initiatives to increase industrial competitiveness and achieve significant net nonwater greenhouse emissions reductions through low-emissions steel manufacturing, including the Department of Defense, Department of Transportation, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HED0A3206C3E544F29753E4845AD9FD3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>Section 1(b) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17001">42 U.S.C. 17001</external-xref> note) is amended in the table of contents by inserting after the item relating to section 454 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H789E576820EB4A61AC85585D21463DB2" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 454A. Low-Emissions Steel Manufacturing Research Program. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

