<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF96B00B04D704F3B94AF3E29C4C46A5F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7656 IH: Stop Reckless Student Loan Actions Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003 to strike the Secretary’s unilateral authority during a national emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF4B41722EAD34C6B95A127BE4820F37A" style="OLC"><section id="HAC0D2CF5813D4907BDB939DCBF9B3C3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Reckless Student Loan Actions Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H46CAA6EFA17046C3A87CCF849505E7AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6CE311EAFE234276A2E948B3F18882A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098aa">20 U.S.C. 1098aa et seq.</external-xref>) was intended to provide relief opportunities for members of the armed services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4FD1728C15F4432A43640F271A92BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The authority provided under the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003 has been abused by the Executive Branch during the COVID–19 national emergency regarding the payment of Federal student loans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC46B25FE4D4CBD83CA1616F5A1EF59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The unilateral payment pause on Federal student loans has cost $100,000,000,000. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9FB5A04F3364345BBE39BF9395090CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The individuals benefiting the most from the payment pause continued by the Executive Branch are doctors, who receive 11 times the benefit of bachelor’s degree recipients and 14 times the benefit of associate’s degree recipients. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H236FE8ECB3A64917AF7E67FDDD42AB8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(2) of the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098ee">20 U.S.C. 1098ee</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD004DF9E4A8B4A18BC46E7227E85AB20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(or the spouse or dependent of the parent, as that term is used in section 480 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087vv">20 U.S.C. 1087vv</external-xref>))</quote> after <quote>an individual</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CBAACB273B8403D8809C2BE18038759"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74D19B3AAF894641B6CF5104F60ED6C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the semicolon and inserting a period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3C5E57D2B17498780A71622C3CC5B1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (C) and (D).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEFCC0F2914AD4FD3A3DF202F8B878A39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Higher education relief opportunities for civilians in the case of a national emergency and limitations on covered loans</header><subsection id="H8CC2865DE636479291BCA7EB81FC4980"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary authority for higher education relief</header><paragraph id="H43A473F7657543D883CDBB4420BB118C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the limitation provided in subsection (c), during the 90-day period after a declaration of a national emergency under section 201 of the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1621">50 U.S.C. 1621</external-xref>), the Secretary of Education may suspend or defer Federal student loan payments or the accrual of interest for loans made, insured or guaranteed under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>; 1087a et seq.; 1087aa et seq.) or loans under the Health Education Assistance Loan Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0A7B6850AE45C8B69192E833E37FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary of Education may not use the temporary authority provided under paragraph (1) in consecutive 90-day periods.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1E3BD51145D4EC9AFEB616EE03A60CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations for higher education relief from the secretary of education</header><text> In the case of a national emergency declared by the President under section 201 of the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1621">50 U.S.C. 1621</external-xref>), the Secretary of Education shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, not later than 60 days after the date of such declaration, a report that includes any recommendations on relief necessary for recipients of student financial assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0EA47D80D0C84113AC1977894EFCB158"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limits on executive authority To suspend or defer federal student loan payments or interest</header><paragraph id="HA93A977640D942DA893994CE7B46C9D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President or the Secretary of Education may not suspend or defer Federal student loan payments on covered loans or the accrual of interest on covered loans of borrowers with annual household incomes over 400 percent of the poverty line (as determined under the poverty guidelines updated periodically in the Federal Register by the Department of Health and Human Services under the authority of section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4821E821FB34975BDC1AB6950BDC935"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of congressional review act</header><text>In any case where the President or the Secretary of Education suspends or defers Federal student loan payments on covered loans or the accrual of interest on covered loans through any type of executive or regulatory action, the suspension or deferral shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HF4223B6736614E1DAD74735DE1DEFFF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deemed to be a major rule for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Congressional Review Act</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17F8D817AD344285B67D235E7941CF4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to congressional disapproval in accordance with such chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6E058C6F4E1498FB0B47354DA74522A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limits on Executive Authority To Cancel Student Loans</header><paragraph id="H53EE9F4E267F4048B0FC745345E482F3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the President or the Secretary of Education may not cancel the outstanding balances, or a portion of the balances, on covered loans due to the COVID–19 national emergency or any other national emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E8E6ECE17084D7E8F13578FA6D376D6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of Congressional Review Act</header><text>In any case where the President or the Secretary of Education cancels the outstanding balances, or portion of the balances, on covered loans through any type of executive or regulatory action, the cancellation shall be— </text><subparagraph id="H10D824887AAE46A3B0576980BE5AA55B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deemed to be a major rule for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the “Congressional Review Act”); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H614590946B704CB980151EC2F578EABF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to congressional disapproval in accordance with such chapter. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBDC8CA0BE3B49C88F866B95F5F99877" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H2C27EB5F59B14D7A9511C65F751B1568" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regarding suspensions or deferments of Federal student loan payments ongoing at the time of enactment</header><text>Not later than the effective date of this Act, any suspension or deferment of Federal student loan payments on covered loans due to the COVID–19 national emergency shall terminate. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a subsequent suspension or deferment of Federal student loan payments on covered loans for the COVID–19 national emergency shall be prohibited.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38BC002E6C1E482F898A0104F09B37FC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regarding cancellation of student loans prior to effective date</header><text>Any cancellation of the outstanding balance, or portion of a balance, on a covered loan made by the President or Secretary of Education through any type of executive or regulatory action in the 30 days before the effective date of this Act shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HA86C95B81D034817AF5F3099FBEF26B9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deemed to be a major rule for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Congressional Review Act</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00D944FB85094E06BAA1713179C16595" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to congressional disapproval in accordance with such chapter. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7766493D54E541A4BEE601E329152E90"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition of covered loan</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered loan</term> means a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>; 1087a et seq.; 1087aa et seq.) or a loan under the Health Education Assistance Loan Program.</text></subsection></section><section id="H743FEA79B7A74589A33E0C0611FFB435"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

