<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HCF5FFE027B7E491EB26B59E804DABB08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3771 EH: South Asian Heart Health Awareness and Research Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3771</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for research and improvement of cardiovascular health among the South Asian population of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H4DB47133B7C84E1C9EBC65CBD7914EF0"> 
<section id="HF6FEC6CD6E3341B6896BF39DD8BDF396" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>South Asian Heart Health Awareness and Research Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H112338D0A263418F8E6C7A4D4A2503BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Heart health promotion grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317U (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-23">42 U.S.C. 247b–23</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block id="H5B914C9F87CC4AC5BFED07C0DFA2EDB8" style="OLC">
<section id="H1AAC9997588C4EAE8B8701EEECE23258"><enum>317V.</enum><header>Heart health promotion grants</header>
<subsection id="HC1EC307871754816B677F115C8281072"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make grants to States for the purpose of promoting awareness of the increasing prevalence of heart disease, including, where appropriate, its relationship to type 2 diabetes, in communities disproportionately affected by heart disease such as South Asian communities in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA56D3DE804034B8FB2BA54225F27E327"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use such grant funds—</text>
<paragraph id="H93CD0C79D6024E5D833C63271413DB5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop culturally appropriate materials on evidence-based heart health promotion topics, such as nutrition education, optimal diet plans, and programs for regular exercise;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AA4F62F683A4944B1AED59000D297FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support heart health promotion activities of community organizations that work with or serve communities disproportionately affected by heart disease, such as South Asian communities in the United States; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDEA87B977533476DA85ABBCE5900BC23"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support, with respect to research conducted relating to heart disease, conferences and workshops on how practices, methodologies, and designs of such research should be changed to include in such research more members of communities disproportionately affected by heart disease, such as South Asian communities in the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H272433CE329F4775B5F91B0CDF1DD113"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header> <paragraph id="HEB7720888F14474D9CDD4705EAE02469"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study on relationship between certain rates of morbidity and mortality as a result of heart disease in at-risk populations</header> <subparagraph id="HABB64B1BBE0B416F8C0DFEE730CB037D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or, if the National Academies decline to enter into the agreement, another appropriate entity) under which the National Academies (or other appropriate entity) will conduct a study of the relationship between COVID–19 and rates of morbidity and mortality as a result of heart disease in at-risk populations, such as South Asian communities in the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4D1E36B0D37B49718247FBD887C3ABDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of the study under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D9361A119EA4AE48A0C5670D5923570"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on outreach</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on outreach efforts and data relating to heart disease in communities disproportionately affected by heart disease, such as South Asian communities in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8468E8D692F0471DBF7611E033F47904"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HD800A22D91A241C7BC5CC3071F7EE2E0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Heart health research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block id="H43372EC8E8D84401A4C08470C1B7CD65" style="OLC">
<section id="HE8F30D98D4E644BFBEEF9CDDDE272746"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Heart health research</header>
<subsection id="HAFE26322AB5F4D5FB4E0200BCCDDA314"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H1D485A529C1B4966A46297237BC91604"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct or support research and related activities regarding cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, and other heart health-related ailments among at-risk populations, including South Asian communities in the United States; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E58A49CFCDD49B08738D7299BB7EF8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an internet clearinghouse to catalog existing evidence-based heart health research and treatment options for communities disproportionately affected by heart disease, such as South Asian communities in the United States, to prevent, treat, or reverse heart disease and diabetes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA5D9E3888A874246BB4FFAE2E8A1AE69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220727" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


