<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7756C800845B40D8A5BAF8612D23FD6C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8315 IH: HARD ROCK Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8315</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize certain actions to address domestic industrial base shortfalls, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A208F714474443D961C3B57BED2CA72" style="OLC"><section id="H49523F1F7EAC4141BE882EBE8C3082FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Acceleration of Recovering Deposits and Renewing Onshore Critical Keystones Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote>HARD ROCK Act of 2022</quote>.</text></section><section id="HED3BB7EC9FD44DA7B01D759282EAC900"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to acquire materials for National Defense Stockpile to address shortfalls</header><subsection id="H3838C1E4D3D246EA8362BC7D2C2C1960"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification of acquisition authority</header><text>Section 5 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98d">50 U.S.C. 98d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4EC9BD4E9D5B476A9E85206733F2E98D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H86EE7F3CF1A842DD982CC0DA95DADFAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HCF8B9544DC3749C497AA8CC04C89E25F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>under the authority of paragraph (3) or</quote> after <quote>Except for acquisitions made</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCBA00ED5DB9E422FAD42317987739FF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>for such acquisition</quote> and inserting <quote>for any acquisition of materials under this Act</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD60A3D6BE74A47ACA38185DF688FF9AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>any such transaction</quote> and inserting <quote>any transaction</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8542BEC243034F76A07AC3063EEBE687"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF0263DF4FAC64B108CEC15B06AB91117" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2072ADC58AF4423BBDF5BBBC7C13A8A7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Using funds available in the National Defense Stockpile Transaction Fund established under section 9, the National Defense Stockpile Manager may acquire materials determined to be strategic and critical under section 3(a) without regard to the requirement of the first sentence of paragraph (1) if the Stockpile Manager determines there is a shortfall of such materials in the stockpile.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A4E9E10B4B34D8483F613EC17DCACC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>to carry out the purposes for which appropriated for a period of two fiscal years, if so provided in appropriation Acts</quote> and inserting <quote>until expended, unless otherwise provided in appropriations Acts</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8667CAA7D3354168825E08A016898BC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification that stockpile may not be used for budgetary purposes</header><text>Section 2(c) of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98">50 U.S.C. 98(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>is not to be used</quote> and inserting <quote>shall not be used</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD05F69F6910345978358732D0A5AD23F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text>Section 11 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98h-2">50 U.S.C. 98h–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA10BD5C0CFF14DBD8EDF29189E450A14" style="OLC"><subsection id="H46C7E013FE0E4371860196CC0A3E24B3"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE6A7B3EBFFA449DD95A2E4C55014D845"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after submitting a report required by subsection (a), the National Defense Stockpile Manager shall brief the committees specified in paragraph (2) on the state of the stockpile and the acquisitions intended to be made within the next fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4350DBBA7E34CE6AB7EB2A905B50C1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The committees specified in this paragraph are—</text><subparagraph id="HF27C1D3C1B4D4A68A10B6A2E12CB1A11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497D3DF01C0A46FAA8976F80B5F77C88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HD572F8C02A95487E8D6FE9520BE6DD63" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increased threshold for actions to remedy certain domestic industrial base shortfalls</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303(a)(6) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4533">50 U.S.C. 4533(a)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1797F6C5B60F41349244174A8246A0F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="HF48AB7211DF3456780093A35B96A41A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>If the taking</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H13B5DF7D95F24BD7AFD8520C28114AA5" style="OLC"><clause id="H62DD7EFF5DFA415FB1ABE832BBBF4E32"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the taking</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D2DB5DEA4674663BE6C0D02DC7BAFD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$50,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>the amount specified in clause (ii)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78D79D02AE164A8C8091CB1A987325A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H28D3C45433D5440AAAD2F4FD2E2483DA" style="OLC"><clause id="HC7C2E2F59FB64564AACC661FEDF65340"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount specified</header><text>The amount specified in this clause is—</text><subclause id="HE5478D0524AC4577BAF5889D870D5DD7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in subclause (II), $50,000,000; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7021252917F543E7877349C4698388B8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a domestic industrial base shortfall relating to an industrial resource described in clause (iii), $350,000,000.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7B4DCABEFF104CC7954F212E7A929E64"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Industrial resources described</header><text>An industrial resource described in this clause is any of the following:</text><subclause id="HE5FEFC7BC4384F1AA4E303FDC831FA0D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A material determined to be a strategic and critical material under section 3(a) of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98b">50 U.S.C. 98b(a)</external-xref>) with respect to which the National Defense Stockpile has a shortfall of more than $100,000,000, as demonstrated by the most recent report required by section 11 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98h-2">50 U.S.C. 98h–2</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H86D0B69F4F60454EAC7E5FA3EB4E9A8F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Any industrial resource necessary for the production, separation, or processing of a critical mineral (as defined in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0714E09635124C459203016DAEABA8D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H569DF50E0D1D451A811605F086602EF5" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H090CD70DFD2249AE9C02A1686D4BF880"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>If entering into an obligation under this section to correct an industrial resource shortfall would cause the aggregate outstanding amount of all such obligations for such industrial resource shortfall to exceed $50,000,000, no such obligation may be entered until the President provides a briefing to Congress on the nature of the shortfall and the action or actions necessary to mitigate the shortfall.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H75B56C825E25479BBC4BA7FD9D0621C2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on modifications to national technology and industrial base</header><subsection id="H8D48D703732A4C0297AFFF6F9A87AB39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 1, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the benefits and risks of potential legislative proposals to increase the availability of strategic and critical materials that are, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, sourced primarily from the People’s Republic of China or the Russian Federation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FD2E39B1BA240CF8A8C455AC5AA3430"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include an assessment of the following:</text><paragraph id="HC6697DC3B3964318B8B3C8B5478942F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The implications of modifying the term <term>domestic source</term> for purposes of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) to <quote>domestic and allied source</quote> and including business concerns in Canada, the United Kingdom, and Australia in the definition of that term.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D0AD7DFEEF14070AA86849ACE2D43F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The benefits of facilitating more effective integration of the national technology and industrial base with the technology and industrial bases of countries that are allies or partners of the United States with respect to technology transfer, socioeconomic procurement requirements, and export controls.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB61437D085ED4BF5BE167C30C8F689B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF476449ED3E14C90AE96B226B9D40132"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6552E7A51262414AB0E3EB9CFEE455DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National technology and industrial base</header><text>The term <term>national technology and industrial base</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4801 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1981D9ED61C24D7EAA8E264F249D4B48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategic and critical materials</header><text>The term <term>strategic and critical materials</term> has the meaning given that term in section 12 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98h-3">50 U.S.C. 98h–3</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

