<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09A58D1918A74D7FA06591DFB0E9DF31" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9629 IH: Corporate Responsibility and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9629</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on employers whose employees receive certain Federal benefits.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD91D6411F4FC40AC9829C1519E6B7F83" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H14CE638AFC3A4CC58E3AA915EB222013" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corporate Responsibility and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3134C296A0044036BD9F32367C021307"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax on employers with employees receiving certain Federal benefits</header> <subsection id="H41DFF9A69C844E9FB46F6528E937708F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after chapter 36 the following new chapter:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC95BB2272FBF4E629289247DFE804CEC" style="OLC">
<chapter id="HD708A3AB44904A608149B0CB34FDA0BE"><enum>37</enum><header>Employers with employees receiving certain Federal benefits</header>
<section id="HB18F766BB4354DB981075D3B786DD763"><enum>4501.</enum><header>Employers with employees receiving certain Federal benefits</header>
<subsection id="HBEB04FBE8ED649CCBFA64FD721CA3ECB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of corporate welfare tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed on each large employer a tax equal to 100 percent of the qualified employee benefits with respect to such employer for the taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA6895806C2C418D8F8607E3C6F2998D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Large employer</header> <paragraph id="H4ACD9FD1E82F4CC5AEE34E47DE102A75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>large employer</term> means, with respect to a calendar year, an employer who employed an average of at least 500 full-time employees on business days during the preceding calendar year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95C1703799A243B7B8A76FA099DD09A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules for determining employer size</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H22D8F4630B2A480C8B45977918A1B881"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application of aggregation rule for employers</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be treated as 1 employer.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3542CE29C3ED4C91A2855E7395085BC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Full-time equivalents treated as full-time employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely for purposes of determining whether an employer is a large employer under this paragraph, an employer shall, in addition to the number of full-time employees for any month otherwise determined, include for such month a number of full-time employees determined by dividing the aggregate number of hours of service of employees who are not full-time employees for the month by 120.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9D699368D1D4A3DAD37E8D07A54FC61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Employers not in existence in preceding year</header><text>In the case of an employer which was not in existence throughout the preceding calendar year, the determination of whether such employer is a large employer shall be based on the average number of employees that it is reasonably expected such employer will employ on business days in the current calendar year.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H82919BD7612B4FAFA8CB36B91E44AC85"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Predecessors</header><text>Any reference in this subsection to an employer shall include a reference to any predecessor of such employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8582C507B0A54CFABA0D276F0D554866"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certain employers exempt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), an employer shall not be considered a large employer if—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5AF6F5AC1F5648F9B2FD2FA07D3E7C42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such employer pays all employees a wage of $15 per hour (or the salaried equivalent) or more, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA2AED771B9A4B34B42C79FE7C2D1DF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such employer holds less than $100 million in assets. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1875FD69493F46559D48B344D5BB7EE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified employee benefits</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4198C19497F64A42BA6A28E7C15C66D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified employee benefits</term> means, with respect to a person for a taxable year, the sum the qualified Federal benefits for which individuals who are employees of such person for such taxable year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4487DE9BE7F14888A2D3F408ACC31004"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified Federal benefits</header><text>The term <term>qualified Federal benefits</term> means, with respect to an individual, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2A4BA67A15C2402087F6C10341D26727"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dollar value of supplemental nutrition assistance for which the household (as defined in section 3(m) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008) that includes such individual is eligible.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H535B4B44C2A64AEC990F219F707FD284"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dollar value of meals that such individual or dependents of such individual are eligible for under the school lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the school breakfast program under section 4 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FC08C37F20649E0B4BDC72D6DDA1599"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of the monthly assistance payments for rental of a dwelling unit that the household of such individual was a member of is eligible to have made of its behalf pursuant to section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H13D54BFFB8AA4FA2876519CED6BF3BFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of payments made under section 1903 of the Social Security Act with respect to expenditures made by a State under a State Medicaid plan under title XIX of such Act (or a waiver of such plan) for medical assistance for such individual or for dependents of such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB45F49F9C92443EBA7BF8965469EBCA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>employee</quote> means—</text>
<paragraph id="HF29A97BC129A43BB997EAB9903543C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any full-time or part-time employee, </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7B5E611C7FC402196EFDFC90ABA3F6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any individual who is a full-time or part-time independent contractor (including any employee of such independent contractor) and provides services to the employer, unless—</text>
<subparagraph id="H352E4588124A4CBC80CA7C3495A459A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual is free from control and direction in connection with the performance of the service, both under the contract for the performance of service and in fact, </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36725C45692D4F20B21748D27A3CE7B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the service is performed outside the usual course of the business of the employer, and </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9181D27CDDE8497FA48EC8AA1881F298"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the individual is customarily engaged in an independently established trade, occupation, professor or business of the same nature as that involved in the service performed, and </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF93B8E32FD3B49DF95AE6C1863CB126B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any individual who is a full-time or part-time joint employee, provided that the employer possess, reserves, or exercises sufficient direct or indirect control over the essential terms and conditions of employment of such employee.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H81EEA38A8CFF49459CE4028531513812"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this chapter.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDF3F0AC6C64543C7A7A2DAEE0836C966"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of chapters for subtitle D of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 36 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B51C5D133C5407CB4F052519ECAC6E7" style="OLC">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="chapter">Chapter 37—Employers with employees receiving certain Federal benefits</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H1E030FABA2F74D2AAF2E007D41E943D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act apply with respect to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2022.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE9EC04815B8A41B5B18DF89309D99D45"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful employment practices related to Federal benefits of applicants</header> <subsection id="HDEE85A7F48CB45949E547A950371BCB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be an unlawful employment practice for any large employer (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4501">section 4501(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) to make inquiries of an applicant for employment, or otherwise seek information about such an applicant (including through the use of any form or application), relating to whether such applicant receives Federal benefits.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H36E5DD2235E348949C6355A1AB21E495"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as, and enforced by the Secretary of Labor in the same manner as, a violation of section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>), except that for purposes of section 15(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215(b)</external-xref>), the employer shall be liable to the individual alleging the violation for any lost wages due the individual and an additional equal amount of liquidated damages.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

