<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BF15B918753495AB2D7720CDE033487" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8729 IH: Debt Cancellation Accountability Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220819">August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000479">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent class-based loan forgiveness for Federal student loans under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 without the explicit appropriation of funds by Congress for such purpose.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H05E6ABCB8F804F6A80962DFF6B39FB9B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A25BE40FD7844EF97A2B353738FED90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Debt Cancellation Accountability Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H592B9CC814E748AFBC06CD8C15CC843A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on class-based loan forgiveness without proper approval</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAF03FDB4B3C44B9893840EC0EF94789">
<section id="H0097ADD2A3034EA28F6BC4523553C471"><enum>494A.</enum><header>Prohibition on class-based loan forgiveness without proper approval</header>
<subsection id="H3F2C02CAF502426FA661A19034A3D2C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD60C152BDCA744329BF6D42B7FAC7718"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Class-based loan forgiveness</header> <subparagraph id="H45F18412F3344CD0B59847ED34D1C08C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>class-based loan forgiveness</term> means the cancellation, waiver, assumption, discharge, reduction, or other forgiveness of any obligation due on covered loans—</text>
<clause id="H9E622B9A72DA4D3FB2343C20FE930BCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on a class-wide basis and for a class of 2 or more covered loan borrowers; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0256AFACEF534FD8A4374575FA5469CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that totals more than $1,000,000. </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H22C717EB326F485C86054CD5E4B3124E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for existing targeted loan forgiveness programs</header><text>The term <term>class-based loan forgiveness</term> does not include a targeted program of loan forgiveness explicitly established under this Act and in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Debt Cancellation Accountability Act of 2022</short-title>, if the cancellation, waiver, assumption, discharge, reduction, or other forgiveness of any obligation due on a covered loan is—</text> <clause id="H52EC022A176C4E6099B4E583D97BDAD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>granted for a single covered loan borrower; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H6BC1FD3F8DE141F8A1D9E796EBD57D15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based upon an individualized, case-by-case determination of the covered loan borrower’s—</text> <subclause id="HDC89BAA42AB548CDBF77DF682D66F63B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>eligibility for the targeted loan forgiveness; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB8C594D952AD49B48E4016C59F895310"><enum>(II)</enum><text>satisfaction of all terms and conditions precedent to receive the targeted loan forgiveness. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F6A4DF1835945E1A9B6C1968C86AB8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered loan</header><text>The term <term>covered loan</term> means a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, D, or E.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0ED8F5983B54428294C5925F026D98DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on Department authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or any other law, the Secretary shall have no authority to provide class-based loan forgiveness unless funds have been specifically requested and appropriated for the purpose through the process described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA3663E8BE9BE4506B02A830442EFC9B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Request and appropriation process</header> <paragraph id="H3B3E65EA1D5F4D82BD624042FECFBB66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall not provide any class-based loan forgiveness until—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD07A6A91FE3A4A26B9BF8BB3185860F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary has submitted a request under paragraph (2); and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD75039AD9E7344F497363F9330B792ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funds have been specifically appropriated for such request by Congress through an appropriations Act or other law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30138C6B3BCC4E96B2F7DABEEA646F97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Request</header><text>In any case where the Secretary determines class-based loan forgiveness is necessary, the Secretary shall submit to the authorizing committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a written request that describes—</text> <subparagraph id="H728BECA8CE9E4B83A17CBDFCA6C024B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of covered loan borrowers in the class and the aggregate amount of the covered student loan obligations that will be cancelled, waived, assumed, discharged, reduced, or otherwise forgiven through the class-based loan forgiveness; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H91052B600A4241FB9B2D27753A8712D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the particular reason for the class-based loan forgiveness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B3B87722743440D9AFC206F46B0070B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the legal authority, including the identification of any authorizing statute or rule, of the Department to grant such class-based loan forgiveness; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE8918E3586944A268DFAE43E361C558D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the particular reason the student loan obligations are being cancelled, waived, assumed, discharged, reduced, or otherwise forgiven on a collective basis, rather than through a case-by-case assessment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E3DB31148DA47B6813224CE1DBE5596"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resubmission of request</header><text>If funds for a class-based loan forgiveness request submitted under paragraph (2) are not specifically appropriated under an appropriations Act or other law during the fiscal year for which the request is submitted—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6876E1556A3A4C11805114C3DD93512E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the request shall expire; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DE542BB71234526B8E763EBE13341A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretary desires the request to be reconsidered in a future fiscal year, the Secretary shall resubmit the request for such fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

