<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2E787306217483C9EC1FFB4C73A430F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6377 IH: Free At-Home Tests for All Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to purchase and make available for free rapid tests for SARS–CoV–2, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1225598EAF644A6AD197CBBD9CF0C01" style="OLC"><section id="H4187D5BCE0644ED78E81EB2AF8545698" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Free At-Home Tests for All Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC64FB3A1FF874449878F9C6AC5254074"><enum>2.</enum><header>Free rapid test program</header><subsection id="H18CF1FCD63BF437C9128FC20435136FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bulk purchases</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall purchase in bulk a sufficient quantity of rapid tests for SARS–CoV–2 to provide two such tests per week to every resident of the United States over the 12-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07EA9A9F8ABA48A8BD6678E9C61A015A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Free availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make the tests purchased pursuant to subsection (a) available for free—</text><paragraph id="H800766C863534C069DD99A8BE7428700" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at pharmacies, including online pharmacies participating in a pharmacy partnership program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2908E71526674DC98E4F05C348A5EFD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at public schools; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3226D23CA4A54C0C9242C91289F8D464"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by online order or phone call directly from the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A7DDFA2E12C45B983F65006DA247B9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proctoring; return envelopes</header><text>The tests purchased pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HFA9EC3E5E27740059CBBC60786F67C3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each be proctored without charge; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53F8578728844DD6B3E4AA4FF304CF30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be made available together with a free postage-paid envelope for delivering completed tests to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention or a relevant public health laboratory for genomic sequencing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3E9BB1C7E3946CFAA01BEBE6DA585A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Materials for individuals who test positive</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H80046B24E3074FFE828DD12A7A04B024"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">distribute to proctors of tests purchased pursuant to subsection (a) informational materials about social distancing, treatment, and further testing for individuals who test positive; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H539F7FE0663A4E3CAF0F8649589A8473"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require such proctors to provide such materials to such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4E5D2974CA04B458CC97E90DF4A8A08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relation to Defense Production Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making purchases authorized under this section, the President may utilize the authorities provided under title I of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4511">50 U.S.C. 4511 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF6B620A0C1AD48D4889D5085DE87BC57"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>rapid test</term> means an antigen diagnostic test.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9EA637F64D6D4EBF80E2EF69CCDB7F83"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary. The amounts authorized to be appropriated by the preceding sentence are in addition to amounts otherwise available to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1CF40B2E510B43389EBA1E346028EAC6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination with Medicare and Medicaid programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H51293EC3E2E7468785CCC0F05076D17D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct outreach to individuals entitled to benefits under the Medicare or Medicaid programs regarding the availability of rapid tests (as defined in section 2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA3FFCBEA7474684AB6B63DB804BFF1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such tests available through the Medicare and Medicaid programs at no cost to such individuals, including by mail.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H076E4176C0F94AEDB86094CFB490623D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Food and Drug Administration</header><subsection id="H4C33FF737A5742A7A8EF8972C8337E73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic EUA</header><paragraph id="H27F01C3532714EFF80D8DE312FF4DD1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), during the period of the public health emergency for COVID–19 in effect under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>), including any extensions thereof, an antigen diagnostic test for SARS–CoV–2 is deemed to have in effect an emergency use authorization under section 564 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-3">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–3</external-xref>) if the test is listed for emergency use by—</text><subparagraph id="HBE28907DF6A842ACBF54374CD4116783"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the World Health Organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16769A8845CC42D5911CB9BBB747B64F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a stringent regulatory authority (as defined by the World Health Organization for purposes of medicine procurement decisions).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83FC87F3510E431DBFAB5172EBEEFAB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued authority</header><text>Upon the deeming of an emergency use authorization by paragraph (1) for a test, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs shall continue to have all authorities vested in such officials by the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) and other applicable law to rescind such emergency use authorization or otherwise regulate such test.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF04C80FD93D4196969524BEA7C84707"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory committee on diagnostic and serological testing</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall establish and maintain a permanent advisory committee to advise the Department of Health and Human Services regarding the development, manufacture, distribution, and use of diagnostic and serological testing for public health needs.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

