<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H35A9ACF231344B1E9C4A78D52FA55816" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7834 IH: Preventing Racism in Medicare Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from selecting certain activities relating to the development of anti-racism plans as clinical practice improvement activities under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5646D9107A9E4F3291BDB3E3CAF744E9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H474CD15E72A34E56968FDCB6D6F20AA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Racism in Medicare Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAB9DD851750D4D79BF53519CF4351D1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting the Secretary of Health and Human Services from selecting certain activities relating to the development of anti-racism plans as clinical practice improvement activities under the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1848(q)(2)(C)(v)(III) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(q)(2)(C)(v)(III)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term does not include any activity consisting of the development of an anti-racism plan (as described in the rule entitled <quote>Medicare Program; CY 2022 Payment Policies Under the Physician Fee Schedule and Other Changes to Part B Payment Policies; Medicare Shared Savings Program Requirements; Provider Enrollment Regulation Updates; and Provider and Supplier Prepayment and Post-Payment Medical Review Requirements</quote> published on November 19, 2021 (86 Fed. Reg. 65969 et seq.)) or any substantially similar activity.</quote>. </text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

