<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEB3C0FD6DB5843C09C1B7AA58ADDF158" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9367 IH: Keep Earth’s Energy Prepared and Stored Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9367</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221130">November 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the National Science Foundation to award a monetary prize for achievement in electricity storage.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0BB318EB61EE4B51B4ECBC50ACF26460" style="OLC"><section id="H5E91855AD0834EE8A2F41381A235C138" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep Earth’s Energy Prepared and Stored Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>KEEPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H514D1752A26444E2BE6E49044681AC53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H70C8815520F3437397A920E3456AA1EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dramatic advances have been made in the manner and means of acquiring oil, natural gas, coal, and other forms of carbon-based energy fuel. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6B7642AAC3E4F068F793166CED2D006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dramatic advances have been made in the manner and means of producing new sources of energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE04A345E824B82A518DF360C1528D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Dramatic advances have been made in the manner and means of producing electricity from various forms of fuel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7ECBFA13B11427C8F16BB7A6E3F946C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>No dramatic advances have been made in the manner and means of storing electricity, so electricity, when produced, must flow and be used promptly or lost.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B509F2C70F4403DA39688723F4BFD98"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the technology and the ability to store electricity for even weeks or months were developed, the energy needs of our Nation could be met through completely clean and environmentally friendly means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57C53F5F88F940809894C5667765F110"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The value to the United States of being able to efficiently store electricity for 30 days or more is incalculable and would free the Nation from reliance on any foreign energy or environmentally destructive sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DBA9A01FAF3439DBD7E06B745692E9F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Though $500,000,000 is a sizable cash prize, if such a prize produced the technology and the ability to store electricity, it would save every American incalculable amounts of money.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD167870FEC714C6B9B17CE643C9CAF4D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prize authority</header><subsection id="HF8716D99109943B8929BE9E43586B141"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall carry out a competition to award a cash prize to the first participant to develop the ability to store multi-megawatt electricity for 30 consecutive days with less than a 10 percent decrease in the electricity stored.</text></subsection><subsection id="H825ED88A307343969E5CF451E3265F6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administering the Competition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H8624E625245648F289A81CBF54BB8863"><enum>(1)</enum><text> widely advertise the prize competition; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F2300E107494C9A9EBA5525659AB683"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop any additional criteria and definitions necessary to award the prize authorized under this Act, with the intention of this Act to be able to immediately, after the award of the prize, be capable of building facilities that will store electricity for wide scale grid usage.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF85EB728D4E441B7879139DE78935F21"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible to win the prize under this Act, an individual or entity—</text><paragraph id="H0C154BF5B4014FB2882B17C428CE973F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a private entity, shall be incorporated in and maintain a primary place of business in the United States, and in the case of an individual, whether participating singly or in a group, shall be a citizen of, or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in, the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF19720EFD764F18A2C9AA53F7DE474C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be a Federal entity, a Federal employee acting within the scope of his employment, or an employee of a national laboratory acting within the scope of his employment.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H16BED0FF75634746A1E537713C1F80BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Intellectual property</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Government shall not, by virtue of offering or awarding the prize under this Act, be entitled to any intellectual property rights derived as a consequence of the participation by a participant in the prize competition authorized by this Act. This section shall not be construed to prevent the Federal Government from negotiating a license for the use of intellectual property developed for the prize competition under this Act.</text></section><section id="HF57B8C0AF7C445F9A1AD03315084BCA2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HDED8FB5796954849A9F2B755EA317A0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB3AA9189B6EB4FD7878B5FDC144FE112"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Carryover of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated to carry out this Act shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8277585C1566462BB91BA3C4B432C523"><enum>7.</enum><header>Nonsubstitution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The prize competition authorized under this Act shall not be considered a substitute for Federal research and development programs.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

