<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H6919465B5149407DB0C590B4790DE0F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4677 RH: New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 417</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4677</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–576]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210722">July 22, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 22, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct restoration and protection of the New York-New Jersey watersheds and estuaries hydrologically connected to New York-New Jersey Harbor, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H0AAD2A9028574374AE2EA36B5822BFAE"><section id="H4172D12A4540409CAE812478BE685514" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H52F26C5CA194462CA654D2AEC06ED3CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H52D83FED9F774BA79E63EBAA33B84394"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved plans</header><text>The term <quote>approved plan</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HDDC784C6259344078633B40E947EFF68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any plan for management of the New York-New Jersey Watershed—</text><clause id="H80868ADE653D42229D707255E825D030"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has been approved by a Federal, regional, State, Tribal, or local governmental entity, including but not limited to State Wildlife Action Plans, Comprehensive Conservation Management Plans, Watershed Improvement Plans; or</text></clause><clause id="HE5A98838B04E482F881C8436BA2B011D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is determined by the Director, in consultation with such entities, to contribute to the achievement of the purposes of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00766F8FAFE34970A90EE895692EF026"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the New York-New Jersey Harbor &amp; Estuary Program (HEP) Action Agenda, the Hudson Raritan Comprehensive Restoration Plan, the Hudson River Comprehensive Restoration Plan, the Hudson River Estuary Program Action Agenda, the Hudson River Park Trust Estuarine Sanctuary Management Plan, the Mohawk River Action Agenda, the Sustainable Raritan River Initiative Action Plan, the Lower Passaic and Bronx &amp; Harlem Federal Urban Waters Partnership Workplans, the New Jersey Sports and Exhibition Authority Meadowlands Restoration Plan, as well as other conservation projects in the region that achieve the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB8AA799523B4BD18ACA9216B7E9CD0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H041F81F889264728A1C4390E9145F954"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <quote>environmental justice</quote> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC95B79764BDA44F09928F5688B38EB3C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <quote>Foundation</quote> means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE00D7D25980547AFB42E707611FBA5D5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>The term <quote>grant program</quote> means the voluntary New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program established under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F19E868E0D64857A6855F2D822F7CE3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>program</quote> means the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program established under section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161E9216DDAD4C288B6740BE6F138939"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Restoration and protection</header><text>The term <quote>restoration and protection</quote> means the conservation, stewardship, and enhancement of habitat for fish and wildlife and water quality to preserve and improve ecosystems and ecological processes on which they depend and for use and enjoyment by the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80B7541D826C4493947C3D3953DE8378"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA890A0F3CD48B990003026118B8234"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Service</header><text>The term <quote>Service</quote> means the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6891ED32631484AA18D414685E34DDA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Watershed</header><text>The term <quote>Watershed</quote> means the New York-New Jersey Watershed, which is comprised of all land area whose surface water drains into New York-New Jersey Harbor, the waters contained within that land area, and the estuaries associated with those watersheds.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCCAEEE6D61724B4C8C1D22C2834AD00D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program establishment</header><subsection id="HFB6E68B340F94615872FA568C5D57719"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a nonregulatory program to be known as the <quote>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC06445099A714798BE40D6DB93626A9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H3BD6D8E29FCA4120B01EC9BED774298A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>draw on existing and new approved plans for the Watershed, or portions of the Watershed, and work in consultation with applicable management entities, including representatives of the New York-New Jersey Harbor and Estuary Program (HEP), Hudson River Estuary Program, Mohawk River Basin Program, Sustainable Raritan River Initiative, the Federal Government, and other State and local governments, and regional and nonprofit organizations, as appropriate, to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and protection activities within the Watershed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F60412B73FD4336A885EF1A704BEE9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adopt a Watershed-wide strategy that—</text><subparagraph id="HAA65A2225CBD48E4904EF7ABDA9C5C8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and protection activities developed in accordance with paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H712C94568CB64C6998647931DAE3EF52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>targets cost-effective projects with measurable results;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1840521A524D43FCA3C2664BD1AA366F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maximizes conservation outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB47166C4C7A2413EA30971050BABC742"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritizes the needs of communities lacking in environmental justice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B213DF8E48A463BA43D4A78B32476A0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establishes the voluntary grant and technical assistance programs authorized in this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C8932002FE04267822ED732A513273F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>In establishing the program, the Secretary shall, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="H8215336866E845E5AE4C6F6FAE8398CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H0E7CFA3789A84607B5E4DB2E86A70FF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the heads of Federal agencies, including—</text><clause id="H144CBF36AF2A42B0BCBFB9B5EB930FB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></clause><clause id="H16E26491FF054139B167F13CCFE9F196"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H2962A28DE21E43CC938754FBC614FE3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Agriculture;</text></clause><clause id="HE4B3BE248CDD4D4485E94F8C6DF56502"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Director of the National Park Service; and</text></clause><clause id="H7BCD9D6EC1F44F64AA8FD7483FB0B965"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other agencies, as appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F585138A6324F84A7F7FBBC87DFCCF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Indian Tribes; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCEEF7DBA6C1498F92F667DEAD4EDCE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate with—</text><subparagraph id="HEC3BF3CBA17D4C6DB80B4918B5521C80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Governors of New York and New Jersey, along with the Commissioner of the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation and the Director of the New Jersey Division of Fish and Wildlife;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC45A44F1F7CC45709523CA6C764E5374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the New York-New Jersey Harbor &amp; Estuary Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H795E7942B32D4362BA607A4F1F8F6DDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other public agencies and organizations with authority for the planning and implementation of conservation strategies in the Watershed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5AF90FF07AA4A20B6544B9DF22B0F77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the program include—</text><paragraph id="H694BF0F321D04D3A8A9CB3A62F4CFF4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinating restoration and protection activities among Federal, State, Tribal, local, and regional entities and conservation partners throughout the Watershed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H677FAA003447471A871CFE16C267C94D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carrying out coordinated restoration and protection activities, and providing for technical assistance throughout the Watershed—</text><subparagraph id="HA6D32175879E490389DE2CE24CC47609"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to sustain and enhance fish and wildlife habitat restoration and protection activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC31127696C44BE93DAF20BE54C39E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve and maintain water quality to support fish, wildlife, and their habitat, as well as to improve opportunities for public access and recreation in the Watershed consistent with the ecological needs of fish and wildlife habitat;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8D4EF8401314F9DAE8AFA351A8B8A3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to advance the use of natural and nature-based features, living shoreline, natural climate solutions, and other green infrastructure techniques to maximize the resilience of communities, natural systems, and habitats under changing sea levels, storm risks, and watershed conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63B87C820E6248B6895138090FC0EF17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to engage the public, particularly communities experiencing environmental injustice, through outreach, education, and community involvement to increase capacity and support for coordinated restoration and protection activities in the Watershed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC2BD10183B84D0DB555E83285515611"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to increase scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary to carry out coordinated restoration and protection activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF61A5CFE18174EC0AF48397F041D2B3F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to provide for feasibility and planning studies for projects that achieve habitat restoration and stormwater management goals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51A3833BBF1C4728B276E8380F550E2C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to support land conservation and management activities necessary to fulfill the Watershed-wide strategy adopted under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF492A77F41B843A588C0F08FFC790CEE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to carry out restoration and protection activities in the Watershed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF61C5E0AFB3B4A6D8DCDD9704ED471F5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to monitor environmental quality to assess progress toward the goals of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F84B6F6EF3417CBE9123AD878ED430"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to improve fish and wildlife habitats, as well as opportunities for personal recreation, along rivers and shore fronts within communities experiencing environmental injustice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44C9C6DA7340498FB11A7C753F928348"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other activities necessary for the implementation of approved plans.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEA839F291A404BAAB11327A417D28487"><enum>4.</enum><header>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program</header><subsection id="HA5C3FE4BD7064D4F88415D401076DF2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a voluntary grant and technical assistance program, to be known as the <quote>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program</quote>, to provide competitive matching grants of varying amounts to State, Tribal and local governments, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, and other eligible entities to carry out activities described in section 3(d)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE7DBA17680D84F939877DC4D3637154F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the agencies, organizations, and other persons referred to in section 3(c), shall develop criteria for the grant program to help ensure that activities funded under this section accomplish one or more of the purposes identified in section 3(d)(2) and advance the implementation of priority actions or needs identified in the Watershed-wide strategy adopted under section 3(b)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H028D8DCDD5D04DB1B7A564C64D52859E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text>The Secretary shall include grant program provisions designed to increase the effectiveness of organizations that work at the nexus of natural resource and community health issues within the New York-New Jersey Watershed by addressing organizational capacity needs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H162CDE573FEB4067B63B84BD2D43590A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><paragraph id="H7BE2E4EADD524CAA9A21A960036F8678"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of the Interior share</header><text>The Department of the Interior share of the cost of a project funded under the grant program shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of the activity, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8CBA44A9694C359F86449A4A897FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Department of the Interior share</header><subparagraph id="H4B53BC905E894D638578B2B63BB64E6D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Department of the Interior share of the cost of a project funded under the grant program may be provided in cash or in the form of an in-kind contribution of services or materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B66A44E255E48DBA71F002F1F221812"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other federal funding</header><text>Non-Department of the Interior Federal funds may be used for not more than 25 percent of the total cost of a project funded under the grant program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1DCC54C6AF34E0E92D96E4D62C41F70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive all or part of the matching requirement under section 4(d) if the Secretary determines that—</text><subparagraph id="HE92DC110748F44F1949B6CEA4CBB983A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no reasonable means are available through which an applicant can meet the matching requirement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0285BBCF45485A83963F07DFE670EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the probable benefit of the project outweighs the public interest in the matching requirement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE79E93E8D42248DE8F92396F3590DD30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HFE2A9883E4C04BBF9003F1E800E9F907"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into an agreement to manage the grant program with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation or a similar organization that offers grant management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H164998255E9940C7A062A7FF10A74F81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement under paragraph (1), the organization selected shall—</text><subparagraph id="H510A7C6A59684E4ABA027F65BEFCD145"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each fiscal year, receive amounts made available to carry out this section in an advance payment of the entire amounts on October 1 of that fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C436DD7E40A414A9C8054175F2EAC97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>invest and reinvest those amounts for the benefit of the grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE19B0487944048C9B3B0E1CA246A87B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise administer the grant program to support partnerships between the public and private sectors in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA364F850F584BA3BBB37769AB695698"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement with the Foundation under paragraph (1), any amounts received by the Foundation under this section shall be subject to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), excluding section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H441C11EBD194424B94FC016A904CD116"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this Act, including a description of each project that has received funding under this Act in the preceding fiscal year.</text></section><section id="H1121A59880AB428FAB46462F5ED54AB3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="H977FA4D8CACB4CE6B3EC6AC3D4AC2B06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3AB74679CA440F09392016A815A46DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use for grant program</header><text>Of any amount made available under this section for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall use at least 75 percent to carry out the grant program under section 4 and to provide, or provide for, technical assistance under such program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

