<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6003C572F83A40B487DDCC9E88741DDA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>89 HR 6785 IH: Right Whale Coexistence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assist in the conservation of the North Atlantic right whale by supporting and providing financial resources for North Atlantic right whale conservation programs and projects of persons with expertise required for the conservation of North Atlantic right whales, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03152359E08340909F182E85268BDDA7" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HCFBC8E33C77D4FC5B0B1991AD78DFF01" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header> Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right Whale Coexistence Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H553020EB6A654CA7ACA58CA32197B5BD" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H4E828307D04E4C4D9FD5DF7FB1F51A9C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HB9B7DFFDA8A848B8AE5537FEF5DBBF36" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">North Atlantic right whales (Eubalaena glacialis) are critically endangered, with fewer than 340 remaining at the time of the introduction of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB26F300019E24F68B2BF9FC124EDFD80" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>historically, the North Atlantic right whale population was decimated by the whaling industry, although the whale population received protections from such industry in the 1930s;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4BC668D7D10437CB482161E30818C55" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">despite a modest recovery prior to 2010, the North Atlantic right whale is one of the most endangered whales in the world and has experienced a significant decline since 2010;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94972F62B12F42D1887913B2D71B94C5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the North Atlantic right whale has been listed as an endangered species under the Endangered Species Conservation Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/669">Public Law 89–669</external-xref>; 80 Stat. 926) and its successor the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) since 1970 and is designated as depleted under the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B9517F53FC43EC917114022629B070" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because North Atlantic right whales are long-lived and highly migratory, and at present rates females give birth to a single calf only once every 5 to 10 years, they are highly vulnerable to the impacts of human activity and habitat degradation, with female whales and calves particularly vulnerable to vessel strikes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C61F59453E400F803B2AD86B5C344D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>North Atlantic right whales frequently cross paths with high vessel traffic areas and fishing grounds, leaving the whales particularly vulnerable to vessel collisions and fishing gear entanglements, the leading causes of injury and death to the species;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E8E193955A2452BAF21557F0D677F41" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>even when North Atlantic right whales do not die as a result of fishing gear entanglement or vessel strike, those whales can still experience significant sub-lethal effects such as chronic stress and reproductive failure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H360B4707C2194561821D4060137CECCC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><text>this ongoing decline due to human impacts resulted in a further 30 percent decline in the population between 2019 and 2020 resulting in the lowest population estimate in the past 2 decades; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9576E236B7B245A9A9D4A01730EBA3CF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><text>based on the current rate of mortality of North Atlantic right whales, and because of the small number of breeding females in the population and low birth rates, recent analysis suggests the species will lose its ability to recover in merely a few decades if human-caused mortality is not reduced immediately;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1472B32424740C49D6398AC1D2D9C1F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(10)</enum><text>under the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>), United States fishermen in certain locations have been required to modify their fishing gear and behavior to minimize the likelihood of entanglements, including by using sinking groundlines, having weak links in buoy lines, using multiple traps per buoy, appropriately marking fishing gear, and complying with seasonal area-specific closures in North Atlantic right whale habitats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4BBC03A9E2D494692A33EB7144377F0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(11)</enum><text>vessels in United States waters that are 65 feet or more in length have been required to comply with a seasonal 10-knot speed limit in certain locations to reduce the threat of vessel collisions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD94F2A76E7240FF8C79265E80E19138" changed="not-changed"><enum>(12)</enum><text>ongoing mortalities, driven in part by shifts in North Atlantic right whale distribution caused by climate change, indicate that additional actions are necessary to reverse this species’ population decline. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCCBFB8F2D9E478A9A37B0A6FBADE966" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H5A27590F42004B4F8D91E8E94D909A61" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Governments of the United States and Canada must work together to reduce lethal and sub-lethal effects of human activities on North Atlantic right whales; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE68972D32A4644469CB3A645228FAC27" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effectively addressing the threats to the long-term viability of the North Atlantic right whales will require a joint commitment and effort from government entities, local communities, marine scientists and conservationists, fishermen, owners and operators of commercial and recreational vessels and others in the boating and shipping industries, and other stakeholders. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H23A8802A176440219358D795796651EB" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are the following:</text><paragraph id="HB0350FCAA2A94A1E9A7CB83B27B6E05C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To rebuild healthy populations of the North Atlantic right whale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD789B706FFA54A06A0FDA7428EE897A3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To assist in the conservation and protection of North Atlantic right whales by supporting North Atlantic right whale conservation programs that minimize conflicts between North Atlantic right whales and human activities.</text></paragraph></section><title id="HD15675403D574200AD4EF9778A5D9DCF" changed="not-changed"><enum>I</enum><header>North Atlantic Right Whale Conservation</header><section id="HCB75D62D147A4C9E94D461D8A8478CCB" changed="not-changed"><enum>101.</enum><header>North Atlantic right whale conservation assistance</header><subsection id="HE671E2515D6A42D98464FBB88A7C9531" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance</header><paragraph id="HFEE89B277F5247CB80C7E71AC019167C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds and in consultation with other Federal officials, the Secretary of Commerce (in this title referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall provide competitive financial assistance, including multiyear grants, for projects designed to reduce the lethal and sub-lethal effects of human activities on North Atlantic right whales for which project proposals are approved by the Secretary in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2DCFE8795C4FCDB2C7566284F99B4C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of existing authorities</header><text>Assistance provided under this section shall be carried out in a manner consistent with authorities available to the Secretary under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DDE744F361548F3AEA9D5C8B1AB9D67" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project proposals</header><paragraph id="HE94083FA33BE431EAC7940796E07D036" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>A project proposal may be submitted to the Secretary under this section by—</text><subparagraph id="H053CCF7B77FF4039BB4805112B46DF78" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant State and tribal agencies, research institutions, and nonprofit organizations with expertise required for the conservation of North Atlantic right whales; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1FABD7F6F524554AE0A266C82FB4C36" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other individual or entity, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, with the expertise required for the conservation of North Atlantic right whales, including—</text><clause changed="not-changed" id="H645A914D7FDF422AB88A6EF07BE4AAD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>large whale disentanglement teams approved by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and members in good standing of the National Marine Mammal Health and Stranding Response Program;</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" id="H9DF014EAF1CD4B8190029AF7FDA1CA5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an owner or operator of a vessel, as defined under section 3 of title 1, United States Code; and</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" id="H2BCFAC2DFB0C49758A15D0EB2276D7C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participants within sectors of the maritime industry, such as boating, shipping, fishing, fishing gear and rope manufacturing, and other maritime activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H371FA021EEC34239A5C5B4FD30CDFD6A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal partnership opportunities</header><text>A Federal agency may not be a lead entity or receive funding for a project under this section, but may be included as a partner or collaborator on a project that receives such funding.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45B120D2EA20470AB4B7995A5CEA000F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual grant project proposal solicitation, review, and approval</header><paragraph id="H86F0DF6FC5DE4C259D3B1251C559946D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall annually—</text><subparagraph id="HB817EA3EA03B4BBC9F72FE1CC2A08FBB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit project proposals for grants under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9341A0794D1F4AA3A9ADB22B6B3EC5F3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to other Federal officials, as appropriate, copies of each proposal submitted in response to the solicitation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87F286C6E4F9456689306256E5A4D4A4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>review each such proposal on a timeline that recognizes the urgency of the declining North Atlantic right whale population to determine whether the proposal meets the criteria specified in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEDBD4D9823642A0B5FAD6A402F8731A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation; approval or disapproval</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds, the Secretary shall, with respect to each project proposal submitted under this section, and after consulting with other Federal officials, as appropriate—</text><subparagraph id="H2CB9AA8BE1664967A5143455265D9453" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult, with respect to the proposal, with the government of each State and foreign country in which the project is to be conducted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D08AC55E2744D62B4ED7E610745A587" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into consideration any comments resulting from the consultation and input from fishing and other stakeholders on the potential impacts as a result of the proposal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6E8D6C3098C49A9BF4B94060D2B6056" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approve or disapprove the proposal in accordance with subsections (d) and (e) and provide written notification of the approval or disapproval to the individual or entity that submitted the proposal, other Federal officials, and each State and foreign country described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C8EB7519C0F4DD2958861B3ADBB1A85" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria for approval</header><text>The Secretary may approve a project proposal under this section that is likely to aid in the recovery and sustainability of a viable population of North Atlantic right whales in the wild. Such projects shall—</text><paragraph id="HCC725C61E2514E90AD2C86ABB7DCBCAC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>address the unintentional conflicts between humans and North Atlantic right whales through development, testing, and use of innovative technology or other methods to reduce the lethal and sub-lethal effects on North Atlantic right whales from fishing gear entanglements and vessel collisions; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A70CE158A504DD4AAE85D5BA4E9CE93" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1126D0E04340422AB7EFF0D7DE5CCB21" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote cooperative projects on such topics with foreign governments; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" indent="up1" id="H6126A41D75BF441D8FD62D1B58A06EC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote cooperative projects on such topics with affected local communities, small businesses such as fishermen, others in the maritime private sector, or nongovernmental organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34F3D43199B14AFFBBCA6CB68B7F2DFD" changed="not-changed" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In determining whether to fund project proposals under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects—</text><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="HE10F94F5EC174349958DC591AD5E9DEA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with a substantial likelihood of reducing lethal and sub-lethal effects on North Atlantic right whales from fishing gear entanglements or vessel collisions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E3A783F317483CA304B09DB40C82BB" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that include cooperation with private sector stakeholders; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF429DAB093D46D794691155CCB094EE" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that demonstrate, or have the potential to provide, economic benefits to small businesses based in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2ECC99B1CCC4E99AA7B6973EBBD28CD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><paragraph id="HB8422AAA05724E07A4B5161EF62CF1F4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the non-Federal share of the costs of an activity conducted with financial assistance under this section shall be 25 percent of such costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC07D3BC168417B9D876F65B6D54B61" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may apply to the non-Federal share of an activity conducted with financial assistance under this section the amount of funds, and the fair market value of property and services, provided by non-Federal sources and used for the activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA903EB8EA4B1437C9F9B55589FB3AF1F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the application of paragraph (1) if the Secretary finds that such waiver is necessary to support a conservation project that the Secretary has identified as of high priority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1504B4BA7EDC440FAB9BB00DBD070C5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Project reporting</header><paragraph id="H993F0531928146DA9F5A5D92750E2A95" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each individual or entity that receives assistance under this section for a project shall submit to the Secretary periodic reports (at such intervals as the Secretary may require) that include all information that the Secretary, after consultation with other government officials, determines is necessary to evaluate the progress and success of the project for the purposes of ensuring positive results, assessing problems, and fostering improvements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF060F77A77C4CAEB832F0E307960686" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>Reports under paragraph (1), and any other documents relating to projects for which financial assistance is provided under this Act, shall be made available to the public in a timely manner.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H20DADC6F39844E87B56B9701A3BB504A" changed="not-changed"><enum>102.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results and effectiveness of projects receiving assistance provided under this title, including recommendations concerning how this title might be improved and whether funding for this title should be continued in the future.</text></section><section id="H875129F6E3CB4CAFB024E0376EEFD766" changed="not-changed"><enum>103.</enum><header>Funding</header><subsection id="HD29EEA13BB2049D78B626180B5BF1AB5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H7D258EFB2A8B459AB92F96AC97618088" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this title $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2032.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB90EBF761C443DAD941406F6A4975A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under this subsection for a fiscal year, the Secretary may expend not more than 5 percent, or up to $80,000, whichever is greater, to pay the administrative expenses necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF086D491E3849168EFA8390412D4046" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>The amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) shall supplement and not supplant other amounts available to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H820843AFDB8C4E96AE0C58895005FAF3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acceptance and use of donations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift, devise, or bequest to provide assistance under section 101.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H73F5B371E0D54734BDDA5B6D8920D1E6" changed="not-changed"><enum>II</enum><header>Continuous Plankton Recorder</header><section id="H0C60545F9F8B4A309A766F12C28D96FF" changed="not-changed"><enum>201.</enum><header>Survey</header><subsection id="HA2F049062E5E425389D192E5E8699571" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and on an ongoing basis thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall conduct a Continuous Plankton Recorder survey.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C0D0410E4324133A1DFFFFFC9E4585F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required elements</header><text>For the purpose of conducting the survey required under subsection (a), the Northeast Fisheries Science Center shall—</text><paragraph id="H5EE142D904894AC8B51CC7EE759B7A1E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent possible, utilize the resources of and partner with, on a volunteer basis, research institutions, nonprofit organizations, commercial vessels, and other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF89B535C0D04A46867B5618B8F2A6B7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in as short a time as possible, ensure relevant survey samples and results are analyzed, stored, archived, and made publicly available;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A863CF6665141ABA4D2DDEA9EF7B11C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prioritize the collection of plankton samples and data that inform the conservation of North Atlantic right whales; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H110C02F2455846BFBBF9313044AFFA10" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, coordinate with the Government of Canada to develop a transboundary understanding of plankton abundance and distribution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF970B34F9F64FBCA7A3EEE02EBACD68" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $300,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2032.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

