<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74E836CE4CBF40369AD01B992799C192" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6662 IH: Electric Vehicles for All Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program to facilitate electric vehicle sharing services operated at public housing projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5BDE4E2CB304E8B857B8D479B7F9A55" style="OLC"><section id="HCA7ED0D252FB4002970AFB49A20A64A6" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electric Vehicles for All Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EVs for All Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HD3D922EA02C74E89B8B0CDC4E1D97345"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Energy electric vehicle sharing service grant program</header><subsection id="H69908C2DA284477D9546FE091BFD4094"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall carry out, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, a program to award, on a competitive basis, grants to facilitate electric vehicle sharing services operated at public housing projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D9F7DEA7A0849628BA89B86A6A609B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><paragraph id="H9E0A94AB63B249BBBC5570439EA5997E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award a grant under this section to the following entities:</text><subparagraph id="HFF10361DDE8946B99F43BCE9EC6320D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A public housing agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2252E4B3182641618A654B496914B722"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A local government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEF2450357E24EE98546E19904925166"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A non-profit organization that has entered into an agreement with a public housing agency or local government under which the agency or government agrees to host an electric vehicle sharing service on the property of such agency or government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0765B56986F84E4690FB6739197D77EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity specified in paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC88F154CEFA4A8FB4D91DC424D82381"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for grant awards</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="HD86EC345CA7D4ABEA2578029FB0F11A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capacity of an applicant to operate a proposed electric vehicle sharing service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H158FE40EA5514B1A904BBA56E3CAC25B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether such proposed service would address—</text><subparagraph id="HDADB8CC979664087A0A93D74CE015EC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the infrastructure needs of the public housing project where such service will be operated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H617447D700674847870B052A51B00132"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the transportation needs of the community surrounding such public housing project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H470171E222FA4343AFAB2B01E5B281FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the applicant has developed a culturally competent community engagement and education plan for outreach regarding such proposed service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60E51D45646C48F5BBF23ABE686245AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The economic and operational sustainability of such proposed service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F34E195D904135A1689CCE23A9DB9E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the applicant proposes to install networked direct current fast charging equipment in connection with such proposed service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD16A777402CC4333A1163C30C1EA9908"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Whether the applicant proposes to purchase electric vehicles with respect to which final assembly occurred at a location operating under a collective bargaining agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4855E41E0F64BD0828F80FDCE0646B9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Whether the applicant proposes to purchase electric vehicles that—</text><subparagraph id="HBD87DA3B572047619B129D1B2DB32C9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to final assembly, are assembled using component parts that are at least 50 percent domestic content; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6290B7E21864FC39E0474458797E0EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are powered by battery cells manufactured in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1986F475DEBB4BD4951E57E06E780CD9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Other criteria as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41BD9CE889934CEC99A663B2ECFDCCDC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Permitted grant uses</header><paragraph id="H8F6A43D63C3D43F1B43B8E6D908EA067"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under this section may only use grant funds for the following to facilitate an electric vehicle sharing service operated at a public housing project:</text><subparagraph id="H3D3F920540F74B588B37849DF4BE4393"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The purchase of light-duty electric vehicles that are not more than 5 years old.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB738154F4A724CEA80E85795BF5B1A2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The purchase, installation, and maintenance of electric vehicle charging infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7526347CA44F4A94B77241ECC3DA72FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Community education and outreach with respect to such service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66AF0EA4A0F24382805BA8F97D15C824"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incentives for residents of the public housing project to use such service, including subsidized fares.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA645CE1C1E54BA48DEFC2578B0C24D0"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintenance, repairs, and other costs associated with operating such service, including towing, impound, and driving infraction fines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H691C1DAE7F094BEC96978EE41AA4F405"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Monitoring, data collection, and evaluation with respect to such service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68E29B6109D34C71B1EAC3EF1252FCCE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Technical assistance relating to the establishment, operation, and evaluation of such service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DBDBA993CFF474FA2B019726CF6B5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum standards for purchased electric vehicles</header><text>The Secretary shall establish minimum standards relating to functionality and range for electric vehicles eligible to be purchased under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA46ADD664A474B4C82D9DFE2463AB961"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant limitations</header><paragraph id="HB29F6D0F702646489B4B74551F61D1EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under this section shall be available to the recipient of such funds for obligation or expenditure during the 5-year period beginning on the date on which such funds are awarded.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35B4956345784618896924378F8A94CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section may not be in an amount that exceeds $1,000,000 for each public housing project at which the grant recipient will operate an electric vehicle sharing service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5CC750BA0F9456B96A84F95E2A19587"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, a grant recipient shall submit to the Secretary, before the end of each year during which the recipient receives grant amounts, a report that—</text><paragraph id="HDC3FA40E86514D4ABCA6786ED07559E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the activities carried out with such amounts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82E156F50F874CDBA3932A58DCCA3994"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes data on—</text><subparagraph id="H47AD315EFEB04F059101827C4C0C2F03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operating and capital costs for the electric vehicle sharing service facilitated with such amounts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80346E11DB244785B6124292511FAF01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the revenue generated by such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB4BC7240D344C84A7EBC58E7DF222AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the daily averages of individual bookings and hours of electric vehicle use for such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H364B7C63750646208B51F733F74681BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of active users of such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9C788A67E4A4BC0BFDBFCEAE920F287"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the distance traveled by the electric vehicles of such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B0CE1DF3455492580AFABD77527E0CA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the estimated reduction in greenhouse gas emissions and criteria air pollutants associated with such service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AEA16A6EB634730A416C0B434CFA7CC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the results of a survey of customers of such service that provides information on customer preferences, destinations, and other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H808EB34250554A4D9D44A627F8B9BA4F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Labor</header><paragraph id="HECB98BA64A3442ACB14E1279FD1E60A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contracts for installation of electric vehicle charging infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, a grant recipient shall ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that—</text><subparagraph id="HE0471D003A50484C8386F31318FEC37D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 40 percent of the employees of any nongovernmental entity that enters into a contract with such recipient, or a subcontract thereof, for the installation of electric vehicle charging infrastructure are—</text><clause id="HD088D2B8C8AF46D596E25078E5B02BE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>domiciled—</text><subclause id="HEAD0E83EEB42421E9E2794AE644E666D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the installation is carried out at a location in a major urban area, not further than 15 miles from the location of such installation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H708DF3CB5EAD4FC5B39E75FB39225EF6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the installation is not carried out at a location in a major urban area, not further than 50 miles from the location of such installation;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC16460BE2E5E4BE68ACFF49A3108D38D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>members of the Armed Forces or veterans;</text></clause><clause id="HC656C127CB5F4C31AFDA0A20598CB525"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">displaced and unemployed energy workers;</text></clause><clause id="H7B2DEE7ECC4949E4AAB0582150D08096"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>registered apprentices who have completed less than 15 percent of the required hours for the apprenticeship program in which they are enrolled; or</text></clause><clause id="HCD9ECF252E144E988395D43ADECCF477"><enum>(v)</enum><text>persons who—</text><subclause id="H480EA8C7B7A84A878ED4CC0DD0C8D8EA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>were formerly—</text><item id="H98D001B8796541F89A4B928DEE4C8F30"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>incarcerated in a juvenile or adult detention or correctional facility; or</text></item><item id="H8E4B067C7CCF43EBA17D793945932271"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>placed on probation, community supervision, or in a diversion program;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H751016AEBDC94303AF933B76AB791800"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are emancipated from the foster care system;</text></subclause><subclause id="H58A34E9A01EE41AEBA67AFF370D0FCF7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have a disability;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5E1982ADC1AA4981BCF53AC00E54C4D0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>are homeless;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEDC65210B532433EB9B9A194B4DF483E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>receive public assistance; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H023B7033CEE545C39A3CEAEB0888557D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>lack a general education or high school diploma; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8C3D27C4399473A810877633BAE4A9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 40 percent of the employees of any such entity hold an Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB92AC1038A34548A221591D960B47B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wages</header><subparagraph id="H4D985E8B14D7410C938E071F718B0725"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, a grant recipient shall ensure that all laborers and mechanics employed by a nongovernmental entity that enters into a contract for the performance of construction, alteration, or repair work that is facilitated, in whole or in part, by such grant, or a subcontract thereof, are paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction, alteration, or repair work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EE16A61216F45DDA9AD436E6CF9AE88"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Labor standards</header><text>With respect to the labor standards in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32903400AC384EDC85418D8A7CD3DAE5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2031.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8039DC877E334012A90323E5ECB01438"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEA96E77E9BC04E5CB520456C387711FF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric vehicle</term> means a vehicle that derives all or part of its power from electricity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24D9FF16188541B59307794011761C3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric vehicle charging infrastructure</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HD8870B6248D14A0B81F239A176494FEC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any property, other than a building or the structural components thereof, that is—</text><clause id="H5BD86030B5E94A81A10B8822AD620887"><enum>(i)</enum><text>used to charge electric vehicles;</text></clause><clause id="H0A15B302018B48F7A659A79A815AFF14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>present at the location where such vehicles are charged; and</text></clause><clause id="H708BE3AEA34C4A2191388D1DC8B95A6D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>available for use by members of the general public; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD65CA8F9381949E881EFD7BEA85A1F55"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any utility service connection, or utility panel upgrade, that is required for the charging of electric vehicles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4FC9962A6544D99772705459FE9827" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>electric vehicle sharing service</term> means a service that—</text><subparagraph id="H6A5AF0BB1F334B6EA2043147DA2D258D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allows an individual to apply for a membership that pre-approves the individual to rent electric vehicles from such service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9875559AEB45C79D021297E87CC128" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>permits pre-approved individuals to rent such vehicles for short periods of time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E8B8D8C3583431287424A51700299EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>final assembly</quote> means the process by which a manufacturer produces a new electric vehicle at, or through the use of, a plant, factory, or other place from which the vehicle is delivered to a dealer or importer with all component parts necessary for the mechanical operation of the vehicle included with the vehicle, whether or not the component parts are permanently installed in or on the vehicle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3A941A9E194A458450A5697EA59E4E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major urban area</term> means a metropolitan statistical area within the United States with an estimated population that is greater than or equal to 1,500,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2854FA2CF9042C5880DB19DEE0AE053" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>networked direct current fast charging equipment</term> means electric vehicle charging equipment that—</text><subparagraph id="H835FC863FE8D406BA241A880AEA7183C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides a direct current power source at a minimum of 50 kilowatts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ABF2160AE3D47B1B8CA0E7C0FD04980" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is enabled to connect to a network to facilitate data collection and access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D466AE9DAE04435A6AEFC6032C64B90"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>registered apprentice</term> means a person participating in a program registered pursuant to the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA1AB9D827234A5381D8C585E294A886"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

