<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H75737408440B460F9802545752E52F54" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8325 IH: Preventing Personal Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220711">July 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 41, United States Code, to prevent personal conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H97E7B0E1EED14F4696D4A19420131698" style="OLC"><section id="H4556A7488DAA49C999095D4FB6B26190" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Personal Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB33B9430D61945CE9E6B0E65B0DF3247"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preventing personal conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition</header><subsection id="H4FDFD98734884794B1F9892C17A4BAFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal acquisition regulation revisions</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall—</text><paragraph id="HD573DD068BE14327AFA19CFD430BF6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand the scope of rules to prevent personal conflicts of interest beyond the limited types of functions or services that are currently addressed in subpart 3.11 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, by including coverage for—</text><subparagraph id="HB1FBB85504694B709CFC846C13CA9E29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consulting, analytical, or advisory services supporting the primary missions, or services supporting the regulatory, policymaking, and adjudicative functions, of an Executive agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7165A4C0B0FA42B7A341BE673BFA7033"><enum>(B)</enum><text>functions closely associated with inherently governmental functions, as defined in the Federal Acquisition Regulation, that give rise to heightened concerns for personal conflicts of interest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H093F47E5527A4E3BB44F8893AF4EFA98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other functions or services that give rise to heightened concerns for personal conflicts of interest, as deemed appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8839BE88921A4A78B6B227BCB70541D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revise the Federal Acquisition Regulation to address the functions and services identified under paragraph (1), including by providing and updating—</text><subparagraph id="H4392EF98FF1E47BCA86BD31C65E8F37A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the definitions, policies, and procedures related to preventing potential personal conflicts of interest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A8D6A5943BE473EAB29478D8DD1C10D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solicitation provisions and contract clauses for Executive agencies to use in solicitations and contracts, where appropriate, to prevent personal conflicts of interest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE9806B29FB544B99277B2B49239B38A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the responsibilities of employers to screen their employees for personal conflicts of interest, to inform their employees of their legal duties related to preventing personal conflicts of interest and the appearance of personal conflicts of interest, and to seek compliance from their employees of such procedures and requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71181283ADC64B8AAB1A3221D45C1A23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the restrictions on a contractor’s employees disclosing, or using for personal gain, confidential information obtained in connection with performing the contract; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5917BCFD748F4E1FB97440F3EDBD4273"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the duties and procedures of reporting apparent violations of rules governing personal conflicts of interest, including to the agency’s Inspector General, where appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2493E67C42824BFC84690F76050180BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ethics safeguards related to contractor conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2303 of title 41, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H855D3AFB3B804BF1B1B92EAC42FB529E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H66902D26D5404F008F637AE501D396DC"><enum>2303.</enum><header>Ethics safeguards related to contractor conflicts of interest</header><subsection id="H5C48C7B933044A67BCB6A4E2EA1F0582"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy on personal conflicts of interest by contractor employees</header><paragraph id="HBEBE570971544575AA56BB941D60CB6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development and issuance of policy</header><text>The Administrator shall develop and issue a standard policy to prevent personal conflicts of interest by contractor employees performing the following functions for or on behalf of an Executive agency or department: </text><subparagraph id="H43F1AE23367B48DEB7139999A2AA2BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Relevant acquisition functions (including the development, award, and administration of Federal Government contracts).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H057FC9FD38624C34A2D2777BC17C39CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Consulting, analytical, and advisory services supporting the primary missions, or services supporting the regulatory, policymaking, and adjudicative functions, of an Executive agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CADD312038045A9A05F4731CA01B093"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other functions or services provided by contractors that present heightened risks of personal conflicts of interest, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0A34DC1238428396C2B17A0EBA07D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of policy</header><text>The policy shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7DEFE03226FD435D819CD8FA9AD6BC5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>define <quote>personal conflict of interest</quote> as it relates to contractor employees performing covered functions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H568A78AA6C394BA6ABBAFF19840F97B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require each contractor whose employees perform relevant acquisition functions to—</text><clause id="HB7945AAC57A643DA88126947FF72495E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify and prevent personal conflicts of interest for the employees;</text></clause><clause id="HA452BD05397C4BEF89AB2AEF76B72CD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prohibit contractor employees who have access to non-public government information obtained while performing covered functions from using the information for personal gain;</text></clause><clause id="H6DDCFC26CED1416184CD7673F7140B76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>report any personal conflict-of-interest violation by an employee to the applicable contracting officer or contracting officer’s representative as soon as it is identified;</text></clause><clause id="HB8AD61B21BA1463FB942BD08B0470C67"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>maintain effective oversight to verify compliance with personal conflict-of-interest safeguards;</text></clause><clause id="H7B0EE4C04C4C4AFDB1644D097E54F88D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>have procedures in place to screen for potential conflicts of interest for all employees performing covered functions; and</text></clause><clause id="H5F029615646A4E15B2A7E23C3A0AF74F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>take appropriate disciplinary action in the case of employees who fail to comply with policies established pursuant to this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A50671E6F0F476F8FF4ECC23429576F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract clause</header><subparagraph id="HAB41E99F845442A89CE1FB468F9132AD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Administrator shall develop a personal conflicts-of-interest clause or a set of clauses for inclusion in solicitations and contracts (and task or delivery orders) for the performance of covered functions that sets forth—</text><clause id="HCA7741F93E964B1A99B47CB0D9E9D7A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the personal conflicts-of-interest policy developed under this subsection; and</text></clause><clause id="H95CF599392A44D008AE567B1798EAD46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contractor’s responsibilities under the policy.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3589468E094347ECBB167ACE961DFAE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Updates to the clause or clauses identified in subparagraph (A) shall take effect one year after enactment, and shall apply to—</text><clause id="H01CE99FEE81E4291BEA10404E6B9E26E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contracts entered into on or after that effective date; and</text></clause><clause id="HC3E605F46F4943368EF1326FBD156798"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>task or delivery orders awarded on or after that effective date, regardless of whether the contracts pursuant to which the task or delivery orders are awarded are entered before, on, or after the effective date.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24A7F946672640CDBB3573873703A168" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partial applicability</header><text> If only a portion of a contract is for the performance of covered functions, then this subsection applies only to that portion of the contract.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB8186D785EF4F25BAAF14C01A5BDF33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Administrator shall, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, develop and maintain a repository of best practices relating to the prevention and mitigation of organizational and personal conflicts of interest in Federal contracting.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E70C37ED9A445CD8B7B36AAA1E6BBC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H809BE0870B5C4EFBAE77864D89548C2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered function</header><text>The term <quote>covered function</quote> means a function described under subsection (a)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA50F5948068646B598D29B42442EC46D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant acquisition function</header><text>The term <quote>relevant acquisition function</quote> means an acquisition function closely associated with inherently governmental functions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0EF307328D7C45EC8B0DFC4C13BA8B30"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition against certain conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/23">Chapter 23</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA33996C01F934CEC958037DF81E33563" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HBD20F41C374F47A2A839F8775CEB94AF"><enum>2314.</enum><header>Prohibition against certain conflicts of interest</header><subsection id="H59C1FD24D37E4AA6B3E8B25D581D5945" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition against certain conflicts of interest</header><paragraph id="H9B454999F2C94A7A98E98A8A20E1B171"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Contractors, contractor employees, and subcontractors and their employees shall not provide services supporting the regulatory, policymaking, or adjudicative functions of an Executive agency at the same time that the contractor, employees, or subcontractor provides services to an entity regulated by, or having non-routine business before, the agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB898F92B08C4E769B45F9E32CA29232"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><subparagraph id="HC4A8C8D282454CF18E893150123E91BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the executive agency may issue an exception to the requirement under paragraph (1) with respect to a contractor, employee, or subcontractor only if the head of the agency determines in writing there is a compelling reason to award a contract, or continue performance of a contract, with such exception.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8072604FB61A4B5197499E5761A6147E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>In determining whether there is a compelling reason under subparagraph (A), the head of an Executive agency shall consider—</text><clause id="H15CD9ED8F8B3413583C624DEE00214A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the nature and extent of the risks associated with the conflict;</text></clause><clause id="H5C4CCF3F33454349841FA0587B25681F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the essential need of the government to receive the services, notwithstanding such a conflict, and direct harm to the government of not receiving the services from the entity or person; and</text></clause><clause id="HDD149CAA8DCB4C2C8DA19F8CA620CAF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ability of the contractor, employee, or subcontractor to mitigate the conflict.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C39E02CB0D84DAC8487C43E372E3193"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Non-delegation of authority</header><text>The head of the Executive agency shall not delegate the authority to issue an exception under this subparagraph below the level of the head of a contracting activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C80E6654BC43E5B715393A5F826D32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public notice of issue of Exception</header><subparagraph id="H5D1BD16A76254EFB8CE8D3408BC5013D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>A notice of an exception issued pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be made publicly available in electronic format through the Government-wide point of entry, as defined in the Federal Acquisition Regulation, at the time of contract award, or at the time that an Executive agency decides to proceed with contract performance, if arising after award.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE2B37557A1D4FCD82BC0B4569BA3EB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of notification</header><text>The notice shall include, at a minimum—</text><clause id="HB210FF42104249EFAD15BF03BEA53F47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the contractor, employee, or subcontractor receiving the exception, although reasonable redactions should be made to the public version of the notice to protect the privacy of individual employees of a contractor or subcontractor; </text></clause><clause id="HA34039331EDE4A828070D4404D022FC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identification of the contract;</text></clause><clause id="H37A4F217CA0240D78994EA8DF86C0252"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the nature of the conflict;</text></clause><clause id="H0407121BF65D4D58A8E20091C01CE904"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the rationale for applying the exception; and </text></clause><clause id="H655DE9BCDBF649508EB9C8F64C1A98D6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the measures that will be taken to mitigate or avoid the conflict. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H929E8865AD154A0AB72DF84CBF69745B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosures and limitations for consultants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contractors providing consulting, analytical, or advisory services in support of the primary missions, or the regulatory, policymaking, or adjudicative functions, of an Executive agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H032232BAF459406599D79AD40587D0FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disclose, in sufficient detail, specific work performed in the last five years on behalf of any entities regulated by, or having non-routine business before, the Executive agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13BBAF2FBD394704B6A9BC1B2DAE8F87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the term of the contract, refrain from entering into consulting or other contractual arrangements with any entity to perform specific work that may reasonably create a conflict of interest, without receiving the written approval of the contracting officer before the execution of the contractual arrangement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B7526A98D174977849BED3326A29619"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><paragraph id="H611665A91D53410FBC4A7C771BD02747"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States against a person who knowingly violates the prohibitions under subsection (a) or fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9346710469D4FF39610068B182F314F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>On proof of that conduct by a preponderance of the evidence—</text><subparagraph id="H00B37974525E404AA841D48DC11DE2B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual shall be liable to the Federal Government for a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation plus the amount of compensation that the individual received under the corresponding Government contract; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC508C6139C41495995AB8D5BC86F9964"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an organization shall be liable to the Federal Government for a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each violation plus the amount of compensation that the organization received under the corresponding Government contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D3C38164B2456987FE898C96387B91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Statute of limitation</header><text>A civil action under paragraph (1) shall be brought within 6 years after the later of the date on which—</text><subparagraph id="H0C3FE7EF17564EF4A43647E6E7D77440"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prohibited conduct establishing the cause of action occurred; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842B428AC0B34F88A33889786D3408A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Government first knew or should reasonably have known that the prohibited conduct had occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4809D7808C994CDB92A4BCFB6F1C552F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>The civil penalties set forth in this subsection are not exclusive and do not limit the potential for a person that violates the prohibitions under subsection (a) or fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (b), to be found liable under the False Claims Act, section 3729 through section 3733 of title 31, or other applicable civil or criminal penalties, as prescribed by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF7169BDF9D040AFA7DD23BAEDF1085B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative actions</header><paragraph id="H4EBAD0DCC10E43AA815E00F134877A82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Types of action that an Executive agency may take</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Executive agency that receives information that a contractor or a person has failed to comply with a legal requirement to disclose an organizational conflict of interest or a personal conflict of interest, as defined in the Federal Acquisition Regulation, or has violated the prohibitions under subsection (a) or fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (b), shall consider taking one or more of the following actions, as appropriate:</text><subparagraph id="H2135806F432147988138001632597E11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Canceling the Executive agency procurement or disqualify a contractor from consideration, if a contract has not yet been awarded.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B60191DF58840A284C15328B6885F60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Terminating a contract with respect to which—</text><clause id="HB76B960588114F1AB4887A4A58FFDC28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the contractor or someone acting for the contractor has been held liable for an offense punishable under subsection (a); or</text></clause><clause id="HC3EFDC8AA00B4FACA5D1D134E2B8E0F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contracting officer determines that a person or contractor failed to disclose a material organizational or personal conflict of interest.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02E4E438511B4060A06CEBE0EBB9C502"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Initiating a suspension or debarment proceeding for the protection of the Federal Government in accordance with procedures in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H960FE215CA374E228243AD86E9DF0411"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount government entitled to recover</header><text>When a Federal agency terminates a contract pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), the Federal Government is entitled to recover, in addition to any penalty prescribed by law, the amount expended under the contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25AF5AD416534B8BAA2DB52FDE871B87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Present responsibility affected by conduct</header><text>For purposes of a suspension or debarment proceeding initiated pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), engaging in conduct constituting an offense under this section affects the present responsibility of a Federal Government contractor or subcontractor.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

