<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB57B3953ADE0482F88CB3F9EE01266E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7479 IH: To provide a means for Congress to prevent an organization’s designation as a foreign terrorist organization from being revoked by the Secretary of State.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7479</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000615">Mr. Pence</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide a means for Congress to prevent an organization’s designation as a foreign terrorist organization from being revoked by the Secretary of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC9CB45841E148C687FEE9F248D8219F" style="OLC"><section id="HBAD4668E244E469CAA6618E5DC2CBD94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Revocation of designation as foreign terrorist organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2F97E3DF23E243EAA41A4565C02D61B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HE5C43FC1A5E44E86AC8FFC2F20EEBB7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraph (5) or (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (5)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A3609DF394C4AC88C3D95283212FF4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (5)(B)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78D78934AF2C4775A2F5BEE25DF14B24"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (5) through (7) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9AC9BE78C42423EAE4CBF4C528BEE4B"><paragraph id="H157F2F41A86C498498131C33A21E7B8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Revocation</header><subparagraph id="H36D9BF5E88F340E8891E76BC27E6C63E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>By an act of congress</header><text>The Congress, by an Act of Congress, may block or revoke a designation made under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H042F1EE05E5741EF8298F57E11C96A03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Based on change in circumstances</header><clause id="HC895E6179B5E4EA385D732F94B6E9C6B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary shall revoke a designation made under paragraph (1) with respect to a particular organization if the Secretary determines, after completing a review in accordance with subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (4), that—</text><subclause id="H26D3CA15D3D341699DBA251739A71983"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the circumstances that were the basis for the designation have changed in such a manner as to warrant such revocation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H6FC40FCD217E43DC9BF4D0CF4EC80544"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the national security of the United States warrants such revocation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H354C4A61CEAC4438A0068A7A35F31AE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>A revocation under this subparagraph may not take effect before the date that is 45 days after the date on which the Secretary, by classified communication, submits written notification to the Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore, the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate, and the members of the relevant committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in writing, of the Secretary’s determination under clause (i), including the justification for such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E2C1984D221437DB6D0F5C90B08444B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint resolution</header><clause id="H045DF0C0D34447D59F89E38706D9216A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (B) shall not take effect with respect to a particular organization if Congress, during the 45-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary notifies Congress pursuant to clause (ii), enacts a joint resolution containing the following statement after the resolving clause: <quote>That the proposed revocation of the designation of ____________ as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)(1)</external-xref>) pursuant to the notification submitted to the Congress on ________ is prohibited.</quote>, with the first blank to be completed with the name of the foreign terrorist organization that is the subject of such proposed revocation and the second blank to be completed with the appropriate date.</text></clause><clause id="H5D0B7C2E44D544058DB95656B4741D97"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text>A joint resolution described in clause (i) and introduced within the appropriate 45-day period shall be considered in the Senate and in the House of Representatives in accordance with the procedures set forth in clauses (iii) through (x).</text></clause><clause id="H9E1F2DA8C9BE44A6BA84A07605D69667"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution described in clause (i) that is introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. A joint resolution described in subclause (I) that is introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>. Such a resolution may not be reported before the eighth day after its introduction.</text></clause><clause id="HA650D8309D394E2D96775DA871F832B9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>If the committee to which a joint resolution described in clause (i) is referred does not report such resolution (or an identical resolution) within 15 days after its introduction—</text><subclause id="H353356A165D34132B4C33A66807BFC44"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such committee shall be discharged from further consideration of such resolution; and </text></subclause><subclause id="HAA8D7B9BE50142948CB93694173BA988"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar of the House involved.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAAAF130AD0E449A19798123162F138F4"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Privileged motion</header><text>When the committee to which a resolution is referred has reported, or has been deemed to be discharged from further consideration of, a resolution described in clause (i), notwithstanding any rule or precedent of the Senate, including Rule 22, it is at any time thereafter in order (even if a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for any Member of the respective House to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution, and all points of order against the resolution (and against consideration of the resolution) are waived. The motion is highly privileged in the House of Representatives and is privileged in the Senate and is not debatable. The motion is not subject to amendment, to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider the vote by which such motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is agreed to, the resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the respective House until disposed.</text></clause><clause id="HEEBA2D2AEA194386AAF25329DA0D47CE"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>Debate on a joint resolution described in clause (i), and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution. A motion to further limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to the joint resolution, a motion to postpone, a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the resolution is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to is not in order.</text></clause><clause id="HE2C5A81B2CF84A748B2E3E8F900DE4E5"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Vote</header><text>Immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a joint resolution described in clause (i), and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the appropriate House, the vote on final passage of the resolution shall occur.</text></clause><clause id="HA98C4D5F96EF4DDBBB817A4F981087B7"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate or of the House of Representatives, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a joint resolution described in clause (i) shall be decided without debate.</text></clause><clause id="HCD05C8D4D2A8430F80F4F0A947C9A52D"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>If, before the passage by the Senate of a joint resolution of the Senate described in clause (i), the Senate receives a joint resolution described in clause (i) from the House of Representatives—</text><subclause id="H0C73B1442BCB4E0C8667770288148DCB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the resolution of the House of Representatives shall not be referred to a committee;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6304929E1C134A4D85C226A9C0D884A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to a joint resolution of the Senate described in clause (i)—</text><item id="HCCCF5C34662F4B9D9B258FFE112434C4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; and</text></item><item id="H1329892208DA4B558D859B61E509A5D4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the vote on final passage shall be on the resolution of the House of Representatives; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HF858681098454403B249D8E2BB020332"><enum>(III)</enum><text>upon disposition of the joint resolution received from the House of Representatives, it shall no longer be in order to consider the joint resolution that originated in the Senate.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3D43979D615144F0A23891B7C761D640"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Senate action</header><text>If the Senate receives a joint resolution described in clause (i) from the House of Representatives after the Senate has disposed of a joint resolution described in clause (i) that originated in the Senate, the action of the Senate regarding the disposition of the Senate originated resolution shall be deemed to be the action of the Senate with regard to the joint resolution that originated in the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAD11FDC1FFF4782AFDE731AD73527EC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>The revocation of a designation under this paragraph shall not affect any action or proceeding based on conduct committed before the effective date of such revocation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H950E181E2308426F9F1556934F2D398A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (6).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

