<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE29FDBCC189343EDA40AC2E2CB56D544" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7296 IH: Government Ownership and Oversight of Data in Artificial Intelligence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7296</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220330">March 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Artificial Intelligence Hygiene Working Group, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H66BFA3235CBE460BBD103A2A6D43E56F" style="OLC"><section id="H989C2EB00D3F46BBAB7326B6EFC69263" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Government Ownership and Oversight of Data in Artificial Intelligence Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GOOD AI Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDD481374D721494CB34E1B8AD101251D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Principles and policies for use of artificial intelligence in government</header><subsection id="H892B6CCB06264EC89383B6F12DE3CAC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB009F118501E4D2E9E25ED5A824F5B27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D61D2E98C614DD48EDA59532EF5A38F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBBF12492327F476D8D6B5523CE9FF732"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE66CCCBCC248BF952B403662AF96E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA62FC4D1014D4149AA6333964FD018FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2358">10 U.S.C. 2358</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81054EC6582E47E2901A4A36E69817B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence system</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H12134703B5014F458EFB2F23EBFAAE4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any data system, software, application, tool, or utility that operates in whole or in part using dynamic or static machine learning algorithms or other forms of artificial intelligence, including a data system, software, application, tool, or utility—</text><clause id="H3CB417A8EF2B478E86A7941618CD0D9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is established primarily for the purpose of researching, developing, or implementing artificial intelligence technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H110140B8591B4D2DB66AA638AE4D68FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the artificial intelligence capability is integrated into another system or agency business process, operational activity, or technology system; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FF5AF27986C4D1BB9AA63466195EF0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any common or commercial product within which artificial intelligence is embedded, such as a word processor or map navigation system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE13F5C78690495D954F84C638CF9AB7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6D1967F4FD649A88480310AD55FAA15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance for agency use of artificial intelligence</header><paragraph id="HF52D9E094266412499DE290466CD909D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In developing an update under section 104(d) of the AI in Government Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/11301">40 U.S.C. 11301</external-xref> note) to the memorandum issued under subsection (a) of that section, the Director shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="H1BD43DF4A9604F618623CD2D34D33D8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the considerations and recommended practices identified by the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence in the report entitled <quote>Key Considerations for Responsible Development and Fielding of AI</quote>, as updated in April 2021;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B5C387E697A4ADB85F01645FCB5E10C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the principles articulated in Executive Order 13960 (85 Fed. Reg. 78939; relating to promoting the use of trustworthy artificial intelligence in the Federal Government); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BD06E35B9034BAFA89894A855BDFB34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the input of—</text><clause id="H5284ADC9A60040D7A3EB5F55474DBC3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board;</text></clause><clause id="HB901C870245E4D4CAC2D2BDB0BA2D2D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>relevant interagency councils, such as the Federal Privacy Council, the Chief Information Officers Council, and the Chief Data Officers Council;</text></clause><clause id="H85EBDA00FD1644A7A4D32DFD3CC7DC19"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other governmental and nongovernmental privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties experts; and</text></clause><clause id="H9EC20F38EF5745EBB7BD79AFF9E19550"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other individual or entity the Director determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0514C8CB9894A34B021C659E32E5A56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This subsection shall cease to have force or effect on the date that is 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7DC1F31128744E986363BB5D969659C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence hygiene and protection of government information, privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties</header><paragraph id="H4F140BC944454E74BF46F4CAF4318330"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a working group to be known as the <quote>Artificial Intelligence Hygiene Working Group</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2EC1A1D0264E1789F5DF5FBBB7D85D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Director shall appoint members to the Artificial Intelligence Hygiene Working Group from among members of appropriate interagency councils.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1991E780B56C469AAE73CBABBC7C17B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with the Artificial Intelligence Hygiene Working Group, shall implement a means by which to—</text><subparagraph id="H74360C36068C4D66B92239A3A9B99129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that contracts for the acquisition of artificial intelligence and artificial intelligence systems—</text><clause id="H846C780CBD4843A3AF0755992593A0CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>align with the memorandum issued, and periodically updated, by the Director under subsections (a) and (d), respectively, of section 104 of the AI in Government Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/11301">40 U.S.C. 11301</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="H37DA695AA52B4DFCA2894D323682997C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>address the protection of privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties;</text></clause><clause id="HC9347FABD8944AD0A7667360EEF48DEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>address the ownership and security of data and other information created, used, processed, stored, maintained, disseminated, disclosed, or disposed of by a contractor or subcontractor on behalf of the Federal Government; and</text></clause><clause id="H878460CFA7434D41AF3967B25A6AB7E2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>address requirements for securing the training data, algorithms, and other components of any artificial intelligence system against—</text><subclause id="H575C204FC038491B8527EE5D5544ED9F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>misuse;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2F3590B2DEB04E9E9A6D66BF4580C9F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>unauthorized alteration;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFC9F1505576A47CD9723946FD1A93141"><enum>(III)</enum><text>degradation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1311B0AA07B643DCB64756A3CF318305"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>being rendered inoperable; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE339204ECF93465D9E2C8B66B0E1EC32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address any other issue or concern the Director determines relevant to ensure—</text><clause id="H49FC16B47F89441BBBEDFF04528697B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the appropriate use of artificial intelligence and artificial intelligence systems; and</text></clause><clause id="H16BEA2615FFC43159605B2B720F3A816"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the protection of privacy, Federal Government data, and other information of the Federal Government.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E47DB2EDC4741049833C3B813BE0296"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approaches</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (3), the Director may use 1 or more approach and tailor requirements based on risk or any other factor determined relevant by the Director and the Artificial Intelligence Hygiene Working Group.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F1F703D38034304B288710EB4B3313F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>On a continuous basis, not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Director shall update the means implemented under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C60CE317A004411AAABD994336F4CBF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, quarterly thereafter until the date on which the Director implements the means required under paragraph (3), and annually thereafter, the Director shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the implementation of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39D9DA8E4DA4DFD839CAB289C510592" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This subsection shall cease to have force or effect on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

