<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5E78157D03194A7683966254141983CA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7911 IH: Safe at Home Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7911</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220531">May 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To unify and strengthen the health and safety inspection standards for housing assisted under programs of the Departments of Housing and Urban Development and Agriculture, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H772A3FD9C1AB49B79436E5E2D8D603E8" style="OLC"><section id="H67FD3B0568294B3E82DFEE85C1E0043C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe at Home Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD88CC2691AAB46A9962A08DB48459041"><enum>2.</enum><header>Uniform inspection standards</header><subsection id="H52D86B7732074F0CACA0F1ED47DEE9C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly carry out a review of all Federal and State statutes, regulations, guidelines, standards, and other requirements applicable to housing assisted under any programs administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Department of Agriculture, respectively, including single-family and multifamily housing, that provide for inspections to ensure or promote the safety, healthiness, decency, habitability, sanitariness, or quality of the housing, and shall identify the requirements that are most stringent in providing protection to residents of the housing.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBA712C76239D4CE58465FFD0512152AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uniform standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly issue regulations that, notwithstanding any other provision of law or Federal regulation, apply the requirements identified pursuant to subsection (a) to all housing assisted under any programs administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Department of Agriculture, with any such variations and exemptions as may be necessary to account for differences in types of assisted housing structures. The regulations issued pursuant to this subsection shall take effect upon the expiration of the 6-month period beginning upon issuance of such regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD85C88EB698B4523AFF9636BA96D4863"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered housing</header><text>The term <quote>housing assisted under any programs administered the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Department of Agriculture</quote> includes—</text><paragraph id="H4464FCFC1815448E9483B7BF31D7876B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public housing, as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07190F752D364030AC6B4E547167FC8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>housing assisted with project-based assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC69CD9C6AB4C86B619ABDD6F6066D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted with tenant-based assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21AE720C178F4A3897B48CAAC5DCFC09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>housing assisted under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04101B8D14044F9EBA9C0001542E41B2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>housing assisted under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61229DAA8C3D4965A57259D7728B329D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C7890BE1AF34204836538F78A4F23A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under the HOME Investment Partnerships Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12721">42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B4AE31EAD7E4D26B60AE1AFE2740F08"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under section 236 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-1">12 U.S.C. 1715z–1</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D6889A6239843F5995BA1AF18B6605F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under the program under paragraph (3) of section 221(d) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715l">12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)</external-xref>) that bears interest at a rate determined under the proviso under paragraph (5) of such section 221(d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H419CFBE7ADC346E48BF4C5FE70AA3CB7"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rural housing assisted under section 514, 515, 516, 521, 533, 538, or 542 of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1484">42 U.S.C. 1484</external-xref>, 1485, 1486, 1490a, 1490m, 1490p–2, or 1490r); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD83F0EE5EB140B4B7A073B3ED0B5734"><enum>(11)</enum><text>housing assisted under any other programs administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Agriculture, as identified by such Secretaries.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

