<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E71DEC5B4D9411989EC61CAD4D953CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8104 IH: Defense Semiconductor Stockpile Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8104</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assess the semiconductor requirements of the Department of Defense in a conflict scenario, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H474BDBA5980B446A95E069AAB86FF2CF" style="OLC"><section id="HDC2CC7A7FDE044B883B879A6612D8214" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Semiconductor Stockpile Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H63A6095DB47B4C29994ED78FB34C8B51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and pilot program on semiconductors and the National Defense Stockpile</header><subsection id="H86FCAF5527AF47B78A6DF265087590AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><paragraph id="H99C81109042A4671A9826BE91F32ACAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall—</text><subparagraph id="H59E95093DC5F42D68810718E56DE87BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a study on the strategic materials required by the Department of Defense to execute the operational plans of the Department in a conflict with a strategic competitor lasting not less than six months; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B09316C5AE1473585EF3F23F844CBD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the congressional defense committees a report on such study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E5E46AC7ECB4452A40EBDB213C90270"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7411F4BB50754D7D89A359D6AC8B7E45"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the specific number and type of semiconductors for key systems and munitions, delineated by technical specifications, performance requirements, and end-use applications, that the Department of Defense requires to execute and sustain the operational plans of the Department during a conflict with a strategic competitor in the Indo-Pacific for not less than six months.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF38AFA3DC74FBB9E51A6E862A71D96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any supply chain vulnerabilities or choke points, including from sole sources of supply or geographic proximity to strategic competitors, involving the critical minerals and strategic raw materials (including chemicals) required to produce the semiconductors described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0607EA18DA00437B8890D55FF4F8C98E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of any supply chain vulnerabilities or choke points, including from sole sources, geographic proximity to strategic competitors, or legacy technology, involving the manufacturing equipment required for each step in the manufacturing process from the raw materials described in subparagraph (B) to the finished and operational semiconductor chip described in subparagraph (A), and an identification of potential secure sources of supply or manufacturing involving the United States, allied, or partner nations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880C040E5B044728ADA73411941B8FE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the ability of the Department of Defense and private industry, as appropriate, to procure the semiconductors described in subparagraph (A) and mitigate the vulnerabilities identified in subparagraphs (B) and (C), during a conflict with a strategic competitor in the Indo-Pacific lasting not less than six months, along with associated recommendations, any additional necessary authorities to carry out such recommendations, and the cost of each recommendation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB653E42B03D4E8287DDA8D066A4552C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A feasibility assessment and recommendations for acquiring for the National Defense Stockpile the semiconductors described in subparagraph (A), including the expected cost.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2267F8968A4F445CB783946C75BC70B9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of options to finance the cost of the recommendations described in subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57CD21E974BA42CBA00B758D74CB774B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HDACCFD3C59014F449B023FB3DE88F351"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Strategic competitor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>strategic competitor</term> means a country labeled as a strategic competitor in the document entitled <quote>Summary of the 2018 National Defense Strategy of the United States of America: Sharpening the American Military’s Competitive Edge</quote>, issued by the Department of Defense pursuant to section 113 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H262E76567F784E8E93879B53A03F268C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Strategic materials</header><text>The term <term>strategic materials</term> means—</text><clause id="HF0FD77A37881432F8538A34F56CB0328" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>semiconductors described in paragraph (2)(A);</text></clause><clause id="H12BBF0999AB94FF7B22B93F0DFB54AF0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>critical minerals and strategic raw materials described in paragraph (2)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="H0ED649E7FAEB4DC2BE774076AA6D670F" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>manufacturing equipment described in paragraph (2)(C).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B3251A292BD43CDB2B31695207BFA36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><paragraph id="H36B3A50C86AC4AB49A0039174B3C6DF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the submission of the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall acquire for the National Defense Stockpile the highest priority minerals, materials, or equipment identified in such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3D197735A4248C3A359F9D4BC0B0724"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the pilot program described in this subsection, and annually thereafter until the date described in paragraph (3), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the status and effects of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5273EC9DC4884180A4C9A55AB621ADE0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pilot program established under this subsection shall terminate on September 30, 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

