<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H3AC2A2078BB04C959BBF0422B7D8CB97" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3544 EH: Computers for Veterans and Students Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3544</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of General Services to transfer certain surplus computers and technology equipment to nonprofit computer refurbishers for repair, distribution, and return, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1364547B62524DBB9EB76C4DCBFEA6AD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6C09D80F78BB4575BCE25AB188027E8B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Computers for Veterans and Students Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COVS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC6CE292B0AC94C80BAF39EEEB2488770"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H54E9F4644E684E209C37E71B94F7EEB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Access to computers and computer technology is indispensable for success in the 21st century. Millions of Americans do not regularly use a computer and research shows that substantial disparities remain in both internet use and the quality of access with the digital divide concentrated among older, less educated, less affluent populations, especially veterans, low-income students, and senior citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF18B8BFF66942CCBC6C3E8BFBCCA06F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The COVID–19 pandemic has highlighted the gap between those with computer access and those without. Millions of students, their families, and workers from across the economy were unable to do schoolwork, work remotely from home, or connect to loved ones and their communities because of the digital divide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5E7A720A2864E2897A4E8CC3AA00FFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any Federal program that distributes surplus Federal computers to a public school, an educational nonprofit, or a nonprofit computer refurbisher for repair and distribution would benefit from a partnership with a nonprofit organization, whose mission is bridging the digital divide.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFD176169AAD7463BBD664815C37F4250"><enum>3.</enum><header>Refurbishment and distribution of surplus computers and technology equipment</header> <subsection id="HF99B422DE85D42B3815B9FA88F2E7E84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GSA transfer</header> <paragraph id="HD0E6D80F8FCA401BBB702008E92EE291"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after State agencies for surplus property have been given an opportunity to review surplus computer or technology equipment that has been determined to be repairable, the Administrator shall transfer to participating nonprofit computer refurbishers such equipment with full title to such equipment, for repair and distribution in accordance with subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D4D6F0C25084C988D9B8A0BD3999786" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on equipment refurbished</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit computer refurbisher that receives surplus computer or technology equipment under this subsection shall provide the Administrator with any information the Administrator determines to be necessary for required reporting, including information about the distribution of such equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51A4CA03BD454B7C80FB6E9984CEE46B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may establish a partnership with non-governmental entities, at no cost, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE798B4D3B1B84F6591BD7F8B9A61BD5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate the identification of nonprofit computer refurbishers and the distribution of surplus computer or technology equipment under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8542E00A12B344C4839A786E97D9C297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate the participation of nonprofit computer refurbishers under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3FE2E2E2C4A043C881473B5ECF69BB7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repair and distribution</header> 
<paragraph id="HD269E76F5A494AED903583A7704DA7CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Distribution to bridge the digital divide</header><text>A nonprofit computer refurbisher that receives equipment under subsection (a) shall repair and distribute such equipment to an educational institution, a veteran, an individual with a disability, a low-income individual, a student, or a senior in need that is residing or based in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B437EE0CC0F4179898A852E2A3BBACB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training programs</header><text>Any nonprofit computer refurbisher that receives any equipment under subsection (a) shall offer training programs on the use of computers and technology equipment for any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H00B83B0DC0574B738A1BE8643A2F6CCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Educational institutions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H036AC1AAAD0F44288F50A5D81839833C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F07148E11A746DBA2EA8775034B9B2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Individuals with disabilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1F4F973A7454E7290055F440B40E99F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Low-income individuals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CF2800E2A8A4BFAB8019A2707B360BF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Students.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD7CEF2805444BBFB022211BD228FDDC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Seniors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF2A2C927984D4248B71FBD27393976FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter for the next 4 years, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the efforts of the Administrator under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC8D9A659C1D746DCA38194403F1B33E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agency reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal agency shall make a report available to the public on the number of repairable computers that were sent to recycling, abandoned, or destroyed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA1F9A124E614A6B94B4D7930BB07FC0" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to supersede the requirements of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/480">Public Law 96–480</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3701">15 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CD7B35BD1394EFF9355A1CDED5B4586"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC3FD480E97A94943AC7A43AC347F133D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01854FEDC28F432F9D545A4AA847B460"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital divide</header><text>The term <term>digital divide</term> means the gap between those who have an internet-connected computer and the skills to use the computer and those who do not.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9945163B45648CF90E134B69B127476"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Educational institution</header><text>The term <term>educational institution</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H20818397FA714244A26F11D247946245"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any public or private child care center, preschool, elementary school, secondary school, accredited institution of vocational or professional education, or institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE22816B983C640EA9575DEB2B104A586"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an accredited institution of vocational or professional education or an institution of higher education composed of more than one school, college, or department that is administratively a separate unit, each such school, college, or department; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE8C13DFD0964D89B33FD763F3BD258E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a home school (whether treated as a home school or a private school for purposes of applicable State law).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9C23DCDFA1B4613B346C309F035CBD4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>federal agency</term> in section 102 of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CAF4B81A58F4051BDF7A3A36331FED7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H062BADD54A02480890D49DC424A5289F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5C0473C8C0E43EB9660E832BF7BA3D0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Low-income individuals</header><text>The term <term>low income individual</term> has the meaning given such term in section 351 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/689">15 U.S.C. 689</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H584991BCB72F49B1BBFBF0964705B843"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nonprofit computer refurbisher</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit computer refurbisher</term> means a nonprofit organization that primarily works to improve access to information and communication technology in their mission to bridge the digital divide.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H935E2E9EAC674C9FB48D5629FFD2B8A6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that is described under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCAD881087AF42ECA8C13D739EBC4839"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Repairable</header><text>The term <term>repairable</term> means property that is unusable in its current state but can be economically repaired.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD37957B0D9B84124B80937087B7AC7E4"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Secondary school</header><text>The term <term>secondary school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5BDA1343C0C4AAF93922256B1CDF81A"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Senior</header><text>The term <term>senior</term> means an individual who is 65 years of age or older.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48F60B54986640E3878FA0D83E54E502"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Senior in need</header><text>The term <term>senior in need</term> means a senior who experiences cultural, social, or geographical isolation that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6567D03CA5548ADAEDA12B24BE21998"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restricts the ability of the senior to perform normal daily tasks; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE04685D5DAB4A8DA012B4DEA38FE40E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>threatens the capacity of the senior to live independently.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA970E733BE9D413A95511F00CC62AAAB" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State agency for surplus property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State agency for surplus property</term> has the meaning given the term <term>state agency</term> under section 549 of title 40, United States Code. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4ADE382F5722407CA27D1094F1EC283C"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Student</header><text>The term <term>student</term> means any individual enrolled in an educational institution, but not a public or private child care center.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B20DF1E8DF4A4195954970F35CC8FA"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Surplus computer or technology equipment</header><text>The term <term>surplus computer or technology equipment</term> means computer or technology equipment that is property described under section 549(b)(2) of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB35D3584A8345369490B6D45AFBA875"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Technology equipment</header><text>The term <term>technology equipment</term> means any physical asset related to a computer or information technology, including any peripheral component, tablet, communication device (such as a router, server, or cell phone), printer, scanner, uninterruptible power source, cable, or connection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDEC42A52A2241559ED5E13971748A10"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H61734437D275412AA1F7B4E420F3F1FA" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may issue regulations that are necessary and appropriate to implement this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF687F5A6BB18467DA2983CE088D6DCC2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220712" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 12, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

