<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77A01D164476446881056BD4E613DCD0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8994 IH: Supporting Our First Responders Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8994</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Emergency Medical Services (EMS) Grant Program through which the Secretary may make grants to EMS organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H165CB0A6F4EA43F7AD809C856DFCB2BD" style="OLC">
<section id="H5896B1DD346C41D4AB57A9FFB168DB5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Our First Responders Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCDB49CC4B40E45D1A298E228E38B8DEC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency Medical Services Grant Program</header> <subsection id="H77091C039DBB4857B461371D431D5BAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency Medical Services Grant Program</header> <paragraph id="H39E11019E00B46E0800A4FE5E72A807B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Emergency Medical Services (EMS) Grant Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), through which the Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to EMS organizations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15D19DEFFC5447BFBAC36AF81BF0EDE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an EMS organization shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services an application at such a time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H85C21C018D06416FB0F858379BA3AA1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the financial need of the EMS organization.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H966163BCC1AE4C3B9B87BBE93DF59AED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the costs and benefits, with respect to improving medical transport and emergency medical services, of the activities to be carried out through the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25FF198F62294FEE8CB39E2DD7AC22C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An EMS organization may submit a joint application with one or more other EMS organizations under this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H006B772576824C1F80934F3C054A2E2B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Peer review of grant applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, after consultation with national EMS organizations, shall appoint representatives of volunteer, municipal, for-profit, and nonprofit EMS organizations and entities to conduct peer review of applications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C15F86E1D9D4590A5F892C8F3F73020"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prioritization of grant awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Program the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consider each of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H239454021C284E1DA508897BF47686D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The findings and recommendations of the peer reviews carried out under paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7587CAD63D8748CE88A0E34DE892AAF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The degree to which an award will improve the coverage, response times, and ability of EMS organizations to provide medical transport and emergency medical services.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H115E9D33E27A47169AD44B58FA94EF33"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent of the need of an applicant for a grant under this subsection and the need to protect the United States as a whole.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB207D15E782457D81DFFF11CCEFE32F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether an EMS organization has previously received Federal funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE30A5C87127E43B88F2A2D9460C1061F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>Grants made under the Program may be used by recipient EMS organizations for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H99E3A9725A214343BEAD9EC625A4D8EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintaining, or, if appropriate, increasing, the number of trained front-line EMS responders, including providing salaries and stipends, providing wellness and fitness programs for EMS organization personnel, and covering or reimbursing costs associated with certification and recertification courses.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC4352EBC77049D2ADECC9ADCB5A984E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obtaining resources, including purchasing EMS vehicles, personal protective equipment, uniforms, medicine, and medical supplies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F549C98BE4D4CA492D2BDCFFBB9B7E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Modifying facilities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1960617821CA4C0486DEC0FCCB7842CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other activity the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H36550FF568DB4217BD4AF443DB8FE1DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation of grant awards</header> <paragraph id="H0DD290EC65FE4B81A0D8D42FA8797ACC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than two percent of grants awarded under the Program may be made available to EMS organizations that operate for profit or to otherwise support efforts to establish or provide emergency medical services, or medical transport, for profit. A grant under the Program to such a for-profit EMS organization (if singly) or to such EMS organizations (if a result of a joint application) or to otherwise so support such efforts shall be in an amount not to exceed $100,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA39DDDCDB214D27BECF78725B0ADE3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Further limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under the Program to a not-for-profit EMS organization or a joint application shall be in an amount not to exceed $300,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCDC48656E5E4666A4A958C27DB1CB05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 20 percent of grants awarded under the Program shall be made available to EMS organizations in rural areas.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C9B7D1A8A274A9CA6563852E81F15A8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Metrics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop metrics to assess the effectiveness of the Program in improving the coverage, response times, and ability of EMS organizations to provide medical transport and emergency medical services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F082B0186384CD8A9E68532A2259529"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Claw backs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make every available effort to recover grant funds in case of noncompliance. To carry out this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a process through which notification is conveyed to EMS organizations determined to be in noncompliance, and such organizations are provided an opportunity to respond to such notification prior to the recovery of such funds.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5DA73F3E17A24D19B842E3DAD3C3BFA9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assessments; reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than biennially after, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE08A42A90882485EA0041414E20D14F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of the Program based on the metrics developed pursuant to subsection (d); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3711D17CB2944DEDAC3DB28489104238" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report summarizing the findings of the assessment and recommendations to strengthen the overall program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H87515AE4F9F445B3B8EF1CB1BE7F3EAC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text>
<paragraph id="H998AD11F990F414582FBEB75A4385381"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out the Program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H134D7A01EDF748CA880650F3AC152C8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for each of such fiscal years to provide technical assistance to EMS organizations completing and submitting applications.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2F11CAD2ECF44E6B8AA77591D8719D37"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDEC39AE9FDB34211BCFC0CD88B52003A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>EMS organization</header><text>The term <quote>EMS organization</quote> means a nongovernmental or governmental entity that provides medical transport and emergency medical services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC3372DE398F4191A5F621A96332A6D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emergency medical services</header><text>The term <quote>emergency medical services</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H5239520D83BB4272B917619B7CB8A875"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means resources used by a licensed entity to deliver medical care outside of a medical facility under emergency conditions that occur as a result of the condition of the patient; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD916E3EE8912456DA5493A97A574F387"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes services delivered (either on a compensated or volunteer basis) by an emergency medical services provider or other provider that is licensed or certified by the State involved as an emergency medical technician, a paramedic, or an equivalent professional (as determined by the State).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49B64FF2CEA64513AD1AE37AD388B44D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>rural area</quote> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5F1FAFD1F0714D8CA8A3A1F8CB49B295"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonmetropolitan statistical area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3321916A10394D1EA74D94BEAF38A259"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an area designated as a rural area by any law or regulation of a State; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HACA9C3313C2540CB839AA714724CE83D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a rural census tract of a metropolitan statistical area (as determined under the most recent rural urban commuting area code as set forth by the Office of Management and Budget).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA8C46D8C46604D6EB194BA8C486ED31A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="H22428E3DC47943E7AD8C25E522B25514"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and EMS stakeholders, shall submit to Congress a report that—</text>
<paragraph id="HCFB4FEED1AA541F98F2F5CDDAF5C578F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details the challenges, disparities, and inadequacies in providing Federal, State, and private (including commercial insurers) reimbursement for medical transport and emergency medical services; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65ACEDFB19504328929657C1A9207FF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides recommendations for improvement with respect to providing such reimbursement.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA772E5568A174EA38C4C828995479CDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>EMS organizations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and EMS stakeholders, shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H2F803D89581F48F0A6072EABAA9CCA4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the challenges specific to EMS organizations, including with respect to Federal, State, and private (including private insurers) reimbursement rates and policies; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0105B57961AC44C392C6F203DFB0A0CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains an action plan to address such challenges through grants and other administrative action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

