<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE08A61B26F14947A07C6D266600F81E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8483 IH: Wildfire Insurance Coverage Study Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require studies regarding insurance coverage for damages from wildfires, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3817CDD15B3641CBAECED3874E8502D0" style="OLC"><section id="H42B8949C6064419092028F7F8708AC61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Insurance Coverage Study Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF810CAE967994D68BB9873F58C77EA49"><enum>2.</enum><header>National wildfire risk assessment</header><subsection id="H7E972C9592C34254A4D6E0F8358019D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall, pursuant to the authority under section 1371 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4122">42 U.S.C. 4122</external-xref>), conduct a study regarding wildfire risk in the United States to—</text><paragraph id="HE623C859F76E4325B4BD92026D2EB612"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify trends in declarations for wildfires under the Fire Management Assistance grant program under section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>), with respect to geography, costs, probability, and frequency of wildfire disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70DB6AB353B9419F92F11A2102F62FDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify mitigation practices that would assist in reducing premiums for insurance policies covering damages from wildfires;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B3E4D35C09842F88AC496B0255DFF96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify existing programs of the Federal Government and State governments that measure wildfire risk and assess their effectiveness in forecasting wildfire events and informing wildfire response; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5FF8540E2AA4D2CBB9C9DE397FE6E78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyze and assess the need for a national map for measuring and quantifying wildfire risk.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D50C0E3532843E28CE2EB3CED8313F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Congress a report regarding the findings and conclusions of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a), which shall include a recommendation with regard to the need for a national map referred to in subsection (a)(4).</text></subsection></section><section id="HA998C0826672426EAF53D091B2FBE83F"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO study regarding insurance for wildfire damage</header><subsection id="H3B8C84F74E37479D8256409F7D4952C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Insurance Office and State insurance regulators, shall conduct a study to analyze and determine the following:</text><paragraph id="HF396229270BA47B18987D5BD4BC2FFAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing state of coverage</header><text>With respect to the existing state of homeowners insurance coverage and commercial property insurance coverage for damage from wildfires in the United States—</text><subparagraph id="H472ECC9CE8524880A9D48FF515F41FEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which private insurers have, during the 10-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, increased rates, cost-sharing provisions, or both for such coverage (after adjusting for inflation) and the geographic areas in which such increased rates, cost-sharing, or both applied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3372D195DC748B091C982FB69523801"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which private insurers have, during the 10-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, refused to renew policies for such coverages and the geographic areas to which such refusals applied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B0C3D8ACCDC445BBB76614E8188F0C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the events that have triggered such increased rates and refusals to renew policies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7DD80A613A44204B8830A34BA5281D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in cases in which private insurers curtail coverage, the extent to which homeowners coverage and commercial property coverage are terminated altogether and the extent to which such coverages are offered but with coverage for damage from wildfires excluded; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1326B003D804244B9732D2517A85BF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which, and circumstances under which, private insurers are continuing to provide coverage for damage from wildfires—</text><clause id="H3749E96FAAC64CC3A8FAE5F3D3CF3EB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in general;</text></clause><clause id="HB79B432AA8434DA5B893A02AC305D5DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to a condition that mitigation activities are taken, such as hardening of properties and landscaping against wildfires, by property owners, State or local governments, park or forest authorities, or other land management authorities; and</text></clause><clause id="HF35518FBD1BC4E89AA880BD331ABDCC2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject to any other conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C853DFDA71945B79FEABADB3ABD2E11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory responses</header><text>With respect to actions taken by State insurance regulatory agencies in response to increased premium rates, cost-sharing, or both for coverage for damage from wildfires and exclusion of such coverage from homeowners policies—</text><subparagraph id="H5AC1CF30E551463D8007228E74B4C5E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent of rate regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF72B35C222043A89C57BB327EB2F6DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent of moratoria on such rate and cost-sharing increases and exclusions and on non-renewals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H782D0D28CBA64922915E4B995B07C3AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which States require homeowners coverage to include coverage for damage from wildfires or make sales of homeowners coverage contingent on the sale, underwriting, or financing of separate wildfire coverage in the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E06F967AB944932A72016BAF387BD78"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which States have established State residual market insurance entities, reinsurance programs, or similar mechanisms for coverage of damages from wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3DC20251EAE448893A6BB73AC3FC6F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other actions States or localities have taken in response to increased premium rates, cost-sharing, or both for coverage for damage from wildfires and exclusion of such coverage from homeowners policies, including forestry and wildfire management policies and subsidies for premiums and cost-sharing for wildfire coverage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AFFEE9750174654A15A2312E72ACF10"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the effects on the homeownership coverage market of such actions taken by States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H996354A9E667453A997677763F5D74F2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the effectiveness and sustainability of such actions taken by States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DFBC5DE5CCD4C8A86F3CAB056AD7C4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Impediments in underwriting wildfire risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to impediments faced by private insurers underwriting wildfire risk, what is or are—</text><subparagraph id="H911FFC556F5B432AB035D4AD7F7034A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the correlated risks and the extent of such risks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C1FFE431D64F1A8933542515193D62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent of private insurers’ inability to estimate magnitude of future likelihood of wildfires and of expected damages from wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H737E218454BC4A46ACD9312AD2095C0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which need for affordable housing contributes to people relocating to more remote, heavily wooded areas with higher wildfire risk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6030B07BAF984AA98D56398FE36205E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the potential for wildfire losses sufficiently large to jeopardize insurers’ solvency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7280D383A86B465C812F9A2184B6E082"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which, and areas in which, risk-adjusted market premiums for wildfire risk are so high as to be unaffordable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65743EF7D65D4EFF822179877BFB1815"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the manners in which the Federal Government and State governments can alleviate any of these impediments, including through—</text><clause id="H4B74B29376AF4E349EFC6A4B68EF50CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improved forest management policies to reduce wildfire risk;</text></clause><clause id="HD72C18FE87A64644B12524B0DF90DD24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improved data to estimate risk;</text></clause><clause id="HB46FAF80E0784CC5BBD7072932C9B41A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relocating homeowners from wildfire zones;</text></clause><clause id="HF79B3EB200124C8782FFBD79D6C0B9B3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>allowing insurers to charge risk-adjusted premiums for wildfire risk, combined with subsidized premiums for lower-income homeowners; and</text></clause><clause id="H37901D7D12634E20AB0012E4E01BC03E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>taking a last-loss position in reinsuring wildfire risk;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA820F674823948EB99C91FE386BA62E5"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the available policy responses if private insurers exit the wildfire coverage market and the advantages and disadvantages of each such response;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4FF554046764D2387D13DDFF35ABAFC"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effects of lack of wildfire coverage or more expensive wildfire coverage rates, cost-sharing, or both—</text><clause id="HA5FD2FA174504203827A98C18D971022"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on local communities, including on low- or moderate-income property owners and small businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H9236B9CD27674483ABC0905D3F3A4E0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by race and ethnicity;</text></clause><clause id="H327AE18420D441E18E63F325EECCCC95"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on rebuilding in communities previously damaged by wildfires; and</text></clause><clause id="H23E4C6AEF3DC4E989ED72753D79A875C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>on the demand for wildfire coverage by property owners;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB3555611506495BA4AFF8CB133E3A24"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effects of potential State prohibitions on termination of policies due to wildfire claims on insurer solvency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5CBCCDA78974E25AB0FDE26BA1EA5B2"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the manner in which private insurers are modeling or estimating future wildfire risk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B8EAA0F68E44D2E9E3517B841A0C73D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 24-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Congress a report identifying the findings and conclusions of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

