<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E635BD75564444E9202E83D9DA8038B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9188 IH: Auto Theft Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9188</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221014">October 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide funding to State and local law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft and stolen automobile trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7875A46E85074EEB9A21B7DD8DFCF619" style="OLC"><section id="HE1F877E419D94E0C81EB1B9622427D73" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Auto Theft Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H892DD728CAB1413B9098098D0B2ABA75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Auto theft prevention grant program</header><subsection id="H966CF40EEE2E471EA2C2DBEFFE4D8A77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice shall establish an auto theft prevention grant program (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to provide funding to State law enforcement agencies and local law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft and stolen vehicle trafficking.</text></subsection><subsection id="H589CA3DBC6634434AFF1FEC79FF1B7AD" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The Director shall make grants under the Program to the Attorney General of each State, with the amount awarded determined by prioritizing States with a higher rate of auto thefts as determined by an equal weighting of the—</text><paragraph id="HF4470E8F974C4E419D546945BCE71720" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>rate of auto thefts faced by the State in the year prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B7302A8A1404BA6AB1DBE26DBA01C49" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">percentage increase in auto thefts between the year that is three years prior to the date of the enactment of this Act and the year prior to the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB65F9C803EE429B93858E29C92972F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><paragraph id="HB4384AB624E249358BBA93A8C4675093"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local law enforcement agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General of a State shall make at least 50 percent of a grant awarded under subsection (b) available as competitive subgrants to local law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft, with the amount awarded determined by prioritizing localities with a higher rate of auto theft as determined by an equal weighting of the—</text><subparagraph id="H867361647F2E4AF5895993F1B84AA921"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rate of auto thefts faced by the locality in the year prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C6B36C330DD4AC7A92A6ECF949740D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>percentage increase in auto thefts between three years prior to the date of the enactment of this Act and the year prior to the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3C27A2C9CBA4537A661241612EF816E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law enforcement agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General of a State shall make at least 25 percent of a grant awarded under subsection (b) available as competitive grants to State law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0895F8BE865B466BA0FDE5B09366BC95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General of a State shall make any proportion of the grant awarded under subsection (b) not allocated under paragraph (1) or (2) available as competitive subgrants to local law enforcement agencies or competitive grants to State law enforcement agencies. Any subgrant made under this paragraph to a local law enforcement agency shall follow the prioritization pursuant to paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H987EC4C8C9D340D8868E2EC16C9FE941"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from a grant awarded under subsection (b) may only be used for the purpose of combating auto theft and combating stolen automobile trafficking, including—</text><paragraph id="HF2F9856555CF4F5F8207CD27EB66B8F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchasing equipment used to combat auto theft, such as law enforcement vehicles and license plate readers; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C7C177566734676990E010BA2DA9B0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hiring additional law enforcement officers and support staff to combat auto theft; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2356CD79D6B42148DC6E18852464C33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funding overtime costs and additional compensation for law enforcement officers and support staff involved in combating auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76FADD7E57524B86A452FAC931509C4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing training for law enforcement officers and support staff to combat auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H684DE498D7A94BAC84F55079BF53BBE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing resources for joint task forces established to combat auto theft; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H368D05AB209547FF82D843F5DCF82E6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>funding law enforcement data collection and research activities related to combating auto theft.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4B251A868D540C4B270DF2F4275C48E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out the Program.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6A11823A37A04934B467D04CD4F0B617"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional authorized uses of cops grant program funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1701(b) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1670C43291B2414E8DA638A898728419"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (23) as paragraph (24);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12FA177CF4BE407CACCD8D244C6C82D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (22)—</text><subparagraph id="HC2648DA9FC41478FBA28D32477D4335C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(21)</quote> and inserting <quote>(22)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E01ADE3EDE745C9927C033FB37DF3AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (22) as paragraph (23); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2BD3873EFAF46FB9FA4AFE42328944B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (21), the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA021E4FFB1B744E3BA7FFC2EE4448622" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HDF182DE50ECF4C729903E6BBC82BA2A3"><enum>(22)</enum><text>to combat auto thefts and combat stolen automobile trafficking by purchasing equipment, hiring law enforcement officers and support staff, covering overtime and officer compensation costs, expanding access to training initiatives, funding joint task forces, and funding law enforcement data collection and research activities related to auto thefts;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H743CB8B099404B85A8DD4E412CCE154E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD842C1FF86FF427FA3F939D4DC2D6CB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <quote>local law enforcement agency</quote> means any entity administered by a locality that exists primarily to prevent and detect crime and enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4899C06171AB4809A631C93E71BA0A4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Locality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>locality</quote> means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38F30BDD4EEB4576BF9DD6201DA3BFFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF94CAA6350364CC693761A815D21099B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <quote>State law enforcement agency</quote> means any State entity that exists primarily to prevent and detect crime and enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

